<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Oncogenic Virus | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/oncogenic-virus/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/oncogenic-virus/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Oncogenic Virus</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Oncogenic Virus</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/oncogenic-virus/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Epstein-Barr virus miR-BART2-5p and miR-BART11-5p regulate cell proliferation, apoptosis, and migration by targeting RB and p21 in gastric carcinoma</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36418188/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36418188/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Epstein-Barr virus (EBV) was the first tumor virus discovered in humans and can cause various types of tumors. Molecular classification suggests that EBV-associated gastric cancer (EBVaGC) is a unique subtype of gastric cancer.EBV was also the first virus found to encode its own microRNAs. However, the functions of many miRNAs remain unknown. This study investigated the roles and targets of miR-BART2-5p (BART2-5p) and miR-BART11-5p (BART11-5p) in EBVaGC. The expression of RB and p21 in EBVaGC and EBV negative GC (EBVnGC) cells was evaluated by western blotting. Expression of BART2-5p and BART11-5p in EBVaGC cells was evaluated by droplet digital PCR. The effects of BART2-5p or BART11-5p and their potential mechanisms were further investigated using cell counting kit-8, colony formation assay, flow cytometry analysis, and transwell assay. BART2-5p and BART11-5p were abundantly expressed and RB and p21 were downregulated in EBVaGC cells. BART2-5p regulates RB and p21 expression by directly targeting them. BART11-5p regulates RB expression by directly targeting RB. Both BART2-5p and BART11-5p promoted proliferation and migration of gastric cancer cells, while inhibiting apoptosis and promoting S-phase arrest of the cell cycle. Thus, BART2-5p and BART11-5p play important roles in promoting proliferation and migration, and inhibiting apoptosis in EBVaGC by targeting RB and p21, thus providing new potential therapeutic targets for EBVaGC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Infection phase-dependent dynamics of the viral and host N6-methyladenosine epitranscriptome in the lifecycle of an oncogenic virus in vivo</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36401345/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36401345/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dynamic alteration of the epitranscriptome exerts regulatory effects on the lifecycle of oncogenic viruses in vitro. However, little is known about these effects in vivo because of the general lack of suitable animal infection models of these viruses. Using a model of rapid-onset Marek&amp;rsquo;s disease lymphoma in chickens, we investigated changes in viral and host mRNA N6-methyladenosine (m&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;A) modification during Marek&amp;rsquo;s disease virus (MDV) infection in vivo. We found that the expression of major epitranscriptomic proteins varies among viral infection phases, reprogramming both the viral and the host epitranscriptomes. Specifically, the METTL3/14 complex was suppressed during the lytic and reactivation phases of the MDV lifecycle, whereas its expression was increased during the latent phase and in MDV-induced tumors. METTL3/14 overexpression inhibits, whereas METTL3/14 knockdown enhances, MDV gene expression and replication. These findings reveal the dynamic features of the mRNA m&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;A modification program during viral replication in vivo, especially in relation to key pathways involved in tumorigenesis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Facts and Hopes in the Relationship of EBV with Cancer Immunity and Immunotherapy</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/35686929/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/35686929/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Epstein-Barr virus (EBV), the first identified human tumor virus, infects and takes up residency in almost every human. However, EBV genome-positive tumors arise in only a tiny minority of infected people, presumably when the virus-carrying tumor cells are able to evade immune surveillance. Traditional views regard viral antigens as the principal targets of host immune surveillance against virus-infected cells. However, recent findings indicate that EBV-infected/-transformed B cells elicit both cytotoxic CD8&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; and CD4&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T-cell responses against a wide range of overexpressed cellular antigens known to function as tumor-associated antigens (TAA), in addition to various EBV-encoded antigens. This not only broadens the ways by which the immune system controls EBV infection and prevents it from causing cancers, but also potentially extends immune protection toward EBV-unrelated cancers by targeting shared TAAs. The goal of this review is to incorporate these new findings with literature data and discuss future directions for improved understanding of EBV-induced antitumor immunity, as well as the hopes for rational immune strategies for cancer prevention and therapy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Time-resolved transcriptomes reveal diverse B cell fate trajectories in the early response to Epstein-Barr virus infection</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36044865/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36044865/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Time-resolved single-cell sequencing captures early host-EBV dynamics in B cells&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A refined germinal center model of EBV infection is validated by tonsil scRNA-seq&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;EBV-induced mimicry of a pre-GC AP-eMBC state is identified and validated in vitro&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;EBV &lt;em&gt;de novo&lt;/em&gt; infection yields non-canonical gene expression in TBX21&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; memory B cells&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Epstein-Barr virus infection of B lymphocytes elicits diverse host responses via well-adapted transcriptional control dynamics. Consequently, this host-pathogen interaction provides a powerful system to explore fundamental processes leading to consensus fate decisions. Here, we use single-cell transcriptomics to construct a genome-wide multistate model of B cell fates upon EBV infection. Additional single-cell data from human tonsils reveal correspondence of model states to analogous &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt; phenotypes within secondary lymphoid tissue, including an EBV&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; analog of multipotent activated precursors that can yield early memory B cells. These resources yield exquisitely detailed perspectives of the transforming cellular landscape during an oncogenic viral infection that simulates antigen-induced B cell activation and differentiation. Thus, they support investigations of state-specific EBV-host dynamics, effector B cell fates, and lymphomagenesis. To demonstrate this potential, we identify EBV infection dynamics in FCRL4&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt;/TBX21&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; atypical memory B cells that are pathogenically associated with numerous immune disorders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
