<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Aging/Senescence | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/aging/senescence/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/aging/senescence/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Aging/Senescence</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Aging/Senescence</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/aging/senescence/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>The metabolite alpha-ketobutyrate extends lifespan by promoting peroxisomal function in C. elegans</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36646719/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36646719/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Metabolism is intimately linked to aging. There is a growing number of studies showing that endogenous metabolites may delay aging and improve healthspan. Through the analysis of existing transcriptome data, we discover a link between activation of the transsulfuration pathway and a transcriptional program involved in peroxisome function and biogenesis in long-lived &lt;em&gt;glp-1(e2141ts)&lt;/em&gt; mutant &lt;em&gt;Caenorhabditis elegans&lt;/em&gt; worms. Subsequently, we show that supplementation with α-ketobutyrate, an intermediate of the transsulfuration pathway, extends lifespan in wild-type worms. Alpha-ketobutyrate augments the production of NAD&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; via the lactate dehydrogenase LDH-1, leading to SIR-2.1/SIRT1-mediated enhanced peroxisome function and biogenesis, along with a concomitant increase in the expression of &lt;em&gt;acox-1.2/ACOX1&lt;/em&gt; in the peroxisomal fatty acid β-oxidation pathway. ACOX-1.2/ACOX1 promotes H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; formation, thereby resulting in activation of SKN-1/NRF2. This transcription factor in turn extends the lifespan of worms by driving expression of autophagic and lysosomal genes. Finally, we show that α-ketobutyrate also delays the cellular senescence in fibroblast cells through the SIRT1-ACOX1-H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;-NRF2 pathway. This finding uncovers a previously unknown role for α-ketobutyrate in organismal lifespan and healthspan by coordinating the NAD&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt;-SIRT1 signaling and peroxisomal function.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hallmarks of aging: An expanding universe</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/36599349/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/36599349/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aging is driven by hallmarks fulfilling the following three premises: (1) their age-associated manifestation, (2) the acceleration of aging by experimentally accentuating them, and (3) the opportunity to decelerate, stop, or reverse aging by therapeutic interventions on them. We propose the following twelve hallmarks of aging: genomic instability, telomere attrition, epigenetic alterations, loss of proteostasis, disabled macroautophagy, deregulated nutrient-sensing, mitochondrial dysfunction, cellular senescence, stem cell exhaustion, altered intercellular communication, chronic inflammation, and dysbiosis. These hallmarks are interconnected among each other, as well as to the recently proposed hallmarks of health, which include organizational features of spatial compartmentalization, maintenance of homeostasis, and adequate responses to stress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meta-hallmarks of aging and cancer</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/36599298/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/36599298/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both aging and cancer are characterized by a series of partially overlapping &amp;ldquo;hallmarks&amp;rdquo; that we subject here to a meta-analysis. Several hallmarks of aging (i.e., genomic instability, epigenetic alterations, chronic inflammation, and dysbiosis) are very similar to specific cancer hallmarks and hence constitute common &amp;ldquo;meta-hallmarks,&amp;rdquo; while other features of aging (i.e., telomere attrition and stem cell exhaustion) act likely to suppress oncogenesis and hence can be viewed as preponderantly &amp;ldquo;antagonistic hallmarks.&amp;rdquo; Disabled macroautophagy and cellular senescence are two hallmarks of aging that exert context-dependent oncosuppressive and pro-tumorigenic effects. Similarly, the equivalence or antagonism between aging-associated deregulated nutrient-sensing and cancer-relevant alterations of cellular metabolism is complex. The agonistic and antagonistic relationship between the processes that drive aging and cancer has bearings for the age-related increase and oldest age-related decrease of cancer morbidity and mortality, as well as for the therapeutic management of malignant disease in the elderly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NIH SenNet Consortium to map senescent cells throughout the human lifespan to understand physiological health</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/s43587-022-00326-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/s43587-022-00326-5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cells respond to many stressors by senescing, acquiring stable growth arrest, morphologic and metabolic changes, and a proinflammatory senescence-associated secretory phenotype. The heterogeneity of senescent cells (SnCs) and senescence-associated secretory phenotype are vast, yet ill characterized. SnCs have diverse roles in health and disease and are therapeutically targetable, making characterization of SnCs and their detection a priority. The Cellular Senescence Network (SenNet), a National Institutes of Health Common Fund initiative, was established to address this need. The goal of SenNet is to map SnCs across the human lifespan to advance diagnostic and therapeutic approaches to improve human health. State-of-the-art methods will be applied to identify, define and map SnCs in 18 human tissues. A common coordinate framework will integrate data to create four-dimensional SnC atlases. Other key SenNet deliverables include innovative tools and technologies to detect SnCs, new SnC biomarkers and extensive public multi-omics datasets. This Perspective lays out the impetus, goals, approaches and products of SenNet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The ZIP8/SIRT1 axis regulates alveolar progenitor cell renewal in aging and idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35389887/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35389887/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Type 2 alveolar epithelial cells (AEC2s) function as progenitor cells in the lung. We have shown previously that failure of AEC2 regeneration results in progressive lung fibrosis in mice and is a cardinal feature of idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis (IPF). In this study, we identified deficiency of a specific zinc transporter, SLC39A8 (ZIP8), in AEC2s from both IPF lungs and lungs of old mice. Loss of ZIP8 expression was associated with impaired renewal capacity of AEC2s and enhanced lung fibrosis. ZIP8 regulation of AEC2 progenitor function was dependent on SIRT1. Replenishment with exogenous zinc and SIRT1 activation promoted self-renewal and differentiation of AEC2s from lung tissues of IPF patients and old mice. Deletion of Zip8 in AEC2s in mice resulted in impaired AEC2 renewal, increased susceptibility to bleomycin injury, and development of spontaneous lung fibrosis. Therapeutic strategies to restore zinc metabolism and appropriate SIRT1 signaling could improve AEC2 progenitor function and mitigate ongoing fibrogenesis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lung Imaging Reveals Stroke-Induced Impairment in Pulmonary Intravascular Neutrophil Function, a Response Exacerbated with Aging</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35365565/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35365565/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In stroke patients, infection is a significant contributor to morbidity and mortality. Moreover, older stroke patients show an increased risk of developing stroke-associated infection, although the mechanisms underlying this increased susceptibility to infection are unknown. In this study, using an experimental mouse model of ischemic stroke, we showed that older (12-15 mo of age) mice had elevated lung bacterial infection and inflammatory damage after stroke when compared with young (8-10 wk of age) counterparts, despite undergoing the same degree of brain injury. Intravital microscopy of the lung microvasculature revealed that in younger mice, stroke promoted neutrophil arrest in pulmonary microvessels, but this response was not seen in older poststroke mice. In addition, bacterial phagocytosis by neutrophils in the lung microvasculature was reduced by both aging and stroke, such that neutrophils in aged poststroke mice showed the greatest impairment in this function. Analysis of neutrophil migration in vitro and in the cremaster muscle demonstrated that stroke alone did not negatively impact neutrophil migration, but that the combination of increased age and stroke led to reduced effectiveness of neutrophil chemotaxis. Transcriptomic analysis of pulmonary neutrophils using RNA sequencing identified 79 genes that were selectively altered in the context of combined aging and stroke, and they were associated with pathways that control neutrophil chemotaxis. Taken together, the findings of this study show that stroke in older animals results in worsening of neutrophil antibacterial responses and changes in neutrophil gene expression that have the potential to underpin elevated risk of stroke-associated infection in the context of increased age.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Age-associated decline of MondoA drives cellular senescence through impaired autophagy and mitochondrial homeostasis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35235784/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35235784/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The transcription factor MondoA is identified as a regulator of cellular senescence&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MondoA counteracts senescence by activating autophagy via the suppression of Rubicon&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MondoA delays senescence by maintaining mitochondrial function through Prdx3&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Decrease of MondoA in the nucleus is correlated with senescence in human aging&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Accumulation of senescent cells affects organismal aging and the prevalence of age-associated disease. Emerging evidence suggests that activation of autophagy protects against age-associated diseases and promotes longevity, but the roles and regulatory mechanisms of autophagy in cellular senescence are not well understood. Here, we identify the transcription factor, MondoA, as a regulator of cellular senescence, autophagy, and mitochondrial homeostasis. MondoA protects against cellular senescence by activating autophagy partly through the suppression of an autophagy-negative regulator, Rubicon. In addition, we identify peroxiredoxin 3 (Prdx3) as another downstream regulator of MondoA essential for mitochondrial homeostasis and autophagy. Rubicon and Prdx3 work independently to regulate senescence. Furthermore, we find that MondoA knockout mice have exacerbated senescence during ischemic acute kidney injury (AKI), and a decrease of MondoA in the nucleus is correlated with human aging and ischemic AKI. Our results suggest that decline of MondoA worsens senescence and age-associated disease.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Epigenetic modifications in spinal ligament aging</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/35218968/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/35218968/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spinal ligament aging is a complex process involving genetic, epigenetic, and environmental factors.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;DNA methylation, histone modifications and ncRNAs exert vital functions in spinal ligament aging.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Epigenetic alterations provide promising diagnostic and therapeutic targets for spinal ligament aging.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spinal stenosis is a common degenerative spine disorder in the aged population and the spinal ligament aging is a main contributor to this chronic disease. However, the underlying mechanisms of spinal ligament aging remain unclear. Epigenetics is the study of heritable and reversible changes in the function of a gene or genome that occur without any alteration in the primary DNA sequence. Epigenetic alterations have been demonstrated to play crucial roles in age-related diseases and conditions, and they are recently studied as biomarkers and therapeutic targets in the field of cancer research. The main epigenetic modifications, including DNA methylation alteration, histone modifications as well as dysregulated noncoding RNA modulation, have all been implicated in spinal ligament aging diseases. DNA methylation modulates the expression of critical genes including WNT5A, GDNF, ACSM5, miR-497 and miR-195 during spinal ligament degeneration. Histone modifications widely affect gene expression and obvious histone modification abnormalities have been found in spinal ligament aging. MicroRNAs (miRNAs), long noncoding RNAs (lncRNAs) and circular RNAs (circRNAs) exert crucial regulating effects on spinal ligament aging conditions via targeting various osteogenic or fibrogenic differentiation related genes. To our knowledge, there is no systematic review yet to summarize the involvement of epigenetic mechanisms of spinal ligament aging in degenerative spinal diseases. In this study, we systematically discussed the different epigenetic modifications and their potential functions in spinal ligament aging process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Loss of legumain induces premature senescence and mediates aging-related renal fibrosis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35195326/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35195326/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aging is an independent risk factor for acute kidney injury and subsequent chronic kidney diseases, while the underlying mechanism is still elusive. Here, we found that renal tubules highly express a conserved lysosomal endopeptidase, legumain, which is significantly downregulated with the growing of age. Tubule-specific legumain-knockout mice exhibit spontaneous renal interstitial fibrosis from the 3rd month. In the tubule-specific legumain-knockout mice and the cultured legumain-knockdown HK-2 cells, legumain deficiency induces the activation of tubular senescence and thus increases the secretion of profibrotic senescence-associated cytokines, which in turn accelerates the activation of fibroblasts. Blockage of senescence mitigates the fibrotic lesion caused by legumain deficiency. Mechanistically, we found that silencing down of legumain leads to the elevated lysosome pH value, enlargement of lysosome size, and increase of lysosomal voltage dependent membrane channel proteins. Either legumain downregulation or aging alone induces the activation of nuclear transcription factors EB (TFEB) while it fails to further upregulate in the elderly legumain-knockdown tubules, accompanied with impaired mitophagy and increased mitochondrial ROS (mtROS) accumulation. Therapeutically, supplementation of exosomal legumain ameliorated fibronectin and collagen I production in an in vitro coculture system of tubular cells and fibroblasts. Altogether, our data demonstrate that loss of legumain in combined with aging dysregulates lysosomal homeostasis, although either aging or legumain deficiency alone induces lysosome adaptation via stimulating lysosomal biogenesis. Consequently, impaired mitophagy leads to mtROS accumulation and therefore activates tubular senescence and boosts the interstitial fibrosis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cucurbitacin E Triggers Cellular Senescence in Colon Cancer Cells via Regulating the miR-371b-5p/TFAP4 Signaling Pathway</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35192356/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35192356/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The induction of cellular senescence is considered as a potent strategy to suppress cancer progression. Cucurbitacin E (CE) belongs to the triterpenoids and has received substantial attention for its antineoplastic property. However, the function of CE on cellular senescence remained elusive. Herein, we revealed that CE significantly induced cellular senescence in colorectal cancer (CRC) cells. The CE effects on the cellular senescence in CRC cells were confirmed by observing the common features of the senescence, such as the enhanced activity of senescence-associated β-galactosidase, γ-H2AX positive staining, and upregulation of senescence-associated proteins including p53, p27, and p21. Moreover, CE exerted pro-senescent effects in CRC cells via attenuating the transcription factor activating enhancer-binding protein 4 (TFAP4) expression, and the ectopic expression of TFAP4 blocked the CE-induced senescence. Mechanistically, CE treatment caused a robust increase in miR-371b-5p, which markedly repressed TFAP4. In contrast, silencing of miR-371b-5p counteracted the percentages of CE-induced senescent cells from 37.49 ± 2.61 to 7.06 ± 0.91% in HCT-116 cells via derepressing TFAP4 to attenuate the expression of p53, p21, and p16. Altogether, these results demonstrated that dietary CE induces CRC cellular senescence via modulating the miR-371b-5p/TFAP4 axis and presents opportunities for potential therapeutic strategies against CRC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DNA methylation signatures in Blood DNA of Hutchinson-Gilford Progeria syndrome</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35045206/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35045206/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hutchinson-Gilford Progeria Syndrome (HGPS) is an extremely rare genetic disorder caused by mutations in the LMNA gene and characterized by premature and accelerated aging beginning in childhood. In this study, we performed the first genome-wide methylation analysis on blood DNA of 15 patients with progeroid laminopathies using Infinium Methylation EPIC arrays including 8 patients with classical HGPS. We could observe DNA methylation alterations at 61 CpG sites as well as 32 significant regions following a 5 Kb tiling analysis. Differentially methylated probes were enriched for phosphatidylinositol biosynthetic process, phospholipid biosynthetic process, sarcoplasm, sarcoplasmic reticulum, phosphatase regulator activity, glycerolipid biosynthetic process, glycerophospholipid biosynthetic process, and phosphatidylinositol metabolic process. Differential methylation analysis at the level of promoters and CpG islands revealed no significant methylation changes in blood DNA of progeroid laminopathy patients. Nevertheless, we could observe significant methylation differences in classic HGPS when specifically looking at probes overlapping solo-WCGW partially methylated domains. Comparing aberrantly methylated sites in progeroid laminopathies, classic Werner syndrome, and Down syndrome revealed a common significantly hypermethylated region in close vicinity to the transcription start site of a long non-coding RNA located anti-sense to the Catenin Beta Interacting Protein 1 gene (CTNNBIP1). By characterizing epigenetically altered sites, we identify possible pathways/mechanisms that might have a role in the accelerated aging of progeroid laminopathies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Hallmarks of Aging</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/23746838/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/23746838/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aging is characterized by a progressive loss of physiological integrity, leading to impaired function and increased vulnerability to death. This deterioration is the primary risk factor for major human pathologies, including cancer, diabetes, cardiovascular disorders, and neurodegenerative diseases. Aging research has experienced an unprecedented advance over recent years, particularly with the discovery that the rate of aging is controlled, at least to some extent, by genetic pathways and biochemical processes conserved in evolution. This Review enumerates nine tentative hallmarks that represent common denominators of aging in different organisms, with special emphasis on mammalian aging. These hallmarks are: genomic instability, telomere attrition, epigenetic alterations, loss of proteostasis, deregulated nutrient sensing, mitochondrial dysfunction, cellular senescence, stem cell exhaustion, and altered intercellular communication. A major challenge is to dissect the interconnectedness between the candidate hallmarks and their relative contributions to aging, with the final goal of identifying pharmaceutical targets to improve human health during aging, with minimal side effects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
