<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tissue Injury | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/tissue-injury/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/tissue-injury/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Tissue Injury</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Tissue Injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/tissue-injury/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interdependent Nuclear Co-Trafficking of ASPP1 and p53 Aggravates Cardiac Ischemia/Reperfusion Injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/23-01-01-10-14/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/23-01-01-10-14/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;OBJECTIVE:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ASPP1 (apoptosis stimulating of p53 protein 1) is critical in regulating cell apoptosis as a cofactor of p53 to promote its transcriptional activity in the nucleus. However, whether cytoplasmic ASPP1 affects p53 nuclear trafficking and its role in cardiac diseases remains unknown. This study aims to explore the mechanism by which ASPP1 modulates p53 nuclear trafficking and the subsequent contribution to cardiac ischemia/reperfusion (I/R) injury.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;METHODS AND RESULTS:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The immunofluorescent staining showed that under normal condition ASPP1 and p53 colocalized in the cytoplasm of neonatal mouse ventricular cardiomyocytes, while they were both upregulated and translocated to the nuclei upon hypoxia/reoxygenation treatment. The nuclear translocation of ASPP1 and p53 was interdependent, as knockdown of either ASPP1 or p53 attenuated nuclear translocation of the other one. Inhibition of importin-β1 resulted in the cytoplasmic sequestration of both p53 and ASPP1 in neonatal mouse ventricular cardiomyocytes with hypoxia/reoxygenation stimulation. Overexpression of ASPP1 potentiated, whereas knockdown of ASPP1 inhibited the expression of Bax (Bcl2-associated X), PUMA (p53 upregulated modulator of apoptosis), and Noxa, direct apoptosis-associated targets of p53. ASPP1 was also increased in the I/R myocardium. Cardiomyocyte-specific transgenic overexpression of ASPP1 aggravated I/R injury as indicated by increased infarct size and impaired cardiac function. Conversely, knockout of ASPP1 mitigated cardiac I/R injury. The same qualitative data were observed in neonatal mouse ventricular cardiomyocytes exposed to hypoxia/reoxygenation injury. Furthermore, inhibition of p53 significantly blunted the proapoptotic activity and detrimental effects of ASPP1 both in vitro and in vivo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;CONCLUSIONS:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Binding of ASPP1 to p53 triggers their nuclear cotranslocation via importin-β1 that eventually exacerbates cardiac I/R injury. The findings imply that interfering the expression of ASPP1 or the interaction between ASPP1 and p53 to block their nuclear trafficking represents an important therapeutic strategy for cardiac I/R injury.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Heparan sulfate proteoglycan-mediated internalization of extracellular vesicles ameliorates liver fibrosis by targeting hepatic stellate cells</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/2022-12-14-1024/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/2022-12-14-1024/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Accumulating evidence shows that stem cell-derived extracellular vesicles (EVs) have shown great promise for tissue regeneration and are considered an alternative to cell-based therapy. However, the mechanisms by which EVs induce tissue repair have not been well demonstrated. Previous work indicates that activation of hepatic stellate cells (HSCs) may contribute to the progression of liver fibrosis. Here, we investigate the therapeutic potential of EVs derived from human placental mesenchymal stem cells (hP-MSCs) for the treatment of carbon tetrachloride (CCl4)-induced liver injury. Our data revealed that EVs derived from hP-MSCs effectively ameliorate liver injury by attenuating inflammation and fibrosis. Further data revealed that heparan sulfate proteoglycans (HSPGs) on the surface of HSCs mediate the internalization of EVs. Furthermore, EVs could inhibit the epithelial–mesenchymal transition (EMT) process in HSCs through the downregulated TGF-/Smad pathway, which was mediated by miR-744-5p in EVs. Meanwhile, glycosaminoglycans on the surface of EVs play a crucial anti-inflammatory role. In conclusion, our results provide evidence that hP-MSC-derived EVs promote the recovery of liver injury by targeting HSPGs on HSCs and inhibiting liver inflammation through glycosaminoglycans from EVs. These findings may provide a novel theoretical basis for the treatment of liver fibrosis based on EVs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Long-Term Culture Captures Injury-Repair Cycles of Colonic Stem Cells</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/31708126/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/31708126/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The colonic epithelium can undergo multiple rounds of damage and repair, often in response to excessive inflammation. The responsive stem cell that mediates this process is unclear, in part because of a lack of in vitro models that recapitulate key epithelial changes that occur in vivo during damage and repair. Here, we identify a Hopx&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; colitis-associated regenerative stem cell (CARSC) population that functionally contributes to mucosal repair in mouse models of colitis. Hopx&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; CARSCs, enriched for fetal-like markers, transiently arose from hypertrophic crypts known to facilitate regeneration. Importantly, we established a long-term, self-organizing two-dimensional (2D) epithelial monolayer system to model the regenerative properties and responses of Hopx&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; CARSCs. This system can reenact the &amp;ldquo;homeostasis-injury-regeneration&amp;rdquo; cycles of epithelial alterations that occur in vivo. Using this system, we found that hypoxia and endoplasmic reticulum stress, insults commonly present in inflammatory bowel diseases, mediated the cyclic switch of cellular status in this process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tolerogenic signaling of alveolar macrophages induces lung adaptation to oxidative injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/31356919/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/31356919/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Inhaled oxidative toxicants present in ambient air cause airway epithelial injury, inflammation, and airway hyperresponsiveness. Effective adaptation to such environmental insults is essential for the preservation of pulmonary function, whereas failure or incomplete adaptation to oxidative injury can render the host susceptible to the development of airway disease.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Objective:&lt;/em&gt; We sought to explore the mechanisms of airway adaptation to oxidative injury.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; For a model to study pulmonary adaptation to oxidative stress-induced lung injury, we exposed mice to repeated nose-only chlorine gas exposures. Outcome measures were evaluated 24 hours after the last chlorine exposure. Lung mechanics and airway responsiveness to methacholine were assessed by using the flexiVent. Inflammation and antioxidant responses were assessed in both bronchoalveolar lavage fluid and lung tissue. Using both loss or gain of function and genomic approaches, we further dissected the cellular and molecular mechanisms involved in pulmonary adaptation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; Repeated exposures to oxidative stress resulted in pulmonary adaptation evidenced by abrogation of neutrophilic inflammation and airway hyperresponsiveness. This adaptation was independent of antioxidant mechanisms and regulatory T cells but dependent on residential alveolar macrophages (AMs). Interestingly, 5% of AMs expressed forkhead box P3, and depletion of these cells abolished adaptation. Results from transcriptomic profiling and loss and gain of function suggest that adaptation might be dependent on TGF-β and prostaglandin E&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/em&gt; Pulmonary adaptation during oxidative stress-induced lung injury is mediated by a novel subset of forkhead box P3-positive AMs that limits inflammation, favoring airway adaptation and host fitness through TGF-β and prostaglandin E&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gata6&#43; Pericardial Cavity Macrophages Relocate to the Injured Heart and Prevent Cardiac Fibrosis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/31315031/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/31315031/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Macrophages play an important role in structural cardiac remodeling and the transition to heart failure following myocardial infarction (MI). Previous research has focused on the impact of blood-derived monocytes on cardiac repair. Here we examined the contribution of resident cavity macrophages located in the pericardial space adjacent to the site of injury. We found that disruption of the pericardial cavity accelerated maladaptive post-MI cardiac remodeling. Gata6&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; macrophages in mouse pericardial fluid contributed to the reparative immune response. Following experimental MI, these macrophages invaded the epicardium and lost Gata6 expression but continued to perform anti-fibrotic functions. Loss of this specialized macrophage population enhanced interstitial fibrosis after ischemic injury. Gata6+ macrophages were present in human pericardial fluid, supporting the notion that this reparative function is relevant in human disease. Our findings uncover an immune cardioprotective role for the pericardial tissue compartment and argue for the reevaluation of surgical procedures that remove the pericardium.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>S100a8/a9 Signaling Causes Mitochondrial Dysfunction and Cardiomyocyte Death in Response to Ischemic/Reperfusion Injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/31220942/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/31220942/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Myocardial ischemia-reperfusion (MI/R) injury is a significant clinical problem without effective therapy. Unbiased omics approaches may reveal key MI/R mediators to initiate MI/R injury.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; We used a dynamic transcriptome analysis of mouse heart exposed to various MI/R periods to identify S100a8/a9 as an early mediator. Using loss/gain-of-function approaches to understand the role of S100a8/a9 in MI/R injury, we explored the mechanisms through transcriptome and functional experiment. Dynamic serum S100a8/a9 levels were measured in patients with acute myocardial infarction before and after percutaneous coronary intervention. Patients were prospectively followed for the occurrence of major adverse cardiovascular events.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; S100a8/a9 was identified as the most significantly upregulated gene during the early reperfusion stage. Knockout of S100a9 markedly decreased cardiomyocyte death and improved heart function, whereas hematopoietic overexpression of S100a9 exacerbated MI/R injury. Transcriptome/functional studies revealed that S100a8/a9 caused mitochondrial respiratory dysfunction in cardiomyocytes. Mechanistically, S100a8/a9 downregulated NDUF gene expression with subsequent mitochondrial complex I inhibition via Toll-like receptor 4/Erk-mediated Pparg coactivator 1 alpha/nuclear respiratory factor 1 signaling suppression. Administration of S100a9 neutralizing antibody significantly reduced MI/R injury and improved cardiac function. Finally, we demonstrated that serum S100a8/a9 levels were significantly increased 1 day after percutaneous coronary intervention in patients with acute myocardial infarction, and elevated S100a8/a9 levels were associated with the incidence of major adverse cardiovascular events.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; Our study identified S100a8/a9 as a master regulator causing cardiomyocyte death in the early stage of MI/R injury via the suppression of mitochondrial function. Targeting S100a8/a9-intiated signaling may represent a novel therapeutic intervention against MI/R injury.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Endotoxin Delivery Protein HMGB1 Mediates Caspase-11-Dependent Lethality in Sepsis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/30314759/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/30314759/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hepatocyte-released HMGB1 mediates caspase-11-dependent lethality in sepsis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;HMGB1-LPS complexes are taken up by macrophages and endothelial cells via RAGE&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;HMGB1 destabilizes phagolysosomes for the transfer of LPS to cytosolic caspase-11&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Neutralizing extracellular HMGB1 inhibits caspase-11 activation in sepsis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Summary&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Caspase-11, a cytosolic endotoxin (lipopolysaccharide: LPS) receptor, mediates pyroptosis, a lytic form of cell death. Caspase-11-dependent pyroptosis mediates lethality in endotoxemia, but it is unclear how LPS is delivered into the cytosol for the activation of caspase-11. Here we discovered that hepatocyte-released high mobility group box 1 (HMGB1) was required for caspase-11-dependent pyroptosis and lethality in endotoxemia and bacterial sepsis. Mechanistically, hepatocyte-released HMGB1 bound LPS and targeted its internalization into the lysosomes of macrophages and endothelial cells via the receptor for advanced glycation end-products (RAGE). Subsequently, HMGB1 permeabilized the phospholipid bilayer in the acidic environment of lysosomes. This resulted in LPS leakage into the cytosol and caspase-11 activation. Depletion of hepatocyte HMGB1, inhibition of hepatocyte HMGB1 release, neutralizing extracellular HMGB1, or RAGE deficiency prevented caspase-11-dependent pyroptosis and death in endotoxemia and bacterial sepsis. These findings indicate that HMGB1 interacts with LPS to mediate caspase-11-dependent pyroptosis in lethal sepsis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Targeting Degradation of the Transcription Factor C/EBPβ Reduces Lung Fibrosis by Restoring Activity of the Ubiquitin-Editing Enzyme A20 in Macrophages</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/31471107/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/31471107/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although recent progress provides mechanistic insights into the pathogenesis of pulmonary fibrosis (PF), rare anti-PF therapeutics show definitive promise for treating this disease. Repeated lung epithelial injury results in injury-repairing response and inflammation, which drive the development of PF. Here, we report that chronic lung injury inactivated the ubiquitin-editing enzyme A20, causing progressive accumulation of the transcription factor C/EBPβ in alveolar macrophages (AMs) from PF patients and mice, which upregulated a number of immunosuppressive and profibrotic factors promoting PF development. In response to chronic lung injury, elevated glycogen synthase kinase-3β (GSK-3β) interacted with and phosphorylated A20 to suppress C/EBPβ degradation. Ectopic expression of A20 or pharmacological restoration of A20 activity by disturbing the A20-GSK-3β interaction accelerated C/EBPβ degradation and showed potent therapeutic efficacy against experimental PF. Our study indicates that a regulatory mechanism of the GSK-3β-A20-C/EBPβ axis in AMs may be a potential target for treating PF and fibroproliferative lung diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
