<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>cGAS/STING | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/cgas/sting/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/cgas/sting/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>cGAS/STING</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>cGAS/STING</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/cgas/sting/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>CD-NTase family member MB21D2 promotes cGAS-mediated antiviral and antitumor immunity</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36681781/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36681781/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;cGAS/DncV-like nucleotidyltransferase (CD-NTase) family members are immune sensors that synthesize diverse nucleotide signals to initiate antiviral response in bacteria and animals. As a founding member of CD-NTase enzyme, cGAS has been identified as a key sensor for cytoplasmic DNA and type I interferons (IFNs) signaling in metazoan. However, the functions of other metazoan CD-NTases remain enigmatic. Here, we showed that Mab-21 domain-containing protein 2 (MB21D2), another member of the CD-NTase family, plays a positive role in modulating the cGAS-STING signaling in myeloid cells. Deficiency of MB21D2 in THP-1 cells or mice macrophages led to impaired production of type I interferon upon DNA stimulation. Consistently, &lt;em&gt;Mb21d2&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; mice showed more susceptible to infection with DNA virus and faster growth of melanoma, compared to its counterparts. Mechanistically, MB21D2 specially bound with the N-terminal of cGAS, facilitated its liquid phase condensation and DNA-binding activity, leading to the enhanced production of cGAMP and subsequent IFN-β production. Thus, our findings unveiled that the CD-NTase family member MB21D2 contributes to host antiviral and antitumor responses by enhancing cGAS activation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Activation of innate immune cGAS-STING pathway contributes to Alzheimer’s pathogenesis in 5×FAD mice</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/s43587-022-00337-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/s43587-022-00337-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;cGAS senses microbial and host-derived double-stranded DNA in cytoplasm to trigger cellular innate immune response in a STING-dependent manner; however, it remains unknown whether the cGAS-STING pathway in innate immunity contributes to Alzheimer’s disease (AD). Here we demonstrated the detectable binding of the cGAS double-stranded DNA in cytoplasm and the activation of the microglial cGAS-STING pathway in brains of human AD and aged mice. &lt;em&gt;Cgas&lt;sup&gt;−/−&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt;; 5×FAD mice were largely protected from cognitive impairment, amyloid-β pathology, neuroinflammation and other sequelae associated with AD. Furthermore, &lt;em&gt;Cgas&lt;/em&gt; deficiency in microglia inhibited a neurotoxic A1 astrocytic phenotype and thus alleviated oligomeric amyloid-β peptide-induced neurotoxicity. Finally, administration of STING inhibitor H-151 potently suppressed the activation of the cGAS-STING pathway and ameliorated AD pathogenesis in 5×FAD mice. In conclusion, our present study has identified a critical molecular link between innate immunity and AD and suggests that therapeutic targeting of the cGAS-STING pathway activity might effectively interfere with the progression of AD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lycopene Attenuates Di(2-ethylhexyl) Phthalate-Induced Mitochondrial Damage and Inflammation in Kidney via cGAS-STING Signaling</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36583613/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36583613/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Di(2-ethylhexyl) phthalate (DEHP) is a highly harmful and persistent environmental pollutant. Due to its unique chemical composition, it frequently dissolves and enters the environment to endanger human and animal health. Lycopene is a natural bioactive component that can potentially reduce the risk of environmental factor-induced chronic diseases. The present study sought to explore the role and underlying mechanism of lycopene (LYC) on DEHP-induced renal inflammatory response and apoptosis. In this study, mice were orally treated with LYC (5 mg/kg BW/day) and/or DEHP (500 or 1000 mg/kg BW/day) for 28 days. Our results indicated that LYC prevented DEHP-induced histopathological alterations and ultrastructural injuries, including decreased mitochondrial membrane potential (ΔΨm), PINK1/Parkin pathway-mediated mitophagy, and mitochondrial energetic deficit. When damaged mitochondria release mitochondrial DNA (mtDNA) into cytosol, LYC can alleviate inflammation and apoptosis caused by DEHP exposure by activating the cyclic GMP-AMP synthase-stimulator of interferon gene (cGAS-STING) signal pathway. Collectively, our data demonstrate that LYC can reduce mitophagy caused by DEHP exposure by activating the PINK1/Parkin pathway and then reduce renal inflammation and apoptosis through the cGAS-STING pathway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JMJD3 Is Required for Acute Pancreatitis and Pancreatitis-Associated Lung Injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36458991/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36458991/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acute pancreatitis (AP) can be complicated by inflammatory disorders of remote organs, such as lung injury, in which Jumonji domain-containing protein 3 (JMJD3) plays a vital role in proinflammatory responses. Currently, we found that JMJD3 expression was upregulated in the pancreas and lung in an AP male mouse model, which was also confirmed in AP patients. Further experiments revealed that the upregulation of JMJD3 and proinflammatory effects were possibly exerted by mitochondrial DNA (mtDNA) or oxidized-mtDNA from tissue injury caused by AP. The release of mtDNA and oxidized-mtDNA contributed to the infiltration of inflammatory monocytes in lung injury through the stimulator of IFN genes (STING)/TLR9-NF-κB-JMJD3-TNF-α pathway. The inhibition of JMJD3 or utilization of Jmjd3-cKO mice significantly alleviated pulmonary inflammation induced by AP. Blocking mtDNA oxidation or knocking down the TLR9/STING pathway effectively alleviated inflammation. Therefore, inhibition of JMJD3 or STING/TLR9 pathway blockage might be a potential therapeutic strategy to treat AP and the associated lung injury.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AMPK directly phosphorylates TBK1 to integrate glucose sensing into innate immunity</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36384137/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36384137/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Viral infection induces acute blood glucose decline in rodents that activates AMPK&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;AMPK directly phosphorylates TBK1 at S511 to prime antiviral sensing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;AMPK-TBK1 couples glucose deficiency sensing and innate immune surveillance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Targeting the AMPK-TBK1 axis compromises innate antiviral immunity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nutrient sensing and damage sensing are two fundamental processes in living organisms. While hyperglycemia is frequently linked to diabetes-related vulnerability to microbial infection, how body glucose levels affect innate immune responses to microbial invasion is not fully understood. Here, we surprisingly found that viral infection led to a rapid and dramatic decrease in blood glucose levels in rodents, leading to robust AMPK activation. AMPK, once activated, directly phosphorylates TBK1 at S511, which triggers IRF3 recruitment and the assembly of MAVS or STING signalosomes. Consistently, ablation or inhibition of AMPK, knockin of TBK1-S511A, or increased glucose levels compromised nucleic acid sensing, while boosting AMPK-TBK1 cascade by AICAR or TBK1-S511E knockin improves antiviral immunity substantially in various animal models. Thus, we identify TBK1 as an AMPK substrate, reveal the molecular mechanism coupling a dual sensing of glucose and nuclei acids, and report its physiological necessity in antiviral defense.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tegument protein UL21 of alpha-herpesvirus inhibits the innate immunity by triggering CGAS degradation through TOLLIP-mediated selective autophagy</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36343628/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36343628/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alpha-herpesvirus causes lifelong infections and serious diseases in a wide range of hosts and has developed multiple strategies to counteract the host defense. Here, we demonstrate that the tegument protein UL21 (unique long region 21) in pseudorabies virus (PRV) dampens type I interferon signaling by triggering the degradation of CGAS (cyclic GMP-AMP synthase) through the macroautophagy/autophagy-lysosome pathway. Mechanistically, the UL21 protein scaffolds the E3 ligase UBE3C (ubiquitin protein ligase E3C) to catalyze the K27-linked ubiquitination of CGAS at Lys384, which is recognized by the cargo receptor TOLLIP (toll interacting protein) and degraded in the lysosome. Additionally, we show that the N terminus of UL21 in PRV is dominant in destabilizing CGAS-mediated innate immunity. Moreover, viral tegument protein UL21 in herpes simplex virus type 1 (HSV-1) also displays the conserved inhibitory mechanisms. Furthermore, by using PRV, we demonstrate the roles of UL21 in degrading CGAS to promote viral infection in vivo. Altogether, these findings describe a distinct pathway where alpha-herpesvirus exploits TOLLIP-mediated selective autophagy to evade host antiviral immunity, highlighting a new interface of interplay between the host and DNA virus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Activation of Stimulator of IFN Genes (STING) Causes Proteinuria and Contributes to Glomerular Diseases</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36198430/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36198430/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; The signaling molecule stimulator of IFN genes (STING) was identified as a crucial regulator of the DNA-sensing cyclic GMP-AMP synthase (cGAS)-STING pathway, and this signaling pathway regulates inflammation and energy homeostasis under conditions of obesity, kidney fibrosis, and AKI. However, the role of STING in causing CKD, including diabetic kidney disease (DKD) and Alport syndrome, is unknown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; To investigate whether STING activation contributes to the development and progression of glomerular diseases such as DKD and Alport syndrome, immortalized human and murine podocytes were differentiated for 14 days and treated with a STING-specific agonist. We used diabetic db/db mice, mice with experimental Alport syndrome, C57BL/6 mice, and STING knockout mice to assess the role of the STING signaling pathway in kidney failure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;In vitro&lt;/em&gt;, murine and human podocytes express all of the components of the cGAS-STING pathway. &lt;em&gt;In vivo&lt;/em&gt;, activation of STING renders C57BL/6 mice susceptible to albuminuria and podocyte loss. STING is activated at baseline in mice with experimental DKD and Alport syndrome. STING activation occurs in the glomerular but not the tubulointerstitial compartment in association with autophagic podocyte death in Alport syndrome mice and with apoptotic podocyte death in DKD mouse models. Genetic or pharmacologic inhibition of STING protects from progression of kidney disease in mice with DKD and Alport syndrome and increases lifespan in Alport syndrome mice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/em&gt; The activation of the STING pathway acts as a mediator of disease progression in DKD and Alport syndrome. Targeting STING may offer a therapeutic option to treat glomerular diseases of metabolic and nonmetabolic origin or prevent their development, progression, or both.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mitochondrial DNA mediates immunoparalysis of dendritic cells in sepsis via STING signalling</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36106559/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36106559/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Mitochondrial DNA (mtDNA) is a potent activator for pro-inflammatory response. Dendritic cells (DCs) are immunosuppressed in sepsis, whether mtDNA mediates immunoparalysis in sepsis remains unknown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; The mRNAs were assessed by qPCR. Flow cytometry was used to measure the expression of costimulatory molecules and the proliferation of CD4&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T cells. Western blot and immunofluorescence staining were used to analyse the expression of proteins. Cytokine secretion was detected by ELISA. Histology of lung tissue was used to assess the inflammatory injury.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; Lipopolysaccharide-induced endotoxemia increased plasma mtDNA levels and immunoparalysis of spleen DCs, while hydrolysing mtDNA reversed immunoparalysis of spleen DCs in vivo. Moreover, cytoplasmic mtDNA of DCs was accumulated in endotoxemia and sepsis. mtDNA transfection into bone marrow-derived DCs (BMDCs) inhibited the expression of costimulatory molecules (e.g., CD40, CD80 and CD86) and the release of IL-12p70, while increasing the secretion of IL-10. Cytoplasmic mtDNA also inhibited the ability of BMDCs to promote the proliferation of CD4&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T cells. Mechanistic analysis revealed that STING signalling was required for mtDNA-mediated immunoparalysis of DCs in vivo and in vitro. Further studies showed deletion of STING reversed mtDNA-mediated immunoparalysis of DCs and improved the prognosis of endotoxemia and sepsis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/em&gt; Our results demonstrated that mtDNA promotes immunoparalysis of DCs, and contributes to sepsis-associated immunosuppression by activating STING signalling. Our study may provide new insights to elucidate the molecular pathogenesis of immunosuppressive DCs in sepsis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NAT10 regulates neutrophil pyroptosis in sepsis via acetylating ULK1 RNA and activating STING pathway</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36068299/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36068299/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Erratum in:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author Correction: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nature.com/articles/s42003-022-04045-w&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;NAT10 regulates neutrophil pyroptosis in sepsis via acetylating ULK1 RNA and activating STING pathway&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Emerging evidence suggests that pyroptosis is involved in sepsis. However, the role of neutrophil pyroptosis in sepsis and the mechanisms remains elusive. We find that N-acetyltransferase 10 (NAT10), an acetyltransferase responsible for the N4-acetylation of Cytidine (ac4C) in mRNA, is significantly downregulated in neutrophils from septic mice. Neutrophil-specific over-expression of NAT10 improves the survival and ameliorates lung injury in septic mice by inhibiting neutrophil pyroptosis. Notably, UNC-52-like kinase 1 (ULK1) is identified as the target of NAT10 in neutrophils. The decreased expression of NAT10 resultes in the decay of ULK1 transcripts and therefore the reduced expression of ULK1. As a regulator of STING phosphorylation, the loss of ULK1 enhances the activation of STING-IRF3 signaling and subsequently the elevated pyroptosis-inducing NLRP3 inflammasome in neutrophils. While over-expression of NAT10 restrains pyroptosis in neutrophils as well as septic lethality in mice by reversing the ULK1-STING-NLRP3 axis. The decreased expression of NAT10 are also observed in sepsis patients and its correlation with clinical severity is found. Collectively, our findings disclose that NAT10 is a negative regulator of neutrophil pyroptosis and its downregulation contributes to the progress of sepsis by exacerbating pyroptosis via the ULK1-STING-NLRP3 axis, therefore revealing a potential therapeutic target for sepsis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inhibition of the cGAS-STING Pathway Attenuates Lung Ischemia/Reperfusion Injury via Regulating Endoplasmic Reticulum Stress in Alveolar Epithelial Type II Cells of Rats</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36091334/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36091334/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Purpose:&lt;/em&gt; Endoplasmic reticulum stress (ERS) plays an important role in the pathogenesis of lung ischemia/reperfusion (I/R) injury. Cyclic GMP-AMP synthase (cGAS) is a cytosol dsDNA sensor, coupling with downstream stimulator of interferon genes (STING) located in the ER, which involves innate immune responses. The aim of our present study was to investigate the effects of cGAS on lung I/R injury via regulating ERS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; We used Sprague-Dawley rats to make the lung I/R model by performing left hilum occlusion-reperfusion surgery. cGAS-specific inhibitor RU.521, STING agonist SR-717, and 4-phenylbutyric acid (4-PBA), the ERS inhibitor, were intraperitoneally administered in rats. Double immunofluorescent staining was applied to detect the colocalization of cGAS or BiP, an ERS protein, with alveolar epithelial type II cells (AECIIs) marker. We used transmission electron microscopy to examine the ultrastructure of ER and mitochondria. Apoptosis and oxidative stress in the lungs were assessed, respectively. The profiles of pulmonary edema and lung tissue injury were evaluated. And the pulmonary ventilation function was measured using a spirometer system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; In lung I/R rats, the cGAS-STING pathway was upregulated, which implied they were activated. After cGAS-STING pathway was inhibited or activated in lung I/R rats, the ERS was alleviated after cGAS was inhibited, while when STING was activated after lung I/R, ERS was aggravated in the AECIIs, these results suggested that cGAS-STING pathway might trigger ERS responses. Furthermore, activation of cGAS-STING pathway induced increased apoptosis, inflammation, and oxidative stress via regulating ERS and therefore resulted in pulmonary edema and pathological injury in the lungs of I/R rats. Inhibition of cGAS-STING pathway attenuated ERS, therefore attenuated lung injury and promoted pulmonary ventilation function in I/R rats.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/em&gt; Inhibition of the cGAS-STING pathway attenuates lung ischemia/reperfusion injury via alleviating endoplasmic reticulum stress in alveolar epithelial type II cells of rats.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Targeting Myocardial Mitochondria-STING-Polyamine Axis Prevents Cardiac Hypertrophy in Chronic Kidney Disease</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36061341/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36061341/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HIGHLIGHTS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mitochondrial damage is early and prominent in cardiomyocytes under CKD milieu.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mitochondrial damage stimulates myocardial STING-NFκB pathway to drive hypertrophy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;NFκB transactivates ODC1-PUT metabolic flux in cardiomyocytes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ODC1-PUT metabolic flux is required for STING/NFκB-driven cardiac hypertrophy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Targeting mitochondria-STING-ODC1 axis prevents cardiac hypertrophy in CKD.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chronic kidney disease (CKD) is well recognized as a distinct contributor to cardiac hypertrophy, while the underlying mechanism remains incompletely understood. Here, the authors show that myocardial mitochondrial oxidative damage is early and prominent in CKD and distinctively stimulates the STING-NFκB pathway by releasing mitochondrial DNA to drive cardiac hypertrophy. Furthermore, the authors reveal that ornithine decarboxylase (ODC1)-putrescine metabolic flux is transactivated by NFκB and is required for the STING-NFκB pathway to drive cardiac hypertrophy. Finally, genetic or pharmacologic inhibition of the myocardial mitochondria-STING-NFκB-ODC1 axis significantly prevents CKD-associated cardiac hypertrophy. Therefore, targeting the myocardial mitochoandria-STING-NFκB-ODC1 axis is a promising therapeutic strategy for cardiac hypertrophy in patients with CKD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transcription-independent regulation of STING activation and innate immune responses by IRF8 in monocytes</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35973990/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35973990/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sensing of cytosolic DNA of microbial or cellular/mitochondrial origin by cGAS initiates innate immune responses via the adaptor protein STING. It remains unresolved how the activity of STING is balanced between a productive innate immune response and induction of autoimmunity. Here we show that interferon regulatory factor 8 (IRF8) is essential for efficient activation of STING-mediated innate immune responses in monocytes. This function of IRF8 is independent of its transcriptional role in monocyte differentiation. In uninfected cells, IRF8 remains inactive via sequestration of its IRF-associated domain by its N- and C-terminal tails, which reduces its association with STING. Upon triggering the DNA sensing pathway, IRF8 is phosphorylated at Serine 151 to allow its association with STING via the IRF-associated domain. This is essential for STING polymerization and TBK1-mediated STING and IRF3 phosphorylation. Consistently, IRF8-deficiency impairs host defense against the DNA virus HSV-1, and blocks DNA damage-induced cellular senescence. Bone marrow-derived mononuclear cells which have an autoimmune phenotype due to deficiency of Trex1, respond to IRF-8 deletion with reduced pro-inflammatory cytokine production. Peripheral blood mononuclear cells from systemic lupus erythematosus patients are characterized by elevated phosphorylation of IRF8 at the same Serine residue we find to be important in STING activation, and in these cells STING is hyper-active. Taken together, the transcription-independent function of IRF8 we describe here appears to mediate STING activation and represents an important regulatory step in the cGAS/STING innate immune pathway in monocytes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PARP inhibitor plus radiotherapy reshapes an inflamed tumor microenvironment that sensitizes small cell lung cancer to the anti-PD-1 immunotherapy</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35926817/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35926817/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PARPI plus radiation further activated cGAS/STING pathway than single treatment.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PARPI plus radiation upregulated the expression of PD-L1.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PARPI plus radiation sensitizes small cell lung cancer to anti-PD-1 immunotherapy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Small cell lung cancer (SCLC) is a highly malignant tumor with extremely poor prognosis. The treatment strategy is very limited, and patient outcomes remain dismal with the 5-year survival rate being mere 3-6%. Thus, novel therapeutic strategies for SCLC patients are urgently needed. In this study, we found that the triple-therapy of poly (ADP-ribose) polymerase (PARP) inhibitor, radiotherapy (RT) and anti-PD-1 treatment significantly inhibited tumor growth and prolonged survival in the syngeneic SCLC models in immunocompetent C57BL/6 mice. Mechanistically, we demonstrated that the combination of PARP inhibitor niraparib and RT reshaped an inflamed tumor microenvironment, including activation of the cGAS/STING immune response pathway, induction of immunogenic cell death, and upregulation of PD-L1 on tumor cells. Furthermore, this triple-therapy substantially augmented CD8+ T cell infiltration and activation, and enhanced anti-tumor effects as revealed by increased median survival time and reduced tumor volume without additional myelosuppression or hepatic injury. Together, our studies demonstrated that PARP inhibitor combined with RT potentiated anti-tumor immunity and enhanced the efficacy of anti-PD-1 immunotherapy in preclinical study, which provided a promising therapeutic strategy for SCLC patients in clinic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docetaxel resistance-derived LINC01085 contributes to the immunotherapy of hormone-independent prostate cancer by activating the STING/MAVS signaling pathway</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35868534/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35868534/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;LINC01085&lt;/em&gt; is deleted in hormone-independent prostate cancer (HIPC) which can predict better outcomes of HIPC patients.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;LINC01085 acts as a tumor suppressor in the tumourigenicity and metastasis of HIPC.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;LINC01085 exerts its functions by both interacting with TBK1 and GSK3β, accelerated TBK1 phosphorylation at the Ser-172 site, in HIPC.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;LINC01085 combined with PARP inhibitor and anti-PD-L1 treatment may be pivotal in the treatment of HIPC patients.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acquired docetaxel (doc) resistance, one of the major reasons for unfavorable prognosis in patients with aggressive hormone-independent prostate cancer (HIPC), is a major obstacle for patient treatment. Dysregulation of long non-coding RNAs promotes or suppresses chemoresistance in multiple cancers; however, the specific molecular mechanisms underlying HIPC remain unknown. In this study, we found that the LINC01085, as a tumor-suppressor, which showed significant clinically relevant in HIPC patients with doc-resistance. Mechanistically, in docetaxel-sensitive cells, LINC01085 could specifically bind to both TANK-binding kinase 1 (TBK1) and glycogen synthase kinase 3β (GSK3β), and higher LINC01085 RNA levels could inhibit TBK1 dimerization. Whereas, in doc-resistant cells, lower LINC01085 RNA level lost the strong binding with both, meanwhile, the interaction between TBK1 and GSK3β enhanced which accelerated TBK1 phosphorylation at the Ser-172 site, resulting in decreased expression levels of PD-L1 and NF-κB as well as the secretion of type I/III interferons. Thus, Overexpression of LINC01085 combined with immune checkpoint blockade is an effective strategy for the treatment of HIPC patients.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Insights on the cGAS-STING Signaling Pathway During Herpesvirus Infections</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/35844623/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/35844623/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Herpesviruses belong to large double-stranded DNA viruses. They are under a wide range of hosts and establish lifelong infection, which creates a burden on human health and animal health. Innate immunity is the host&amp;rsquo;s innate defense ability. Activating the innate immune signaling pathway and producing type I interferon is the host&amp;rsquo;s first line of defense against infectious pathogens. Emerging evidence indicates that the cGAS-STING signaling pathway plays an important role in the innate immunity in response to herpesvirus infections. In parallel, because of the constant selective pressure imposed by host immunity, herpesvirus also evolves to target the cGAS-STING signaling pathway to inhibit or escape the innate immune responses. In the current review, we insight on the classical cGAS-STING signaling pathway. We describe the activation of cGAS-STING signaling pathway during herpesvirus infections and strategies of herpesvirus targeting this pathway to evade host antiviral response. Furthermore, we outline the immunotherapy boosting cGAS-STING signaling pathway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New mechanism of nephrotoxicity of triptolide: Oxidative stress promotes cGAS-STING signaling pathway</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35697291/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35697291/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Triptolide activates the cGAS-STING signaling pathway in kidney tubular cells in vivo and in vitro.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;STING inhibitor C176 had protective effects in TPL-induced nephrocyte damage.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Triptolide induced an enhancement in protein levels of BACH1, while the expression of HMOX1 was reduced.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Oxidative stress-induced mtDNA damage and DNA leakage were the causes of the activation of cGAS-STING signaling pathway.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Triptolide (TPL) is a bioactive component extracted from the traditional Chinese herb Tripterygium wilfordii Hook F., and has multiple pharmacological activities, such as anti-tumor activity. However, severe adverse effects and toxicity, especially nephrotoxicity, limit its clinical application. It has been demonstrated that mitochondrial defect is a major toxic effects of TPL. In this study, we show that triptolide activated the cGAS-STING signaling pathway in kidney tubular cells in vivo and in vitro. Renal injury models were established in BALB/c mice and human tubular epithelial cells using TPL. We found that TPL enhanced the phosphorylation levels of STING, TBK1 and IRF3, and upregulated the expression of IFNβ, which is the production of cGAS-STING signaling pathway. STING inhibitor C176 had protective effects in TPL-induced nephrocyte damage. STING siRNA down regulated the expression level of IFNβ. In addition, triptolide induced an increase in protein levels of the transcription factor BACH1, while transcriptional expression of the antioxidant enzyme HMOX1 was reduced due to the increased expression of BACH1. Furthermore, oxidative stress-induced mtDNA damage and DNA leakage caused activation of the cGAS-STING signaling pathway. Altogether, cGAS-STING signaling pathway involved in TPL induced nephrotoxicity. Inhibiting cGAS-STING over-activation may be a new strategy for alleviating renal injury of triptolide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The gut microbiota prime systemic antiviral immunity via the cGAS-STING-IFN-I axis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35545033/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35545033/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Suppression of gut microbiota renders mice susceptible to systemic viral infections&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The gut microbiota drive systemic antiviral immunity via IFN-I priming&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Microbiota-driven IFN-I priming involves the cGAS-STING axis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Microbiota mediate systemic IFN-I priming via DNA-containing membrane vesicles&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The microbiota are vital for immune homeostasis and provide a competitive barrier to bacterial and fungal pathogens. Here, we investigated how gut commensals modulate systemic immunity and response to viral infection. Antibiotic suppression of the gut microbiota reduced systemic tonic type I interferon (IFN-I) and antiviral priming. The microbiota-driven tonic IFN-I-response was dependent on cGAS-STING but not on TLR signaling or direct host-bacteria interactions. Instead, membrane vesicles (MVs) from extracellular bacteria activated the cGAS-STING-IFN-I axis by delivering bacterial DNA into distal host cells. DNA-containing MVs from the gut microbiota were found in circulation and promoted the clearance of both DNA (herpes simplex virus type 1) and RNA (vesicular stomatitis virus) viruses in a cGAS-dependent manner. In summary, this study establishes an important role for the microbiota in peripheral cGAS-STING activation, which promotes host resistance to systemic viral infections. Moreover, it uncovers an underappreciated risk of antibiotic use during viral infections.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cytoplasmic PARP1 links the genome instability to the inhibition of antiviral immunity through PARylating cGAS</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35460603/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35460603/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;DNA damage induces the cytosolic translocation of PARP1 in an iNOS-dependent manner&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;DNA-PK phosphorylates PARP1 on Thr&lt;sup&gt;594&lt;/sup&gt; and instructs its cytosolic translocation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PARP1 PARylates human cGAS on D191 or mouse cGAS on E176 to terminate its DNA binding&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PARP1-mediated PARylation of cGAS inhibits antiviral immunity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Virus infection modulates both host immunity and host genomic stability. Poly(ADP-ribose) polymerase 1 (PARP1) is a key nuclear sensor of DNA damage, which maintains genomic integrity, and the successful application of PARP1 inhibitors for clinical anti-cancer therapy has lasted for decades. However, precisely how PARP1 gains access to cytoplasm and regulates antiviral immunity remains unknown. Here, we report that DNA virus induces a reactive nitrogen species (RNS)-dependent DNA damage and activates DNA-dependent protein kinase (DNA-PK). Activated DNA-PK phosphorylates PARP1 on Thr&lt;sup&gt;594&lt;/sup&gt;, thus facilitating the cytoplasmic translocation of PARP1 to inhibit the antiviral immunity both in vitro and in vivo. Mechanistically, cytoplasmic PARP1 interacts with and directly PARylates cyclic GMP-AMP synthase (cGAS) on Asp&lt;sup&gt;191&lt;/sup&gt; to inhibit its DNA-binding ability. Together, our findings uncover an essential role of PARP1 in linking virus-induced genome instability with inhibition of host immunity, which is of relevance to cancer, autoinflammation, and other diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cGAS modulates cytokine secretion and bacterial burdens by altering the release of mitochondrial DNA in pseudomonas pulmonary infection</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35420160/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35420160/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cyclic GMP-AMP synthase (cGAS) is essential for fighting against viruses and bacteria, but how cGAS is involved in host immune response remains largely elusive. Here, we uncover the crucial role of cGAS in host immunity based on a &lt;em&gt;Pseudomonas aeruginosa&lt;/em&gt; pulmonary infection model. &lt;em&gt;cGAS&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; mice showed more heavy bacterial burdens and serious lung injury accompanied with exorbitant proinflammatory cytokines than wild-type mice. cGAS deficiency caused an accumulation of mitochondrial DNA in the cytoplasm, which, in turn, induced excessive secretion of proinflammatory factors by activating inflammasome and TLR9 signalling. Mechanistically, cGAS deficiency inhibited the recruitment of LC3 by reducing the binding capacity of TBK-1 to p62, leading to impaired mitophagy and augmented release of mitochondrial DNA. Importantly, cytoplasmic mitochondrial DNA also acted as a feedback signal that induced the activation of cGAS. Altogether, these findings identify protective and homeostasis functions of cGAS against &lt;em&gt;Pseudomonas aeruginosa&lt;/em&gt; infection, adding significant insight into the pathogenesis of bacterial infectious diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LncRNA PCAT1 activates SOX2 and suppresses radioimmune responses via regulating cGAS/STING signalling in non-small cell lung cancer</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35415876/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35415876/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; The expression of long non-coding RNA (lncRNA) prostate cancer-associated ncRNA transcripts 1 (PCAT1) is increased in non-small cell lung cancer (NSCLC). It stimulates tumour growth and metastasis, but its role in the radioimmune responses remain unknown. We aimed to explore the impacts of PCAT1 on tumorigenesis and radioimmune responses and the underlying molecular mechanisms in NSCLC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; Comprehensive bioinformatics analysis was performed to identify immunosuppressive lncRNAs involved with tumour invasion in NSCLC. The expression levels of PCAT1 were analysed by in situ hybridisation in 55 paired NSCLC tissues and adjacent normal tissues. Both loss- and gain-of-function assays were performed to examine the effects of PCAT1 and SOX2 on NSCLC cell behaviours in vivo and in vitro. Bioinformatic analyses, chromatin isolation by RNA purification (ChIRP) and dual-luciferase reporter assays were applied to validate the regulatory effects of PCAT1 on SOX2 expression. Chromatin immunoprecipitation, luciferase and rescue assays were utilised to identify the relationship between SOX2 and the cGAS/stimulator of interferon genes (STING) signalling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; PCAT1 was immunosuppressive and related with NSCLC invasion. Increased PCAT1 was negatively correlated with immune cell infiltration in NSCLC. PCAT1 knockdown restrained proliferation, increased apoptosis, and repressed cell metastasis in vivo and in vitro. PCAT1 activated SOX2 that accelerated tumorigenesis and immunosuppression. SOX2 promoted tumour growth through inhibiting cytotoxic T-cell immunity. Moreover, SOX2 restrained cGAS transcription and hampered downstream type I interferon (IFN)-induced immune responses. Inhibition of PCAT1/SOX2 in collaboration with radiation further inhibited tumour growth, and initiated the cGAS/STING signalling pathway, which enhanced the immune responses of radiotherapy in NSCLC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; PCAT1/SOX2 axis promoted tumorigenesis and immunosuppression through inhibition of cGAS/STING signalling-mediated T-cell activation. Inhibition of PCAT1 and SOX2 synergised with radiotherapy to activate the immune response and could serve as potential therapeutic targets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
