<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data Visualization | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/data-visualization/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/data-visualization/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Data Visualization</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 14 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Data Visualization</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/data-visualization/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transformer for one stop interpretable cell type annotation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36641532/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36641532/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consistent annotation transfer from reference dataset to query dataset is fundamental to the development and reproducibility of single-cell research. Compared with traditional annotation methods, deep learning based methods are faster and more automated. A series of useful single cell analysis tools based on autoencoder architecture have been developed but these struggle to strike a balance between depth and interpretability. Here, we present &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/JackieHanLab/TOSICA&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;TOSICA&lt;/a&gt;, a multi-head self-attention deep learning model based on Transformer that enables interpretable cell type annotation using biologically understandable entities, such as pathways or regulons. We show that &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/JackieHanLab/TOSICA&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;TOSICA&lt;/a&gt; achieves fast and accurate one-stop annotation and batch-insensitive integration while providing biologically interpretable insights for understanding cellular behavior during development and disease progressions. We demonstrate &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/JackieHanLab/TOSICA&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;TOSICA&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s advantages by applying it to scRNA-seq data of tumor-infiltrating immune cells, and CD14&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; monocytes in COVID-19 to reveal rare cell types, heterogeneity and dynamic trajectories associated with disease progression and severity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VSOLassoBag: a variable-selection oriented LASSO bagging algorithm for biomarker discovery in omic-based translational research</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/vsolassobag/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/vsolassobag/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Screening biomolecular markers from high-dimensional biological data is one of the longstanding tasks for biomedical translational research. With its advantages in both feature shrinkage and biological interpretability, Least Absolute Shrinkage and Selection Operator (LASSO) algorithm is one of the most popular methods for the scenarios of clinical biomarker development. However, in practice, applying LASSO on omics-based data with high dimensions and low-sample size may usually result in an excess number of predictive variables, leading to overfitting of the model. Here, we present &lt;a href=&#34;https://seqworld.com/VSOLassoBag/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;VSOLassoBag&lt;/a&gt;, a wrapped LASSO approach by integrating an ensemble learning strategy to help select efficient, stable, and highly confidential variables from omics-based data. Using a bagging strategy in combination with a parametric method or inflection point search method, &lt;a href=&#34;https://seqworld.com/VSOLassoBag/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;VSOLassoBag&lt;/a&gt; can integrate and vote variables generated from multiple LASSO models to determine the optimal candidates. The application of &lt;a href=&#34;https://seqworld.com/VSOLassoBag/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;VSOLassoBag&lt;/a&gt; on both simulation datasets and real-world datasets shows that the algorithm can effectively identify markers for either case-control binary classification or prognosis prediction. In addition, by comparing with multiple existing algorithms, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://seqworld.com/VSOLassoBag/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;VSOLassoBag&lt;/a&gt; shows a comparable performance under different scenarios while resulting in fewer features than others. In summary, &lt;a href=&#34;https://seqworld.com/VSOLassoBag/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;VSOLassoBag&lt;/a&gt; provides an alternative strategy for screening reliable biomarkers from high-dimensional omics data. For user’s convenience, we implement &lt;a href=&#34;https://seqworld.com/VSOLassoBag/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;VSOLassoBag&lt;/a&gt; as an R package that provides multithreading computing configurations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Methods for inference and analysis of cell-cell communication</title>
      <link>https://example.com/blog/2023-01-02-infer-anal-ccc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/blog/2023-01-02-infer-anal-ccc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cellphonedb.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CellPhoneDB&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a publicly available repository of curated receptors, ligands and their interactions. Subunit architecture is included for both ligands and receptors, representing heteromeric complexes accurately. This is crucial, as cell-cell communication relies on multi-subunit protein complexes that go beyond the binary representation used in most databases and studies. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cellphonedb.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CellPhoneDB&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; integrates existing datasets that pertain to cellular communication and new manually reviewed information. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cellphonedb.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CellPhoneDB&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; utilises information from the following data bases: UniProt, Ensembl, PDB, the IMEx consortium, IUPHAR. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cellphonedb.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CellPhoneDB&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; can be used to search for a particular ligand/receptor or interrogate your own single-cell transcriptomics data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Reference(s):&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/34857954/&#34;&gt;Mapping the temporal and spatial dynamics of the human endometrium in vivo and in vitro&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/32103204/&#34;&gt;CellPhoneDB: Inferring cell-cell communication from combined expression of multi-subunit receptor-ligand complexes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Research into the Human Connectome has exploded since the original Human Connectome Project grants were awarded by the NIH in 2011. Over the next decade, we expect to see dozens of new projects at institutions around the world researching aspects of how age, growth, disease, and other factors can affect the ever-changing connections in the human brain. The &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.humanconnectome.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Connectome Coordination Facility (CCF)&lt;/a&gt; has been chartered to help coordinate these myriad research projects, harmonize their data, and facilitate the distribution and dissemination of results. The CCF has three primary aims:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Run a “data acquisition help desk,” to facilitate in the collection of HCP-style data for optimal comparability.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Maintain and expand the HCP informatics infrastructure, to host and distribute connectome data from multiple studies on &lt;a href=&#34;https://db.humanconnectome.org/app/template/Login.vm&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ConnectomeDB&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and Amazon Web Services.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Serve as a “harmonization center,” to make data from multiple studies and institutions as comparable as possible.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The goal of &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/arc85/celltalker&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;celltalker&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is to infer putative ligand and receptor interactions from single-cell RNAseq data. This is accomplished by evaluating known cognate ligand/receptor interactions across groups of cells. Interactions are scored by jointly weighting the expression levels of ligands and receptors, and significance is evaluated by comparing to a background distribution of scrambled ligands and receptors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Coolgenome/iTALK&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;iTALK&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is an R toolkit for characterizing and illustrating intercellular communication, developed and maintained by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mdanderson.org/research/departments-labs-institutes/labs/linghua-wang-laboratory.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Linghua Wang Lab&lt;/a&gt; at the University of Texas MD Anderson Cancer Center. &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Coolgenome/iTALK&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;iTALK&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; can be used to visualize the complexity, diversity and dynamics of cell-cell communication in a wide range of biological processes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Reference(s):&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/italk/&#34;&gt;iTALK: an R Package to Characterize and Illustrate Intercellular Communication&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Recent development of high throughput single-cell sequencing technologies has made it cost-effective to profile thousands of cells from a complex sample. Examining ligand and receptor expression patterns in the cell types identified from these datasets allows prediction of cell-to-cell communication at the level of niches, tissues and organism-wide. Here, we developed &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/forrest-lab/NATMI/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NATMI (Network Analysis Toolkit for Multicellular Interactions)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, a Python-based toolkit for multi-cellular communication network construction and network analysis of multispecies single-cell and bulk gene expression and proteomic data. &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/forrest-lab/NATMI/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NATMI&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; uses connectomeDB2020 (the most up-to-date manually curated ligand-receptor interaction list) and user supplied gene expression tables with cell type labels to predict and visualize cell-to-cell communication networks. By interrogating the Tabula Muris cell atlas we demonstrate the utility of &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/forrest-lab/NATMI/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NATMI&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; to identify cellular communities and the key ligands and receptors involved. Notably, we confirm our previous predictions from bulk data that autocrine signalling is a major feature of cell-to-cell communication networks and for the first time ever show a substantial potential for self-signalling of individual cells through hundreds of co-expressed ligand-receptor pairs. Lastly, we identify age related changes in intercellular communication between the mammary gland of 3 and 18-month-old mice in the Tabula Muris dataset. &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/forrest-lab/NATMI/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NATMI&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and our updated ligand-receptor lists are freely available to the research community.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fast, flexible and easy-to-use command-line tool to construct cell-to-cell communication networks from user-supplied multi-omics data (single-cell and bulk) in a variety of species.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Python-based (software requirements), but no additional coding in python is required. After the analysis is finished, results can be viewed directly or imported to other software of choice such as, for example, R or excel.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Built on connectomeDB2020 (default), but users can also add and interrogate their own interactions in any species or explore existing Tabula Muris, Tabula Muris Senis and FANTOM5 cell atlas datastets.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Reference(s):&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/33024107/&#34;&gt;Predicting cell-to-cell communication networks using NATMI&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cellchat.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CellChat Explorer&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; contains two major components: (a) Ligand-Receptor Interaction Explorer that allows easy exploration of our ligand-receptor interaction database, and (b) Cell-Cell Communication Atlas Explorer that allows easy exploration of the cell-cell communications for any given scRNA-seq dataset that has been processed by &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/sqjin/CellChat&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;R toolkit CellChat&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Reference(s):&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/33597522/&#34;&gt;Inference and analysis of cell-cell communication using CellChat&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/SCA-IRCM&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SingleCellSignalR&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a R package to study Cell Signaling Using Single Cell RNAseq Data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Reference(s):&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/32196115/&#34;&gt;SingleCellSignalR: inference of intercellular networks from single-cell transcriptomics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The goal of &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/saeyslab/nichenetr&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NicheNet&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is to study intercellular communication from a computational perspective. &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/saeyslab/nichenetr&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NicheNet&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; uses human or mouse gene expression data of interacting cells as input and combines this with a prior model that integrates existing knowledge on ligand-to-target signaling paths. This allows to predict ligand-receptor interactions that might drive gene expression changes in cells of interest.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Reference(s):&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/31819264/&#34;&gt;NicheNet: modeling intercellular communication by linking ligands to target genes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/blog/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Blog &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ggplot2</title>
      <link>https://example.com/books/2022-12-31-ggplot2-book-r-3ed/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/books/2022-12-31-ggplot2-book-r-3ed/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The book &lt;a href=&#34;https://ggplot2-book.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;ggplot2: Elegant Graphics for Data Analysis&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; gives some details on the basics of &lt;a href=&#34;https://cran.r-project.org/web/packages/ggplot2/index.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;ggplot2&lt;/a&gt;, its primary focus is explaining the Grammar of Graphics that &lt;a href=&#34;https://cran.r-project.org/web/packages/ggplot2/index.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;ggplot2&lt;/a&gt; uses, and describing the full details. It is not a cookbook, and won’t necessarily help you create any specific graphic that you need. But it will help you understand the details of the underlying theory, giving you the power to tailor any plot specifically to your needs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Major changes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Data Analysis&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Data Transformation&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Modelling for Visualisation&lt;/em&gt; chapters have been removed so that the book can focus on visualisation. If you’re looking for general advice on doing data science in R, I recommend &lt;a href=&#34;https://r4ds.had.co.nz/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;R for Data Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Toolbox&lt;/em&gt; chapter has been expanded into six chapters that cover practical applications of layers. This includes more material on maps and annotations, and a new chapter that discusses how to arrange multiple plots on one page.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Similarly, the old &lt;em&gt;Scales&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Axes&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Legends&lt;/em&gt; chapter has been split into into four chapters. The first three cover the practical combination of scales and guides for the most common scale types, and the final chapter focusses on the underlying theory.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The old &lt;em&gt;Positioning&lt;/em&gt; chapter has been split into new &lt;em&gt;Coordinate Systems&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Faceting&lt;/em&gt; chapters, giving more room for details on these important topics.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New chapters describe more about the internals of &lt;a href=&#34;https://cran.r-project.org/web/packages/ggplot2/index.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;ggplot2&lt;/a&gt;, and how you can extend it in your own package.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/books/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Books &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Metabolite annotation from knowns to unknowns through knowledge-guided multi-layer metabolic networking</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36333358/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36333358/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Liquid chromatography - mass spectrometry (LC-MS) based untargeted metabolomics allows to measure both known and unknown metabolites in the metabolome. However, unknown metabolite annotation is a major challenge in untargeted metabolomics. Here, we develop an approach, namely, &lt;a href=&#34;http://metdna.zhulab.cn/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;knowledge-guided multi-layer network (KGMN)&lt;/a&gt;, to enable global metabolite annotation from knowns to unknowns in untargeted metabolomics. The &lt;a href=&#34;http://metdna.zhulab.cn/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;KGMN&lt;/a&gt; approach integrates three-layer networks, including knowledge-based metabolic reaction network, knowledge-guided MS/MS similarity network, and global peak correlation network. To demonstrate the principle, we apply &lt;a href=&#34;http://metdna.zhulab.cn/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;KGMN&lt;/a&gt; in an in vitro enzymatic reaction system and different biological samples, with ~100-300 putative unknowns annotated in each data set. Among them, &amp;gt;80% unknown metabolites are corroborated with in silico MS/MS tools. Finally, we validate 5 metabolites that are absent in common MS/MS libraries through repository mining and synthesis of chemical standards. Together, the &lt;a href=&#34;http://metdna.zhulab.cn/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;KGMN&lt;/a&gt; approach enables efficient unknown annotations, and substantially advances the discovery of recurrent unknown metabolites for common biological samples from model organisms, towards deciphering dark matter in untargeted metabolomics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Circular visualization for high-throughput data</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tool/2022-11-03-data-circ-vis/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/tool/2022-11-03-data-circ-vis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Circular layout is an efficient way for the visualization of huge amounts of information and flexible NOT only for genomics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When faced with generating a visual representation of information, it&amp;rsquo;s useful to ask the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What are the important features and patterns I wish to communicate?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What are the unimportant features and patterns, and how can I effectively minimize their visual impact? Can I hide them altogether?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How dense (or sparse) is my data?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What data resolution is required? Can I bin the data, or show summary statistics instead of the data (e.g. min/avg/max)?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is the length scale of significant variation and non-signficant noise?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In what media will the figure be shown? How does the resolution of the media compare to the resolution of my data?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do I have the time/energy/motivation to worry about black-and-white reproduction or readers with color blindness?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://circos.ca/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Circos&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a software package for visualizing data and information. It visualizes data in a circular layout — this makes Circos ideal for exploring relationships between objects or positions. There are other reasons why a circular layout is advantageous, not the least being the fact that it is attractive. &lt;a href=&#34;http://circos.ca/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Circos&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is ideal for creating publication-quality infographics and illustrations with a high data-to-ink ratio, richly layered data and pleasant symmetries. You have fine control each element in the figure to tailor its focus points and detail to your audience. &lt;a href=&#34;http://circos.ca/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Circos&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is flexible. Although originally designed for visualizing genomic data, it can create figures from data in any field—from genomics to visualizing migration to mathematical art. If you have data that describes relationships or multi-layered annotations of one or more scales, &lt;a href=&#34;http://circos.ca/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Circos&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is for you. &lt;a href=&#34;http://circos.ca/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Circos&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; can be automated. It is controlled by plain-text configuration files, which makes it easily incorporated into data acquisition, analysis and reporting pipelines (a data pipeline is a multi-step process in which data is analyzed by multiple and typically independent tools, each passing their output as the input to the next step). Before &lt;a href=&#34;http://circos.ca/software/download/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;download&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://circos.ca/software/install&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;install&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://circos.ca/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Circos&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, you need to understand the &lt;a href=&#34;http://circos.ca/software/requirements/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;requirements&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. If you are a Windows user, read about pertinent &lt;a href=&#34;http://circos.ca/documentation/tutorials/configuration/unix_vs_windows/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;differences between UNIX and Windows&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. To learn how to use &lt;a href=&#34;http://circos.ca/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Circos&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;code&gt;free tutorials&lt;/code&gt; are also &lt;a href=&#34;http://circos.ca/documentation/tutorials/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;available online&lt;/a&gt;. Alternatively, you can &lt;a href=&#34;http://circos.ca/software/download/tutorials/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;click here&lt;/a&gt; and scroll down to the bottom to &lt;code&gt;download the tutorials&lt;/code&gt;, which contain many examples to demonstrate features of &lt;a href=&#34;http://circos.ca/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Circos&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
















&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-screen-shot-of-circos-website&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Screen shot of Circos website&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /media/circos_hu17fdf256f26ad48685fa2a1664a3a11d_533571_d1bef767c31e1a2df57446ad3bdbdf66.webp 400w,
               /media/circos_hu17fdf256f26ad48685fa2a1664a3a11d_533571_56a8051fc99ce5399b671648e28f044d.webp 760w,
               /media/circos_hu17fdf256f26ad48685fa2a1664a3a11d_533571_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos_3.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://example.com/media/circos_hu17fdf256f26ad48685fa2a1664a3a11d_533571_d1bef767c31e1a2df57446ad3bdbdf66.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;727&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption data-pre=&#34;Figure&amp;nbsp;&#34; data-post=&#34;:&amp;nbsp;&#34; class=&#34;numbered&#34;&gt;
      Screen shot of Circos website
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apart from &lt;a href=&#34;http://circos.ca/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Circos&lt;/a&gt;, an &lt;a href=&#34;https://cran.r-project.org/web/packages/available_packages_by_name.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;R package&lt;/a&gt; named &lt;a href=&#34;https://cran.r-project.org/web/packages/circlize/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;circlize&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; can help you as well. The &lt;a href=&#34;https://cran.r-project.org/web/packages/circlize/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;circlize&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; package was developed by Zuguang GU &lt;em&gt;etc.&lt;/em&gt; and published on &lt;a href=&#34;https://academic.oup.com/bioinformatics/article/30/19/2811/2422259?login=false&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Bioinformatics&lt;/a&gt; and is free available on &lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/24930139/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;. If you are to learn &lt;a href=&#34;https://cran.r-project.org/web/packages/circlize/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;circlize&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, you can turn to the &lt;code&gt;free online tutorial&lt;/code&gt;, which can be accessed by &lt;a href=&#34;https://jokergoo.github.io/circlize_book/book/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;clicking here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
















&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-circlize-implements-and-enhances-circular-visualization-in-r&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;circlize implements and enhances circular visualization in R&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /media/circlize_huc77ec5577e2e7d9b225bd6492fa8acd7_308457_5e1d5af82c3ed7faee828e7bb5a9389d.webp 400w,
               /media/circlize_huc77ec5577e2e7d9b225bd6492fa8acd7_308457_ec79e8c575d4d0cadd8b055f6b5d523d.webp 760w,
               /media/circlize_huc77ec5577e2e7d9b225bd6492fa8acd7_308457_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos_3.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://example.com/media/circlize_huc77ec5577e2e7d9b225bd6492fa8acd7_308457_5e1d5af82c3ed7faee828e7bb5a9389d.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;491&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption data-pre=&#34;Figure&amp;nbsp;&#34; data-post=&#34;:&amp;nbsp;&#34; class=&#34;numbered&#34;&gt;
      circlize implements and enhances circular visualization in R
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/tag/softwares/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Softwares &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/tool/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Tools &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ggtree: A serialized data object for visualization of a phylogenetic tree and annotation data</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/imt2.56/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/imt2.56/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The phylogenetic tree and diverse accompanying data can be stored in a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bioconductor.org/packages/ggtree&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;ggtree&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; graph object, which improves the reproducibility and reusability of phylogenetic data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The phylogenetic tree and associated data can be extracted from the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bioconductor.org/packages/ggtree&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;ggtree&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; object, which can be reanalyzed and help various scientific disciplines synthesize their comparative studies and phylogenetic information.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bioconductor.org/packages/ggtree&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;ggtree&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; graph object can be rendered as a static image, and the visualization directives that were previously saved in the object can be reused to display a different tree object in a manner akin to Microsoft Word Format Painter.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While phylogenetic trees and associated data have been getting easier to generate, it has been difficult to reuse, combine, and synthesize the information they provided, because published trees are often only available as image files and associated data are often stored in incompatible formats. To increase the reproducibility and reusability of phylogenetic data, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bioconductor.org/packages/ggtree&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;ggtree&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; object was designed for storing phylogenetic tree and associated data, as well as visualization directives. The &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bioconductor.org/packages/ggtree&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;ggtree&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; object itself is a graphic object and can be rendered as a static image. More importantly, the input tree and associated data that are used in visualization can be extracted from the graphic object, making it an ideal data structure for publishing tree (image, tree, and data in one single object) and thus enhancing data reuse and analytical reproducibility, as well as facilitating integrative and comparative studies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python for Data Analysis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/books/2022-09-20-py-data-anal/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/books/2022-09-20-py-data-anal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The 3rd edition of &lt;a href=&#34;https://wesmckinney.com/book&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Python for Data Analysis&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is now available as an “Open Access” HTML version in addition to the usual print and e-book formats. This edition was initially published in August 2022 and will have errata fixed periodically over the coming months and years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/books/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Books &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>scRNA-seq of gastric tumor shows complex intercellular interaction with an alternative T cell exhaustion trajectory</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35999201/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35999201/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tumor microenvironment (TME) in gastric cancer (GC) has been shown to be important for tumor control but the specific characteristics for GC are not fully appreciated. We generated an atlas of 166,533 cells from 10 GC patients with matched paratumor tissues and blood. Our results show tumor-associated stromal cells (TASCs) have upregulated activity of Wnt signaling and angiogenesis, and are negatively correlated with survival. Tumor-associated macrophages and LAMP3&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; DCs are involved in mediating T cell activity and form intercellular interaction hubs with TASCs. Clonotype and trajectory analysis demonstrates that Tc17 (IL-17&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt;CD8&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T cells) originate from tissue-resident memory T cells and can subsequently differentiate into exhausted T cells, suggesting an alternative pathway for T cell exhaustion. Our results indicate that IL17&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; cells may promote tumor progression through IL17, IL22, and IL26 signaling, highlighting the possibility of targeting IL17&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; cells and associated signaling pathways as a therapeutic strategy to treat GC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>massDatabase: utilities for the operation of the public compound and pathway database</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35944213/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35944213/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Summary: One of the major challenges in liquid chromatography coupled to mass spectrometry data is converting many metabolic feature entries to biological function information, such as metabolite annotation and pathway enrichment, which are based on the compound and pathway databases. Multiple online databases have been developed. However, no tool has been developed for operating all these databases for biological analysis. Therefore, we developed &lt;a href=&#34;https://massdatabase.tidymass.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;massDatabase&lt;/a&gt;, an R package that operates the online public databases and combines with other tools for streamlined compound annotation and pathway enrichment. &lt;a href=&#34;https://massdatabase.tidymass.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;massDatabase&lt;/a&gt; is a flexible, simple and powerful tool that can be installed on all platforms, allowing the users to leverage all the online public databases for biological function mining. A detailed tutorial and a case study are provided in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/uploads/35944213_supplementary_data.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Supplementary Material&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TidyMass an object-oriented reproducible analysis framework for LC-MS data</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35902589/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35902589/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reproducibility, traceability, and transparency have been long-standing issues for metabolomics data analysis. Multiple tools have been developed, but limitations still exist. Here, we present the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tidymass.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;tidyMass&lt;/a&gt; project, a comprehensive R-based computational framework that can achieve the traceable, shareable, and reproducible workflow needs of data processing and analysis for LC-MS-based untargeted metabolomics. TidyMass is an ecosystem of R packages that share an underlying design philosophy, grammar, and data structure, which provides a comprehensive, reproducible, and object-oriented computational framework. The modular architecture makes &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tidymass.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;tidyMass&lt;/a&gt; a highly flexible and extensible tool, which other users can improve and integrate with other tools to customize their own pipeline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sangerbox: A comprehensive, interaction-friendly clinical bioinformatics analysis platform</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/imt2.36/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/imt2.36/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In recent decades, with the continuous development of high-throughput sequencing technology, data volume in medical research has increased, at the same time, almost all clinical researchers have their own independent omics data, which provided a better condition for data mining and a deeper understanding of gene functions. However, for these large amounts of data, many common and cutting-edge effective bioinformatics research methods still cannot be widely used. This has encouraged the establishment of many analytical platforms, a portion of databases or platforms were designed to solve the special analysis needs of users, for instance, MG RAST, IMG/M, Qiita, BIGSdb, and TRAPR were developed for specific omics research, and some databases or servers provide solutions for special problems solutions. Metascape was designed to only provide functional annotations of genes as well as function enrichment analysis; BioNumerics and RidomSeqSphere+ perform multilocus sequence typing; CARD provides only antimicrobial resistance annotations. Additionally, some web services are outdated, and inefficient interaction often fails to meet the needs of researchers, such as our previous versions of the platform. Therefore, the demand to complete massive data processing tasks urgently requires a comprehensive bioinformatics analysis platform. Hence, we have developed a website platform, &lt;a href=&#34;http://vip.sangerbox.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sangerbox&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 3.0, a web-based tool platform. On a user-friendly interface that also supports differential analysis, the platform provides interactive customizable analysis tools, including various kinds of correlation analyses, pathway enrichment analysis, weighted correlation network analysis, and other common tools and functions, users only need to upload their own corresponding data into &lt;a href=&#34;http://vip.sangerbox.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sangerbox&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 3.0, select required parameters, submit, and wait for the results after the task has been completed. We have also established a new interactive plotting system that allows users to adjust the parameters in the image; moreover, optimized plotting performance enables users to adjust large-capacity vector maps on the web site. At the same time, we have integrated GEO, TCGA, ICGC, and other databases and processed data in batches, greatly reducing the difficulty to obtain data and improving the efficiency of bioimformatics study for users. Finally, we also provide users with rich sources of bioinformatics analysis courses, offering a platform for researchers to share and exchange knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ggClusterNet: An R package for microbiome network analysis and modularity-based multiple network layouts</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/imt2.32/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/imt2.32/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ggClusterNet is an R package for microbial networks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Analysis functions could help the user to easily complete network analysis and interpretation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ten network layout algorithms allow users more alternatives to plot the network and generate published-ready figures.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It is free to access on GitHub and Gitee.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The network analysis has attracted increasing attention and interest from ecological academics, thus it is of great necessity to develop more convenient and powerful tools. For that reason, we have developed an R package, named “ggClusterNet,” to complete and display the network analysis in an easier manner. In that package, ten network layout algorithms are designed to better display the modules of microbiome network (randomClusterG, PolygonClusterG, PolygonRrClusterG, ArtifCluster, randSNEClusterG, PolygonModsquareG, PolyRdmNotdCirG, model_Gephi.2, model_igraph, and model_maptree). For the convenience of the users, many functions related to microbial network analysis, such as corMicor(), net_properties(), node_properties(), ZiPiPlot(), random_Net_compate(), are integrated to complete the network mining. Furthermore, the pipeline function named network.2() and corBionetwork() are also added for the quick achievement of the network or bipartite network analysis as well as their in-depth mining. The ggClusterNet is publicly available via &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/taowenmicro/ggClusterNet/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://gitee.com/wentaomicro/ggClusterNet&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Gitee&lt;/a&gt; for users&amp;rsquo; access. A complete description of the usages can be found on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/taowenmicro/ggClusterNet/wiki&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;manuscript&amp;rsquo;s GitHub page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comparison of methods and resources for cell-cell communication inference from single-cell RNA-Seq data</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35680885/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35680885/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The growing availability of single-cell data, especially transcriptomics, has sparked an increased interest in the inference of cell-cell communication. Many computational tools were developed for this purpose. Each of them consists of a resource of intercellular interactions prior knowledge and a method to predict potential cell-cell communication events. Yet the impact of the choice of resource and method on the resulting predictions is largely unknown. To shed light on this, we systematically compare 16 cell-cell communication inference resources and 7 methods, plus the consensus between the methods’ predictions. Among the resources, we find few unique interactions, a varying degree of overlap, and an uneven coverage of specific pathways and tissue-enriched proteins. We then examine all possible combinations of methods and resources and show that both strongly influence the predicted intercellular interactions. Finally, we assess the agreement of cell-cell communication methods with spatial colocalisation, cytokine activities, and receptor protein abundance and find that predictions are generally coherent with those data modalities. To facilitate the use of the methods and resources described in this work, we provide LIANA, a LIgand-receptor ANalysis frAmework as an open-source interface to all the resources and methods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>iMetaLab Suite: A one-stop toolset for metaproteomics</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/imt2.25/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/imt2.25/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A one-stop solution for metaproteomics data analysis for nonexpert.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Database search and result reports that include taxonomy and function.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Interactive tools for frequently used metaproteomics data analysis tools.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Metaproteomics is a recently thriving technique that studies the collection of proteins in complex microbiomes of the human, animal, plant, and environment. The bioinformatics workflow required for metaproteomics research, from the database search and protein quantification to downstream functional and taxonomic analysis has been challenging and thus limiting the accessibility of metaproteomics to microbiome researchers. To overcome these challenges, we have developed a set of tools named &lt;a href=&#34;https://imetalab.ca/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;iMetaLab Suite&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;https://imetalab.ca/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;iMetaLab Suite&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; includes the following components:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MetaLab Desktop, an automated database search software that facilities proteins identification and quantitation from microbiomes;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the automated iMetaReport that allows users to quickly access database search results and data set profiles;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;an interactive online toolset, iMetaShiny, covering most frequently used functional, taxonomic, and statistical analysis in metaproteomics.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://imetalab.ca/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;iMetaLab Suite&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a free, easily accessible, and actively updated toolset available to assist researchers to explore metaproteomic data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interactive Analysis, Exploration, and Visualization of RNA-Seq Data with SeqCVIBE</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35314664/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35314664/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ImageGP: An easy-to-use data visualization web server for scientific researchers</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/imt2.5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/imt2.5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data visualization plays a crucial role in illustrating results and sharing knowledge among researchers. Though many types of visualization tools are widely used, most of them require enough coding experience or are designed for specialized usages, or are not free. Here, we present &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ehbio.com/ImageGP/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;ImageGP&lt;/a&gt;, a specialized visualization platform designed for biology and chemistry data illustration. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ehbio.com/ImageGP/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;ImageGP&lt;/a&gt; could generate generalized plots like lines, bars, scatters, boxes, sets, heatmaps, and histograms with the most common input content in a user-friendly interface. Normally plotting using &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ehbio.com/ImageGP/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;ImageGP&lt;/a&gt; only needs a few mouse clicks. For some plots, one only needs to just paste data and click submit to get the visualization results. Additionally, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ehbio.com/ImageGP/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;ImageGP&lt;/a&gt; supplies up to 26 parameters to meet customizable requirements. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ehbio.com/ImageGP/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;ImageGP&lt;/a&gt; also contains specialized plots like volcano plot, functional enrichment plot for most omics-data analysis, and other four specialized functions for microbiome analysis. Since 2017, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ehbio.com/ImageGP/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;ImageGP&lt;/a&gt; has been running for nearly 5 years and serving 336,951 visits from all over the world. Together, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ehbio.com/ImageGP/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;ImageGP&lt;/a&gt; is an effective and efficient tool for experimental researchers to comprehensively visualize and interpret data generated from wet-lab and dry-lab.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SCANNER: a web platform for annotation, visualization and sharing of single cell RNA-seq data</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35134150/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35134150/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In recent years, efficient scRNA-seq methods have been developed, enabling the transcriptome profiling of single cells massively in parallel. Meanwhile, its high dimensionality and complexity bring challenges to the data analysis and require extensive collaborations between biologists and bioinformaticians and/or biostatisticians. The communication between these two units demands a platform for easy data sharing and exploration. Here we developed Single-Cell Transcriptomics Annotated Viewer (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.thecailab.com/scanner/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;SCANNER&lt;/a&gt;), as a public web resource for the scientific community, for sharing and analyzing scRNA-seq data in a collaborative manner. It is easy-to-use without requiring special software or extensive coding skills. Moreover, it equipped a real-time database for secure data management and enables an efficient investigation of the activation of gene sets on a single-cell basis. Currently, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.thecailab.com/scanner/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;SCANNER&lt;/a&gt; hosts a database of 19 types of cancers and COVID-19, as well as healthy samples from lungs of smokers and non-smokers, human brain cells and peripheral blood mononuclear cells (PBMC). The database will be frequently updated with datasets from new studies. Using &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.thecailab.com/scanner/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;SCANNER&lt;/a&gt;, we identified a larger proportion of cancer-associated fibroblasts cells and more active fibroblast growth-related genes in melanoma tissues in female patients compared to male patients. Moreover, we found ACE2 is mainly expressed in lung pneumocytes, secretory cells and ciliated cells and differentially expressed in lungs of smokers and never smokers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Key Points&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.thecailab.com/scanner/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;SCANNER&lt;/a&gt; provides a new web resource to bridge the data analysis and the biological experiment units.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.thecailab.com/scanner/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;SCANNER&lt;/a&gt; enables comprehensive and dynamic analysis, visualization, functional annotation and easy data sharing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.thecailab.com/scanner/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;SCANNER&lt;/a&gt; hosts a real-time database for data and user management.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Identification of key immune genes for sepsis-induced ARDS based on bioinformatics analysis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34898369/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34898369/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regarding the extremely high mortality caused by sepsis-induced acute respiratory distress syndrome (ARDS), it is urgent to develop new biomarkers of sepsis-induced ARDS for treatment. Here, 532 differential expression genes (DEGs) related to sepsis and 433 DEGs related to sepsis-induced ARDS were screened in the GSE32707 dataset. Compared with sepsis samples, sepsis ARDS samples showed a higher infiltration of activated memory CD4 T cells and naive B cells, but a relatively lower infiltration of CD8 T cells. The pink and green modules which are significantly associated with sepsis-induced ARDS were then screened through co-expression network analysis. Differentially up-regulated GYPE and aberrantly down-regulated HSPB1, were subsequently found in the pink module of ARDS. CD81 and RPL22, two differentially low-expressed genes peculiar to ARDS, were identified in the green module. The function of CD81 was verified at the cellular level, and it was found that the up-regulation of CD81 in A549 could alleviate the LPS-induced injury of A549 cells. More importantly, the overexpressed CD81 can also increase the content of CD4&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; CD25&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; Foxp3&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; Treg in Jurkat cells, and after the co-culture of overexpressed CD81 Jurkat cells with LPS treatment A549 cells, the LPS-induced lung epithelial cell damage can be improved. Overall, four new plasma biomarker candidates were found in sepsis-induced ARDS, and we verified that CD81 may play critical roles in the biological and immunological processes of sepsis-induced ARDS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mapping the temporal and spatial dynamics of the human endometrium in vivo and in vitro</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34857954/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34857954/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The endometrium, the mucosal lining of the uterus, undergoes dynamic changes throughout the menstrual cycle in response to ovarian hormones. We have generated dense single-cell and spatial reference maps of the human uterus and three-dimensional endometrial organoid cultures. We dissect the signaling pathways that determine cell fate of the epithelial lineages in the lumenal and glandular microenvironments. Our benchmark of the endometrial organoids reveals the pathways and cell states regulating differentiation of the secretory and ciliated lineages both in vivo and in vitro. In vitro downregulation of WNT or NOTCH pathways increases the differentiation efficiency along the secretory and ciliated lineages, respectively. We utilize our cellular maps to deconvolute bulk data from endometrial cancers and endometriotic lesions, illuminating the cell types dominating in each of these disorders. These mechanistic insights provide a platform for future development of treatments for common conditions including endometriosis and endometrial carcinoma.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SLAW: A Scalable and Self-Optimizing Processing Workflow for Untargeted LC-MS</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34735114/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34735114/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Metabolomics has been shown to be promising for diverse applications in basic, applied, and clinical research. These applications often require large-scale data, and while the technology to perform such experiments exists, downstream analysis remains challenging. Different tools exist in a variety of ecosystems, but they often do not scale to large data and are not integrated into a single coherent workflow. Moreover, the outcome of processing is very sensitive to a multitude of algorithmic parameters. Hence, parameter optimization is not only critical but also challenging. We present &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/zamboni-lab/SLAW&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;SLAW&lt;/a&gt;, a scalable and yet easy-to-use workflow for processing untargeted LC-MS data in metabolomics and lipidomics. The capabilities of &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/zamboni-lab/SLAW&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;SLAW&lt;/a&gt; include (1) state-of-the-art peak-picking algorithms, (2) a new automated parameter optimization routine, (3) an efficient sample alignment procedure, (4) gap filling by data recursion, and (5) the extraction of consolidated MS&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; and an isotopic pattern across all samples. Importantly, both the workflow and the parameter optimization were designed for robust analysis of untargeted studies with thousands of individual LC-MS&lt;sup&gt;n&lt;/sup&gt; runs. We compared &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/zamboni-lab/SLAW&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;SLAW&lt;/a&gt; to two state-of-the-art workflows based on openMS and XCMS. &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/zamboni-lab/SLAW&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;SLAW&lt;/a&gt; was able to detect and align more reproducible features in all data sets considered. &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/zamboni-lab/SLAW&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;SLAW&lt;/a&gt; scaled well, and its analysis of a data set with 2500 LC-MS files consumed 40% less memory and was 6 times faster than that using the XCMS-based workflow. &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/zamboni-lab/SLAW&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;SLAW&lt;/a&gt; also extracted 2-fold more isotopic patterns and MS&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; spectra, which in 60% of the cases led to positive matches against a spectral library.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Identification and Characterization of Robust Hepatocellular Carcinoma Prognostic Subtypes Based on an Integrative Metabolite-Protein Interaction Network</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34247449/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34247449/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Metabolite-protein interactions (MPIs) play key roles in cancer metabolism. However, our current knowledge about MPIs in cancers remains limited due to the complexity of cancer cells. Herein, the authors construct an integrative MPI network and propose a MPI network based hepatocellular carcinoma (HCC) subtyping and mechanism exploration workflow. Based on the expressions of hub proteins on the MPI network, two prognosis-distinctive HCC subtypes are identified. Meanwhile, multiple interdependent features of the poor prognostic subtype are observed, including hypoxia, DNA hypermethylation of metabolic pathways, fatty acid accumulation, immune pathway up-regulation, and exhausted T-cell infiltration. Notably, the immune pathway up-regulation is probably induced by accumulated unsaturated fatty acids which are predicted to interact with multiple immune regulators like SRC and TGFB1. Moreover, based on tumor microenvironment compositions, the poor prognostic subtype is further divided into two sub-populations showing remarkable differences in metabolism. The subtyping shows a strong consistency across multiple HCC cohorts including early-stage HCC. Overall, the authors redefine robust HCC prognosis subtypes and identify potential MPIs linking metabolism to immune regulations, thus promoting understanding and clinical applications about HCC metabolism heterogeneity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>KOBAS-i: intelligent prioritization and exploratory visualization of biological functions for gene enrichment analysis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34086934/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34086934/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gene set enrichment (GSE) analysis plays an essential role in extracting biological insight from genome-scale experiments. ORA (overrepresentation analysis), FCS (functional class scoring), and PT (pathway topology) approaches are three generations of GSE methods along the timeline of development. Previous versions of &lt;a href=&#34;http://kobas.cbi.pku.edu.cn/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;KOBAS&lt;/a&gt; provided services based on just the ORA method. Here we presented version 3.0 of &lt;a href=&#34;http://kobas.cbi.pku.edu.cn/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;KOBAS&lt;/a&gt;, which is named &lt;a href=&#34;http://kobas.cbi.pku.edu.cn/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;KOBAS&lt;/a&gt;-i (short for &lt;a href=&#34;http://kobas.cbi.pku.edu.cn/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;KOBAS&lt;/a&gt; intelligent version). It introduced a novel machine learning-based method we published earlier, CGPS, which incorporates seven FCS tools and two PT tools into a single ensemble score and intelligently prioritizes the relevant biological pathways. In addition, &lt;a href=&#34;http://kobas.cbi.pku.edu.cn/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;KOBAS&lt;/a&gt; has expanded the downstream exploratory visualization for selecting and understanding the enriched results. The tool constructs a novel view of cirFunMap, which presents different enriched terms and their correlations in a landscape. Finally, based on the previous version&amp;rsquo;s framework, &lt;a href=&#34;http://kobas.cbi.pku.edu.cn/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;KOBAS&lt;/a&gt; increased the number of supported species from 1327 to 5944. For an easier local run, it also provides a prebuilt Docker image that requires no installation, as a supplementary to the source code version.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The mirror site can be freely accessed by &lt;a href=&#34;http://bioinfo.org/kobas&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;clicking here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inference and analysis of cell-cell communication using CellChat</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33597522/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33597522/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Understanding global communications among cells requires accurate representation of cell-cell signaling links and effective systems-level analyses of those links. We construct a database of interactions among ligands, receptors and their cofactors that accurately represent known heteromeric molecular complexes. We then develop &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/sqjin/CellChat&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CellChat&lt;/a&gt;, a tool that is able to quantitatively infer and analyze intercellular communication networks from single-cell RNA-sequencing (scRNA-seq) data. &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/sqjin/CellChat&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CellChat&lt;/a&gt; predicts major signaling inputs and outputs for cells and how those cells and signals coordinate for functions using network analysis and pattern recognition approaches. Through manifold learning and quantitative contrasts, &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/sqjin/CellChat&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CellChat&lt;/a&gt; classifies signaling pathways and delineates conserved and context-specific pathways across different datasets. Applying &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/sqjin/CellChat&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CellChat&lt;/a&gt; to mouse and human skin datasets shows its ability to extract complex signaling patterns. Our versatile and easy-to-use toolkit &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/sqjin/CellChat&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CellChat&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cellchat.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;a web-based Explorer&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; will help discover novel intercellular communications and build cell-cell communication atlases in diverse tissues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>intePareto: an R package for integrative analyses of RNA-Seq and ChIP-Seq data</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33372591/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33372591/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; RNA-Seq, the high-throughput sequencing (HT-Seq) of mRNAs, has become an essential tool for characterizing gene expression differences between different cell types and conditions. Gene expression is regulated by several mechanisms, including epigenetically by post-translational histone modifications which can be assessed by ChIP-Seq (Chromatin Immuno-Precipitation Sequencing). As more and more biological samples are analyzed by the combination of ChIP-Seq and RNA-Seq, the integrated analysis of the corresponding data sets becomes, theoretically, a unique option to study gene regulation. However, technically such analyses are still in their infancy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; Here we introduce &lt;a href=&#34;https://cran.r-project.org/web/packages/intePareto/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;intePareto&lt;/a&gt;, a computational tool for the integrative analysis of RNA-Seq and ChIP-Seq data. With &lt;a href=&#34;https://cran.r-project.org/web/packages/intePareto/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;intePareto&lt;/a&gt; we match RNA-Seq and ChIP-Seq data at the level of genes, perform differential expression analysis between biological conditions, and prioritize genes with consistent changes in RNA-Seq and ChIP-Seq data using Pareto optimization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://cran.r-project.org/web/packages/intePareto/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;intePareto&lt;/a&gt; facilitates comprehensive understanding of high dimensional transcriptomic and epigenomic data. Its superiority to a naive differential gene expression analysis with RNA-Seq and available integrative approach is demonstrated by analyzing a public dataset.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>scGMAI: a Gaussian mixture model for clustering single-cell RNA-Seq data based on deep autoencoder</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33300547/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33300547/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rapid development of single-cell RNA sequencing (scRNA-Seq) technology provides strong technical support for accurate and efficient analyzing single-cell gene expression data. However, the analysis of scRNA-Seq is accompanied by many obstacles, including dropout events and the curse of dimensionality. Here, we propose the scGMAI, which is a new single-cell Gaussian mixture clustering method based on autoencoder networks and the fast independent component analysis (FastICA). Specifically, scGMAI utilizes autoencoder networks to reconstruct gene expression values from scRNA-Seq data and FastICA is used to reduce the dimensions of reconstructed data. The integration of these computational techniques in scGMAI leads to outperforming results compared to existing tools, including Seurat, in clustering cells from 17 public scRNA-Seq datasets. In summary, scGMAI is an effective tool for accurately clustering and identifying cell types from scRNA-Seq data and shows the great potential of its applicative power in scRNA-Seq data analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Visualization with R</title>
      <link>https://example.com/books/2020-12-01-data-vis-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/books/2020-12-01-data-vis-r/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.r-project.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;R&lt;/a&gt; is an amazing platform for data analysis, capable of creating almost any type of graph. &lt;a href=&#34;https://rkabacoff.github.io/datavis/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Data Visualization with R&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; helps you create the most popular visualizations - from quick and dirty plots to publication-ready graphs. The text relies heavily on the &lt;a href=&#34;%28https://ggplot2.tidyverse.org%29&#34;&gt;ggplot2&lt;/a&gt; package for graphics, but other approaches are covered as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/books/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Books &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Predicting cell-to-cell communication networks using NATMI</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33024107/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33024107/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Development of high throughput single-cell sequencing technologies has made it cost-effective to profile thousands of cells from diverse samples containing multiple cell types. To study how these different cell types work together, here we develop &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/forrest-lab/NATMI/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NATMI (Network Analysis Toolkit for Multicellular Interactions)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/forrest-lab/NATMI/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NATMI&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; uses &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.humanconnectome.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;connectomeDB2020&lt;/a&gt; (a database of 2293 manually curated ligand-receptor pairs with literature support) to predict and visualise cell-to-cell communication networks from single-cell (or bulk) expression data. Using multiple published single-cell datasets we demonstrate how &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/forrest-lab/NATMI/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NATMI&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; can be used to identify (i) the cell-type pairs that are communicating the most (or most specifically) within a network, (ii) the most active (or specific) ligand-receptor pairs active within a network, (iii) putative highly-communicating cellular communities and (iv) differences in intercellular communication when profiling given cell types under different conditions. Furthermore, analysis of the Tabula Muris (organism-wide) atlas confirms our previous prediction that autocrine signalling is a major feature of cell-to-cell communication networks, while also revealing that hundreds of ligands and their cognate receptors are co-expressed in individual cells suggesting a substantial potential for self-signalling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SingleCellSignalR: inference of intercellular networks from single-cell transcriptomics</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32196115/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32196115/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Single-cell transcriptomics offers unprecedented opportunities to infer the ligand-receptor (LR) interactions underlying cellular networks. We introduce a new, curated LR database and a novel regularized score to perform such inferences. For the first time, we try to assess the confidence in predicted LR interactions and show that our regularized score outperforms other scoring schemes while controlling false positives. &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/SCA-IRCM&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SingleCellSignalR&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is implemented as an open-access R package accessible to entry-level users and available from &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/SCA-IRCM&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;. Analysis results come in a variety of tabular and graphical formats. For instance, we provide a unique network view integrating all the intercellular interactions, and a function relating receptors to expressed intracellular pathways. A detailed comparison of related tools is conducted. Among various examples, we demonstrate &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/SCA-IRCM&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SingleCellSignalR&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; on mouse epidermis data and discover an oriented communication structure from external to basal layers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CellPhoneDB: inferring cell-cell communication from combined expression of multi-subunit ligand-receptor complexes</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32103204/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32103204/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cell-cell communication mediated by ligand-receptor complexes is critical to coordinating diverse biological processes, such as development, differentiation and inflammation. To investigate how the context-dependent crosstalk of different cell types enables physiological processes to proceed, we developed &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cellphonedb.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CellPhoneDB&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, a novel repository of ligands, receptors and their interactions. In contrast to other repositories, our database takes into account the subunit architecture of both ligands and receptors, representing heteromeric complexes accurately. We integrated our resource with a statistical framework that predicts enriched cellular interactions between two cell types from single-cell transcriptomics data. Here, we outline the structure and content of our repository, provide procedures for inferring cell-cell communication networks from single-cell RNA sequencing data and present a practical step-by-step guide to help implement the protocol. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cellphonedb.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CellPhoneDB&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; v.2.0 is an updated version of our resource that incorporates additional functionalities to enable users to introduce new interacting molecules and reduces the time and resources needed to interrogate large datasets. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cellphonedb.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CellPhoneDB&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; v.2.0 is publicly available, both as code and as a user-friendly web interface; it can be used by both experts and researchers with little experience in computational genomics. In our protocol, we demonstrate how to evaluate meaningful biological interactions with &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cellphonedb.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CellPhoneDB&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; v.2.0 using published datasets. This protocol typically takes ~2 h to complete, from installation to statistical analysis and visualization, for a dataset of ~10 GB, 10,000 cells and 19 cell types, and using five threads.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using MicrobiomeAnalyst for comprehensive statistical, functional, and meta-analysis of microbiome data</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/31942082/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/31942082/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.microbiomeanalyst.ca/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;MicrobiomeAnalyst&lt;/a&gt; is an easy-to-use, web-based platform for comprehensive analysis of common data outputs generated from current microbiome studies. It enables researchers and clinicians with little or no bioinformatics training to explore a wide variety of well-established methods for microbiome data processing, statistical analysis, functional profiling and comparison with public datasets or known microbial signatures. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.microbiomeanalyst.ca/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;MicrobiomeAnalyst&lt;/a&gt; currently contains four modules: Marker-gene Data Profiling (MDP), Shotgun Data Profiling (SDP), Projection with Public Data (PPD), and Taxon Set Enrichment Analysis (TSEA). This protocol will first introduce the MDP module by providing a step-wise description of how to prepare, process and normalize data; perform community profiling; identify important features; and conduct correlation and classification analysis. We will then demonstrate how to perform predictive functional profiling and introduce several unique features of the SDP module for functional analysis. The last two sections will describe the key steps involved in using the PPD and TSEA modules for meta-analysis and visual exploration of the results. In summary, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.microbiomeanalyst.ca/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;MicrobiomeAnalyst&lt;/a&gt; offers a one-stop shop that enables microbiome researchers to thoroughly explore their preprocessed microbiome data via intuitive web interfaces. The complete protocol can be executed in ~70 min.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NicheNet: modeling intercellular communication by linking ligands to target genes</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/31819264/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/31819264/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Computational methods that model how gene expression of a cell is influenced by interacting cells are lacking. We present &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/saeyslab/nichenetr&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;NicheNet&lt;/a&gt;, a method that predicts ligand-target links between interacting cells by combining their expression data with prior knowledge on signaling and gene regulatory networks. We applied &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/saeyslab/nichenetr&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;NicheNet&lt;/a&gt; to tumor and immune cell microenvironment data and demonstrate that &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/saeyslab/nichenetr&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;NicheNet&lt;/a&gt; can infer active ligands and their gene regulatory effects on interacting cells.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Visualisation with R: 111 Examples</title>
      <link>https://example.com/books/2019-11-23-data-vis-r-111-examp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/books/2019-11-23-data-vis-r-111-examp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.datavisualisation-r.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Data Visualisation with R: 111 Examples (2nd Edition)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; introduces readers to the fundamentals of creating presentation graphics using &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.r-project.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;R&lt;/a&gt;, based on 111 detailed and complete scripts. It shows how bar and column charts, population pyramids, Lorenz curves, box plots, scatter plots, time series, radial polygons, Gantt charts, heat maps, bump charts, mosaic and balloon charts, and a series of different thematic map types can be created using R’s Base Graphics System. Every example uses real data and includes step-by-step explanations of the figures and their programming. This second edition contains additional examples for cartograms, chord-diagrams and networks, and interactive visualizations with Javascript.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/books/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Books &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gallery for R graphs and charts</title>
      <link>https://example.com/blog/2019-08-11-r-graphics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/blog/2019-08-11-r-graphics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://r-project.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;R&lt;/a&gt; is a great tool for &lt;a href=&#34;%28https://www.data-to-viz.com/%29&#34;&gt;data visualization&lt;/a&gt;. The native tool becomes even better thanks to external packages such as &lt;a href=&#34;https://cran.r-project.org/web/packages/ggplot2/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;ggplot2&lt;/a&gt; that are widely used in the gallery. If you&amp;rsquo;re wondering what you can do with &lt;a href=&#34;https://r-project.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;R&lt;/a&gt; in terms of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.data-to-viz.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;dataviz&lt;/a&gt;, the following online resources may help you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.data-to-viz.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;From Data to Viz&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a classification of chart types based on input data format. It comes in the form of a decision tree leading to a set of potentially appropriate visualizations to represent the dataset. The project is built on two underlying philosophies. &lt;em&gt;First&lt;/em&gt;, that most data analysis can be summarized in about twenty different dataset formats. &lt;em&gt;Second&lt;/em&gt;, that both data and context determine the appropriate chart. Thus, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.data-to-viz.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;From Data to Viz&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; suggested method consists in identifying and trying all feasible chart types to find out which suits your data and idea best. Once this set of graphics is identified, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.data-to-viz.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;From Data to Viz&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; aims to guide you toward the best decision. It also provides a list of common caveats to avoid and always provides a reproducible code snippet in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://r-project.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;R programming language&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.data-to-viz.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Dataviz&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a world with endless possibilities and this project does not claim to be exhaustive. However, it should provide you with a good starting point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://r-charts.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;R CHARTS&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; web site has been created without any financial support by José Carlos Soage. It was generated with &lt;a href=&#34;https://cran.r-project.org/web/packages/blogdown/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;blogdown&lt;/a&gt;, an &lt;a href=&#34;https://cran.r-project.org/web/packages/available_packages_by_name.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;R package&lt;/a&gt; which allows creating static web sites using the HUGO generator. The theme of this site is a custom theme inspired by Kross and Academic themes. The classification of the charts is based on the Financial Times visual vocabulary. On the site of &lt;a href=&#34;https://r-charts.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;R CHARTS&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; you will find code examples of &lt;a href=&#34;https://r-project.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;R&lt;/a&gt; graphs made with base &lt;a href=&#34;https://r-project.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;R&lt;/a&gt; graphics, &lt;a href=&#34;https://cran.r-project.org/web/packages/ggplot2/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;ggplot2&lt;/a&gt; and other &lt;a href=&#34;https://cran.r-project.org/web/packages/available_packages_by_name.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;R package&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://r-graph-gallery.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;R graph gallery&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a collection of charts made with the &lt;a href=&#34;https://r-project.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;R programming language&lt;/a&gt;. Charts are organized by family and types. Hundreds (~ 400 charts) of charts are displayed in several sections, always with their reproducible code and explanations available. The gallery makes a focus on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tidyverse.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;tidyverse&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://cran.r-project.org/web/packages/ggplot2/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;ggplot2&lt;/a&gt;. For each chart, a focus is made on code, but a link toward &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.data-to-viz.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;data-to-viz&lt;/a&gt; is provided to give more information concerning the theory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/blog/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Blog &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R project and commonly used packages</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tool/2019-06-25-r-com-used-pkgs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/tool/2019-06-25-r-com-used-pkgs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://r-project.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;R&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a free software environment for statistical computing and graphics. It is the most widely used language for data science, together with &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.python.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;python&lt;/a&gt;. The &lt;a href=&#34;https://r-project.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;R Project&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; for Statistical Computing provide multiple &lt;a href=&#34;https://cran.r-project.org/mirrors.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CRAN Mirrors to &lt;strong&gt;Download R&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. In China mainland, at least 10 mirror sites are available, such as those of &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirrors.ustc.edu.cn/CRAN/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;USTC&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.lzu.edu.cn/CRAN/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;LZU&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirrors.sustech.edu.cn/CRAN/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;SUSTech&lt;/a&gt;. Pick whatever one seems closest to you and start your work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://cran.r-project.org/bin/windows/Rtools/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rtools&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; : Toolchains for building &lt;a href=&#34;https://cran.r-project.org/mirrors.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;R&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://cran.r-project.org/web/packages/available_packages_by_name.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;R package&lt;/a&gt; from source on Windows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://posit.co/downloads/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;RStudio&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is also hepful and friendly supplement for &lt;a href=&#34;https://cran.r-project.org/mirrors.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;R&lt;/a&gt; and can be downloaded by click the names.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.rstudio.com/products/connect/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;RStudio Connect&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is the best way to host and share data products made with &lt;a href=&#34;https://cran.r-project.org/mirrors.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;R&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.python.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Python&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ggplot2.tidyverse.org&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ggplot2&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a &lt;a href=&#34;https://cran.r-project.org/web/packages/available_packages_by_name.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;R package&lt;/a&gt; dedicated to create &lt;a href=&#34;https://ggplot2-book.org/index.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Elegant Graphics for Data Analysis&lt;/a&gt;. It can greatly improve the quality and aesthetics of your graphics, and will make you much more efficient in creating them. &lt;a href=&#34;https://ggplot2.tidyverse.org&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ggplot2&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; allows to &lt;a href=&#34;https://r-graph-gallery.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;build almost any type of chart&lt;/a&gt; ans is avaliable on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/tidyverse/ggplot2&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt; as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Complex heatmaps are efficient to visualize associations between different sources of data sets and reveal potential patterns. Here the &lt;a href=&#34;https://jokergoo.github.io/ComplexHeatmap-reference/book/index.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ComplexHeatmap&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; package&lt;/a&gt; provides a highly flexible way to arrange multiple heatmaps and supports self-defined annotation graphics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bioconductor.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bioconductor&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; uses the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.r-project.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;R statistical programming language&lt;/a&gt;, and is open source and open development. It has two releases each year, and an active user community. Bioconductor is also available as &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bioconductor.org/help/docker/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Docker&lt;/a&gt; images. The mission of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bioconductor.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bioconductor&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; project is to develop, support, and disseminate free open source software that facilitates rigorous and reproducible analysis of data from current and emerging biological assays. We are dedicated to building a diverse, collaborative, and welcoming community of developers and data scientists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://yulab-smu.top/biomedical-knowledge-mining-book/index.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Biomedical Knowledge Mining using GOSemSim and clusterProfiler&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is meant as a guide for mining biological knowledge to elucidate or interpret molecular mechanisms using a suite of &lt;a href=&#34;https://cran.r-project.org/web/packages/available_packages_by_name.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;R package&lt;/a&gt;, including &lt;a href=&#34;http://bioconductor.org/packages/release/bioc/html/ChIPseeker.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;ChIPseeker&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://bioconductor.org/packages/release/bioc/html/clusterProfiler.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;clusterProfiler&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://bioconductor.org/packages/release/bioc/html/DOSE.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;DOSE&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://bioconductor.org/packages/release/bioc/html/enrichplot.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;enrichplot&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://bioconductor.org/packages/release/bioc/html/GOSemSim.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;GOSemSim&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://bioconductor.org/packages/release/bioc/html/meshes.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;meshes&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://bioconductor.org/packages/release/bioc/html/ReactomePA.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;ReactomePA&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://horvath.genetics.ucla.edu/html/CoexpressionNetwork/Rpackages/WGCNA/index.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;WGCNA&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://r-project.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;R&lt;/a&gt; software package is a comprehensive collection of &lt;a href=&#34;https://r-project.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;R&lt;/a&gt; functions for performing various aspects of weighted correlation network analysis. The package includes functions for network construction, module detection, gene selection, calculations of topological properties, data simulation, visualization, and interfacing with external software. Click here to access the &lt;a href=&#34;https://horvath.genetics.ucla.edu/html/CoexpressionNetwork/Rpackages/WGCNA/Tutorials/index.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;tutorial&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/tag/softwares/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Softwares &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/tool/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Tools &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fundamentals of Data Visualization</title>
      <link>https://example.com/books/2019-04-30-basic-data-viz/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/books/2019-04-30-basic-data-viz/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://clauswilke.com/dataviz/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Fundamentals of Data Visualization&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is meant as a guide to making visualizations that accurately reflect the data, tell a story, and look professional. It has grown out of experience of the author working with students and postdocs in laboratory on thousands of data visualizations. Over the years, the autor has noticed that the same issues arise over and over and have attempted to collect my accumulated knowledge from these interactions in the form of this book. The website of &lt;a href=&#34;https://clauswilke.com/dataviz/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Fundamentals of Data Visualization&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; contains the complete author manuscript before final copy-editing and other quality control.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/books/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Books &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Metabolic reaction network-based recursive metabolite annotation for untargeted metabolomics</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/30944337/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/30944337/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Large-scale metabolite annotation is a challenge in liquid chromatogram-mass spectrometry (LC-MS)-based untargeted metabolomics. Here, we develop a metabolic reaction network (MRN)-based recursive algorithm (MetDNA) that expands metabolite annotations without the need for a comprehensive standard spectral library. MetDNA is based on the rationale that seed metabolites and their reaction-paired neighbors tend to share structural similarities resulting in similar MS2 spectra. MetDNA characterizes initial seed metabolites using a small library of MS2 spectra, and utilizes their experimental MS2 spectra as surrogate spectra to annotate their reaction-paired neighbor metabolites, which subsequently serve as the basis for recursive analysis. Using different LC-MS platforms, data acquisition methods, and biological samples, we showcase the utility and versatility of MetDNA and demonstrate that about 2000 metabolites can cumulatively be annotated from one experiment. Our results demonstrate that MetDNA substantially expands metabolite annotation, enabling quantitative assessment of metabolic pathways and facilitating integrative multi-omics analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Statistical Analysis of Microbiome Data with R</title>
      <link>https://example.com/books/2019-02-02-stat-analy-microbiome-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/books/2019-02-02-stat-analy-microbiome-r/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This unique book addresses the statistical modelling and analysis of microbiome data using cutting-edge R software. It includes real-world data from the authors’ research and from the public domain, and discusses the implementation of R for data analysis step by step. The data and R computer programs are publicly available, allowing readers to replicate the model development and data analysis presented in each chapter, so that these new methods can be readily applied in their own research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The book also discusses recent developments in statistical modelling and data analysis in microbiome research, as well as the latest advances in next-generation sequencing and big data in methodological development and applications. This timely book will greatly benefit all readers involved in microbiome, ecology and microarray data analyses, as well as other fields of research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/books/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Books &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>iTALK: an R Package to Characterize and Illustrate Intercellular Communication</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/italk/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/italk/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Crosstalk between tumor cells and other cells within the tumor microenvironment (TME) plays a crucial role in tumor progression, metastases, and therapy resistance. We present &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Coolgenome/iTALK&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;iTALK&lt;/a&gt;, a computational approach to characterize and illustrate intercellular communication signals in the multicellular tumor ecosystem using single-cell RNA sequencing data. &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Coolgenome/iTALK&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;iTALK&lt;/a&gt; can in principle be used to dissect the complexity, diversity, and dynamics of cell-cell communication from a wide range of cellular processes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R Graphics Cookbook</title>
      <link>https://example.com/books/2018-11-30-r-graphics/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/books/2018-11-30-r-graphics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://r-graphics.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;R Graphics Cookbook&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a practical guide that provides more than 150 recipes to help you generate high-quality graphs quickly, without having to comb through all the details of R’s graphing systems. Each recipe tackles a specific problem with a solution you can apply to your own project, and includes a discussion of how and why the recipe works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/books/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Books &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quantifying tumor-infiltrating immune cells from transcriptomics data</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/29541787/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/29541787/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By exerting pro- and anti-tumorigenic actions, tumor-infiltrating immune cells can profoundly influence tumor progression, as well as the success of anti-cancer therapies. Therefore, the quantification of tumor-infiltrating immune cells holds the promise to unveil the multi-faceted role of the immune system in human cancers and its involvement in tumor escape mechanisms and response to therapy. Tumor-infiltrating immune cells can be quantified from RNA sequencing data of human tumors using bioinformatics approaches. In this review, we describe state-of-the-art computational methods for the quantification of immune cells from transcriptomics data and discuss the open challenges that must be addressed to accurately quantify immune infiltrates from RNA sequencing data of human bulk tumors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R for Data Science</title>
      <link>https://example.com/books/2017-01-31-r4ds/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/books/2017-01-31-r4ds/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Data science is an exciting discipline that allows you to turn raw data into understanding, insight, and knowledge. The goal of &lt;a href=&#34;https://r4ds.had.co.nz/index.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;R for Data Science&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is to help you learn the most important tools in &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.r-project.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;R&lt;/a&gt; that will allow you to do data science. And the website of &lt;a href=&#34;https://r4ds.had.co.nz/index.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;R for Data Science&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is and will always be free to use. After reading this book, you’ll have the tools to tackle a wide variety of data science challenges, using the best parts of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.r-project.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;R&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://r4ds.had.co.nz/index.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;R for Data Science&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; teaches you how to do data science with R: You’ll learn how to get your data into R, get it into the most useful structure, transform it, visualise it and model it. In &lt;a href=&#34;https://r4ds.had.co.nz/index.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;R for Data Science&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, you will find a practicum of skills for data science. Just as a chemist learns how to clean test tubes and stock a lab, you’ll learn how to clean data and draw plots—and many other things besides. These are the skills that allow data science to happen, and here you will find the best practices for doing each of these things with R. You’ll learn how to use the grammar of graphics, literate programming, and reproducible research to save time. You’ll also learn how to manage cognitive resources to facilitate discoveries when wrangling, visualising, and exploring data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/books/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Books &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
