<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hepatitis Virus | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/hepatitis-virus/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/hepatitis-virus/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Hepatitis Virus</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Hepatitis Virus</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/hepatitis-virus/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Discovery of a first-in-class orally available HBV cccDNA inhibitor</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36587899/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36587899/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background &amp;amp; Aims&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The persistence of covalently closed circular DNA (cccDNA) in infected hepatocytes is the major barrier preventing viral eradication with existing therapies in patients with chronic hepatitis B (CHB). Therapeutic agents that can eliminate cccDNA are urgently needed to achieve virus eradication and thus HBV cure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A phenotypic assay with HBV-infected primary human hepatocytes (PHHs) was employed to screen for novel cccDNA inhibitors. A HBVcircle mouse model and a urokinase-type plasminogen activator-severe combined immunodeficiency (uPA-SCID) humanized liver mouse model were used to evaluate the anti-HBV efficacy of the discovered cccDNA inhibitors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Potent and dose-dependent reductions in extracellular HBV DNA, HBsAg, and HBeAg levels were achieved upon the initiation of ccc_R08 treatment two days after the HBV infection of PHHs. More importantly, the level of cccDNA was specifically reduced by ccc_R08, while it did not obviously affect mitochondrial DNA. Additionally, ccc_R08 showed no significant cytotoxicity in PHHs or in multiple proliferating cell lines. The twice daily oral administration of ccc_R08 to HBVcircle model mice, which contained surrogate cccDNA molecules, significantly decreased the serum levels of HBV DNA and antigens, and these effects were sustained during the off-treatment follow-up period. Moreover, at the end of the follow-up, the levels of surrogate cccDNA molecules in the livers of ccc_R08-treated HBVcircle mice were reduced to below the lower limit of quantification (LLOQ).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have discovered a small molecule cccDNA inhibitor that reduces HBV cccDNA levels. cccDNA inhibitors potentially represent a new approach to completely cure patients chronically infected with HBV.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Impact and Implications&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;cccDNA persistence in HBV-infected hepatocytes is the root cause of chronic hepatitis B. We discovered a novel small molecule cccDNA inhibitor that can specifically reduce cccDNA levels in HBV infected hepatocytes. This type of molecule offers a new approach to completely cure patients chronically infected with HBV.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Viral protease cleavage of MAVS in genetically modified mice with hepatitis A virus infection</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36152761/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36152761/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background &amp;amp; aims:&lt;/em&gt; Consistent with its relatively narrow host species range, hepatitis A virus (HAV) cannot infect C57BL/6 mice. However, in &lt;em&gt;Mavs&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; mice with genetic deficiency of the innate immune signaling adaptor MAVS, HAV replicates robustly in the absence of disease. The HAV 3ABC protease cleaves MAVS in human cells, thereby disrupting virus-induced IFN responses, but it cannot cleave murine MAVS (mMAVS) due to sequence differences at the site of scission. Here, we sought to elucidate the role of 3ABC MAVS cleavage in determining HAV pathogenesis and host species range.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; Using CRISPR/Cas9 gene editing, we established two independent lineages of C57BL/6 mice with knock-in mutations altering two amino acids in mMAVS (&amp;lsquo;mMAVS-VS&amp;rsquo;), rendering it susceptible to 3ABC cleavage without loss of signaling function. We challenged homozygous &lt;em&gt;Mavs&lt;sup&gt;vs/vs&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; mice with HAV, and compared infection outcomes with C57BL/6 and genetically deficient &lt;em&gt;Mavs&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; mice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; The humanized murine mMAVS-VS protein was cleaved as efficiently as human MAVS when co-expressed with 3ABC in Huh-7 cells. In embyronic fibroblasts from &lt;em&gt;Mavs&lt;sup&gt;vs/vs&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; mice, mMAVS-VS was cleaved by ectopically expressed 3ABC, significantly disrupting Sendai virus-induced IFN responses. However, in contrast to &lt;em&gt;Mavs&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; mice with genetic MAVS deficiency, HAV failed to establish infection in &lt;em&gt;Mavs&lt;sup&gt;vs/vs&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; mice, even with additional genetic knockout of &lt;em&gt;Trif&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;Irf1&lt;/em&gt;. Nonetheless, when crossed with permissive &lt;em&gt;Ifnar1&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; mice lacking type I IFN receptors, &lt;em&gt;Mavs&lt;sup&gt;vs/vs&lt;/sup&gt;Ifnar1&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; mice demonstrated enhanced viral replication coupled with significant reductions in serum alanine aminotransferase, hepatocellular apoptosis, and intrahepatic inflammatory cell infiltrates compared with &lt;em&gt;Ifnar1&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; mice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; MAVS cleavage by 3ABC boosts viral replication and disrupts disease pathogenesis, but it is not by itself sufficient to break the host-species barrier to HAV infection in mice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Impact and implications:&lt;/em&gt; The limited host range of human hepatitis viruses could be explained by species-specific viral strategies that disrupt innate immune responses. Both hepatitis A virus (HAV) and hepatitis C virus express viral proteases that cleave the innate immune adaptor protein MAVS, in human but not mouse cells. However, the impact of this immune evasion strategy has never been assessed in vivo. Here we show that HAV 3ABC protease cleavage of MAVS enhances viral replication and lessens liver inflammation in mice lacking interferon receptors, but that it is insufficient by itself to overcome the cross-species barrier to infection in mice. These results enhance our understanding of how hepatitis viruses interact with the host and their impact on innate immune responses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Urine is a viral antigen reservoir in hepatitis E virus infection</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36106666/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36106666/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background and aims:&lt;/em&gt; HEV ORF2 antigen (Ag) in serum has become a tool for diagnosing current HEV infection. Particularly, urinary shedding of HEV Ag has been gaining increasing interest. We aim to uncover the origin, antigenicity, diagnostic performance, and diagnostic significance of Ag in urine in HEV infection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Approach and results:&lt;/em&gt; Clinical serum and urine samples from patients with acute and chronic HEV infection were analyzed for their Ag levels. Ag in urine was analyzed by biochemical and proteomic approaches. The origin of urinary Ag and Ag kinetics during HEV infection was investigated in mouse and rabbit models, respectively. We found that both the Ag level and diagnostic sensitivity in urine were higher than in serum. Antigenic protein in urine was an E2s-like dimer spanning amino acids 453-606. pORF2 entered urine from serum in mice i.v. injected with pORF2. Ag in urine originated from the secreted form of pORF2 (ORF2&lt;sup&gt;S&lt;/sup&gt;) that abundantly existed in hepatitis E patients&amp;rsquo; serum. HEV Ag was specifically taken up by renal cells and was disposed into urine, during which the level of Ag was concentrated &amp;gt;10-fold, resulting in the higher diagnosing sensitivity of urine Ag than serum Ag. Moreover, Ag in urine appeared 6 days earlier, lasted longer than viremia and antigenemia, and showed good concordance with fecal RNA in a rabbit model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; Our findings demonstrated the origin and diagnostic value of urine Ag and provided insights into the disposal of exogenous protein of pathogens by the host kidney.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Circular RNA circSFMBT2 downregulation by HBx promotes hepatocellular carcinoma metastasis via the miR-665/TIMP3 axis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36159591/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36159591/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hepatitis B virus X protein (HBx) is considered as an oncogene in tumorigenesis and progression of hepatocellular carcinoma (HCC). In recent years, the important role of circular RNAs (circRNAs) in HCC has been increasingly demonstrated. However, the regulatory mechanisms of HBx on circRNAs remains largely unknown. In this study, we identified that a novel circRNA, circSFMBT2, was markedly downregulated by HBx. Low expression of circSFMBT2 was correlated with poor prognosis and vascular invasion. Functionally, overexpression of circSFMBT2 significantly inhibited HCC metastasis both in vitro and in vivo. The mechanism of circSFMBT2 was to as a sponge of miR-665, which is a negative regulator of tissue inhibitor of metalloproteinases 3 (TIMP3). However, HBx downregulated circSFMBT2 via the interaction with DExH-box helicase 9 (DHX9), which binds to flanking circRNA-forming introns. In conclusion, circSFMBT2, which is downregulated by HBx, acts as a tumor suppressor to inhibit tumor metastasis through the miR-665/TIMP3 axis. Our study suggests that circSFMBT2 could be a potential prognostic biomarker and therapeutic target for HCC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A roadmap for serum biomarkers for hepatitis B virus: current status and future outlook</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/35859026/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/35859026/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Globally, 296 million people are infected with hepatitis B virus (HBV), and approximately one million people die annually from HBV-related causes, including liver cancer. Although there is a preventative vaccine and antiviral therapies suppressing HBV replication, there is no cure. Intensive efforts are under way to develop curative HBV therapies. Currently, only a few biomarkers are available for monitoring or predicting HBV disease progression and treatment response. As new therapies become available, new biomarkers to monitor viral and host responses are urgently needed. In October 2020, the International Coalition to Eliminate Hepatitis B Virus (ICE-HBV) held a virtual and interactive workshop on HBV biomarkers endorsed by the International HBV Meeting. Various stakeholders from academia, clinical practice and the pharmaceutical industry, with complementary expertise, presented and participated in panel discussions. The clinical utility of both classic and emerging viral and immunological serum biomarkers with respect to the course of infection, disease progression, and response to current and emerging treatments was appraised. The latest advances were discussed, and knowledge gaps in understanding and interpretation of HBV biomarkers were identified. This Roadmap summarizes the strengths, weaknesses, opportunities and challenges of HBV biomarkers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Key points&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As new therapies for hepatitis B virus (HBV) infection become available, new biomarkers to monitor viral and host responses are urgently needed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This Roadmap summarizes current knowledge on existing and emerging serum biomarkers in the context of chronic HBV infection.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This Roadmap discusses the strengths, weaknesses, opportunities and challenges of serum HBV biomarkers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This Roadmap provides suggestions of the way forward to advance the biomarkers required to fast-track an HBV cure for all, irrespective of resources, HBV genotype or disease stage.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The ZCCHC14/TENT4 complex is required for hepatitis A virus RNA synthesis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35867748/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35867748/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Significance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite excellent vaccines, unprecedented outbreaks of hepatitis A have resulted in more than 400 fatal infections in the United States since 2016. Many gaps exist in our current understanding of the responsible pathogen, hepatitis A virus (HAV), for which there are no available antiviral therapies. Here, we show how the RNA genome of this unique, hepatotropic picornavirus interacts with a host cell protein complex required for synthesis of the viral RNA. We demonstrate that targeting this complex with an orally delivered small-molecule therapeutic ablates viral replication and reverses liver inflammation in a mouse model of hepatitis A, providing proof-of-principle for antiviral therapy and showing the potential for chemoprevention of hepatitis A in outbreak settings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite excellent vaccines, resurgent outbreaks of hepatitis A have caused thousands of hospitalizations and hundreds of deaths within the United States in recent years. There is no effective antiviral therapy for hepatitis A, and many aspects of the hepatitis A virus (HAV) replication cycle remain to be elucidated. Replication requires the zinc finger protein ZCCHC14 and noncanonical TENT4 poly(A) polymerases with which it associates, but the underlying mechanism is unknown. Here, we show that ZCCHC14 and TENT4A/B are required for viral RNA synthesis following translation of the viral genome in infected cells. Cross-linking immunoprecipitation sequencing (CLIP-seq) experiments revealed that ZCCHC14 binds a small stem-loop in the HAV 5&amp;rsquo; untranslated RNA possessing a Smaug recognition-like pentaloop to which it recruits TENT4. TENT4 polymerases lengthen and stabilize the 3&amp;rsquo; poly(A) tails of some cellular and viral mRNAs, but the chemical inhibition of TENT4A/B with the dihydroquinolizinone RG7834 had no impact on the length of the HAV 3&amp;rsquo; poly(A) tail, stability of HAV RNA, or cap-independent translation of the viral genome. By contrast, RG7834 inhibited the incorporation of 5-ethynyl uridine into nascent HAV RNA, indicating that TENT4A/B function in viral RNA synthesis. Consistent with potent in vitro antiviral activity against HAV (IC&lt;sub&gt;50&lt;/sub&gt; 6.11 nM), orally administered RG7834 completely blocked HAV infection in &lt;em&gt;Ifnar1&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; mice, and sharply reduced serum alanine aminotransferase activities, hepatocyte apoptosis, and intrahepatic inflammatory cell infiltrates in mice with acute hepatitis A. These results reveal requirements for ZCCHC14-TENT4A/B in hepatovirus RNA synthesis, and suggest that TENT4A/B inhibitors may be useful for preventing or treating hepatitis A in humans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Pannexin 1/Purinergic Receptor P2X4 Pathway Controls the Secretion of MicroRNA-Containing Exosomes by HCV-Infected Hepatocytes</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34218459/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34218459/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background and aims:&lt;/em&gt; HCV infection is a major risk factor that can lead to chronic liver disease, including fibrosis, cirrhosis, and HCC. Progression of chronic liver disease by HCV infection is caused by a complex intercellular reaction. Especially, exosomes and microRNAs (miRNAs) from HCV-infected hepatocytes play a role in the pathogenesis of liver disease by facilitating cellular communication between parenchymal and nonparenchymal cells. However, the underlying mechanism of secretions of exosome and miRNAs during HCV infection is still open for study.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Approach and results:&lt;/em&gt; In this study, we demonstrated a pathway for the release of exosome and exosomal miRNAs through caspase-3/pannexin 1 (Panx1)/P2X4 activation during HCV infection in hepatocytes. We found that HCV infection induced the stimulation of exosome release and activation of the caspase-3/Panx1/P2X4 pathway in Huh7.5.1 cells. In addition, miR-122 and miR-146a levels in extracellular exosomes from HCV-infected cells were dramatically increased whereas intracellular miR122 and miR-146a expression had no large changes. Notably, secretions of exosomes and exosomal miRNAs were decreased by inhibition of caspase 3, Panx1, and P2X4 whereas inhibition of ROCK-1 cleavage did not affect these during HCV infection in Huh7.5.1 cells.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; These results suggested that HCV infection caused secretions of exosomes and exosomal miRNAs dependent on the caspase 3/Panx1/P2X4 pathway. Our study provides a possible therapeutic intervention using Panx1 suppression for liver disease development mediated by exosomes from HCV-infected hepatocytes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hepatitis C virus modulates signal peptide peptidase to alter host protein processing</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34035171/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34035171/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Immunoevasins are viral proteins that prevent antigen presentation on major histocompatibility complex (MHC) class I, thus evading host immune recognition. Hepatitis C virus (HCV) evades immune surveillance to induce chronic infection; however, how HCV-infected hepatocytes affect immune cells and evade immune recognition remains unclear. Herein, we demonstrate that HCV core protein functions as an immunoevasin. Its expression interfered with the maturation of MHC class I molecules catalyzed by the signal peptide peptidase (SPP) and induced their degradation via HMG-CoA reductase degradation 1 homolog, thereby impairing antigen presentation to CD8&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T cells. The expression of MHC class I in the livers of HCV core transgenic mice and chronic hepatitis C patients was impaired but was restored in patients achieving sustained virological response. Finally, we show that the human cytomegalovirus US2 protein, possessing a transmembrane region structurally similar to the HCV core protein, targets SPP to impair MHC class I molecule expression. Thus, SPP represents a potential target for the impairment of MHC class I molecules by DNA and RNA viruses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The mirror site can be freely accessed by &lt;a href=&#34;http://bioinfo.org/kobas&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;clicking here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A genome-wide CRISPR screen identifies UFMylation and TRAMP-like complexes as host factors required for hepatitis A virus infection</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33730579/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33730579/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A genome-wide CRISPR screen identifies host factors important for hepatitis A virus&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;UFMylation of the ribosomal protein RPL26 enhances viral translation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PAPD5/7-ZCCHC14 TRAMP-like complexes are important for hepatitis A virus&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pharmacological inhibition of PAPD5/7 reduces hepatitis A virus replication&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Summary&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hepatitis A virus (HAV) is a positive-sense RNA virus causing acute inflammation of the liver. Here, using a genome-scale CRISPR screen, we provide a comprehensive picture of the cellular factors that are exploited by HAV. We identify genes involved in sialic acid/ganglioside biosynthesis and members of the eukaryotic translation initiation factor complex, corroborating their putative roles for HAV. Additionally, we uncover all components of the cellular machinery for UFMylation, a ubiquitin-like protein modification. We show that HAV translation specifically depends on UFM1 conjugation of the ribosomal protein RPL26. Furthermore, we find that components related to the yeast Trf4/5-Air1/2-Mtr4 polyadenylation (TRAMP) complex are required for viral translation independent of controlling viral poly(A) tails or RNA stability. Finally, we demonstrate that pharmacological inhibition of the TRAMP-like complex decreases HAV replication in hepatocyte cells and human liver organoids, thus providing a strategy for host-directed therapy of HAV infection&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GP73 represses host innate immune response to promote virus replication by facilitating MAVS and TRAF6 degradation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/28394926/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/28394926/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Erratum in:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Correction: &lt;a href=&#34;https://journals.plos.org/plospathogens/article?id=10.1371/journal.ppat.1006938&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;GP73 represses host innate immune response to promote virus replication by facilitating MAVS and TRAF6 degradation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hepatitis C virus (HCV) infection is a leading cause of chronic liver diseases and hepatocellular carcinoma (HCC) and Golgi protein 73 (GP73) is a serum biomarker for liver diseases and HCC. However, the mechanism underlying GP73 regulates HCV infection is largely unknown. Here, we revealed that GP73 acts as a novel negative regulator of host innate immunity to facilitate HCV infection. GP73 expression is activated and correlated with interferon-beta (IFN-β) production during HCV infection in patients&amp;rsquo; serum, primary human hepatocytes (PHHs) and human hepatoma cells through mitochondrial antiviral signaling protein (MAVS), TNF receptor-associated factor 6 (TRAF6) and mitogen-activated protein kinase kinase/extracellular regulated protein kinase (MEK/ERK) pathway. Detailed studies revealed that HCV infection activates MAVS that in turn recruits TRAF6 via TRAF-interacting-motifs (TIMs), and TRAF6 subsequently directly recruits GP73 to MAVS via coiled-coil domain. After binding with MAVS and TRAF6, GP73 promotes MAVS and TRAF6 degradation through proteasome-dependent pathway. Moreover, GP73 attenuates IFN-β promoter, IFN-stimulated response element (ISRE) and nuclear factor κB (NF-κB) promoter and down-regulates IFN-β, IFN-λ1, interleukin-6 (IL-6) and IFN-stimulated gene 56 (ISG56), leading to the repression of host innate immunity. Finally, knock-down of GP73 down-regulates HCV infection and replication in Huh7-MAVSR cells and primary human hepatocytes (PHHs), but such repression is rescued by GP73m4 (a mutant GP73 resists to GP73-shRNA#4) in Huh7-MAVSR cells, suggesting that GP73 facilitates HCV infection. Taken together, we demonstrated that GP73 acts as a negative regulator of innate immunity to facilitate HCV infection by interacting with MAVS/TRAF6 and promoting MAVS/TRAF6 degradation. This study provides new insights into the mechanism of HCV infection and pathogenesis, and suggests that GP73 is a new potential antiviral target in the prevention and treatment of HCV associated diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ly6Chi monocytes regulate T cell responses in viral hepatitis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/27777980/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/27777980/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Viral hepatitis remains a global health challenge despite recent progress in the development of more effective therapies. Although virus-specific CD8+ and CD4+ T cell responses are essential for viral clearance, it remains largely unknown what regulates T cell-mediated viral clearance. Thus, a better understanding of the regulation of anti-viral T cell immunity would be critical for the design of more effective therapies for viral hepatitis. Using a model of adenovirus-induced hepatitis, here we showed that adenoviral infection induced recruitment of Ly6C&lt;sup&gt;hi&lt;/sup&gt; monocytes to the liver in a CCR2-dependent manner. These recruited Ly6C&lt;sup&gt;hi&lt;/sup&gt; monocytes suppressed CD8&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; and CD4&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T cell responses to adenoviral infection, leading to a delay in viral clearance. In vivo depletion of Ly6C&lt;sup&gt;hi&lt;/sup&gt; monocytes markedly enhanced anti-viral T cell responses and promoted viral clearance. Mechanistically, we showed that induction of iNOS and the production of NO by Ly6C&lt;sup&gt;hi&lt;/sup&gt; monocytes are critical for the suppression of T cell responses. In addition, a contact-dependent mechanism mediated by PD-1 and PD-L1 interaction is also required for T cell suppression by Ly6C&lt;sup&gt;hi&lt;/sup&gt; monocytes. These findings suggest a critical role for Ly6C&lt;sup&gt;hi&lt;/sup&gt; monocytes in the regulation of T cell immunity in viral hepatitis and may provide new insights into development of more effective therapies for treating viral hepatitis based on targeting the immunosuppressing monocytes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
