<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Endocytosis | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/endocytosis/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/endocytosis/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Endocytosis</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Endocytosis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/endocytosis/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>GPR97 deficiency ameliorates renal interstitial fibrosis in mouse hypertensive nephropathy</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36635422/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36635422/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hypertensive nephropathy (HTN) ranks as the second-leading cause of end-stage renal disease (ESRD). Accumulating evidence suggests that persistent hypertension injures tubular cells, leading to tubulointerstitial fibrosis (TIF), which is involved in the pathogenesis of HTN. G protein-coupled receptors (GPCRs) are implicated in many important pathological and physiological processes and act as important drug targets. In this study, we explored the intrarenal mechanisms underlying hypertension-associated TIF, and particularly, the potential role of GPR97, a member of the adhesion GPCR subfamily, in TIF. A deoxycorticosterone acetate (DOCA)/salt-induced hypertensive mouse model was used. We revealed a significantly upregulated expression of GPR97 in the kidneys, especially in renal tubules, of the hypertensive mice and 10 patients with biopsy-proven hypertensive kidney injury. GPR97-/- mice showed markedly elevated blood pressure, which was comparable to that of wild-type mice following DOCA/salt treatment, but dramatically ameliorated renal injury and TIF. In NRK-52E cells, we demonstrated that knockdown of GPR97 suppressed the activation of TGF-β signaling by disturbing small GTPase RhoA-mediated cytoskeletal reorganization, thus inhibiting clathrin-mediated endocytosis of TGF-β receptors and subsequent Smad activation. Collectively, this study demonstrates that GPR97 contributes to hypertension-associated TIF at least in part by facilitating TGF-β signaling, suggesting that GPR97 is a pivotal intrarenal factor for TIF progression under hypertensive conditions, and therapeutic strategies targeting GPR97 may improve the outcomes of patients with HTN.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Polystyrene microplastics significantly facilitate influenza A virus infection of host cells</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36623344/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36623344/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Microplastics (MPs) are emerging pollutants which exist in various environments and pose a potential threat to human health. However, the effect of MP on respiratory pathogens-infected organisms is unknown. In order to explore the effect of MP on respiratory pathogen infection, we studied the effect of polystyrene microplastics (PS) on influenza A virus (IAV)-infected A549 cells. Western blot, qPCR, and viral plaque assay demonstrated that PS could promote IAV infection. Further study by bioluminescence imaging showed that a large number of IAV could be enriched on PS and entered cells through endocytosis. Meanwhile, the expression of IFITM3 in cells was significantly reduced. In addition, our results showed that PS down-regulated IRF3 and its active form P-IRF3 by down-regulating RIG-I and inhibiting TBK1 phosphorylation activation, which then significantly reduced IFN-β expression and affected the cellular innate antiviral immune system. Taken together, our results indicate the potential threat of MPs to respiratory diseases caused by IAV and provide new insights into human health protection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
