<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Organoid | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/organoid/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/organoid/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Organoid</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Organoid</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/organoid/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>A DLG1-ARHGAP31-CDC42 axis is essential for the intestinal stem cell response to fluctuating niche Wnt signaling</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36640764/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36640764/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Polarity of the mammalian intestinal epithelium is independent of &lt;em&gt;Dlg1&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Loss of &lt;em&gt;Dlg1&lt;/em&gt; in ISCs results in cell death under high Wnt conditions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ISCs lacking &lt;em&gt;Dlg1&lt;/em&gt; have impaired cell division and migration&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Canonical WNT ligands activate non-canonical Wnt signaling via DLG1-ARHGAP31-CDC42&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A central factor in the maintenance of tissue integrity is the response of stem cells to variations in the levels of niche signals. In the gut, intestinal stem cells (ISCs) depend on Wnt ligands for self-renewal and proliferation. Transient increases in Wnt signaling promote regeneration after injury or in inflammatory bowel diseases, whereas constitutive activation of this pathway leads to colorectal cancer. Here, we report that Discs large 1 (&lt;em&gt;Dlg1&lt;/em&gt;), although dispensable for polarity and cellular turnover during intestinal homeostasis, is required for ISC survival in the context of increased Wnt signaling. RNA sequencing (RNA-seq) and genetic mouse models demonstrated that DLG1 regulates the cellular response to increased canonical Wnt ligands. This occurs via the transcriptional regulation of &lt;em&gt;Arhgap31&lt;/em&gt;, a GTPase-activating protein that deactivates CDC42, an effector of the non-canonical Wnt pathway. These findings reveal a DLG1-ARHGAP31-CDC42 axis that is essential for the ISC response to increased niche Wnt signaling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analogous comparison unravels heightened antiviral defense and boosted viral infection upon immunosuppression in bat organoids</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36529763/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36529763/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Horseshoe bats host numerous SARS-related coronaviruses without overt disease signs. Bat intestinal organoids, a unique model of bat intestinal epithelium, allow direct comparison with human intestinal organoids. We sought to unravel the cellular mechanism(s) underlying bat tolerance of coronaviruses by comparing the innate immunity in bat and human organoids. We optimized the culture medium, which enabled a consecutive passage of bat intestinal organoids for over one year. Basal expression levels of IFNs and IFN-stimulated genes were higher in bat organoids than in their human counterparts. Notably, bat organoids mounted a more rapid, robust and prolonged antiviral defense than human organoids upon Poly(I:C) stimulation. TLR3 and RLR might be the conserved pathways mediating antiviral response in bat and human intestinal organoids. The susceptibility of bat organoids to a bat coronavirus CoV-HKU4, but resistance to EV-71, an enterovirus of exclusive human origin, indicated that bat organoids adequately recapitulated the authentic susceptibility of bats to certain viruses. Importantly, TLR3/RLR inhibition in bat organoids significantly boosted viral growth in the early phase after SARS-CoV-2 or CoV-HKU4 infection. Collectively, the higher basal expression of antiviral genes, especially more rapid and robust induction of innate immune response, empowered bat cells to curtail virus propagation in the early phase of infection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SARS-CoV-2 replication in airway epithelia requires motile cilia and microvillar reprogramming</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36580912/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36580912/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SARS-CoV-2 binds ACE2 on multicilia in airway epithelia immediately upon infection&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Depleting motile cilia inhibits viral entry by SARS-CoV-2 and other respiratory viruses&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SARS-CoV-2 activates PAK kinases to rearrange airway microvilli driving viral exit&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Omicron variants accelerate cilia-dependent entry through the airway mucin barrier&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How SARS-CoV-2 penetrates the airway barrier of mucus and periciliary mucins to infect nasal epithelium remains unclear. Using primary nasal epithelial organoid cultures, we found that the virus attaches to motile cilia via the ACE2 receptor. SARS-CoV-2 traverses the mucus layer, using motile cilia as tracks to access the cell body. Depleting cilia blocks infection for SARS-CoV-2 and other respiratory viruses. SARS-CoV-2 progeny attach to airway microvilli 24 h post-infection and trigger formation of apically extended and highly branched microvilli that organize viral egress from the microvilli back into the mucus layer, supporting a model of virus dispersion throughout airway tissue via mucociliary transport. Phosphoproteomics and kinase inhibition reveal that microvillar remodeling is regulated by p21-activated kinases (PAK). Importantly, Omicron variants bind with higher affinity to motile cilia and show accelerated viral entry. Our work suggests that motile cilia, microvilli, and mucociliary-dependent mucus flow are critical for efficient virus replication in nasal epithelia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generation and multiomic profiling of a TP53/CDKN2A double-knockout gastroesophageal junction organoid model</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36449602/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36449602/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inactivation of the tumor suppressor genes tumor protein p53 (&lt;em&gt;TP53&lt;/em&gt;) and cyclin-dependent kinase inhibitor 2A (&lt;em&gt;CDKN2A&lt;/em&gt;) occurs early during gastroesophageal junction (GEJ) tumorigenesis. However, because of a paucity of GEJ-specific disease models, cancer-promoting consequences of &lt;em&gt;TP53&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;CDKN2A&lt;/em&gt; inactivation at the GEJ have not been characterized. Here, we report the development of a wild-type primary human GEJ organoid model and a CRISPR-edited transformed GEJ organoid model. CRISPR-Cas9–mediated &lt;em&gt;TP53&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;CDKN2A&lt;/em&gt; knockout (&lt;em&gt;TP53/CDKN2A&lt;sup&gt;KO&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt;) in GEJ organoids induced morphologic dysplasia and proneoplastic features in vitro and tumor formation in vivo. Lipidomic profiling identified several platelet-activating factors (PTAFs) among the most up-regulated lipids in CRISPR-edited organoids. PTAF/PTAF receptor (PTAFR) abrogation by siRNA knockdown or a pharmacologic inhibitor (WEB2086) reduced proliferation and other proneoplastic features of &lt;em&gt;TP53/CDKN2A&lt;sup&gt;KO&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; GEJ organoids in vitro and tumor formation in vivo. In addition, murine xenografts of Eso26, an established human esophageal adenocarcinoma cell line, were suppressed by WEB2086. Mechanistically, &lt;em&gt;TP53/CDKN2A&lt;/em&gt; dual inactivation disrupted both the transcriptome and the DNA methylome, likely mediated by key transcription factors, particularly forkhead box M1 (FOXM1). FOXM1 activated &lt;em&gt;PTAFR&lt;/em&gt; transcription by binding to the &lt;em&gt;PTAFR&lt;/em&gt; promoter, further amplifying the PTAF-PTAFR pathway. Together, these studies established a robust model system for investigating early GEJ neoplastic events, identified crucial metabolic and epigenomic changes occurring during GEJ model tumorigenesis, and revealed a potential cancer therapeutic strategy. This work provides insights into proneoplastic mechanisms associated with &lt;em&gt;TP53/CDKN2A&lt;/em&gt; inactivation in early GEJ neoplasia, which may facilitate early diagnosis and prevention of GEJ neoplasms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>B cell expansion hinders the stroma-epithelium regenerative cross talk during mucosal healing</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36462502/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36462502/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;B cells are the dominant immune cell type during colonic mucosal healing (MH)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;IFN-induced B cells are associated with injury and expand during MH&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;B cell depletion results in enhanced MH following intestinal injury&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;B cells impair the interactions between IEC and stromal cells during MH&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therapeutic promotion of intestinal regeneration holds great promise, but defining the cellular mechanisms that influence tissue regeneration remains an unmet challenge. To gain insight into the process of mucosal healing, we longitudinally examined the immune cell composition during intestinal damage and regeneration. B cells were the dominant cell type in the healing colon, and single-cell RNA sequencing (scRNA-seq) revealed expansion of an IFN-induced B cell subset during experimental mucosal healing that predominantly located in damaged areas and associated with colitis severity. B cell depletion accelerated recovery upon injury, decreased epithelial ulceration, and enhanced gene expression programs associated with tissue remodeling. scRNA-seq from the epithelial and stromal compartments combined with spatial transcriptomics and multiplex immunostaining showed that B cells decreased interactions between stromal and epithelial cells during mucosal healing. Activated B cells disrupted the epithelial-stromal cross talk required for organoid survival. Thus, B cell expansion during injury impairs epithelial-stromal cell interactions required for mucosal healing, with implications for the treatment of IBD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generation of neural organoids for spinal-cord regeneration via the direct reprogramming of human astrocytes</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36424465/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36424465/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Organoids with region-specific architecture could facilitate the repair of injuries of the central nervous system. Here we show that human astrocytes can be directly reprogrammed into early neuroectodermal cells via the overexpression of &lt;em&gt;OCT4&lt;/em&gt;, the suppression of &lt;em&gt;p53&lt;/em&gt; and the provision of the small molecules CHIR99021, SB431542, RepSox and Y27632. We also report that the activation of signalling mediated by fibroblast growth factor, sonic hedgehog and bone morphogenetic protein 4 in the reprogrammed cells induces them to form spinal-cord organoids with functional neurons specific to the dorsal and ventral domains. In mice with complete spinal-cord injury, organoids transplanted into the lesion differentiated into spinal-cord neurons, which migrated and formed synapses with host neurons. The direct reprogramming of human astrocytes into neurons may pave the way for in vivo neural organogenesis from endogenous astrocytes for the repair of injuries to the central nervous system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A human kidney and liver organoid-based multi-organ-on-a-chip model to study the therapeutic effects and biodistribution of mesenchymal stromal cell-derived extracellular vesicles</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36382606/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36382606/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mesenchymal stromal cell (MSC)-derived small extracellular vesicles (sEVs) show therapeutic potential in multiple disease models, including kidney injury. Clinical translation of sEVs requires further preclinical and regulatory developments, including elucidation of the biodistribution and mode of action (MoA). Biodistribution can be determined using labelled sEVs in animal models which come with ethical concerns, are time-consuming and expensive, and may not well represent human physiology. We hypothesised that, based on developments in microfluidics and human organoid technology, in vitro multi-organ-on-a-chip (MOC) models allow us to study effects of sEVs in modelled human organs like kidney and liver in a semi-systemic manner. Human kidney- and liver organoids combined by microfluidic channels maintained physiological functions, and a kidney injury model was established using hydrogenperoxide. MSC-sEVs were isolated, and their size, density and potential contamination were analysed. These sEVs stimulated recovery of the renal epithelium after injury. Microscopic analysis shows increased accumulation of PKH67-labelled sEVs not only in injured kidney cells, but also in the unharmed liver organoids, compared to healthy control conditions. In conclusion, this new MOC model recapitulates therapeutic efficacy and biodistribution of MSC-sEVs as observed in animal models. Its human background allows for in-depth analysis of the MoA and identification of potential side effects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extended longevity geometrically-inverted proximal tubule organoids</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36215909/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36215909/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This study reports the cellular self-organization of primary human renal proximal tubule epithelial cells (RPTECs) around a minimal Matrigel scaffold to produce basal-in and apical-out proximal tubule organoids (tubuloids). These tubuloids are produced and maintained in hanging drop cultures for 90+ days, the longest such culture of any kind reported to date. The tubuloids upregulate maturity markers, such as aquaporin-1 (AQP1) and megalin (LRP2), and exhibit less mesenchymal and proliferation markers, such as vimentin and Ki67, compared to 2D cultures. They also experience changes over time as revealed by a comparison of gene expression patterns of cells in 2D culture and in day 31 and day 67 tubuloids. Gene expression analysis and immunohistochemistry reveal an increase in the expression of megalin, an endocytic receptor that can directly bind and uptake protein or potentially assist protein uptake. The tubuloids, including day 90 tubuloids, uptake fluorescent albumin and reveal punctate fluorescent patterns, suggesting functional endocytic uptake through these receptors. Furthermore, the tubuloids release kidney injury molecule-1 (KIM-1), a common biomarker for kidney injury, when exposed to albumin in both dose- and time-dependent manners. While this study focuses on potential applications for modeling proteinuric kidney disease, the tubuloids may have broad utility for studies where apical proximal tubule cell access is required.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adipocyte-Derived Exosomal MTTP Suppresses Ferroptosis and Promotes Chemoresistance in Colorectal Cancer</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35978266/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35978266/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Obesity is closely related to a poor prognosis in patients with advanced colorectal cancer (CRC), but the mechanisms remain unclear. Ferroptosis is a form of nonapoptotic cell death characterized by lipid reactive oxygen species (ROS) accumulation and iron dependency and is associated with the chemoresistance of tumors. Here, it is shown that adipose-derived exosomes reduce ferroptosis susceptibility in CRC, thus promoting chemoresistance to oxaliplatin. It is found that microsomal triglyceride transfer protein (MTTP) expression is increased in the plasma exosomes of CRC patients with a high body fat ratio, serving as an inhibitor of ferroptosis and reducing sensitivity to chemotherapy. Mechanistically, the MTTP/proline-rich acidic protein 1 (PRAP1) complex inhibited zinc finger E-box binding homeobox 1 expression and upregulated glutathione peroxidase 4 and xCT, leading to a decreased polyunsaturated fatty acids ratio and lipid ROS levels. Moreover, experiments are carried out in organoids, and a tumor implantation model is established in obese mice, demonstrating that the inhibition of MTTP increases the sensitivity to chemotherapy. The results reveal a novel intracellular signaling pathway mediated by adipose-derived exosomes and suggest that treatments targeting secreted MTTP might reverse oxaliplatin resistance in CRC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recapitulating influenza virus infection and facilitating antiviral and neuroprotective screening in tractable brain organoids</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35910807/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35910807/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Human pluripotent stem cell derived brain organoids offer an unprecedented opportunity for various applications as &lt;em&gt;in vitro&lt;/em&gt; model. Currently, human brain organoids as models have been used to understand virus-induced neurotoxicity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; The brain organoids were separately challenged by multiple viruses including influenza viruses (H1N1-WSN and H3N2-HKT68), Enteroviruses (EV68 and EV71) and Severe Fever with Thrombocytopenia Syndrome Virus (SFTSV) to investigate the impaired effect of these viruses on human brain development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; The brain organoids challenged by influenza viruses had decreased overall organoid size, while enteroviruses infected brain organoids displayed the opposite result. Then, we found WSN preferentially infected MAP2+ neurons compared to SOX2+ neural stem cells (NSCs) and GFAP+ astrocytes in brain organoids, and induced apoptosis of NSCs and neurons, and released inflammatory factors (TNF-α, INF-γ, and IL-6), facilitating brain damage. Furthermore, transcriptional profiling revealed several co-upregulated genes (&lt;em&gt;CSAG3&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;OAS2&lt;/em&gt;) and co-downregulated genes (&lt;em&gt;CDC20B&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;KCNJ13&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;OTX2-AS1&lt;/em&gt;) after WSN infection for 24 hpi and 96 hpi, implicating target for antiviral drugs development. Finally, we explored compound PYC-12 could significantly suppress virus infection, apoptosis, and inflammatory responses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; Collectively, we established a tractable experimental model to investigate the impact and mechanism of virus infection on human brain development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MECP2-related pathways are dysregulated in a cortical organoid model of myotonic dystrophy</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35767654/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35767654/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Myotonic dystrophy type 1 (DM1) is a multisystem, autosomal-dominant inherited disorder caused by CTG microsatellite repeat expansions (MREs) in the 3&amp;rsquo; untranslated region of the dystrophia myotonica-protein kinase (&lt;em&gt;DMPK&lt;/em&gt;) gene. Despite its prominence as the most common adult-onset muscular dystrophy, patients with congenital to juvenile-onset forms of DM1 can present with debilitating neurocognitive symptoms along the autism spectrum, characteristic of possible in utero cortical defects. However, the molecular mechanism by which CTG MREs lead to these developmental central nervous system (CNS) manifestations is unknown. Here, we showed that CUG foci found early in the maturation of three-dimensional (3D) cortical organoids from DM1 patient-derived induced pluripotent stem cells (iPSCs) cause hyperphosphorylation of CUGBP Elav-like family member 2 (CELF2) protein. Integrative single-cell RNA sequencing and enhanced cross-linking and immunoprecipitation (eCLIP) analysis revealed that reduced CELF2 protein-RNA substrate interactions results in misregulation of genes critical for excitatory synaptic signaling in glutamatergic neurons, including key components of the methyl-CpG binding protein 2 (MECP2) pathway. Comparisons to MECP2&lt;sup&gt;(y/-)&lt;/sup&gt; cortical organoids revealed convergent molecular and cellular defects such as glutamate toxicity and neuronal loss. Our findings provide evidence suggesting that early-onset DM1 might involve neurodevelopmental disorder-associated pathways and identify N-methyl-d-aspartic acid (NMDA) antagonists as potential treatment avenues for neuronal defects in DM1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Uptake of Functional Ultrasmall Gold Nanoparticles in 3D Gut Cell Models</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35712760/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35712760/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ultrasmall gold nanoparticles (2 nm) easily penetrate the membranes of intestinal murine epithelial cells (MODE-K) and colorectal cancer cells (CT-26). They are also taken up by 3D spheroids (400 µm) of these cell types and primary gut organoids (500 µm). In contrast, dissolved dyes are not taken up by any of these cells or 3D structures. The distribution of fluorescent ultrasmall gold nanoparticles inside cells, spheroids, and gut organoids is examined by confocal laser scanning microscopy. Nanoparticles conjugated with the cytostatic drug doxorubicin and a fluorescent dye exhibit significantly greater cytotoxicity toward CT-26 tumor spheroids than equally concentrated dissolved doxorubicin, probably because they enter the interior of a spheroid much more easily than dissolved doxorubicin. Comprehensive analyses show that the cellular uptake of ultrasmall gold nanoparticles occurs by different endocytosis pathways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>KMT2C deficiency promotes small cell lung cancer metastasis through DNMT3A-mediated epigenetic reprogramming</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35449309/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35449309/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Small cell lung cancer (SCLC) is notorious for its early and frequent metastases, which contribute to it as a recalcitrant malignancy. To understand the molecular mechanisms underlying SCLC metastasis, we generated SCLC mouse models with orthotopically transplanted genome-edited lung organoids and performed multiomics analyses. We found that a deficiency of KMT2C, a histone H3 lysine 4 methyltransferase frequently mutated in extensive-stage SCLC, promoted multiple-organ metastases in mice. Metastatic and KMT2C-deficient SCLC displayed both histone and DNA hypomethylation. Mechanistically, KMT2C directly regulated the expression of DNMT3A, a de novo DNA methyltransferase, through histone methylation. Forced DNMT3A expression restrained metastasis of KMT2C-deficient SCLC through repressing metastasis-promoting MEIS/HOX genes. Further, S-(5′-adenosyl)-L-methionine, the common cofactor of histone and DNA methyltransferases, inhibited SCLC metastasis. Thus, our study revealed a concerted epigenetic reprogramming of KMT2C- and DNMT3A-mediated histone and DNA hypomethylation underlying SCLC metastasis, which suggested a potential epigenetic therapeutic vulnerability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wnt Signaling in 3D: Recent Advances in the Applications of Intestinal Organoids</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/31718893/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/31718893/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Using organoid technology, adult epithelial stem cells can be expanded &lt;em&gt;in vitro&lt;/em&gt; to generate self-organizing 3D epithelial structures that closely recapitulate the architecture and cellular composition of the tissue of origin.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Because of their strict dependence on Wnt ligands for survival and growth, intestinal organoids have become the tool of choice for &lt;em&gt;in vitro&lt;/em&gt; studies aimed at revealing mechanistic aspects of Wnt signaling.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Adult stem cell- and patient-derived intestinal organoids can serve as a platform for investigating mutation-induced disease mechanisms. Insights into how specific mutations alter Wnt activity are becoming a key determinant for tailored therapeutic approaches.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Given the rapid expansion of the organoid field and its applications, there is an increasing need for a standardized method to interpret organoid genotype–phenotype relationships.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Intestinal organoids grown from adult stem cells have emerged as prototype 3D organotypic models for studying tissue renewal and homeostasis. Owing to their strict dependence on Wnt signaling, intestinal organoids offer an unprecedented opportunity to examine Wnt pathway regulation in normal physiology and cancer. We review how alterations in growth factor dependency and organoid morphology can be exploited to identify Wnt signaling mechanisms, characterize mutated pathway components, and predict responses of patient-derived tumors to targeted therapy. We discuss current deficits in the understanding of genotype-phenotype relationships that are to be considered when interpreting mutation-induced changes in organoid morphology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Disease Modeling in Stem Cell-Derived 3D Organoid Systems</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/28341301/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/28341301/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Organoids are 3D in vitro culture systems derived from self-organizing stem cells. They can recapitulate the in vivo architecture, functionality, and genetic signature of original tissues. Thus, organoid technology has been rapidly applied to understanding stem cell biology, organogenesis, and various human pathologies. The recent development of human patient-derived organoids has enabled disease modeling with precision, highlighting their great potential in biomedical applications, translational medicine, and personalized therapy. In light of recent breakthroughs using organoids, it is only apt that we appreciate the advantages and shortcomings of this technology to exploit its full potential. We discuss recent advances in the application of organoids in studying cancer and hereditary diseases, as well as in the examination of host cell-microorganism interactions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
