<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Wound Healing | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/wound-healing/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/wound-healing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Wound Healing</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Wound Healing</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/wound-healing/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Injectable adhesive self-healing biocompatible hydrogel for haemostasis, wound healing, and postoperative tissue adhesion prevention in nephron-sparing surgery</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36100176/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36100176/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Statement of significance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Extended warm ischemia time during nephron sparing surgery negatively affected postoperative renal function due to the need for hemostasis at the wound with abundant blood supply, and postoperative wound healing and additional adhesions caused by the surgical procedure deserve attention. Based on the efficient and stable adhesion properties of hydrogels and the ability to promote wound healing. Herein, a series of adhesive self-healing biocompatible hydrogels were prepared based on free-radical polymerization of acryloyl-6-aminocaproic acid (AA) and N-acryloyl 2-glycine (NAG) and the ionic coordination between Ca2+ with the abundant carboxyl groups in AA and NAG. AA/NAG/Ca hydrogel showed hemostasis property in nephron sparing surgery model, promote kidney wound healing, and could perform anti-postoperative adhesion efficacy in an abdomen-caecum adhesion model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nephron-sparing surgery is a well-established treatment in patients with T1a renal cell carcinoma; however, the complex suturing process prolongs warm ischaemia time, affects the preservation of normal renal parenchymal function, and causes avoidable postoperative tissue adhesion complications, including chronic abdominal pain, intestinal obstruction, and female infertility. Hence, the design of multifunctional biomaterials with haemostasis, postoperative wound management, and postoperative tissue adhesion prevention properties for nephron-sparing surgeries is urgently needed. In this study, a series of injectable adhesive multifunctional biocompatible hydrogels were designed based on the free-radical polymerisation of monomers acryloyl-6-aminocaproic acid (AA) and N-acryloyl 2-glycine (NAG), and the ionic coordination between Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt; and the abundant carboxyl groups in AA and NAG. AA/NAG/Ca (AA, NAG, and Ca refer to acryloyl-6-aminocaproic acid, N-acryloyl 2-glycine and calcium chloride, respectively) hydrogel exhibited good mechanical properties, swelling and adhesion properties, flexibility, in vitro blood-clotting ability, and cytocompatibility. In vivo experiments on liver injury models and rat/rabbit nephron-sparing surgery models elucidated that the AA/NAG/Ca hydrogel had haemostasis performance and wound healing properties that led to short bleeding time, reduced bleeding volume, and well-organised nephron structures. An abdomen-caecum adhesion model indicated that the AA/NAG/Ca hydrogel showed excellent anti-adhesion properties. In summary, this multifunctional hydrogel exhibited potential for improving haemostasis and wound management in nephron-sparing surgeries, showing potential for clinical application. STATEMENT OF SIGNIFICANCE: Extended warm ischemia time during nephron sparing surgery negatively affected postoperative renal function due to the need for hemostasis at the wound with abundant blood supply, and postoperative wound healing and additional adhesions caused by the surgical procedure deserve attention. Based on the efficient and stable adhesion properties of hydrogels and the ability to promote wound healing. Herein, a series of adhesive self-healing biocompatible hydrogels were prepared based on free-radical polymerization of acryloyl-6-aminocaproic acid (AA) and N-acryloyl 2-glycine (NAG) and the ionic coordination between Ca2+ with the abundant carboxyl groups in AA and NAG. AA/NAG/Ca hydrogel showed hemostasis property in nephron sparing surgery model, promote kidney wound healing, and could perform anti-postoperative adhesion efficacy in an abdomen-caecum adhesion model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
