<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hedgehog | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/hedgehog/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/hedgehog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Hedgehog</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Hedgehog</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/hedgehog/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hedgehog pathway and its inhibitors in chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD)</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/36191777/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/36191777/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;COPD affects millions of people and is now ranked as the third leading cause of death worldwide. This largely untreatable chronic airway disease results in irreversible destruction of lung architecture. The small lung hypothesis is now supported by epidemiological, physiological and clinical studies. Accordingly, the early and severe COPD phenotype carries the most dreadful prognosis and finds its roots during lung growth. Pathophysiological mechanisms remain poorly understood and implicate individual susceptibility (genetics), a large part of environmental factors (viral infections, tobacco consumption, air pollution) and the combined effects of those triggers on gene expression. Genetic susceptibility is most likely involved as the disease is severe and starts early in life. The latter observation led to the identification of Mendelian inheritance via disease-causing variants of SERPINA1 - known as the basis for alpha-1 anti-trypsin deficiency, and TERT. In the last two decades multiple genome wide association studies (GWAS) identified many single nucleotide polymorphisms (SNPs) associated with COPD. High significance SNPs are located in 4q31 near HHIP which encodes an evolutionarily highly conserved physiological inhibitor of the Hedgehog signaling pathway (HH). HHIP is critical to several in utero developmental lung processes. It is also implicated in homeostasis, injury response, epithelial-mesenchymal transition and tumor resistance to apoptosis. A few studies have reported decreased HHIP RNA and protein levels in human adult COPD lungs. HHIP+/- murine models led to emphysema. HH pathway inhibitors, such as vismodegib and sonidegib, are already validated in oncology, whereas other drugs have evidenced in vitro effects. Targeting the Hedgehog pathway could lead to a new therapeutic avenue in COPD. In this review, we focused on the early and severe COPD phenotype and the small lung hypothesis by exploring genetic susceptibility traits that are potentially treatable, thus summarizing promising therapeutics for the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Garcinone C Suppresses Tumorsphere Formation and Invasiveness by Hedgehog/Gli1 Signaling in Colorectal Cancer Stem-like Cells</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35749593/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35749593/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hyperactivation of hedgehog signaling occurs in colorectal cancer stem-like cells (CSCs), a rare subpopulation, potentially involved in metastasis, chemotherapy resistance, and cancer relapse. Garcinone C, a xanthone isolated from mangosteen (&lt;em&gt;Garcinia mangostana&lt;/em&gt;), suppresses colorectal cancer &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;in vitro&lt;/em&gt; by inhibiting Gli1-dependent noncanonical hedgehog signaling. Herein, we investigated the effect of garcinone C on cancer stemness and invasiveness in colorectal cancer; Gli1 was noted as pivotal in maintaining stemness and invasiveness in HCT116 and HT29 CSCs. Garcinone C inhibited the proliferation and self-renewal of HCT116 and HT29 CSCs. Colon cancer stemness markers such as CD44, CD133, ALDH1, and Nanog were significantly decreased by garcinone C. Computational studies showed that garcinone C showed a high affinity with the Gli1 protein ZF domain by forming hydrogen bonds with amino acid residues of ASP244, ARG223, and ASP216. Besides, MG132 blocked the effects of garcinone C on Gli1. Thus, garcinone C suppressed colorectal CSCs by binding to Gli1 and enhancing its degradation. MMP2 and MMP9 levels, invasive-related markers, were increased in HCT116 CSCs but decreased by garcinone C. E-cadherin level was reduced in HCT116 CSCs, while the presence of garcinone C was restored. Garcinone C inhibited the proliferation and invasiveness of colorectal CSCs by targeting Gli1-dependent Hh signaling. Garcinone C may be a potent natural agent against colorectal cancer relapse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pirfenidone ameliorates early pulmonary fibrosis in LPS-induced acute respiratory distress syndrome by inhibiting endothelial-to-mesenchymal transition via the Hedgehog signaling pathway</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35504205/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35504205/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlight&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pirfenidone(PFD) treatment can inhibit the progress of pulmonary fibrosis and notably reduce the mortality of ARDS mice in early stage of ARDS.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PFD reduces early pulmonary fibrosis stimulated by LPS, which is related to the inhibition of EndMT.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PFD may ameliorate LPS-induced ARDS by regulating the HH signaling pathway.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pulmonary vascular endothelial dysfunction is a key pathogenic mechanism in acute respiratory distress syndrome (ARDS), resulting in fibrosis in lung tissues, including in the context of COVID-19. Pirfenidone (PFD) has become a novel therapeutic agent for treating idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis (IPF) and can improve lung function, inhibit fibrosis and inhibit inflammation. Recently, endothelial-to-mesenchymal transition (EndMT) was shown to play a crucial role in various respiratory diseases. However, the role of PFD in the course of EndMT in LPS-induced ARDS remains poorly understood. The purpose of this study was to explore the anti-EndMT effects of PFD on pulmonary fibrosis after LPS-induced ARDS. First, we determined that PFD significantly reduced LPS-induced ARDS, as shown by significant pathological alterations, and alleviated the oxidative stress and inflammatory response in vitro and in vivo. Furthermore, PFD decreased pulmonary fibrosis in LPS-induced ARDS by inhibiting EndMT and reduced the expression levels of Hedgehog (HH) pathway target genes, such as Gli1 and α-SMA, after LPS induction. In summary, this study confirmed that inhibiting the HH pathway by PFD could decrease pulmonary fibrosis by downregulating EndMT in LPS-induced ARDS. In conclusion, we demonstrate that PFD is a promising agent to attenuate pulmonary fibrosis following ARDS in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A novel promoter-associated non-coding small RNA paGLI1 recruits FUS/P65 to transactivate GLI1 gene expression and promotes infiltrating glioma progression</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35051534/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35051534/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Discovery of the first sense promoter-associated ncRNA derived from GLI1 (paGLI1), which is overexpressed in diffusely infiltrating gliomas.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PaGLI1 promotes GLI1 gene transcription by interacting with paGLI1 DNA, binding to and recruitment of transcription factor complex FUS/P65 to the GLI1 promoter, which results in enhancement of glioma cell proliferation and invasiveness.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Over-expression of paGLI1 is a significant unfavorable prognosticator for both disease-specific and progression-free survival in glioma patients.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Glioma-associated oncogene homolog 1 (GLI1) is a core component of the Hedgehog (HH) signalling pathway and is a transcription activator of numerous oncogenes, such as SOX9, VEGFA, BCL2, and CDK2. The complex regulation of GLI1 involves numerous pathways and molecules, including HH-dependent and independent, epigenetic and post-transcriptional mechanisms. Here, we report the discovery, characterization and function of a novel sense promoter-associated ncRNA, paGLI1 that is overexpressed in infiltrating glioma. We show that paGLI1 promotes GLI1 gene transcription through binding to and recruitment of the transcription factor complex FUS/P65 by interacting with paGLI1 DNA sequence. This interaction facilitates FUS/P65 binding to the GLI1 promoter to activate GLI1 transcription and hence its downstream oncogenes, which results in enhancement of glioma cell proliferation and invasiveness. Importantly, over-expression of paGLI1 is a significant unfavorable prognosticator for both disease-specific and progression-free survival in glioma patients, with relative risks being 2.932 (95% confidence interval: 1.280 to 6.713) (P &amp;lt; 0.05) and 2.284 (95% confidence interval: 1.051 to 4.966) (P &amp;lt; 0.05), respectively. The novel paGLI1/FUS/P65 regulatory mechanisms play important roles in infiltrating glioma progression and may serve as potential targets for future therapeutics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
