<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Meta Analysis | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/meta-analysis/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/meta-analysis/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Meta Analysis</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Meta Analysis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/meta-analysis/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Genetic loci and prioritization of genes for kidney function decline derived from a meta-analysis of 62 longitudinal genome-wide association studies</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35716955/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35716955/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Estimated glomerular filtration rate (eGFR) reflects kidney function. Progressive eGFR-decline can lead to kidney failure, necessitating dialysis or transplantation. Hundreds of loci from genome-wide association studies (GWAS) for eGFR help explain population cross section variability. Since the contribution of these or other loci to eGFR-decline remains largely unknown, we derived GWAS for annual eGFR-decline and meta-analyzed 62 longitudinal studies with eGFR assessed twice over time in all 343,339 individuals and in high-risk groups. We also explored different covariate adjustment. Twelve genome-wide significant independent variants for eGFR-decline unadjusted or adjusted for eGFR-baseline (11 novel, one known for this phenotype), including nine variants robustly associated across models were identified. All loci for eGFR-decline were known for cross-sectional eGFR and thus distinguished a subgroup of eGFR loci. Seven of the nine variants showed variant-by-age interaction on eGFR cross section (further about 350,000 individuals), which linked genetic associations for eGFR-decline with age-dependency of genetic cross-section associations. Clinically important were two to four-fold greater genetic effects on eGFR-decline in high-risk subgroups. Five variants associated also with chronic kidney disease progression mapped to genes with functional in-silico evidence (UMOD, SPATA7, GALNTL5, TPPP). An unfavorable versus favorable nine-variant genetic profile showed increased risk odds ratios of 1.35 for kidney failure (95% confidence intervals 1.03-1.77) and 1.27 for acute kidney injury (95% confidence intervals 1.08-1.50) in over 2000 cases each, with matched controls). Thus, we provide a large data resource, genetic loci, and prioritized genes for kidney function decline, which help inform drug development pipelines revealing important insights into the age-dependency of kidney function genetics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Effects of Flavonoid Supplementation on Nanomaterial-Induced Toxicity: A Meta-Analysis of Preclinical Animal Studies</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35774549/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35774549/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Nanomaterials, widely applied in various fields, are reported to have toxic effects on human beings; thus, preventive or therapeutic measures are urgently needed. Given the anti-inflammatory and antioxidant activities, supplementation with flavonoids that are abundant in the human diet has been suggested as a potential strategy to protect against nanomaterial-induced toxicities. However, the beneficial effects of flavonoids remain inconclusive. In the present study, we performed a meta-analysis to comprehensively explore the roles and mechanisms of flavonoids for animals intoxicated with nanomaterials.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; A systematic literature search in PubMed, EMBASE, and Cochrane Library databases was performed up to April 2022. STATA 15.0 software was used for meta-analyses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; A total of 26 studies were identified. The results showed that flavonoid supplementation could significantly increase the levels of antioxidative enzymes (superoxide dismutase, catalase, glutathione, glutathione peroxidase, and glutathione-S-transferase), reduce the production of oxidative agents (malonaldehyde) and pro-inflammatory mediators (tumor necrosis factor-α, interleukin-6, IL-1β, C-reactive protein, immunoglobulin G, nitric oxide, vascular endothelial growth factor, and myeloperoxidase), and alleviate cell apoptosis (manifested by decreases in the mRNA expression levels of pro-apoptotic factors, such as caspase-3, Fas cell surface death receptor, and Bax, and increases in the mRNA expression levels of Bcl2), DNA damage (reductions in tail length and tail DNA%), and nanomaterial-induced injuries of the liver (reduced alanine aminotransferase and aspartate aminotransferase activities), kidney (reduced urea, blood urea nitrogen, creatinine, and uric acid concentration), testis (increased testosterone, sperm motility, 17β-hydroxysteroid dehydrogenase type, and reduced sperm abnormalities), and brain (enhanced acetylcholinesterase activities). Most of the results were not changed by subgroup analyses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/em&gt; Our findings suggest that appropriate supplementation of flavonoids may be effective to prevent the occupational detriments resulting from nanomaterial exposure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
