<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Meta Analysis | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/meta-analysis/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/meta-analysis/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Meta Analysis</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Meta Analysis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/meta-analysis/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Genetic loci and prioritization of genes for kidney function decline derived from a meta-analysis of 62 longitudinal genome-wide association studies</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35716955/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35716955/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Estimated glomerular filtration rate (eGFR) reflects kidney function. Progressive eGFR-decline can lead to kidney failure, necessitating dialysis or transplantation. Hundreds of loci from genome-wide association studies (GWAS) for eGFR help explain population cross section variability. Since the contribution of these or other loci to eGFR-decline remains largely unknown, we derived GWAS for annual eGFR-decline and meta-analyzed 62 longitudinal studies with eGFR assessed twice over time in all 343,339 individuals and in high-risk groups. We also explored different covariate adjustment. Twelve genome-wide significant independent variants for eGFR-decline unadjusted or adjusted for eGFR-baseline (11 novel, one known for this phenotype), including nine variants robustly associated across models were identified. All loci for eGFR-decline were known for cross-sectional eGFR and thus distinguished a subgroup of eGFR loci. Seven of the nine variants showed variant-by-age interaction on eGFR cross section (further about 350,000 individuals), which linked genetic associations for eGFR-decline with age-dependency of genetic cross-section associations. Clinically important were two to four-fold greater genetic effects on eGFR-decline in high-risk subgroups. Five variants associated also with chronic kidney disease progression mapped to genes with functional in-silico evidence (UMOD, SPATA7, GALNTL5, TPPP). An unfavorable versus favorable nine-variant genetic profile showed increased risk odds ratios of 1.35 for kidney failure (95% confidence intervals 1.03-1.77) and 1.27 for acute kidney injury (95% confidence intervals 1.08-1.50) in over 2000 cases each, with matched controls). Thus, we provide a large data resource, genetic loci, and prioritized genes for kidney function decline, which help inform drug development pipelines revealing important insights into the age-dependency of kidney function genetics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Effects of Flavonoid Supplementation on Nanomaterial-Induced Toxicity: A Meta-Analysis of Preclinical Animal Studies</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35774549/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35774549/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Nanomaterials, widely applied in various fields, are reported to have toxic effects on human beings; thus, preventive or therapeutic measures are urgently needed. Given the anti-inflammatory and antioxidant activities, supplementation with flavonoids that are abundant in the human diet has been suggested as a potential strategy to protect against nanomaterial-induced toxicities. However, the beneficial effects of flavonoids remain inconclusive. In the present study, we performed a meta-analysis to comprehensively explore the roles and mechanisms of flavonoids for animals intoxicated with nanomaterials.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; A systematic literature search in PubMed, EMBASE, and Cochrane Library databases was performed up to April 2022. STATA 15.0 software was used for meta-analyses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; A total of 26 studies were identified. The results showed that flavonoid supplementation could significantly increase the levels of antioxidative enzymes (superoxide dismutase, catalase, glutathione, glutathione peroxidase, and glutathione-S-transferase), reduce the production of oxidative agents (malonaldehyde) and pro-inflammatory mediators (tumor necrosis factor-α, interleukin-6, IL-1β, C-reactive protein, immunoglobulin G, nitric oxide, vascular endothelial growth factor, and myeloperoxidase), and alleviate cell apoptosis (manifested by decreases in the mRNA expression levels of pro-apoptotic factors, such as caspase-3, Fas cell surface death receptor, and Bax, and increases in the mRNA expression levels of Bcl2), DNA damage (reductions in tail length and tail DNA%), and nanomaterial-induced injuries of the liver (reduced alanine aminotransferase and aspartate aminotransferase activities), kidney (reduced urea, blood urea nitrogen, creatinine, and uric acid concentration), testis (increased testosterone, sperm motility, 17β-hydroxysteroid dehydrogenase type, and reduced sperm abnormalities), and brain (enhanced acetylcholinesterase activities). Most of the results were not changed by subgroup analyses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/em&gt; Our findings suggest that appropriate supplementation of flavonoids may be effective to prevent the occupational detriments resulting from nanomaterial exposure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Urinary Proteomics Identifies Cathepsin D as a Biomarker of Rapid eGFR Decline in Type 1 Diabetes</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35377940/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35377940/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Objective:&lt;/em&gt; Understanding mechanisms underlying rapid estimated glomerular filtration rate (eGFR) decline is important to predict and treat kidney disease in type 1 diabetes (T1D).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Research design and methods:&lt;/em&gt; We performed a case-control study nested within four T1D cohorts to identify urinary proteins associated with rapid eGFR decline. Case and control subjects were categorized based on eGFR decline ≥3 and &amp;lt;1 mL/min/1.73 m2/year, respectively. We used targeted liquid chromatography-tandem mass spectrometry to measure 38 peptides from 20 proteins implicated in diabetic kidney disease. Significant proteins were investigated in complementary human cohorts and in mouse proximal tubular epithelial cell cultures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; The cohort study included 1,270 participants followed a median 8 years. In the discovery set, only cathepsin D peptide and protein were significant on full adjustment for clinical and laboratory variables. In the validation set, associations of cathepsin D with eGFR decline were replicated in minimally adjusted models but lost significance with adjustment for albuminuria. In a meta-analysis with combination of discovery and validation sets, the odds ratio for the association of cathepsin D with rapid eGFR decline was 1.29 per SD (95% CI 1.07-1.55). In complementary human cohorts, urine cathepsin D was associated with tubulointerstitial injury and tubulointerstitial cathepsin D expression was associated with increased cortical interstitial fractional volume. In mouse proximal tubular epithelial cell cultures, advanced glycation end product-BSA increased cathepsin D activity and inflammatory and tubular injury markers, which were further increased with cathepsin D siRNA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; Urine cathepsin D is associated with rapid eGFR decline in T1D and reflects kidney tubulointerstitial injury.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neurologic Prognostication After Cardiac Arrest Using Brain Biomarkers: A Systematic Review and Meta-analysis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35226054/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35226054/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Importance:&lt;/em&gt; Brain injury biomarkers released into circulation from the injured neurovascular unit are important prognostic tools in patients with cardiac arrest who develop hypoxic ischemic brain injury (HIBI) after return of spontaneous circulation (ROSC).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Objective:&lt;/em&gt; To assess the neuroprognostic utility of bloodborne brain injury biomarkers in patients with cardiac arrest with HIBI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Data sources:&lt;/em&gt; Studies in electronic databases from inception to September 15, 2021. These databases included MEDLINE, Embase, Evidence-Based Medicine Reviews, CINAHL, Cochrane Database of Systematic Reviews, and the World Health Organization Global Health Library.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Study selection:&lt;/em&gt; Articles included in this systmatic review and meta-analysis were independently assessed by 2 reviewers. We included studies that investigated neuron-specific enolase, S100 calcium-binding protein β, glial fibrillary acidic protein, neurofilament light, tau, or ubiquitin carboxyl hydrolase L1 in patients with cardiac arrest aged 18 years and older for neurologic prognostication. We excluded studies that did not (1) dichotomize neurologic outcome as favorable vs unfavorable, (2) specify the timing of blood sampling or outcome determination, or (3) report diagnostic test accuracy or biomarker concentration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Data extraction and synthesis:&lt;/em&gt; Data on the study design, inclusion and exclusion criteria, brain biomarkers levels, diagnostic test accuracy, and neurologic outcome were recorded. This study was conducted in accordance with the Preferred Reporting Items for Systematic Reviews and Meta-Analyses (PRISMA) guideline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Main outcomes and measures:&lt;/em&gt; Summary receiver operating characteristic curve analysis was used to calculate the area under the curve, sensitivity, specificity, and optimal thresholds for each biomarker. Risk of bias and concerns of applicability were assessed with the Quality Assessment of Diagnostic Accuracy Studies (QUADAS-2) tool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; We identified 2953 studies, of which 86 studies with 10 567 patients (7777 men [73.6] and 2790 women [26.4]; pooled mean [SD] age, 62.8 [10.2] years) were included. Biomarker analysis at 48 hours after ROSC demonstrated that neurofilament light had the highest predictive value for unfavorable neurologic outcome, with an area under the curve of 0.92 (95% CI, 0.84-0.97). Subgroup analyses of patients treated with targeted temperature management and those who specifically had an out-of-hospital cardiac arrest showed similar results (targeted temperature management, 0.92 [95% CI, 0.86-0.95] and out-of-hospital cardiac arrest, 0.93 [95% CI, 0.86-0.97]).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions and relevance:&lt;/em&gt; Neurofilament light, which reflects white matter damage and axonal injury, yielded the highest accuracy in predicting neurologic outcome in patients with HIBI at 48 hours after ROSC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Association of SGLT2 inhibitors with cardiovascular, kidney, and safety outcomes among patients with diabetic kidney disease: a meta-analysis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35321742/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35321742/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; We conducted a systematic review and meta-analysis of the cardiovascular, kidney, and safety outcomes of sodium-glucose cotransporter 2 inhibitors (SGLT2i) among patients with diabetic kidney disease (DKD).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; We searched electronic databases for major randomized placebo-controlled clinical trials published up to September 30, 2021 and reporting on cardiovascular and kidney outcomes of SGLT2i in patients with DKD. DKD was defined as chronic kidney disease in individuals with type 2 diabetes. Random-effects meta-analysis models were used to estimate pooled hazard ratios (HR) and 95% confidence intervals (CI) for clinical outcomes including major adverse cardiovascular events (MACE: myocardial infarction [MI], stroke, and cardiovascular death), kidney composite outcomes (a combination of worsening kidney function, end-stage kidney disease, or death from renal or cardiovascular causes), hospitalizations for heart failure (HHF), deaths and safety events (mycotic infections, diabetic ketoacidosis [DKA], volume depletion, amputations, fractures, urinary tract infections [UTI], acute kidney injury [AKI], and hyperkalemia).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; A total of 26,106 participants with DKD from 8 large-scale trials were included (median age: 65.2 years, 29.7-41.8% women, 53.2-93.2% White, median follow-up: 2.5 years). SGLT2i were associated with reduced risks of MACE (HR 0.83, 95% CI 0.75-0.93), kidney composite outcomes (HR 0.66, 95% CI 0.58-0.75), HHF (HR 0.62, 95% CI 0.55-0.71), cardiovascular death (HR 0.84, 95% CI 0.74-0.96), MI (HR 0.78, 95% CI 0.67-0.92), stroke (HR 0.76, 95% CI 0.59-0.97), and all-cause death (HR 0.86, 95% CI 0.77-0.96), with no significant heterogeneity detected. Similar results were observed among participants with reduced estimated glomerular filtration rate (eGFR: &amp;lt; 60 mL/min/1.73m&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;). The relative risks (95% CI) for adverse events were 3.89 (1.42-10.62) and 2.50 (1.32-4.72) for mycotic infections in men and women respectively, 3.54 (0.82-15.39) for DKA, and 1.29 (1.13-1.48) for volume depletion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; Among adults with DKD, SGLT2i were associated with reduced risks of MACE, kidney outcomes, HHF, and death. With a few exceptions of more clear safety signals, we found overall limited data on the associations between SGLT2i and safety outcomes. More research is needed on the safety profile of SGLT2i in this population.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
