<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>NEDDylation | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/neddylation/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/neddylation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>NEDDylation</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>NEDDylation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/neddylation/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>SHP2 deneddylation mediates tumor immunosuppression in colon cancer via the CD47/SIRPα axis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36626230/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36626230/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SIPRα on macrophages binds with CD47 to resist pro-engulfment signals, but how the downstream signal of SIPRα controls tumor-infiltrating macrophages (TIMs) is still poorly clarified. Here we reported that the CD47/SIRPα axis requires the deneddylation of tyrosine phosphatase SHP2. Mechanistically, SHP2 is constitutively neddylated on K358 and K364 sites, thus its auto-inhibited conformation is maintained. In response to CD47-liganded SIRPα, SHP2 is deneddylated by SENP8, which leads to the dephosphorylation of relevant substrates at the phagocytic cup and subsequent inhibition of macrophage phagocytosis. Furthermore, neddylation inactivated myeloid-SHP2 and greatly boosted the efficacy of colorectal cancer (CRC) immunotherapy. Importantly, we observed that the supplementation with SHP2 allosteric inhibitors sensitized the immune treatment-resistant CRC to immunotherapy. Our results emphasized that the CRC subtype which is unresponsive to immunotherapy relies on SIRPαhiSHP2hiNEDD8lo TIMs, and highlighted the need to further combine the strategy of SHP2 targeting in colorectal cancer therapy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hepatic neddylation deficiency triggers fatal liver injury via inducing NF-κB-inducing kinase in mice</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36526632/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36526632/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The conjugation of neural precursor cell expressed, developmentally downregulated 8 (NEDD8) to target proteins, termed neddylation, participates in many cellular processes and is aberrant in various pathological diseases. Its relevance to liver function and failure remains poorly understood. Herein, we show dysregulated expression of NAE1, a regulatory subunit of the only NEDD8 E1 enzyme, in human acute liver failure. Embryonic- and adult-onset deletion of NAE1 in hepatocytes causes hepatocyte death, inflammation, and fibrosis, culminating in fatal liver injury in mice. Hepatic neddylation deficiency triggers oxidative stress, mitochondrial dysfunction, and hepatocyte reprogramming, potentiating liver injury. Importantly, NF-κB-inducing kinase (NIK), a serine/Thr kinase, is a neddylation substrate. Neddylation of NIK promotes its ubiquitination and degradation. Inhibition of neddylation conversely causes aberrant NIK activation, accentuating hepatocyte damage and inflammation. Administration of N-acetylcysteine, a glutathione surrogate and antioxidant, mitigates liver failure caused by hepatic NAE1 deletion in adult male mice. Therefore, hepatic neddylation is important in maintaining postnatal and adult liver homeostasis, and the identified neddylation targets/pathways provide insights into therapeutically intervening acute liver failure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Selective inhibition of cullin 3 neddylation through covalent targeting DCN1 protects mice from acetaminophen-induced liver toxicity</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33976147/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33976147/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cullin-RING E3 ligases (CRLs) regulate the turnover of approximately 20% of mammalian cellular proteins. Neddylation of individual cullin proteins is essential for the activation of each CRL. We report herein the discovery of DI-1548 and DI-1859 as two potent, selective and covalent DCN1 inhibitors. These inhibitors selectively inhibit neddylation of cullin 3 in cells at low nanomolar concentrations and are 2–3 orders of magnitude more potent than our previously reported reversible DCN1 inhibitor. Mass spectrometric analysis and co-crystal structures reveal that these compounds employ a unique mechanism of covalent bond formation with DCN1. DI-1859 induces a robust increase of NRF2 protein, a CRL3 substrate, in mouse liver and effectively protects mice from acetaminophen-induced liver damage. Taken together, this study demonstrates the therapeutic potential of selective inhibition of cullin neddylation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
