<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Lung | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/lung/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/lung/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Lung</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 24 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Lung</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/lung/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tripterin liposome relieves severe acute respiratory syndrome as a potent COVID-19 treatment</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36566328/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36566328/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19), caused by severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 (SARS-CoV-2), 15-30% of patients are likely to develop COVID-19-related acute respiratory distress syndrome (ARDS). There are still few effective and well-understood therapies available. Novel variants and short-lasting immunity are posing challenges to vaccine efficacy, so finding antiviral and antiinflammatory treatments remains crucial. Here, tripterin (TP), a traditional Chinese medicine, was encapsulated into liposome (TP lipo) to investigate its antiviral and antiinflammatory effects in severe COVID-19. By using two severe COVID-19 models in human ACE2-transgenic (hACE2) mice, an analysis of TP lipo&amp;rsquo;s effects on pulmonary immune responses was conducted. Pulmonary pathological alterations and viral burden were reduced by TP lipo treatment. TP lipo inhibits SARS-CoV-2 replication and hyperinflammation in infected cells and mice, two crucial events in severe COVID-19 pathophysiology, it is a promising drug candidate to treat SARS-CoV-2-induced ARDS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A spatially resolved atlas of the human lung characterizes a gland-associated immune niche</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36543915/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36543915/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Single-cell transcriptomics has allowed unprecedented resolution of cell types/states in the human lung, but their spatial context is less well defined. To (re)define tissue architecture of lung and airways, we profiled five proximal-to-distal locations of healthy human lungs in depth using multi-omic single cell/nuclei and spatial transcriptomics at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.lungcellatlas.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lung Cell Atlas&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Using computational data integration and analysis, we extend beyond the suspension cell paradigm and discover macro and micro-anatomical tissue compartments including previously unannotated cell types in the epithelial, vascular, stromal and nerve bundle micro-environments. We identify and implicate peribronchial fibroblasts in lung disease. Importantly, we discover and validate a survival niche for IgA plasma cells in the airway submucosal glands (SMG). We show that gland epithelial cells recruit B cells and IgA plasma cells, and promote longevity and antibody secretion locally through expression of CCL28, APRIL and IL-6. This new ‘gland-associated immune niche’ has implications for respiratory health.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Locally organised and activated Fth1hi neutrophils aggravate inflammation of acute lung injury in an IL-10-dependent manner</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36513690/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36513690/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acute respiratory distress syndrome (ARDS) is a common respiratory critical syndrome with no effective therapeutic intervention. Neutrophils function in the overwhelming inflammatory process of acute lung injury (ALI) caused by ARDS; however, the phenotypic heterogeneity of pulmonary neutrophils in ALI/ARDS remains largely unknown. Here, using single-cell RNA sequencing, we identify two transcriptionally and functionally heterogeneous neutrophil populations (Fth1&lt;sup&gt;hi&lt;/sup&gt; Neu and Prok2&lt;sup&gt;hi&lt;/sup&gt; Neu) with distinct locations in LPS-induced ALI mouse lungs. Exposure to LPS promotes the Fth1&lt;sup&gt;hi&lt;/sup&gt; Neu subtype, with more inflammatory factors, stronger antioxidant, and decreased apoptosis under the regulation of interleukin-10. Furthermore, prolonged retention of Fth1&lt;sup&gt;hi&lt;/sup&gt; Neu within lung tissue aggravates inflammatory injury throughout the development of ALI/ARDS. Notably, ARDS patients have high ratios of Fth1 to Prok2 expression in pulmonary neutrophils, suggesting that the Fth1&lt;sup&gt;hi&lt;/sup&gt; Neu population may promote the pathological development and provide a marker of poor outcome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maturation and specialization of group 2 innate lymphoid cells through the lung-gut axis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36494354/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36494354/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Innate lymphoid cells (ILC) are abundant in mucosal tissues. They serve critical functions in anti-pathogen response and tissue homeostasis. However, the heterogenous composition of ILCs in mucosal sites and their various maturation trajectories are less well known. In this study, we characterize ILC types and functions from both the lung and the small intestine, and identify their tissue-specific markers. We find that ILC2s residing in the lung express CCR2, whereas intestinal ILC2s express CCR4. Through the use of CCR2 and CCR4 reporter mice, we show that ILC2s undergo translocation via the lung-gut axis upon IL-33 treatment. This trajectory of ILC2s is also observed at the postnatal stage. Allergen-induced activation of lung ILC2s affects the homeostasis of gut ILC2s. Together, our findings implicate that ILCs display tissue-specific features in both the lung and gut, and ILC2s mature along the lung-gut axis in particular homeostatic and inflammatory conditions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A human fetal lung cell atlas uncovers proximal-distal gradients of differentiation and key regulators of epithelial fates</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36493756/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36493756/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spatiotemporal atlas of human lung development identifies 144 cell types/states&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tracking the developmental origins of multiple cell types, including new progenitors&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Functional diversity of fibroblasts in distinct anatomical signaling niches&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Experimental validation of TFs controlling neuroendocrine cell heterogeneity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We present a multiomic cell atlas of human lung development that combines single-cell RNA and ATAC sequencing, high-throughput spatial transcriptomics, and single-cell imaging. Coupling single-cell methods with spatial analysis has allowed a comprehensive cellular survey of the epithelial, mesenchymal, endothelial, and erythrocyte/leukocyte compartments from 5–22 post-conception weeks. We identify previously uncharacterized cell states in all compartments. These include developmental-specific secretory progenitors and a subtype of neuroendocrine cell related to human small cell lung cancer. Our datasets are available through our web interface (&lt;a href=&#34;https://lungcellatlas.org&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://lungcellatlas.org&lt;/a&gt;). To illustrate its general utility, we use our cell atlas to generate predictions about cell-cell signaling and transcription factor hierarchies which we rigorously test using organoid models.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Suppression of PD-L1 release from small extracellular vesicles promotes systemic anti-tumor immunity by targeting ORAI1 calcium channels</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36482876/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36482876/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blockade of immune checkpoints as a strategy of cancer cells to overcome the immune response has received ample attention in cancer research recently. In particular, expression of PD-L1 by various cancer cells has become a paradigm in this respect. Delivery of PD-L1 to its site of action occurs either by local diffusion, or else by transport via small extracellular vesicles (sEVs, commonly referred to as exosomes). Many steps of sEVs formation, their packaging with PD-L1 and their release into the extracellular space have been studied in detail. The likely dependence of release on Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt;-signaling, however, has received little attention. This is surprising, since the intracellular Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt;-concentration is known as a prominent regulator of many secretory processes. Here, we report on the roles of three Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt;-dependent proteins in regulating release of PD-L1-containing sEVs, as well as on the growth of tumors in mouse models. We show that sEVs release in cancer cell lines is Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt;-dependent and the knockdown of the gene coding the Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt;-channel protein ORAI1 reduces Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt;-signals and release of sEVs. Consequently, the T cell response is reinvigorated and tumor progression in mouse models is retarded. Furthermore, analysis of protein expression patterns in samples from human cancer tissue shows that the ORAI1 gene is significantly upregulated. Such upregulation is identified as an unfavorable prognostic factor for survival of patients with non-small-cell lung cancer. We show that reduced Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt;-signaling after knockdown of ORAI1 gene also compromises the activity of melanophilin and Synaptotagmin-like protein 2, two proteins, which are important for correct localization of secretory organelles within cancer cells and their transport to sites of exocytosis. Thus, the Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt;-channel ORAI1 and Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt;-dependent proteins of the secretion pathway emerge as important targets for understanding and manipulating immune checkpoint blockade by PD-L1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lipid-laden lung mesenchymal cells foster breast cancer metastasis via metabolic reprogramming of tumor cells and natural killer cells</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36476935/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36476935/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lung mesenchymal cells (MCs) store neutral lipids during breast cancer progression&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IL-1β elicits neutral lipid accumulation in lung MCs to foster metastasis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lipid-laden MCs metabolically reprogram both tumor cells and NK cells&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Targeting lipid-laden MCs improves the efficacy of NK cell-based immunotherapy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Summary&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the distant organ environment is known to support metastasis of primary tumors, its metabolic roles in this process remain underdetermined. Here, in breast cancer models, we found lung-resident mesenchymal cells (MCs) accumulating neutral lipids at the pre-metastatic stage. This was partially mediated by interleukin-1β (IL-1β)-induced hypoxia-inducible lipid droplet-associated (HILPDA) that subsequently represses adipose triglyceride lipase (ATGL) activity in lung MCs. MC-specific ablation of the ATGL or HILPDA genes in mice reinforced and reduced lung metastasis of breast cancer respectively, suggesting a metastasis-promoting effect of lipid-laden MCs. Mechanistically, lipid-laden MCs transported their lipids to tumor cells and natural killer (NK) cells via exosome-like vesicles, leading to heightened tumor cell survival and proliferation and NK cell dysfunction. Blockage of IL-1β, which was effective singly, improved the efficacy of adoptive NK cell immunotherapy in mitigating lung metastasis. Collectively, lung MCs metabolically regulate tumor cells and anti-tumor immunity to facilitate breast cancer lung metastasis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Species-agnostic polymeric formulations for inhalable messenger RNA delivery to the lung</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36443576/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36443576/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Messenger RNA has now been used to vaccinate millions of people. However, the diversity of pulmonary pathologies, including infections, genetic disorders, asthma and others, reveals the lung as an important organ to directly target for future RNA therapeutics and preventatives. Here we report the screening of 166 polymeric nanoparticle formulations for functional delivery to the lungs, obtained from a combinatorial synthesis approach combined with a low-dead-volume nose-only inhalation system for mice. We identify P76, a poly-β-amino-thio-ester polymer, that exhibits increased expression over formulations lacking the thiol component, delivery to different animal species with varying RNA cargos and low toxicity. P76 allows for dose sparing when delivering an mRNA-expressed Cas13a-mediated treatment in a SARS-CoV-2 challenge model, resulting in similar efficacy to a 20-fold higher dose of a neutralizing antibody. Overall, the combinatorial synthesis approach allowed for the discovery of promising polymeric formulations for future RNA pharmaceutical development for the lungs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chronic exposure to carbon black ultrafine particles reprograms macrophage metabolism and accelerates lung cancer</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36383649/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36383649/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chronic exposure to airborne carbon black ultrafine (nCB) particles generated from incomplete combustion of organic matter drives IL-17A–dependent emphysema. However, whether and how they alter the immune responses to lung cancer remains unknown. Here, we show that exposure to nCB particles increased PD-L1&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; PD-L2&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; CD206&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; antigen-presenting cells (APCs), exhausted T cells, and Treg cells. Lung macrophages that harbored nCB particles showed selective mitochondrial structure damage and decreased oxidative respiration. Lung macrophages sustained the HIF1α axis that increased glycolysis and lactate production, culminating in an immunosuppressive microenvironment in multiple mouse models of non–small cell lung cancers. Adoptive transfer of lung APCs from nCB-exposed wild type to susceptible mice increased tumor incidence and caused early metastasis. Our findings show that nCB exposure metabolically rewires lung macrophages to promote immunosuppression and accelerates the development of lung cancer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>High-resolution single-cell atlas reveals diversity and plasticity of tissue-resident neutrophils in non-small cell lung cancer</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36368318/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36368318/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Non-small cell lung cancer (NSCLC) is characterized by molecular heterogeneity with diverse immune cell infiltration patterns, which has been linked to therapy sensitivity and resistance. However, full understanding of how immune cell phenotypes vary across different patient subgroups is lacking. Here, we dissect the NSCLC tumor microenvironment at high resolution by integrating 1,283,972 single cells from 556 samples and 318 patients across 29 datasets, including our dataset capturing cells with low mRNA content. We stratify patients into immune-deserted, B cell, T cell, and myeloid cell subtypes. Using bulk samples with genomic and clinical information, we identify cellular components associated with tumor histology and genotypes. We then focus on the analysis of tissue-resident neutrophils (TRNs) and uncover distinct subpopulations that acquire new functional properties in the tissue microenvironment, providing evidence for the plasticity of TRNs. Finally, we show that a TRN-derived gene signature is associated with anti-programmed cell death ligand 1 (PD-L1) treatment failure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Single-cell transcriptome analysis of the in vivo response to viral infection in the cave nectar bat Eonycteris spelaea</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36351376/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36351376/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;scRNAseq analyses of bat lung immune cells upon &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt; viral infection&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;E. spelaea&lt;/em&gt; neutrophils have high basal expression of IDO1&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Antiviral responses upon &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt; infection driven primarily by lung myeloid cells&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Transcriptional evidence of broad NK and T cells activation early after infection&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bats are reservoir hosts of many zoonotic viruses with pandemic potential. We utilized single-cell transcriptome sequencing (scRNA-seq) to analyze the immune response in bat lungs upon &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt; infection with a double-stranded RNA virus, &lt;em&gt;Pteropine orthoreovirus&lt;/em&gt; PRV3M. Bat neutrophils were distinguished by high basal &lt;em&gt;IDO1&lt;/em&gt; expression. NK cells and T cells were the most abundant immune cells in lung tissue. Three distinct CD8&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; effector T cell populations could be delineated by differential expression of &lt;em&gt;KLRB1&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;GFRA2&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;DPP4&lt;/em&gt;. Select NK and T clusters increased expression of genes involved in T cell activation and effector function early after viral infection. Alveolar macrophages and classical monocytes drove antiviral interferon signaling. Infection expanded a &lt;em&gt;CSF1R&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; population expressing collagen-like genes, which became the predominant myeloid cell type post-infection. This work uncovers features relevant to viral disease tolerance in bats, lays a foundation for future experimental work, and serves as a resource for comparative immunology studies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Circadian clock-based therapeutics in chronic pulmonary diseases</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/36302705/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/36302705/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The circadian clock is the biochemical oscillator that orchestrates the observable circadian rhythms in physiology and behavior. Disruption of the circadian clock in the lungs during chronic pulmonary diseases is considered one of the key etiological risk factors that drive pathobiology. Preclinical studies support that pharmacological manipulation of the circadian clock is a conceivable approach for the development of novel clock-based therapeutics. Despite recent advances, no effort has been undertaken to integrate novel findings for the treatment and management of chronic lung diseases. We, therefore, recognize the need to discuss the candidate clock genes that can be potentially targeted for therapeutic intervention. Here, we aim to create the first roadmap that will advance the development of circadian- clock-based therapeutics that may provide better outcomes in treating chronic pulmonary diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sentinel p16INK4a&#43; cells in the basement membrane form a reparative niche in the lung</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36227993/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36227993/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We engineered an ultrasensitive reporter of p16&lt;sup&gt;INK4a&lt;/sup&gt;, a biomarker of cellular senescence. Our reporter detected p16&lt;sup&gt;INK4a&lt;/sup&gt;-expressing fibroblasts with certain senescent characteristics that appeared shortly after birth in the basement membrane adjacent to epithelial stem cells in the lung. Furthermore, these p16&lt;sup&gt;INK4a+&lt;/sup&gt; fibroblasts had enhanced capacity to sense tissue inflammation and respond through their increased secretory capacity to promote epithelial regeneration. In addition, p16&lt;sup&gt;INK4a&lt;/sup&gt; expression was required in fibroblasts to enhance epithelial regeneration. This study highlights a role for p16&lt;sup&gt;INK4a+&lt;/sup&gt; fibroblasts as tissue-resident sentinels in the stem cell niche that monitor barrier integrity and rapidly respond to inflammation to promote tissue regeneration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The human lung microbiome—A hidden link between microbes and human health and diseases</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/imt2.33/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/imt2.33/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once thought to be sterile, the human lung is now well recognized to harbor a consortium of microorganisms collectively known as the lung microbiome. The lung microbiome is altered in an array of lung diseases, including chronic lung diseases such as chronic obstructive pulmonary disease, asthma, and bronchiectasis, acute lung diseases caused by pneumonia, sepsis, and COVID-19, and other lung complications such as those related to lung transplantation, lung cancer, and human immunodeficiency virus. The effects of lung microbiome in modulating host immunity and inflammation in the lung and distal organs are being elucidated. However, the precise mechanism by which members of microbiota produce structural ligands that interact with host genes and pathways remains largely uncharacterized. Multiple unique challenges, both technically and biologically, exist in the field of lung microbiome, necessitating the development of tailored experimental and analytical approaches to overcome the bottlenecks. In this review, we first provide an overview of the principles and methodologies in studying the lung microbiome. We next review current knowledge of the roles of lung microbiome in human diseases, highlighting mechanistic insights. We finally discuss critical challenges in the field and share our thoughts on broad topics for future investigation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Circadian molecular clock disruption in chronic pulmonary diseases</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/35508604/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/35508604/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The circadian clock is the biochemical oscillator with a near 24-h period that is responsible for generating the circadian rhythms in peripheral organs including the lung. Mounting evidence suggests that circadian clock disruption during chronic lung diseases plays an essential role in augmented oxidative stress, inflammatory response, metabolic imbalances, hypoxia/hyperoxia, mucus secretion, dysregulated autophagy, and alters pulmonary function. Here, we review circadian clock disruption and discuss candidate clock genes that are altered at the transcriptional or translational level in chronic pulmonary diseases. This review aims to provide the current knowledge and understanding of the circadian molecular clock disruption in chronic pulmonary diseases which will further advance the development of novel clock-based therapeutics in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>KMT2C deficiency promotes small cell lung cancer metastasis through DNMT3A-mediated epigenetic reprogramming</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35449309/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35449309/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Small cell lung cancer (SCLC) is notorious for its early and frequent metastases, which contribute to it as a recalcitrant malignancy. To understand the molecular mechanisms underlying SCLC metastasis, we generated SCLC mouse models with orthotopically transplanted genome-edited lung organoids and performed multiomics analyses. We found that a deficiency of KMT2C, a histone H3 lysine 4 methyltransferase frequently mutated in extensive-stage SCLC, promoted multiple-organ metastases in mice. Metastatic and KMT2C-deficient SCLC displayed both histone and DNA hypomethylation. Mechanistically, KMT2C directly regulated the expression of DNMT3A, a de novo DNA methyltransferase, through histone methylation. Forced DNMT3A expression restrained metastasis of KMT2C-deficient SCLC through repressing metastasis-promoting MEIS/HOX genes. Further, S-(5′-adenosyl)-L-methionine, the common cofactor of histone and DNA methyltransferases, inhibited SCLC metastasis. Thus, our study revealed a concerted epigenetic reprogramming of KMT2C- and DNMT3A-mediated histone and DNA hypomethylation underlying SCLC metastasis, which suggested a potential epigenetic therapeutic vulnerability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neuropilin-1 mediates lung tissue-specific control of ILC2 function in type 2 immunity</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35075279/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35075279/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Group 2 innate lymphoid cells (ILC2s) are highly heterogeneous tissue-resident lymphocytes that regulate inflammation and tissue homeostasis in health and disease. However, how these cells integrate into the tissue microenvironment to perform tissue-specific functions is unclear. Here, we show neuropilin-1 (Nrp1), which is induced postnatally and sustained by lung-derived transforming growth factor beta-1 (TGFβ1), is a tissue-specific marker of lung ILC2s. Genetic ablation or pharmacological inhibition of Nrp1 suppresses IL-5 and IL-13 production by ILC2s and protects mice from the development of pulmonary fibrosis. Mechanistically, TGFβ1-Nrp1 signaling enhances ILC2 function and type 2 immunity by upregulating IL-33 receptor ST2 expression. These findings identify Nrp1 as a tissue-specific regulator of lung-resident ILC2s and highlight Nrp1 as a potential therapeutic target for pulmonary fibrosis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coal dust exposure triggers heterogeneity of transcriptional profiles in mouse pneumoconiosis and Vitamin D remedies</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35057792/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35057792/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Coal dust particles (CDP), an inevitable by-product of coal mining for the environment, mainly causes coal workers&amp;rsquo; pneumoconiosis (CWP). Long-term exposure to coal dust leads to a complex alternation of biological processes during regeneration and repair in the healing lung. However, the cellular and complete molecular changes associated with pulmonary homeostasis caused by respiratory coal dust particles remain unclear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; This study mainly investigated the pulmonary toxicity of respirable-sized CDP in mice using unbiased single-cell RNA sequencing. CDP (&amp;lt; 5 μm) collected from the coal mine was analyzed by Scanning Electron Microscope (SEM) and Mass Spectrometer. In addition, western blotting, Elisa, QPCR was used to detect gene expression at mRNA or protein levels. Pathological analysis including HE staining, Masson staining, immunohistochemistry, and immunofluorescence staining were performed to characterize the structure and functional alternation in the pneumoconiosis mouse and verify the reliability of single-cell sequencing results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; SEM image and Mass Spectrometer analysis showed that coal dust particles generated during coal mine production have been crushed and screened with a diameter of less than 5 µm and contained less than 10% silica. Alveolar structure and pulmonary microenvironment were destroyed, inflammatory and death (apoptosis, autophagy, and necrosis) pathways were activated, leading to pneumoconiosis in post 9 months coal dust stimulation. A distinct abnormally increased alveolar type 2 epithelial cell (AT2) were classified with a highly active state but reduced the antimicrobial-related protein expression of LYZ and Chia1 after CDP exposure. Beclin1, LC3B, LAMP2, TGF-ß, and MLPH were up-regulated induced by CDP, promoting autophagy and pulmonary fibrosis. A new subset of macrophages with M2-type polarization double expressed MLPH + /CD206 + was found in mice having pneumoconiosis but markedly decreased after the Vitamin D treatment. Activated MLPH + /CD206 + M2 macrophages secreted TGF-β1 and are sensitive to Vitamin D treatment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; This is the first study to reconstruct the pathologic progression and transcriptome pattern of coal pneumoconiosis in mice. Coal dust had obvious toxic effects on lung epithelial cells and macrophages and eventually induced pulmonary fibrosis. CDP-induced M2-type macrophages could be inhibited by VD, which may be related to the alleviation of the pulmonary fibrosis process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RBMS1 regulates lung cancer ferroptosis through translational control of SLC7A11</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34609966/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34609966/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ferroptosis, an iron-dependent nonapoptotic cell death, is a highly regulated tumor suppressing process. However, functions and mechanisms of RNA-binding proteins in regulation of evasion of ferroptosis during lung cancer progression are still largely unknown. Here, we report that the RNA-binding protein RBMS1 participates in lung cancer development via mediating ferroptosis evasion. Through an shRNA-mediated systematic screen, we discovered that RBMS1 is a key ferroptosis regulator. Clinically, RBMS1 was elevated in lung cancer and its high expression was associated with reduced patient survival. Conversely, depletion of RBMS1 inhibited lung cancer progression both in vivo and in vitro. Mechanistically, RBMS1 interacted with the translation initiation factor eIF3d directly to bridge the 3&amp;rsquo;- and 5&amp;rsquo;-UTR of SLC7A11. RBMS1 ablation inhibited the translation of SLC7A11, reduced SLC7A11-mediated cystine uptake, and promoted ferroptosis. In a drug screen that targeted RBMS1, we further uncovered that nortriptyline hydrochloride decreased the level of RBMS1, thereby promoting ferroptosis. Importantly, RBMS1 depletion or inhibition by nortriptyline hydrochloride sensitized radioresistant lung cancer cells to radiotherapy. Our findings established RBMS1 as a translational regulator of ferroptosis and a prognostic factor with therapeutic potential and clinical value.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cis-acting lnc-Cxcl2 restrains neutrophil-mediated lung inflammation by inhibiting epithelial cell CXCL2 expression in virus infection</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34607953/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34607953/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chemokine production by epithelial cells is important for neutrophil recruitment during viral infection, the appropriate regulation of which is critical for restraining inflammation and attenuating subsequent tissue damage. Epithelial cell expression of long noncoding RNAs (lncRNAs), RNA-binding proteins, and their functional interactions during viral infection and inflammation remain to be fully understood. Here, we identified an inducible lncRNA in the &lt;em&gt;Cxcl2&lt;/em&gt; gene locus, lnc-Cxcl2, which could selectively inhibit &lt;em&gt;Cxcl2&lt;/em&gt; expression in mouse lung epithelial cells but not in macrophages. lnc-Cxcl2-deficient mice exhibited increased &lt;em&gt;Cxcl2&lt;/em&gt; expression, enhanced neutrophils recruitment, and more severe inflammation in the lung after influenza virus infection. Mechanistically, nucleus-localized lnc-Cxcl2 bound to &lt;em&gt;Cxcl2&lt;/em&gt; promoter, recruited a ribonucleoprotein La, which inhibited the chromatin accessibility of chemokine promoters, and consequently inhibited &lt;em&gt;Cxcl2&lt;/em&gt; transcription in cis However, unlike mouse lnc-Cxcl2, human lnc-CXCL2-4-1 inhibited multiple immune cytokine expressions including chemokines in human lung epithelial cells. Together, our results demonstrate a self-protecting mechanism within epithelial cells to restrain chemokine and neutrophil-mediated inflammation, providing clues for better understanding chemokine regulation and epithelial cell function in lung viral infection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Biosafety Level 2 Mouse Model for Studying Betacoronavirus-Induced Acute Lung Damage and Systemic Manifestations</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34495692/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34495692/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The emergence of life-threatening zoonotic diseases caused by betacoronaviruses, including the ongoing coronavirus disease 19 (COVID-19) pandemic, has highlighted the need for developing preclinical models mirroring respiratory and systemic pathophysiological manifestations seen in infected humans. Here, we showed that C57BL/6J wild-type mice intranasally inoculated with the murine betacoronavirus murine hepatitis coronavirus 3 (MHV-3) develop a robust inflammatory response leading to acute lung injuries, including alveolar edema, hemorrhage, and fibrin thrombi. Although such histopathological changes seemed to resolve as the infection advanced, they efficiently impaired respiratory function, as the infected mice displayed restricted lung distention and increased respiratory frequency and ventilation. Following respiratory manifestation, the MHV-3 infection became systemic, and a high virus burden could be detected in multiple organs along with morphological changes. The systemic manifestation of MHV-3 infection was also marked by a sharp drop in the number of circulating platelets and lymphocytes, besides the augmented concentration of the proinflammatory cytokines interleukin 1 beta (IL-1β), IL-6, IL-12, gamma interferon (IFN-γ), and tumor necrosis factor (TNF), thereby mirroring some clinical features observed in moderate and severe cases of COVID-19. Importantly, both respiratory and systemic changes triggered by MHV-3 infection were greatly prevented by blocking TNF signaling, either via genetic or pharmacologic approaches. In line with this, TNF blockage also diminished the infection-mediated release of proinflammatory cytokines and virus replication of human epithelial lung cells infected with severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 (SARS-CoV-2). Collectively, results show that MHV-3 respiratory infection leads to a large range of clinical manifestations in mice and may constitute an attractive, lower-cost, biosafety level 2 (BSL2) in vivo platform for evaluating the respiratory and multiorgan involvement of betacoronavirus infections.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Importance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mouse models have long been used as valuable in vivo platforms to investigate the pathogenesis of viral infections and effective countermeasures. The natural resistance of mice to the novel betacoronavirus SARS-CoV-2, the causative agent of COVID-19, has launched a race toward the characterization of SARS-CoV-2 infection in other animals (e.g., hamsters, cats, ferrets, bats, and monkeys), as well as adaptation of the mouse model, by modifying either the host or the virus. In the present study, we utilized a natural pathogen of mice, MHV, as a prototype to model betacoronavirus-induced acute lung injure and multiorgan involvement under biosafety level 2 conditions. We showed that C57BL/6J mice intranasally inoculated with MHV-3 develops severe disease, which includes acute lung damage and respiratory distress that precede systemic inflammation and death. Accordingly, the proposed animal model may provide a useful tool for studies regarding betacoronavirus respiratory infection and related diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IL-1β augments TGF-β inducing epithelial-mesenchymal transition of epithelial cells and associates with poor pulmonary function improvement in neutrophilic asthmatics</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34344357/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34344357/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Neutrophilic asthmatics (NA) have less response to inhaled corticosteroids. We aimed to find out the predictor of treatment response in NA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Asthmatics (n = 115) and healthy controls (n = 28) underwent clinical assessment during 6-month follow-up with standardized therapy. Asthmatics were categorized by sputum differential cell count. The mRNA expressions were measured by RT-qPCR for sputum cytokines (IFN-γ, IL-1β, IL-27, FOXP3, IL-17A, and IL-5). The protein of IL-1β in sputum supernatant was detected by ELISA. Reticular basement membranes (RBM) were measured in the biopsy samples. The role and signaling pathways of IL-1β mediating the epithelial-mesenchymal transition (EMT) process were explored through A549 cells.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NA had increased baseline sputum cell IL-1β expression compared to eosinophilic asthmatics (EA). After follow-up, NA had less improvement in FEV1 compared to EA. For all asthmatics, sputum IL-1β mRNA was positively correlated with protein expression. Sputum IL-1β mRNA and protein levels were negatively correlated to FEV1 improvement. After subgrouping, the correlation between IL-1β mRNA and FEV1 improvement was significant in NA but not in EA. Thickness of RBM in asthmatics was greater than that of healthy controls and positively correlated with neutrophil percentage in bronchoalveolar lavage fluid. In vitro experiments, the process of IL-1β augmenting TGF-β1-induced EMT cannot be abrogated by glucocorticoid or montelukast sodium, but can be reversed by MAPK inhibitors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;IL-1β level in baseline sputum predicts the poor lung function improvement in NA. The potential mechanism may be related to IL-1β augmenting TGF-β1-induced steroid-resistant EMT through MAPK signaling pathways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SARS-CoV-2 N protein promotes NLRP3 inflammasome activation to induce hyperinflammation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34341353/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34341353/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Erratum in:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Author Correction: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-021-25629-w&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;SARS-CoV-2 N protein promotes NLRP3 inflammasome activation to induce hyperinflammation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Excessive inflammatory responses induced upon SARS-CoV-2 infection are associated with severe symptoms of COVID-19. Inflammasomes activated in response to SARS-CoV-2 infection are also associated with COVID-19 severity. Here, we show a distinct mechanism by which SARS-CoV-2 N protein promotes NLRP3 inflammasome activation to induce hyperinflammation. N protein facilitates maturation of proinflammatory cytokines and induces proinflammatory responses in cultured cells and mice. Mechanistically, N protein interacts directly with NLRP3 protein, promotes the binding of NLRP3 with ASC, and facilitates NLRP3 inflammasome assembly. More importantly, N protein aggravates lung injury, accelerates death in sepsis and acute inflammation mouse models, and promotes IL-1β and IL-6 activation in mice. Notably, N-induced lung injury and cytokine production are blocked by MCC950 (a specific inhibitor of NLRP3) and Ac-YVAD-cmk (an inhibitor of caspase-1). Therefore, this study reveals a distinct mechanism by which SARS-CoV-2 N protein promotes NLRP3 inflammasome activation and induces excessive inflammatory responses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Age-dependent alveolar epithelial plasticity orchestrates lung homeostasis and regeneration</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33974915/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33974915/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regeneration of the architecturally complex alveolar niche of the lung requires precise temporal and spatial control of epithelial cell behavior. Injury can lead to a permanent reduction in gas exchange surface area and respiratory function. Using mouse models, we show that alveolar type 1 (AT1) cell plasticity is a major and unappreciated mechanism that drives regeneration, beginning in the early postnatal period during alveolar maturation. Upon acute neonatal lung injury, AT1 cells reprogram into alveolar type 2 (AT2) cells, promoting alveolar regeneration. In contrast, the ability of AT2 cells to regenerate AT1 cells is restricted to the mature lung. Unbiased genomic assessment reveals that this previously unappreciated level of plasticity is governed by the preferential activity of Hippo signaling in the AT1 cell lineage. Thus, cellular plasticity is a temporally acquired trait of the alveolar epithelium and presents an alternative mode of tissue regeneration in the postnatal lung.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Temporal landscape of human gut RNA and DNA virome in SARS-CoV-2 infection and severity</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33853691/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33853691/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) caused by the enveloped RNA virus SARS-CoV-2 primarily affects the respiratory and gastrointestinal tracts. SARS-CoV-2 was isolated from fecal samples, and active viral replication was reported in human intestinal cells. The human gut also harbors an enormous amount of resident viruses (collectively known as the virome) that play a role in regulating host immunity and disease pathophysiology. Understanding gut virome perturbation that underlies SARS-CoV-2 infection and severity is an unmet need.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; We enrolled 98 COVID-19 patients with varying disease severity (3 asymptomatic, 53 mild, 34 moderate, 5 severe, 3 critical) and 78 non-COVID-19 controls matched for gender and co-morbidities. All subjects had fecal specimens sampled at inclusion. Blood specimens were collected for COVID-19 patients at admission to test for inflammatory markers and white cell counts. Among COVID-19 cases, 37 (38%) patients had serial fecal samples collected 2 to 3 times per week from time of hospitalization until after discharge. Using shotgun metagenomics sequencing, we sequenced and profiled the fecal RNA and DNA virome. We investigated alterations and longitudinal dynamics of the gut virome in association with disease severity and blood parameters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; Patients with COVID-19 showed underrepresentation of Pepper mild mottle virus (RNA virus) and multiple bacteriophage lineages (DNA viruses) and enrichment of environment-derived eukaryotic DNA viruses in fecal samples, compared to non-COVID-19 subjects. Such gut virome alterations persisted up to 30 days after disease resolution. Fecal virome in SARS-CoV-2 infection harbored more stress-, inflammation-, and virulence-associated gene encoding capacities including those pertaining to bacteriophage integration, DNA repair, and metabolism and virulence associated with their bacterial host. Baseline fecal abundance of 10 virus species (1 RNA virus, pepper chlorotic spot virus, and 9 DNA virus species) inversely correlated with disease COVID-19 severity. These viruses inversely correlated with blood levels of pro-inflammatory proteins, white cells, and neutrophils. Among the 10 COVID-19 severity-associated DNA virus species, 4 showed inverse correlation with age; 5 showed persistent lower abundance both during disease course and after disease resolution relative to non-COVID-19 subjects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; Both enteric RNA and DNA virome in COVID-19 patients were different from non-COVID-19 subjects, which persisted after disease resolution of COVID-19. Gut virome may calibrate host immunity and regulate severity to SARS-CoV-2 infection. Our observation that gut viruses inversely correlated with both severity of COVID-19 and host age may partly explain that older subjects are prone to severe and worse COVID-19 outcomes. Altogether, our data highlight the importance of human gut virome in severity and potentially therapeutics of COVID-19.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lung virome: New potential biomarkers for asthma severity and exacerbation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33757721/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33757721/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Although some respiratory virus infections are known to contribute to the development and exacerbation of asthma, commensal viromes in airway have not been extensively studied due to technical challenges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Objectives:&lt;/em&gt; This study investigated the characteristics of the virome in asthmatic airways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; Both the bacteriome and virome profiles in sputum from 12 healthy individuals, 15 patients with nonsevere asthma, and 15 patients with severe asthma were analyzed and assessed for the association with clinical characteristics such as severity, exacerbation, Asthma Control Test (ACT), and lung function.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; While analysis of the 16S ribosomal RNA bacteriome in the airway showed no differences, clear contrasts in the diversity and composition of airway viromes were observed between healthy controls and patients with asthma. Herpesviruses were the most abundant type of virus in the asthma group (44.6 ± 4.6%), mainly with cytomegalovirus (CMV) and EBV accounting for 24.5 ± 3.3% and 16.9 ± 3.5%, respectively, in contrast to those in the healthy controls (5.4 ± 2.5% and 7.1 ± 3.0%, respectively). CMV and EBV were more abundant in patients with asthma who experienced exacerbation, and their abundance showed correlation with more severe asthma, lower ACT score, and lower lung function. On the contrary, bacteriophage that is abundant in healthy controls was severely reduced in patients with asthma in the order of nonsevere and severe asthma and presented significant positive correlation with ACT and FEV1/forced vital capacity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; Lung viromes, especially, CMV, EBV, and bacteriophage may be potential biomarkers of asthma severity and exacerbation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integrated gut virome and bacteriome dynamics in COVID-19 patients</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33678150/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33678150/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SARS-CoV-2 is the cause of the current global pandemic of COVID-19; this virus infects multiple organs, such as the lungs and gastrointestinal tract. The microbiome in these organs, including the bacteriome and virome, responds to infection and might also influence disease progression and treatment outcome. In a cohort of 13 COVID-19 patients in Beijing, China, we observed that the gut virome and bacteriome in the COVID-19 patients were notably different from those of five healthy controls. We identified a bacterial dysbiosis signature by observing reduced diversity and viral shifts in patients, and among the patients, the bacterial/viral compositions were different between patients of different severities, although these differences are not entirely distinguishable from the effect of antibiotics. Severe cases of COVID-19 exhibited a greater abundance of opportunistic pathogens but were depleted for butyrate-producing groups of bacteria compared with mild to moderate cases. We replicated our findings in a mouse COVID-19 model, confirmed virome differences and bacteriome dysbiosis due to SARS-CoV-2 infection, and observed that immune/infection-related genes were differentially expressed in gut epithelial cells during infection, possibly explaining the virome and bacteriome dynamics. Our results suggest that the components of the microbiome, including the bacteriome and virome, are affected by SARS-CoV-2 infections, while their compositional signatures could reflect or even contribute to disease severity and recovery processes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SRSF1 inhibits autophagy through regulating Bcl-x splicing and interacting with PIK3C3 in lung cancer</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33664238/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33664238/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alternative splicing is a critical process to generate protein diversity. However, whether and how alternative splicing regulates autophagy remains largely elusive. Here we systematically identify the splicing factor SRSF1 as an autophagy suppressor. Specifically, SRSF1 inhibits autophagosome formation by reducing the accumulation of LC3-II and numbers of autophagosomes in different cell lines. Mechanistically, SRSF1 promotes the splicing of the long isoform of Bcl-x that interacts with Beclin1, thereby dissociating the Beclin1-PIK3C3 complex. In addition, SRSF1 also directly interacts with PIK3C3 to disrupt the interaction between Beclin1 and PIK3C3. Consequently, the decrease of SRSF1 stabilizes the Beclin1 and PIK3C3 complex and activates autophagy. Interestingly, SRSF1 can be degraded by starvation- and oxidative stresses-induced autophagy through interacting with LC3-II, whereas reduced SRSF1 further promotes autophagy. This positive feedback is critical to inhibiting Gefitinib-resistant cancer cell progression both in vitro and in vivo. Consistently, the expression level of SRSF1 is inversely correlated to LC3 level in clinical cancer samples. Our study not only provides mechanistic insights of alternative splicing in autophagy regulation but also discovers a new regulatory role of SRSF1 in tumorigenesis, thereby offering a novel avenue for potential cancer therapeutics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lung Myofibroblasts Promote Macrophage Profibrotic Activity through Lactate-induced Histone Lactylation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33074715/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33074715/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Augmented glycolysis due to metabolic reprogramming in lung myofibroblasts is critical to their profibrotic phenotype. The primary glycolysis byproduct, lactate, is also secreted into the extracellular milieu, together with which myofibroblasts and macrophages form a spatially restricted site usually described as fibrotic niche. Therefore, we hypothesized that myofibroblast glycolysis might have a non-cell autonomous effect through lactate regulating the pathogenic phenotype of alveolar macrophages. Here, we demonstrated that there was a markedly increased lactate in the conditioned media of TGF-β1 (transforming growth factor-β1)-induced lung myofibroblasts and in the BAL fluids (BALFs) from mice with TGF-β1- or bleomycin-induced lung fibrosis. Importantly, the media and BALFs promoted profibrotic mediator expression in macrophages. Mechanistically, lactate induced histone lactylation in the promoters of the profibrotic genes in macrophages, consistent with the upregulation of this epigenetic modification in these cells in the fibrotic lungs. The lactate inductions of the histone lactylation and profibrotic gene expression were mediated by p300, as evidenced by their diminished concentrations in p300-knockdown macrophages. Collectively, our study establishes that in addition to protein, lipid, and nucleic acid molecules, a metabolite can also mediate intercellular regulations in the setting of lung fibrosis. Our findings shed new light on the mechanism underlying the key contribution of myofibroblast glycolysis to the pathogenesis of lung fibrosis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Identification and Validation of Autophagy-Related Genes in Chronic Obstructive Pulmonary Disease</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33469280/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33469280/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Purpose:&lt;/em&gt; Autophagy plays essential roles in the development of COPD. We aim to identify and validate the potential autophagy-related genes of COPD through bioinformatics analysis and experiment validation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; The mRNA expression profile dataset GSE38974 was obtained from GEO database. The potential differentially expressed autophagy-related genes of COPD were screened by R software. Then, protein–protein interactions (PPI), correlation analysis, gene-ontology (GO) enrichment analysis and Kyoto Encyclopedia of Genes and Genomes (KEGG) pathway enrichment analysis were applied for the differentially expressed autophagy-related genes. Finally, RNA expression of top five differentially expressed autophagy-related genes was validated in blood samples from COPD patients and healthy controls by qRT-PCR.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; A total of 40 differentially expressed autophagy-related genes (14 up-regulated genes and 26 down-regulated genes) were identified between 23 COPD patients and 9 healthy controls. The PPI results demonstrated that these autophagy-related genes interacted with each other. The GO and KEGG enrichment analysis of differentially expressed autophagy-related genes indicated several enriched terms related to autophagy and mitophagy. The results of qRT-PCR showed that the expression levels of &lt;em&gt;HIF1A&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;CDKN1A&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;BAG3&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;ERBB2&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;ATG16L1&lt;/em&gt; in COPD patients and healthy controls were consistent with the bioinformatics analysis results from mRNA microarray.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/em&gt; We identified 40 potential autophagy-related genes of COPD through bioinformatics analysis. &lt;em&gt;HIF1A&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;CDKN1A&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;BAG3&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;ERBB2&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;ATG16L1&lt;/em&gt; may affect the development of COPD by regulating autophagy. These results may expand our understanding of COPD and might be useful in the treatment of COPD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A molecular cell atlas of the human lung from single-cell RNA sequencing</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33208946/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33208946/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although single-cell RNA sequencing studies have begun to provide compendia of cell expression profiles, it has been difficult to systematically identify and localize all molecular cell types in individual organs to create a full molecular cell atlas. Here, using droplet- and plate-based single-cell RNA sequencing of approximately 75,000 human cells across all lung tissue compartments and circulating blood, combined with a multi-pronged cell annotation approach, we create an extensive cell atlas of the human lung. We define the gene expression profiles and anatomical locations of 58 cell populations in the human lung, including 41 out of 45 previously known cell types and 14 previously unknown ones. This comprehensive molecular atlas identifies the biochemical functions of lung cells and the transcription factors and markers for making and monitoring them; defines the cell targets of circulating hormones and predicts local signalling interactions and immune cell homing; and identifies cell types that are directly affected by lung disease genes and respiratory viruses. By comparing human and mouse data, we identified 17 molecular cell types that have been gained or lost during lung evolution and others with substantially altered expression profiles, revealing extensive plasticity of cell types and cell-type-specific gene expression during organ evolution including expression switches between cell types. This atlas provides the molecular foundation for investigating how lung cell identities, functions and interactions are achieved in development and tissue engineering and altered in disease and evolution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mesenchymal stem cells alleviate LPS-induced acute lung injury by inhibiting the proinflammatory function of Ly6C&#43; CD8&#43; T cells</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33024074/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33024074/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Systemic inflammatory processes, including alveolar injury, cytokine induction, and neutrophil accumulation, play key roles in the pathophysiology of acute lung injury (ALI). The immunomodulatory effects of mesenchymal stem cells (MSCs) can contribute to the treatment of inflammatory disorders. In previous studies, the focus was on innate immune cells and the effects of MSCs on ALI through CD8&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T cells remain unclear. In the present study, lipopolysaccharide (LPS) was used to induce ALI in mice. ALI mice were treated with MSCs via intratracheal instillation. Survival rate, histopathological changes, protein levels, total cell count, cytokine levels, and chemokine levels in alveolar lavage fluid were used to determine the efficacy of MSCs. Mass cytometry and single-cell RNA sequencing (scRNA-seq) were used to characterize the CD8&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T cells in the lungs. Ly6C&lt;sup&gt;-&lt;/sup&gt; CD8&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T cells are prevalent in normal mice, whereas a specialized effector phenotype expressing a high level of Ly6C is predominant in advanced disease. MSCs significantly mitigated ALI and improved survival. MSCs decreased the infiltration of CD8&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T cells, especially Ly6C&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; CD8&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T cells into the lungs. Mass cytometry revealed that CD8&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T cells expressing high Ly6C and CXCR3 levels caused tissue damage in the lungs of ALI mice, which was alleviated by MSCs. The scRNA-seq showed that Ly6C&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; CD8&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T cells exhibited a more activated phenotype and decreased expression of proinflammatory factors that were enriched the most in immune chemotaxis after treatment with MSCs. We showed that CD8&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T cells play an important role in MSC-mediated ALI remission, and both infiltration quantity and proinflammatory function were inhibited by MSCs, indicating a potential mechanism for therapeutic intervention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Immunosuppressive effects of mesenchymal stem cells on lung B cell gene expression in LPS-induced acute lung injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32977837/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32977837/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Immune system disorders play important roles in acute lung injury (ALI), and mesenchymal stem cell (MSC) treatment can reduce inflammation during ALI. In this study, we compared the changes in lung B cells during MSC treatment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; We investigated the effects of MSCs on lung B cells in a mouse model of lipopolysaccharide (LPS)-induced ALI. MSCs were administered intratracheally 4 h after LPS. As vehicle-treated controls, mice were treated with phosphate-buffered saline (PBS) containing 2% C57BL/6 (PBS group). Histopathological changes, survival rate, inflammatory factor levels, and the number of neutrophils in bronchoalveolar lavage fluid (BALF) were determined. Single-cell RNA sequencing (scRNA-Seq) analysis was performed to evaluate the transcriptional changes in lung B cells between the PBS, LPS, and LPS/MSC groups on days 3 and 7.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; MSC treatment ameliorated LPS-induced ALI, as indicated by the reductions in mortality, the levels of chemokines and cytokines in BALF, and the severity of lung tissue histopathology in ALI mice. Lung B cells in the PBS group remained undifferentiated and had an inhibitory phenotype. Based on our scRNA-Seq results, the differentially expressed genes (DEGs) in lung B cells in both the PBS group and LPS group were involved in chemotaxis processes and some proinflammatory pathways. MSC treatment inhibited the expression of chemokine genes that were upregulated by LPS and were related to the recruitment of neutrophils into lung tissues. Immunoglobulin-related gene expression was decreased in lung B cells of mice treated with LPS/MSC for 7 days. The DEGs regulated by MSCs were enriched in biological processes, including humoral immune response and apoptotic signaling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; Lung B cells played an important role in the effects of treatment of ALI with MSCs. These observations provide new insights into the mechanisms underlying the effects of MSC treatment for ALI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inflammatory Signals Induce AT2 Cell-Derived Damage-Associated Transient Progenitors that Mediate Alveolar Regeneration</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32750316/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32750316/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tissue regeneration is a multi-step process mediated by diverse cellular hierarchies and states that are also implicated in tissue dysfunction and pathogenesis. Here we leveraged single-cell RNA sequencing in combination with in vivo lineage tracing and organoid models to finely map the trajectories of alveolar-lineage cells during injury repair and lung regeneration. We identified a distinct AT2-lineage population, damage-associated transient progenitors (DATPs), that arises during alveolar regeneration. We found that interstitial macrophage-derived IL-1β primes a subset of AT2 cells expressing Il1r1 for conversion into DATPs via a HIF1α-mediated glycolysis pathway, which is required for mature AT1 cell differentiation. Importantly, chronic inflammation mediated by IL-1β prevents AT1 differentiation, leading to aberrant accumulation of DATPs and impaired alveolar regeneration. Together, this stepwise mapping to cell fate transitions shows how an inflammatory niche controls alveolar regeneration by controlling stem cell fate and behavior.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Altered Gut Microbiome Profile in Patients With Pulmonary Arterial Hypertension</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32088998/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32088998/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pulmonary arterial hypertension (PAH) is considered a disease of the pulmonary vasculature. Limited progress has been made in preventing or arresting progression of PAH despite extensive efforts. Our previous studies indicated that PAH could be considered a systemic disease since its pathology involves interplay of multiple organs. This, coupled with increasing implication of the gut and its microbiome in chronic diseases, led us to hypothesize that patients with PAH exhibit a distinct gut microbiome that contributes to, and predicts, the disease. Fecal microbiome of 18 type 1 PAH patients (mean pulmonary arterial pressure, 57.4, SD 16.7 mm Hg) and 13 reference subjects were compared by shotgun metagenomics to evaluate this hypothesis. Significant taxonomic and functional changes in microbial communities in the PAH cohort were observed. Pathways for the synthesis of arginine, proline, and ornithine were increased in PAH cohort compared with reference cohort. Additionally, groups of bacterial communities associated with trimethylamine/ trimethylamine N-oxide and purine metabolism were increased in PAH cohort. In contrast, butyrate-and propionate-producing bacteria such as Coprococcus, Butyrivibrio, Lachnospiraceae, Eubacterium, Akkermansia, and Bacteroides were increased in reference cohort. A random forest model predicted PAH from the composition of the gut microbiome with 83% accuracy. Finally, virome analysis showed enrichment of Enterococcal and relative depletion of Lactococcal phages in the PAH cohort. In conclusion, patients with PAH exhibit a unique microbiome profile that has the high predictive potential for PAH. This highlights previously unknown roles of gut bacteria in this disease and could lead to new therapeutic, diagnostic, or management paradigms for PAH.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transcriptomic and epigenetic mechanisms underlying myeloid diversity in the lung</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/31959980/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/31959980/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The lung is inhabited by resident alveolar and interstitial macrophages as well as monocytic cells that survey lung tissues. Each cell type plays distinct functional roles under homeostatic and inflammatory conditions, but mechanisms establishing their molecular identities and functional potential remain poorly understood. In the present study, systematic evaluation of transcriptomes and open chromatin of alveolar macrophages (AMs), interstitial macrophages (IMs) and lung monocytes from two mouse strains enabled inference of common and cell-specific transcriptional regulators. We provide evidence that these factors drive selection of regulatory landscapes that specify distinct phenotypes of AMs and IMs and entrain qualitatively different responses to toll-like receptor 4 signaling in vivo. These studies reveal a striking divergence in a fundamental innate immune response pathway in AMs and establish a framework for further understanding macrophage diversity in the lung.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Progressive Pulmonary Fibrosis Is Caused by Elevated Mechanical Tension on Alveolar Stem Cells</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/31866069/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/31866069/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Erratum in:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674%2821%2900063-5&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Progressive pulmonary fibrosis is caused by elevated mechanical tension on alveolar stem cells&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fibrosis can develop in most organs and causes organ failure. The most common type of lung fibrosis is known as idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis, in which fibrosis starts at the lung periphery and then progresses toward the lung center, eventually causing respiratory failure. Little is known about the mechanisms underlying the pathogenesis and periphery-to-center progression of the disease. Here we discovered that loss of Cdc42 function in alveolar stem cells (AT2 cells) causes periphery-to-center progressive lung fibrosis. We further show that Cdc42-null AT2 cells in both post-pneumonectomy and untreated aged mice cannot regenerate new alveoli, resulting in sustained exposure of AT2 cells to elevated mechanical tension. We demonstrate that elevated mechanical tension activates a TGF-β signaling loop in AT2 cells, which drives the periphery-to-center progression of lung fibrosis. Our study establishes a direct mechanistic link between impaired alveolar regeneration, mechanical tension, and progressive lung fibrosis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Age-Related Dopaminergic Innervation Augments T Helper 2-Type Allergic Inflammation in the Postnatal Lung</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/31757673/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/31757673/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Young children are more susceptible to developing allergic asthma than adults. As neural innervation of the peripheral tissue continues to develop after birth, neurons may modulate tissue inflammation in an age-related manner. Here we showed that sympathetic nerves underwent a dopaminergic-to-adrenergic transition during post-natal development of the lung in mice and humans. Dopamine signaled through a specific dopamine receptor (DRD4) to promote T helper 2 (Th2) cell differentiation. The dopamine-DRD4 pathway acted synergistically with the cytokine IL-4 by upregulating IL-2-STAT5 signaling and reducing inhibitory histone trimethylation at Th2 gene loci. In murine models of allergen exposure, the dopamine-DRD4 pathway augmented Th2 inflammation in the lungs of young mice. However, this pathway operated marginally after sympathetic nerves became adrenergic in the adult lung. Taken together, the communication between dopaminergic nerves and CD4&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T cells provides an age-related mechanism underlying the susceptibility to allergic inflammation in the early lung.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Targeting Degradation of the Transcription Factor C/EBPβ Reduces Lung Fibrosis by Restoring Activity of the Ubiquitin-Editing Enzyme A20 in Macrophages</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/31471107/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/31471107/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although recent progress provides mechanistic insights into the pathogenesis of pulmonary fibrosis (PF), rare anti-PF therapeutics show definitive promise for treating this disease. Repeated lung epithelial injury results in injury-repairing response and inflammation, which drive the development of PF. Here, we report that chronic lung injury inactivated the ubiquitin-editing enzyme A20, causing progressive accumulation of the transcription factor C/EBPβ in alveolar macrophages (AMs) from PF patients and mice, which upregulated a number of immunosuppressive and profibrotic factors promoting PF development. In response to chronic lung injury, elevated glycogen synthase kinase-3β (GSK-3β) interacted with and phosphorylated A20 to suppress C/EBPβ degradation. Ectopic expression of A20 or pharmacological restoration of A20 activity by disturbing the A20-GSK-3β interaction accelerated C/EBPβ degradation and showed potent therapeutic efficacy against experimental PF. Our study indicates that a regulatory mechanism of the GSK-3β-A20-C/EBPβ axis in AMs may be a potential target for treating PF and fibroproliferative lung diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tolerogenic signaling of alveolar macrophages induces lung adaptation to oxidative injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/31356919/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/31356919/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Inhaled oxidative toxicants present in ambient air cause airway epithelial injury, inflammation, and airway hyperresponsiveness. Effective adaptation to such environmental insults is essential for the preservation of pulmonary function, whereas failure or incomplete adaptation to oxidative injury can render the host susceptible to the development of airway disease.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Objective:&lt;/em&gt; We sought to explore the mechanisms of airway adaptation to oxidative injury.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; For a model to study pulmonary adaptation to oxidative stress-induced lung injury, we exposed mice to repeated nose-only chlorine gas exposures. Outcome measures were evaluated 24 hours after the last chlorine exposure. Lung mechanics and airway responsiveness to methacholine were assessed by using the flexiVent. Inflammation and antioxidant responses were assessed in both bronchoalveolar lavage fluid and lung tissue. Using both loss or gain of function and genomic approaches, we further dissected the cellular and molecular mechanisms involved in pulmonary adaptation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; Repeated exposures to oxidative stress resulted in pulmonary adaptation evidenced by abrogation of neutrophilic inflammation and airway hyperresponsiveness. This adaptation was independent of antioxidant mechanisms and regulatory T cells but dependent on residential alveolar macrophages (AMs). Interestingly, 5% of AMs expressed forkhead box P3, and depletion of these cells abolished adaptation. Results from transcriptomic profiling and loss and gain of function suggest that adaptation might be dependent on TGF-β and prostaglandin E&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/em&gt; Pulmonary adaptation during oxidative stress-induced lung injury is mediated by a novel subset of forkhead box P3-positive AMs that limits inflammation, favoring airway adaptation and host fitness through TGF-β and prostaglandin E&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Identification of a novel anoikis-related gene signature to predict prognosis and tumor microenvironment in lung adenocarcinoma</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36507553/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jun 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36507553/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Lung adenocarcinoma (LUAD) is the most prevalent histotype of non-small cell lung cancer. Anoikis, an alternative form of programmed cell death, plays a pivotal role in cancer invasion and metastasis, preventing the detached cancer cells from readhering to other substrates for abnormal proliferation. The aim of this study was to conduct a comprehensive analyses of the prognostic implications of anoikis-related genes (ARGs) in LUAD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; ARGs were selected from The Cancer Genome Atlas (TCGA) database and Genecards dataset using differential expression analysis. The signature incorporating ARGs was identified using univariate Cox regression analysis and LASSO regression analysis. Furthermore, a nomogram containing the signature and clinical information was developed through univariate and multivariate Cox regression analysis. Kaplan-Meier survival analysis and receiver operating characteristic (ROC) curves were applied to evaluate the predictive validity of these risk models. Finally, functional analysis of the selected ARGs in signature and analysis of immune landscape were also conducted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; A 16-gene signature was integrated to stratify LUAD patients into different survival risk groups. The prognostic risk score generated from the signature and TNM stage were identified as independent prognostic factors and utilized to develop a nomogram. Both the signature and the nomogram showed satisfactory prediction performance in predicting overall survival (OS) of LUAD patients. The ARGs were enriched in several biological functions and signaling pathways. Finally, differences of immune landscape were investigated among the high- and low-risk groups stratified by the signature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; This study revealed potential relationships between ARGs and prognosis of LUAD. The prognostic predictors identified in present study could be utilized as potential biomarkers for clinical applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mesenchymal stem cell-mediated immunomodulation of recruited mononuclear phagocytes during acute lung injury: a high-dimensional analysis study</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33500722/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jun 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33500722/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rationale:&lt;/em&gt; Acute lung injury (ALI)-recruited mononuclear phagocytes play a pivotal role in lung injury and repair. This study investigated the types of recruited mononuclear phagocytes and the immunotherapeutic effects of allograft mesenchymal stem cells (MSCs) in a mouse model of lipopolysaccharide (LPS)-induced ALI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; C57BL/6 mice were orotracheally instilled with LPS (20 mg/kg). Compact bone-derived MSCs were administered orotracheally 4 h after LPS inhalation. Mononuclear phagocytes recruited in the lung tissues were characterized at different timepoints by high-dimensional analysis including flow cytometry, mass cytometry, and single-cell RNA sequencing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; Eight mononuclear phagocyte subsets recruited to LPS-challenged lungs were precisely identified. On day 3 after LPS administration, both Ly6C&lt;sup&gt;hi&lt;/sup&gt;CD38&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; and Ly6C&lt;sup&gt;low&lt;/sup&gt;CD38&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; monocytes were recruited into acutely injured lungs, which was associated with increased secretion of neutrophil chemokines. Ly6C&lt;sup&gt;hi&lt;/sup&gt;CD38&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; monocytes differentiated into M1 macrophages on day 3, and subsequently differentiated into CD38&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; monocyte-derived dendritic cells (mo-DCs) on day 7, while Ly6C&lt;sup&gt;low&lt;/sup&gt;CD38&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; monocytes differentiated into CD11b&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt;CD38&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; DCs on day 7. When ALI mice were treated with MSCs, the mortality significantly reduced. Notably, MSCs reduced the amount of M1 macrophages and reduced the secretion of neutrophil chemokines on day 3. Furthermore, MSCs reduced the number of CD38&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; mo-DCs and CD11b&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt;CD38&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; DCs on day 7, suppressing the antigen presentation process. Recruited mononuclear phagocyte subsets with a high level of CD38 exhibited an activated phenotype and could secrete higher levels of cytokines and chemokines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; This study characterized the dynamic functions and phenotypes of recruited mononuclear phagocytes in ALI mice and MSC-treated ALI mice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
