<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Respiratory Syncytial Virus | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/respiratory-syncytial-virus/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/respiratory-syncytial-virus/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Respiratory Syncytial Virus</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Respiratory Syncytial Virus</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/respiratory-syncytial-virus/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Maresin 1-LGR6 axis decreases respiratory syncytial virus-induced lung inflammation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36595677/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36595677/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The resolution of infection is an active process with specific molecular and cellular mechanisms that temper inflammation and enhance pathogen clearance. Here, the specialized pro-resolving mediator (SPM) Maresin 1 (MaR1) inhibited respiratory syncytial virus (RSV)-induced inflammation. inlerleukin-13 production from type 2 innate lymphoid cells (ILC) and CD4 T helper type 2 cells was decreased by exogenous MaR1. In addition, MaR1 increased amphiregulin production and decreased RSV viral transcripts to promote resolution. MaR1 also promoted interferon-β production in mouse lung tissues and also in pediatric lung slices. MaR1 significantly inhibited the RSV-triggered aberrant inflammatory phenotype in FoxP3-expressing Tregs. The receptor for MaR1, leucine-rich repeat-containing G protein-coupled receptor 6 (LGR6), was constitutively expressed on Tregs. Following RSV infection, mice lacking Lgr6 had exacerbated type 2 immune responses with an increased viral burden and blunted responses to MaR1. Together, these findings have uncovered a multi-pronged protective signaling axis for MaR1-Lgr6, improving Tregs&amp;rsquo;s suppressive function and upregulating host antiviral genes resulting in decreased viral burden and pathogen-mediated inflammation, ultimately promoting restoration of airway mucosal homeostasis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
