<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Respiratory Syncytial Virus | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/respiratory-syncytial-virus/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/respiratory-syncytial-virus/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Respiratory Syncytial Virus</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Respiratory Syncytial Virus</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/respiratory-syncytial-virus/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Maresin 1-LGR6 axis decreases respiratory syncytial virus-induced lung inflammation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36595677/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36595677/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The resolution of infection is an active process with specific molecular and cellular mechanisms that temper inflammation and enhance pathogen clearance. Here, the specialized pro-resolving mediator (SPM) Maresin 1 (MaR1) inhibited respiratory syncytial virus (RSV)-induced inflammation. inlerleukin-13 production from type 2 innate lymphoid cells (ILC) and CD4 T helper type 2 cells was decreased by exogenous MaR1. In addition, MaR1 increased amphiregulin production and decreased RSV viral transcripts to promote resolution. MaR1 also promoted interferon-β production in mouse lung tissues and also in pediatric lung slices. MaR1 significantly inhibited the RSV-triggered aberrant inflammatory phenotype in FoxP3-expressing Tregs. The receptor for MaR1, leucine-rich repeat-containing G protein-coupled receptor 6 (LGR6), was constitutively expressed on Tregs. Following RSV infection, mice lacking Lgr6 had exacerbated type 2 immune responses with an increased viral burden and blunted responses to MaR1. Together, these findings have uncovered a multi-pronged protective signaling axis for MaR1-Lgr6, improving Tregs&amp;rsquo;s suppressive function and upregulating host antiviral genes resulting in decreased viral burden and pathogen-mediated inflammation, ultimately promoting restoration of airway mucosal homeostasis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Acteoside attenuates RSV-induced lung injury by suppressing necroptosis and regulating metabolism</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36059973/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36059973/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Necroptosis and inflammation are closely related to the pathogenesis of respiratory syncytial virus (RSV). Acteoside (AC), a natural phenylpropanoid glycoside from Kuding Tea, has significant anti-RSV effect. However, the roles of AC on RSV-induced lung necroptosis and inflammation are yet to be elucidated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; The effects of AC were investigated in BALB/c mice and A549 cells. Lung histopathology was observed through H&amp;amp;E staining. The viral titer was assessed via plaque assay. The RSV-F expression was determined by RT-qPCR and immunohistochemistry assay. The levels of cytokines were detected by ELISA and RT-qPCR. The necroptosis rate and mitochondrial membrane potential were evaluated via flow cytometry. The expressions of HMGB1/NF-κB and RIP1/RIP3/MLKL/PGAM5/DRP1 were detected by western blot. Additionally, untargeted metabolomics was conducted to investigate the metabolic profiles and related metabolic pathways via Gas Chromatography-Mass Spectrometry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; The results showed that compared with the RSV-infected group, AC treatment significantly attenuated lung pathological damage, virus replication, and cytokines levels. AC also alleviated RSV-induced necroptosis and mitochondrial dysfunction &lt;em&gt;in vitro&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt;. Moreover, AC treatment down-regulated the expression of HMGB1, p-Iκbα/Iκbα, p-p65/p65, RIP1, RIP3, MLKL, PGAM5, and DRP1. Furthermore, metabolomic analyses suggested that the perturbations in major metabolites of AC therapy were related to variations in amino acid and energy metabolism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/em&gt; Our findings validated the beneficial effects of AC in suppressing necroptosis and regulating metabolism, suggesting AC may be a new drug candidate for RSV infection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Long-term expanding human airway organoids for disease modeling</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/30643021/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/30643021/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Organoids are self-organizing 3D structures grown from stem cells that recapitulate essential aspects of organ structure and function. Here, we describe a method to establish long-term-expanding human airway organoids from broncho-alveolar resections or lavage material. The pseudostratified airway organoids consist of basal cells, functional multi-ciliated cells, mucus-producing secretory cells, and CC10-secreting club cells. Airway organoids derived from cystic fibrosis (CF) patients allow assessment of CFTR function in an organoid swelling assay. Organoids established from lung cancer resections and metastasis biopsies retain tumor histopathology as well as cancer gene mutations and are amenable to drug screening. Respiratory syncytial virus (RSV) infection recapitulates central disease features, dramatically increases organoid cell motility via the non-structural viral NS2 protein, and preferentially recruits neutrophils upon co-culturing. We conclude that human airway organoids represent versatile models for the &lt;em&gt;in vitro&lt;/em&gt; study of hereditary, malignant, and infectious pulmonary disease.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
