<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Esophagus | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/esophagus/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/esophagus/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Esophagus</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Esophagus</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/esophagus/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generation and multiomic profiling of a TP53/CDKN2A double-knockout gastroesophageal junction organoid model</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36449602/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36449602/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inactivation of the tumor suppressor genes tumor protein p53 (&lt;em&gt;TP53&lt;/em&gt;) and cyclin-dependent kinase inhibitor 2A (&lt;em&gt;CDKN2A&lt;/em&gt;) occurs early during gastroesophageal junction (GEJ) tumorigenesis. However, because of a paucity of GEJ-specific disease models, cancer-promoting consequences of &lt;em&gt;TP53&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;CDKN2A&lt;/em&gt; inactivation at the GEJ have not been characterized. Here, we report the development of a wild-type primary human GEJ organoid model and a CRISPR-edited transformed GEJ organoid model. CRISPR-Cas9–mediated &lt;em&gt;TP53&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;CDKN2A&lt;/em&gt; knockout (&lt;em&gt;TP53/CDKN2A&lt;sup&gt;KO&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt;) in GEJ organoids induced morphologic dysplasia and proneoplastic features in vitro and tumor formation in vivo. Lipidomic profiling identified several platelet-activating factors (PTAFs) among the most up-regulated lipids in CRISPR-edited organoids. PTAF/PTAF receptor (PTAFR) abrogation by siRNA knockdown or a pharmacologic inhibitor (WEB2086) reduced proliferation and other proneoplastic features of &lt;em&gt;TP53/CDKN2A&lt;sup&gt;KO&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; GEJ organoids in vitro and tumor formation in vivo. In addition, murine xenografts of Eso26, an established human esophageal adenocarcinoma cell line, were suppressed by WEB2086. Mechanistically, &lt;em&gt;TP53/CDKN2A&lt;/em&gt; dual inactivation disrupted both the transcriptome and the DNA methylome, likely mediated by key transcription factors, particularly forkhead box M1 (FOXM1). FOXM1 activated &lt;em&gt;PTAFR&lt;/em&gt; transcription by binding to the &lt;em&gt;PTAFR&lt;/em&gt; promoter, further amplifying the PTAF-PTAFR pathway. Together, these studies established a robust model system for investigating early GEJ neoplastic events, identified crucial metabolic and epigenomic changes occurring during GEJ model tumorigenesis, and revealed a potential cancer therapeutic strategy. This work provides insights into proneoplastic mechanisms associated with &lt;em&gt;TP53/CDKN2A&lt;/em&gt; inactivation in early GEJ neoplasia, which may facilitate early diagnosis and prevention of GEJ neoplasms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
