<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Esophagus | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/esophagus/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/esophagus/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Esophagus</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Esophagus</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/esophagus/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generation and multiomic profiling of a TP53/CDKN2A double-knockout gastroesophageal junction organoid model</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36449602/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36449602/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inactivation of the tumor suppressor genes tumor protein p53 (&lt;em&gt;TP53&lt;/em&gt;) and cyclin-dependent kinase inhibitor 2A (&lt;em&gt;CDKN2A&lt;/em&gt;) occurs early during gastroesophageal junction (GEJ) tumorigenesis. However, because of a paucity of GEJ-specific disease models, cancer-promoting consequences of &lt;em&gt;TP53&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;CDKN2A&lt;/em&gt; inactivation at the GEJ have not been characterized. Here, we report the development of a wild-type primary human GEJ organoid model and a CRISPR-edited transformed GEJ organoid model. CRISPR-Cas9–mediated &lt;em&gt;TP53&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;CDKN2A&lt;/em&gt; knockout (&lt;em&gt;TP53/CDKN2A&lt;sup&gt;KO&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt;) in GEJ organoids induced morphologic dysplasia and proneoplastic features in vitro and tumor formation in vivo. Lipidomic profiling identified several platelet-activating factors (PTAFs) among the most up-regulated lipids in CRISPR-edited organoids. PTAF/PTAF receptor (PTAFR) abrogation by siRNA knockdown or a pharmacologic inhibitor (WEB2086) reduced proliferation and other proneoplastic features of &lt;em&gt;TP53/CDKN2A&lt;sup&gt;KO&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; GEJ organoids in vitro and tumor formation in vivo. In addition, murine xenografts of Eso26, an established human esophageal adenocarcinoma cell line, were suppressed by WEB2086. Mechanistically, &lt;em&gt;TP53/CDKN2A&lt;/em&gt; dual inactivation disrupted both the transcriptome and the DNA methylome, likely mediated by key transcription factors, particularly forkhead box M1 (FOXM1). FOXM1 activated &lt;em&gt;PTAFR&lt;/em&gt; transcription by binding to the &lt;em&gt;PTAFR&lt;/em&gt; promoter, further amplifying the PTAF-PTAFR pathway. Together, these studies established a robust model system for investigating early GEJ neoplastic events, identified crucial metabolic and epigenomic changes occurring during GEJ model tumorigenesis, and revealed a potential cancer therapeutic strategy. This work provides insights into proneoplastic mechanisms associated with &lt;em&gt;TP53/CDKN2A&lt;/em&gt; inactivation in early GEJ neoplasia, which may facilitate early diagnosis and prevention of GEJ neoplasms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lipid metabolism-related lncRNA SLC25A21-AS1 promotes the progression of oesophageal squamous cell carcinoma by regulating the NPM1/c-Myc axis and SLC25A21 expression</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35735113/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35735113/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Obesity alters metabolic microenvironment and is thus associated with several tumours. The aim of the present study was to investigate the role, molecular mechanism of action, and potential clinical value of lipid metabolism-related long non-coding RNA (lncRNA) SLC25A21-AS1 in oesophageal squamous cell carcinoma (ESCC).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; A high-fat diets (HFDs)-induced obesity nude mouse model was established, and targeted metabolomics analysis was used to identify critical medium-long chain fatty acids influencing the growth of ESCC cells. Transcriptomic analysis of public dataset GSE53625 confirmed that lncRNA SLC25A21-AS1 was a lipid metabolism-related lncRNA. The biological function of lncRNA SLC25A21-AS1 in ESCC was investigated both in vivo and in vitro. Chromatin immunoprecipitation(ChIP)assay, RNA-pull down, mass spectrometry, co-IP, and RNA IP(RIP) were performed to explore the molecular mechanism. Finally, an ESCC cDNA microarray was used to determine the clinical prognostic value of SLC25A21-AS1 by RT-qPCR.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; Palmitic acid (PA) is an important fatty acid component of HFD and had an inhibitory effect on ESCC cell lines. LncRNA SLC25A21-AS1 expression was downregulated by PA and associated with the proliferation and migration of ESCC cells in vitro and in vivo. Mechanistically, SLC25A21-AS1 interacted with nucleophosmin-1 (NPM1) protein to promote the downstream gene transcription of the c-Myc in the nucleus. In the cytoplasm, SLC25A21-AS1 maintained the stability of SLC25A21 mRNA and reduced the intracellular NAD+ /NADH ratio by influencing tryptophan catabolism. Finally, we demonstrated that high expression of SLC25A21-AS1 promoted resistance to cisplatin-induced apoptosis and was correlated with poor tumour grade and overall survival.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; HFD/PA has an inhibitory effect on ESCC cells and SLC25A21-AS1 expression. SLC25A21-AS1 promotes the proliferation and migration of ESCC cells by regulating the NPM1/c-Myc axis and SLC25A21 expression. In addition, lncRNA SLC25A21-AS1 may serve as a favourable prognostic biomarker and a potential therapeutic target for ESCC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multi-omic characterization of genome-wide abnormal DNA methylation reveals diagnostic and prognostic markers for esophageal squamous-cell carcinoma</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35210398/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35210398/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Viruses are intracellular pathogens that hijack host cell machinery and resources to replicate. Rather than being constant, host physiology is rhythmic, undergoing circadian (∼24 h) oscillations in many virus-relevant pathways, but whether daily rhythms impact on viral replication is unknown. We find that the time of day of host infection regulates virus progression in live mice and individual cells. Furthermore, we demonstrate that herpes and influenza A virus infections are enhanced when host circadian rhythms are abolished by disrupting the key clock gene transcription factor Bmal1. Intracellular trafficking, biosynthetic processes, protein synthesis, and chromatin assembly all contribute to circadian regulation of virus infection. Moreover, herpesviruses differentially target components of the molecular circadian clockwork. Our work demonstrates that viruses exploit the clockwork for their own gain and that the clock represents a novel target for modulating viral replication that extends beyond any single family of these ubiquitous pathogens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nucleic acid aptamer controls mycoplasma infection for inhibiting the malignancy of esophageal squamous cell carcinoma</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35189346/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35189346/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Esophageal cancer is one of the most frequent malignant tumors of the digestive tract, among which esophageal squamous cell carcinoma (ESCC) is the main pathological type worldwide. Previous studies have shown microbial infections in the upper digestive tract to be a potential risk factor in ESCC etiology. In this study, we identified that Mycoplasma hyorhinis infection promoted the malignancy of ESCC. In response, we generated a single-stranded DNA aptamer, ZY3A, against M. hyorhinis using the cell-SELEX strategy. The underlying recognition mechanism of ZY3A on M. hyorhinis involves its binding to M. hyorhinis-specific p37 protein. This tool allowed us to provide the first proof-of-concept evidence using a nucleic acid aptamer to control mycoplasma infection. More specifically, we found that ZY3A could neutralize M. hyorhinis infection on ESCC cells by blocking the interaction between p37 protein and its receptor TLR4 on the ESCC cell membrane. As a result, ZY3A inhibited the migration and invasion of M. hyorhinis-infected ESCC cells in vitro and metastasis in vivo. Taken together, these findings indicate that aptamer ZY3A is a potential candidate for development into a novel molecular tool for treatment of M. hyorhinis infection and a safe first-in-class M. hyorhinis-targeting antitumor agent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ATXN2-mediated translation of TNFR1 promotes esophageal squamous cell carcinoma via m6A-dependent manner</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34995801/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34995801/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;N&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;-methyladenosine (m&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;A) is the most prevalent RNA modification, and the effect of its dysregulation on esophageal squamous cell carcinoma (ESCC) development remains unclear. Here, by performing transcriptome-wide m&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;A sequencing in 16 ESCC tissue samples, we identified the key roles of m&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;A in TNFRSF1A (also known as TNFR1)-mediated MAPK and NF-κB activation in ESCC. Mechanistically, a functional protein involved in m&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;A methylation, ATXN2, is identified that augments the translation of TNFRSF1A by binding to m&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;A-modified TNFRSF1A mRNA. Upregulation of the TNFRSF1A protein level, a vital upstream switch for TNFRSF1A-mediated signaling events, activates the NF-κB and MAPK pathways and thus promotes ESCC development. Furthermore, TNFRSF1A m&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;A modifications and protein levels are upregulated in ESCC, and high levels of TNFRSF1A m&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;A and protein are correlated with poor ESCC patient survival. These results collectively indicate that the m&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;A-TNFRSF1A axis is critical for ESCC development and thus may serve as a potential druggable target.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integrated single-cell transcriptome analysis reveals heterogeneity of esophageal squamous cell carcinoma microenvironment</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34921160/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34921160/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tumor microenvironment is a highly complex ecosystem of diverse cell types, which shape cancer biology and impact the responsiveness to therapy. Here, we analyze the microenvironment of esophageal squamous cell carcinoma (ESCC) using single-cell transcriptome sequencing in 62,161 cells from blood, adjacent nonmalignant and matched tumor samples from 11 ESCC patients. We uncover heterogeneity in most cell types of the ESCC stroma, particularly in the fibroblast and immune cell compartments. We identify a tumor-specific subset of CST1+ myofibroblasts with prognostic values and potential biological significance. CST1+ myofibroblasts are also highly tumor-specific in other cancer types. Additionally, a subset of antigen-presenting fibroblasts is revealed and validated. Analyses of myeloid and T lymphoid lineages highlight the immunosuppressive nature of the ESCC microenvironment, and identify cancer-specific expression of immune checkpoint inhibitors. This work establishes a rich resource of stromal cell types of the ESCC microenvironment for further understanding of ESCC biology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Long non-coding RNA NORAD/miR-224-3p/MTDH axis contributes to CDDP resistance of esophageal squamous cell carcinoma by promoting nuclear accumulation of β-catenin</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34893064/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34893064/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Cis-diamminedichloro-platinum (CDDP)-based chemotherapy regimens are the most predominant treatment strategies for patients with esophageal squamous cell carcinoma (ESCC). Dysregulated long non-coding RNAs (lncRNAs) contribute to CDDP resistance, which results in treatment failure in ESCC patients. However, the majority of lncRNAs involved in CDDP resistance in ESCC remain to be elucidated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; The public Gene Expression Omnibus (GEO) dataset GSE45670 was analysed to reveal potential lncRNAs involved in CDDP resistance of ESCC. Candidate upregulated lncRNAs were detected in ESCC specimens by qRT-PCR to identify crucial lncRNAs. Non-coding RNA activated by DNA damage (NORAD) was selected for further study. Kaplan-Meier analysis and a COX proportional regression model were performed to analyse the potential of NORAD for predicting prognosis of ESCC patients. The role of NORAD in CDDP resistance were determined by conducting gain and loss-of-function experiments in vitro. Fluorescence in situ hybridization (FISH) was performed to determine the subcellular location of NORAD in ESCC cells. A public GEO dataset and bioinformatic algorithms were used to predict the microRNAs (miRNAs) that might be latently sponged by NORAD. qRT-PCR was conducted to verify the expression of candidate miRNAs. Luciferase reporter and Argonaute-2 (Ago2)-RNA immunoprecipitation (RIP) assays were conducted to evaluate the interaction between NORAD and candidate miRNAs. A miRNA rescue experiment was performed to authenticate the NORAD regulatory axis and its effects on CDDP resistance in ESCC cells. Western blotting was conducted to confirm the precise downstream signalling pathway of NORAD. A xenograft mouse model was established to reveal the effect of NORAD on CDDP resistance in vivo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; The expression of NORAD was higher in CDDP-resistant ESCC tissues and cells than in CDDP-sensitive tissues and cells. NORAD expression was negatively correlated with the postoperative prognosis of ESCC patients who underwent CDDP-based chemotherapy. NORAD knockdown partially arrested CDDP resistance of ESCC cells. FISH showed that NORAD was located in the cytoplasm in ESCC cells. Furthermore, overlapping results from bioinformatic algorithms analyses and qRT-PCR showed that NORAD could sponge miR-224-3p in ESCC cells. Ago2-RIP demonstrated that NORAD and miR-224-3p occupied the same Ago2 to form an RNA-induced silencing complex (RISC) and subsequently regulated the expression of metadherin (MTDH) in ESCC cells. The NORAD/miR-224-3p/MTDH axis promoted CDDP resistance and progression in ESCC cells by promoting nuclear accumulation of β-catenin in vitro and in vivo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; NORAD upregulates MTDH to promote CDDP resistance and progression in ESCC by sponging miR-224-3p. Our results highlight the potential of NORAD as a therapeutic target in ESCC patients receiving CDDP-based chemotherapy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interferon-α exerts proinflammatory properties in experimental radiation-induced esophagitis: Possible involvement of plasmacytoid dendritic cells</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34890590/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34890590/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Irradiation to esophagus induce IFN-α in the esophageal mucosa.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IFN-α induce and promote inflammation in radiation-induced esophagitis.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Inhibition of IFN-α ameliorate radiation-induced esophagitis.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Depletion or inactivation of pDC reduce IFN-α in radiation-induced esophagitis.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Depletion or inactivation of pDC ameliorate radiation-induced esophagitis.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Aims:&lt;/em&gt; Radiation-induced esophagitis, experienced during radiation therapy for lung cancer and head and neck cancer, is a major dose-limiting side effect of the treatment. This study aimed to elucidate the role of interferon-α (IFN-α) in radiation-induced esophagitis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Main methods:&lt;/em&gt; C57BL/6 mice were exposed to 10 and 25Gy of single thoracic irradiation. Esophageal mucosal damage and inflammatory reactions were assessed for 5 days after irradiation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Key findings:&lt;/em&gt; Irradiation induced esophagitis, characterized by reduction in the thickness of epithelial layer, upregulation of proinflammatory cytokines and chemokines, infiltration of inflammatory cells into the esophageal mucosa, and apoptosis of epithelial cells. Irradiation upregulated the level of gene expression for IFN-α in the esophageal tissue, and the neutralizing antibody against IFN-α ameliorated radiation-induced esophageal mucosal damage, while administration of IFN-α receptor agonist (RO8191) had an inverse effect. Depletion of plasmacytoid dendritic cells (pDCs) by anti-CD317 antibody or pharmacological inactivation with bortezomib suppressed radiation-induced mucosal inflammation and damage, accompanied by decrease in IFN-α expression level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Significance:&lt;/em&gt; These findings suggest that IFN-α and pDCs exert proinflammatory properties in the pathophysiology of radiation-induced esophagitis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
