<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CRISPR-Cas | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/crispr-cas/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/crispr-cas/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>CRISPR-Cas</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>CRISPR-Cas</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/crispr-cas/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced RNA knockdown efficiency with engineered fusion guide RNAs that function with both CRISPR-CasRx and hammerhead ribozyme</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36650600/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36650600/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; CRISPR-Cas13 is a newly emerging RNA knockdown technology that is comparable to RNAi. Among all members of Cas13, CasRx degrades RNA in human cells with high precision and effectiveness. However, it remains unclear whether the efficiency of this technology can be further improved and applied to gene therapy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; In this study, we fuse CasRx crRNA with an antisense ribozyme to construct a synthetic fusion guide RNA that can interact with both CasRx protein and ribozyme and tested the ability of this approach in RNA knockdown and cancer gene therapy. We show that the CasRx-crRNA-ribozyme system (CCRS) is more efficient for RNA knockdown of mRNAs and non-coding RNAs than conventional methods, including CasRx, shRNA, and ribozyme. In particular, CCRS is more effective than wild-type CasRx when targeting multiple transcripts simultaneously. We next use bladder cancer as a model to evaluate the anticancer effects of CCRS targeting multiple genes &lt;em&gt;in vitro&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt;. CCRS shows a higher anticancer effect than conventional methods, consistent with the gene knockdown results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions&lt;/em&gt;: Thus, our study demonstrates that CCRS expands the design ideas and RNA knockdown capabilities of Cas13 technology and has the potential to be used in disease treatment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The compact Casπ (Cas12l) &#39;bracelet&#39; provides a unique structural platform for DNA manipulation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36650285/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36650285/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CRISPR-Cas modules serve as the adaptive nucleic acid immune systems for prokaryotes, and provide versatile tools for nucleic acid manipulation in various organisms. Here, we discovered a new miniature type V system, CRISPR-Casπ (Cas12l) (~860 aa), from the environmental metagenome. Complexed with a large guide RNA (~170 nt) comprising the tracrRNA and crRNA, Casπ (Cas12l) recognizes a unique 5&amp;rsquo; C-rich PAM for DNA cleavage under a broad range of biochemical conditions, and generates gene editing in mammalian cells. Cryo-EM study reveals a &amp;lsquo;bracelet&amp;rsquo; architecture of Casπ effector encircling the DNA target at 3.4 Å resolution, substantially different from the canonical &amp;rsquo;two-lobe&amp;rsquo; architectures of Cas12 and Cas9 nucleases. The large guide RNA serves as a &amp;rsquo;two-arm&amp;rsquo; scaffold for effector assembly. Our study expands the knowledge of DNA targeting mechanisms by CRISPR effectors, and offers an efficient but compact platform for DNA manipulation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An evolved AAV variant enables efficient genetic engineering of murine T cells</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36638795/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36638795/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A murine T cell-specific AAV variant, Ark313, is discovered through AAV6 evolution&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A genome-wide CRISPR screen identifies QA2 an essential factor for Ark313 transduction&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ark313 enables efficient transgene delivery and targeting of large DNA payloads&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Trac&lt;/em&gt; targeting of a CAR outperforms semi-random integration in a solid tumor model&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Precise targeting of large transgenes to T cells using homology-directed repair has been transformative for adoptive cell therapies and T cell biology. Delivery of DNA templates via adeno-associated virus (AAV) has greatly improved knockin efficiencies, but the tropism of current AAV serotypes restricts their use to human T cells employed in immunodeficient mouse models. To enable targeted knockins in murine T cells, we evolved Ark313, a synthetic AAV that exhibits high transduction efficiency in murine T cells. We performed a genome-wide knockout screen and identified QA2 as an essential factor for Ark313 infection. We demonstrate that Ark313 can be used for nucleofection-free DNA delivery, CRISPR-Cas9-mediated knockouts, and targeted integration of large transgenes. Ark313 enables preclinical modeling of &lt;em&gt;Trac&lt;/em&gt;-targeted CAR-T and transgenic TCR-T cells in immunocompetent models. Efficient gene targeting in murine T cells holds great potential for improved cell therapies and opens avenues in experimental T cell immunology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Identification of astrocyte regulators by nucleic acid cytometry</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36599367/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36599367/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Multiple sclerosis (MS) is a chronic inflammatory disease of the central nervous system (CNS). Astrocytes are heterogeneous CNS-resident glial cells that participate in the pathogenesis of MS and its model experimental autoimmune encephalomyelitis (EAE). However, few unique surface markers are available for the isolation of astrocyte subsets, preventing their analysis and the identification of candidate therapeutic targets; these limitations are further amplified by the rarity of pathogenic astrocytes. To address these challenges, we developed FIND-seq (&lt;u&gt;F&lt;/u&gt;ocused &lt;u&gt;I&lt;/u&gt;nterrogation of cells by &lt;u&gt;N&lt;/u&gt;ucleic acid &lt;u&gt;D&lt;/u&gt;etection and &lt;u&gt;Seq&lt;/u&gt;uencing), a high-throughput microfluidic cytometry method that combines encapsulation of cells in droplets, PCR-based detection of target nucleic acids, and droplet sorting to enable in-depth transcriptomic analyses of cells of interest at single-cell resolution. We applied FIND-seq to study the regulation of astrocytes characterized by the splicing-driven activation of the transcription factor XBP1, which promotes disease pathology in MS and EAE. Using FIND-seq in combination with conditional knock-out mice, in vivo CRISPR/Cas9-driven genetic perturbation studies, and bulk and single-cell RNA-seq analyses of mouse EAE and human MS samples, we identified a new role for the nuclear receptor NR3C2 and its corepressor NCOR2 in limiting XBP1-driven pathogenic astrocyte responses. In summary, FIND-seq enabled the identification of a therapeutically targetable mechanism that limits XBP1-driven pathogenic astrocyte responses. FIND-seq allows the investigation of previously inaccessible cells, including rare cell subsets defined by unique gene expression signatures or other nucleic acid markers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Staphylococcal virulence factor HlgB targets the endoplasmic-reticulum-resident E3 ubiquitin ligase AMFR to promote pneumonia</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36593296/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36593296/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Staphylococcus aureus&lt;/em&gt; invades cells and persists intracellularly, causing persistent inflammation that is notoriously difficult to treat. Here we investigated host-pathogen interactions underlying intracellular &lt;em&gt;S. aureus&lt;/em&gt; infection in macrophages and discovered that the endoplasmic reticulum (ER) is an important cellular compartment for intracellular &lt;em&gt;S. aureus&lt;/em&gt; infection. Using CRISPR-Cas9 guide RNA library screening, we determined that the autocrine motility factor receptor (AMFR), an ER-resident E3 ubiquitin ligase, played an essential role in mediating intracellular &lt;em&gt;S. aureus&lt;/em&gt;-induced inflammation. AMFR directly interacted with TAK1-binding protein 3 (TAB3) in the ER, inducing K27-linked polyubiquitination of TAB3 on lysine 649 and promoting TAK1 activation. Moreover, the virulence factor γ-haemolysin B (HIgB) of &lt;em&gt;S. aureus&lt;/em&gt; bound to the AMFR and regulated TAB3. Our findings highlight an unknown role of AMFR in intracellular &lt;em&gt;S. aureus&lt;/em&gt; infection-induced pneumonia and suggest that pharmacological interruption of AMFR-mediated TAB3 signalling cascades and HIgB targeting may prevent invasive staphylococci-mediated pneumonia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CRISPR screens for functional interrogation of immunity</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/36481809/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/36481809/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CRISPR-based technologies represent a major breakthrough in biomedical science as they offer a powerful platform for unbiased screening and functional genomics in various fields, including immunology. Pooled and arrayed CRISPR screens have uncovered previously unknown intracellular drivers in innate and adaptive immune cells for immune regulation as well as intercellular regulators mediating cell-cell interactions. Recent single-cell CRISPR screening platforms expand the readouts to the transcriptome and enable the inference of gene regulatory networks for better mechanistic insights. CRISPR screens also allow for mapping of genetic interactions to identify genes that synergize or alleviate complex immune phenotypes. Here, we review the progress in and emerging adaptation of CRISPR technologies to advance our fundamental immunological knowledge and identify novel disease targets for immunotherapy of infection, inflammation and cancer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generation and multiomic profiling of a TP53/CDKN2A double-knockout gastroesophageal junction organoid model</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36449602/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36449602/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inactivation of the tumor suppressor genes tumor protein p53 (&lt;em&gt;TP53&lt;/em&gt;) and cyclin-dependent kinase inhibitor 2A (&lt;em&gt;CDKN2A&lt;/em&gt;) occurs early during gastroesophageal junction (GEJ) tumorigenesis. However, because of a paucity of GEJ-specific disease models, cancer-promoting consequences of &lt;em&gt;TP53&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;CDKN2A&lt;/em&gt; inactivation at the GEJ have not been characterized. Here, we report the development of a wild-type primary human GEJ organoid model and a CRISPR-edited transformed GEJ organoid model. CRISPR-Cas9–mediated &lt;em&gt;TP53&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;CDKN2A&lt;/em&gt; knockout (&lt;em&gt;TP53/CDKN2A&lt;sup&gt;KO&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt;) in GEJ organoids induced morphologic dysplasia and proneoplastic features in vitro and tumor formation in vivo. Lipidomic profiling identified several platelet-activating factors (PTAFs) among the most up-regulated lipids in CRISPR-edited organoids. PTAF/PTAF receptor (PTAFR) abrogation by siRNA knockdown or a pharmacologic inhibitor (WEB2086) reduced proliferation and other proneoplastic features of &lt;em&gt;TP53/CDKN2A&lt;sup&gt;KO&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; GEJ organoids in vitro and tumor formation in vivo. In addition, murine xenografts of Eso26, an established human esophageal adenocarcinoma cell line, were suppressed by WEB2086. Mechanistically, &lt;em&gt;TP53/CDKN2A&lt;/em&gt; dual inactivation disrupted both the transcriptome and the DNA methylome, likely mediated by key transcription factors, particularly forkhead box M1 (FOXM1). FOXM1 activated &lt;em&gt;PTAFR&lt;/em&gt; transcription by binding to the &lt;em&gt;PTAFR&lt;/em&gt; promoter, further amplifying the PTAF-PTAFR pathway. Together, these studies established a robust model system for investigating early GEJ neoplastic events, identified crucial metabolic and epigenomic changes occurring during GEJ model tumorigenesis, and revealed a potential cancer therapeutic strategy. This work provides insights into proneoplastic mechanisms associated with &lt;em&gt;TP53/CDKN2A&lt;/em&gt; inactivation in early GEJ neoplasia, which may facilitate early diagnosis and prevention of GEJ neoplasms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Diverse virus-encoded CRISPR-Cas systems include streamlined genome editors</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36423580/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36423580/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CRISPR pathways encoded in diverse bacteriophage are hypercompact anti-viral systems&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Phage-encoded CRISPR systems encompass all known CRISPR-Cas types&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Casλ enzyme’s compact structure is capable of plant and human cell genome editing&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These findings reveal a new source of CRISPR-Cas enzymes with value as genome editors&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CRISPR-Cas systems are host-encoded pathways that protect microbes from viral infection using an adaptive RNA-guided mechanism. Using genome-resolved metagenomics, we find that CRISPR systems are also encoded in diverse bacteriophages, where they occur as divergent and hypercompact anti-viral systems. Bacteriophage-encoded CRISPR systems belong to all six known CRISPR-Cas types, though some lack crucial components, suggesting alternate functional roles or host complementation. We describe multiple new Cas9-like proteins and 44 families related to type V CRISPR-Cas systems, including the Casλ RNA-guided nuclease family. Among the most divergent of the new enzymes identified, Casλ recognizes double-stranded DNA using a uniquely structured CRISPR RNA (crRNA). The Casλ-RNA-DNA structure determined by cryoelectron microscopy reveals a compact bilobed architecture capable of inducing genome editing in mammalian, Arabidopsis, and hexaploid wheat cells. These findings reveal a new source of CRISPR-Cas enzymes in phages and highlight their value as genome editors in plant and human cells.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GPSAdb: a comprehensive web resource for interactive exploration of genetic perturbation RNA-seq datasets</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36416261/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36416261/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gene knock-out/down methods are commonly used to explore the functions of genes of interest, but a database that systematically collects perturbed data is not available currently. Manual curation of all the available human cell line perturbed RNA-seq datasets enabled us to develop a comprehensive human perturbation database-&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gpsadb.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;GPSAdb&lt;/a&gt;. The current version of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gpsadb.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;GPSAdb&lt;/a&gt; collected 3048 RNA-seq datasets associated with 1458 genes, which were knocked out/down by siRNA, shRNA, CRISPR/Cas9, or CRISPRi. The database provides full exploration of these datasets and generated 6096 new perturbed gene sets (up and down separately). &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gpsadb.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;GPSAdb&lt;/a&gt; integrated the gene sets and developed an online tool, genetic perturbation similarity analysis (GPSA), to identify candidate causal perturbations from differential gene expression data. In summary, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gpsadb.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;GPSAdb&lt;/a&gt; is a powerful platform that aims to assist life science researchers to easily access and analyze public perturbed data and explore differential gene expression data in depth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The phenotypic landscape of essential human genes</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36347254/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36347254/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Image-based pooled screen of 5,072 essential genes reveals multidimensional phenotypes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Phenotypic clustering of cell image parameters defines diverse co-functional genes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Live-cell pooled imaging screen identifies genes required for chromosome segregation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A resource defining the phenotypic consequences of disrupting core cellular processes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Understanding the basis for cellular growth, proliferation, and function requires determining the roles of essential genes in diverse cellular processes, including visualizing their contributions to cellular organization and morphology. Here, we combined pooled CRISPR-Cas9-based functional screening of 5,072 fitness-conferring genes in human HeLa cells with microscopy-based imaging of DNA, the DNA damage response, actin, and microtubules. Analysis of &amp;gt;31 million individual cells identified measurable phenotypes for &amp;gt;90% of gene knockouts, implicating gene targets in specific cellular processes. Clustering of phenotypic similarities based on hundreds of quantitative parameters further revealed co-functional genes across diverse cellular activities, providing predictions for gene functions and associations. By conducting pooled live-cell screening of ∼450,000 cell division events for 239 genes, we additionally identified diverse genes with functional contributions to chromosome segregation. Our work establishes a resource detailing the consequences of disrupting core cellular processes that represents the functional landscape of essential human genes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cellular glycan modification by B3GAT1 broadly restricts influenza virus infection</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36309510/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36309510/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Communicable respiratory viral infections pose both epidemic and pandemic threats and broad-spectrum antiviral strategies could improve preparedness for these events. To discover host antiviral restriction factors that may act as suitable targets for the development of host-directed antiviral therapies, we here conduct a whole-genome CRISPR activation screen with influenza B virus (IBV). A top hit from our screen, beta-1,3-glucuronyltransferase 1 (B3GAT1), effectively blocks IBV infection. Subsequent studies reveal that B3GAT1 activity prevents cell surface sialic acid expression. Due to this mechanism of action, B3GAT1 expression broadly restricts infection with viruses that require sialic acid for entry, including Victoria and Yamagata lineage IBVs, H1N1/H3N2 influenza A viruses (IAVs), and the unrelated enterovirus D68. To understand the potential utility of B3GAT1 induction as an antiviral strategy in vivo, we specifically express B3GAT1 in the murine respiratory epithelium and find that overexpression is not only well-tolerated, but also protects female mice from a lethal viral challenge with multiple influenza viruses, including a pandemic-like H1N1 IAV. Thus, B3GAT1 may represent a host-directed broad-spectrum antiviral target with utility against clinically relevant respiratory viruses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A novel protein RASON encoded by a lncRNA controls oncogenic RAS signaling in KRAS mutant cancers</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36241718/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36241718/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mutations of the RAS oncogene are found in around 30% of all human cancers yet direct targeting of RAS is still considered clinically impractical except for the KRAS&lt;sup&gt;G12C&lt;/sup&gt; mutant. Here we report that RAS-ON (RASON), a novel protein encoded by the long intergenic non-protein coding RNA 00673 (&lt;em&gt;LINC00673&lt;/em&gt;), is a positive regulator of oncogenic RAS signaling. RASON is aberrantly overexpressed in pancreatic ductal adenocarcinoma (PDAC) patients, and it promotes proliferation of human PDAC cell lines &lt;em&gt;in vitro&lt;/em&gt; and tumor growth &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt;. CRISPR/Cas9-mediated knockout of &lt;em&gt;Rason&lt;/em&gt; in mouse embryonic fibroblasts inhibits KRAS-mediated tumor transformation. Genetic deletion of &lt;em&gt;Rason&lt;/em&gt; abolishes oncogenic KRAS-driven pancreatic and lung cancer tumorigenesis in &lt;em&gt;LSL-Kras&lt;sup&gt;G12D&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt;; &lt;em&gt;Trp53&lt;sup&gt;R172H/+&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; mice. Mechanistically, RASON directly binds to KRAS&lt;sup&gt;G12D/V&lt;/sup&gt; and inhibits both intrinsic and GTPase activating protein (GAP)-mediated GTP hydrolysis, thus sustaining KRAS&lt;sup&gt;G12D/V&lt;/sup&gt; in the GTP-bound hyperactive state. Therapeutically, deprivation of RASON sensitizes KRAS mutant pancreatic cancer cells and patient-derived organoids to EGFR inhibitors. Our findings identify RASON as a critical regulator of oncogenic KRAS signaling and a promising therapeutic target for KRAS mutant cancers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Precise DNA cleavage using CRISPR-SpRYgests</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36203014/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36203014/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Methods for in vitro DNA cleavage and molecular cloning remain unable to precisely cleave DNA directly adjacent to bases of interest. Restriction enzymes (REs) must bind specific motifs, whereas wild-type CRISPR–Cas9 or CRISPR–Cas12 nucleases require protospacer adjacent motifs (PAMs). Here we explore the utility of our previously reported near-PAMless SpCas9 variant, named SpRY, to serve as a universal DNA cleavage tool for various cloning applications. By performing SpRY DNA digests (SpRYgests) using more than 130 guide RNAs (gRNAs) sampling a wide diversity of PAMs, we discovered that SpRY is PAMless in vitro and can cleave DNA at practically any sequence, including sites refractory to cleavage with wild-type SpCas9. We illustrate the versatility and effectiveness of SpRYgests to improve the precision of several cloning workflows, including those not possible with REs or canonical CRISPR nucleases. We also optimize a rapid and simple one-pot gRNA synthesis protocol to streamline SpRYgest implementation. Together, SpRYgests can improve various DNA engineering applications that benefit from precise DNA breaks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inhibition of the CtBP complex and FBXO11 enhances MHC class II expression and anti-cancer immune responses</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36179686/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36179686/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The CtBP complex transcriptionally represses MHC class II pathway genes in AML&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;FBXO11 restricts MHC class II expression by targeting CIITA for degradation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Restoring MHC class II expression on leukemic blasts stimulates CD4+ T cell responses&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Inducing tumor cell MHC class II may enhance alloSCT and immunotherapy outcomes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is increasing recognition of the prognostic significance of tumor cell major histocompatibility complex (MHC) class II expression in anti-cancer immunity. Relapse of acute myeloid leukemia (AML) following allogeneic stem cell transplantation (alloSCT) has recently been linked to MHC class II silencing in leukemic blasts; however, the regulation of MHC class II expression remains incompletely understood. Utilizing unbiased CRISPR-Cas9 screens, we identify that the C-terminal binding protein (CtBP) complex transcriptionally represses MHC class II pathway genes, while the E3 ubiquitin ligase complex component FBXO11 mediates degradation of CIITA, the principal transcription factor regulating MHC class II expression. Targeting these repressive mechanisms selectively induces MHC class II upregulation across a range of AML cell lines. Functionally, MHC class II+ leukemic blasts stimulate antigen-dependent CD4&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T cell activation and potent anti-tumor immune responses, providing fundamental insights into the graft-versus-leukemia effect. These findings establish the rationale for therapeutic strategies aimed at restoring tumor-specific MHC class II expression to salvage AML relapse post-alloSCT and also potentially to enhance immunotherapy outcomes in non-myeloid malignancies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guide RNA engineering enables efficient CRISPR editing with a miniature Syntrophomonas palmitatica Cas12f1 nuclease</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36170834/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36170834/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gene therapy is limited by inefficient delivery of large clustered regularly interspaced short palindromic repeat (CRISPR) effectors, such as Cas9 and Cas12a nucleases. Cas12f nucleases are currently one of the most compact CRISPR genome editors. However, the available toolkit of efficient Cas12f editors is limited. Here, we report the characterization and engineering of a miniature CRISPR-Cas12f system from Syntrophomonas palmitatica (SpaCas12f1, 497 amino acids). We show that CRISPR-SpaCas12f1 cleaves double-stranded DNA (dsDNA) with 5&amp;rsquo; T-rich PAM specificity and is naturally active for genome editing in bacteria. We identify that CRISPR-SpaCas12f1 trans-activating CRISPR RNA (tracrRNA) harbors a unique head-to-toe hairpin structure, and the natural hairpin structure is a key factor in restricting genome editing by SpaCas12f1 in human cells. Systematical engineering of SpaCas12f1 guide RNA transforms CRISPR-SpaCas12f1 into an efficient genome editor comparable to Francisella novicida CRISPR-Cas12a. Our findings expand the mini CRISPR toolbox, paving the way for therapeutic applications of CRISPR-SpaCas12f1 and engineering compact genome manipulation technologies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In vivo CRISPR screens reveal the landscape of immune evasion pathways across cancer</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36151395/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36151395/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The immune system can eliminate tumors, but checkpoints enable immune escape. Here, we identify immune evasion mechanisms using genome-scale in vivo CRISPR screens across cancer models treated with immune checkpoint blockade (ICB). We identify immune evasion genes and important immune inhibitory checkpoints conserved across cancers, including the non-classical major histocompatibility complex class I (MHC class I) molecule Qa-1&lt;sup&gt;b&lt;/sup&gt;/HLA-E. Surprisingly, loss of tumor interferon-γ (IFNγ) signaling sensitizes many models to immunity. The immune inhibitory effects of tumor IFN sensing are mediated through two mechanisms. First, tumor upregulation of classical MHC class I inhibits natural killer cells. Second, IFN-induced expression of Qa-1&lt;sup&gt;b&lt;/sup&gt; inhibits CD8&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T cells via the NKG2A/CD94 receptor, which is induced by ICB. Finally, we show that strong IFN signatures are associated with poor response to ICB in individuals with renal cell carcinoma or melanoma. This study reveals that IFN-mediated upregulation of classical and non-classical MHC class I inhibitory checkpoints can facilitate immune escape.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Viral protease cleavage of MAVS in genetically modified mice with hepatitis A virus infection</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36152761/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36152761/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background &amp;amp; aims:&lt;/em&gt; Consistent with its relatively narrow host species range, hepatitis A virus (HAV) cannot infect C57BL/6 mice. However, in &lt;em&gt;Mavs&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; mice with genetic deficiency of the innate immune signaling adaptor MAVS, HAV replicates robustly in the absence of disease. The HAV 3ABC protease cleaves MAVS in human cells, thereby disrupting virus-induced IFN responses, but it cannot cleave murine MAVS (mMAVS) due to sequence differences at the site of scission. Here, we sought to elucidate the role of 3ABC MAVS cleavage in determining HAV pathogenesis and host species range.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; Using CRISPR/Cas9 gene editing, we established two independent lineages of C57BL/6 mice with knock-in mutations altering two amino acids in mMAVS (&amp;lsquo;mMAVS-VS&amp;rsquo;), rendering it susceptible to 3ABC cleavage without loss of signaling function. We challenged homozygous &lt;em&gt;Mavs&lt;sup&gt;vs/vs&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; mice with HAV, and compared infection outcomes with C57BL/6 and genetically deficient &lt;em&gt;Mavs&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; mice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; The humanized murine mMAVS-VS protein was cleaved as efficiently as human MAVS when co-expressed with 3ABC in Huh-7 cells. In embyronic fibroblasts from &lt;em&gt;Mavs&lt;sup&gt;vs/vs&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; mice, mMAVS-VS was cleaved by ectopically expressed 3ABC, significantly disrupting Sendai virus-induced IFN responses. However, in contrast to &lt;em&gt;Mavs&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; mice with genetic MAVS deficiency, HAV failed to establish infection in &lt;em&gt;Mavs&lt;sup&gt;vs/vs&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; mice, even with additional genetic knockout of &lt;em&gt;Trif&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;Irf1&lt;/em&gt;. Nonetheless, when crossed with permissive &lt;em&gt;Ifnar1&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; mice lacking type I IFN receptors, &lt;em&gt;Mavs&lt;sup&gt;vs/vs&lt;/sup&gt;Ifnar1&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; mice demonstrated enhanced viral replication coupled with significant reductions in serum alanine aminotransferase, hepatocellular apoptosis, and intrahepatic inflammatory cell infiltrates compared with &lt;em&gt;Ifnar1&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; mice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; MAVS cleavage by 3ABC boosts viral replication and disrupts disease pathogenesis, but it is not by itself sufficient to break the host-species barrier to HAV infection in mice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Impact and implications:&lt;/em&gt; The limited host range of human hepatitis viruses could be explained by species-specific viral strategies that disrupt innate immune responses. Both hepatitis A virus (HAV) and hepatitis C virus express viral proteases that cleave the innate immune adaptor protein MAVS, in human but not mouse cells. However, the impact of this immune evasion strategy has never been assessed in vivo. Here we show that HAV 3ABC protease cleavage of MAVS enhances viral replication and lessens liver inflammation in mice lacking interferon receptors, but that it is insufficient by itself to overcome the cross-species barrier to infection in mice. These results enhance our understanding of how hepatitis viruses interact with the host and their impact on innate immune responses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exosome-mediated delivery of Cas9 ribonucleoprotein complexes for tissue-specific gene therapy of liver diseases</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36103526/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36103526/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CRISPR-Cas9 gene editing has emerged as a powerful therapeutic technology, but the lack of safe and efficient in vivo delivery systems, especially for tissue-specific vectors, limits its broad clinical applications. Delivery of Cas9 ribonucleoprotein (RNP) owns competitive advantages over other options; however, the large size of RNPs exceeds the loading capacity of currently available delivery vectors. Here, we report a previously unidentified genome editing delivery system, named exosome&lt;sup&gt;RNP&lt;/sup&gt;, in which Cas9 RNPs were loaded into purified exosomes isolated from hepatic stellate cells through electroporation. Exosome&lt;sup&gt;RNP&lt;/sup&gt; facilitated effective cytosolic delivery of RNP in vitro while specifically accumulated in the liver tissue in vivo. Exosome&lt;sup&gt;RNP&lt;/sup&gt; showed vigorous therapeutic potential in acute liver injury, chronic liver fibrosis, and hepatocellular carcinoma mouse models via targeting p53 up-regulated modulator of apoptosis (&lt;em&gt;PUMA&lt;/em&gt;), cyclin E1 (&lt;em&gt;CcnE1&lt;/em&gt;), and K (lysine) acetyltransferase 5 (&lt;em&gt;KAT5&lt;/em&gt;), respectively. The developed exosomeRNP provides a feasible platform for precise and tissue-specific gene therapies of liver diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Knockout of the Circadian Clock Protein PER1 (Period1) Exacerbates Hypertension and Increases Kidney Injury in Dahl Salt-Sensitive Rats</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36093781/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36093781/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Circadian rhythms play an essential role in physiological function. The molecular clock that underlies circadian physiological function consists of a core group of transcription factors, including the protein PER1 (Period1). Studies in mice show that PER1 plays a role in the regulation of blood pressure and renal sodium handling; however, the results are dependent on the strain being studied. Using male Dahl salt-sensitive (SS) rats with global knockout of PER1 (&lt;em&gt;SS&lt;sup&gt;Per1-/-&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt;), we aim to test the hypothesis that PER1 plays a key role in the regulation of salt-sensitive blood pressure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; The model was generated using CRISPR/Cas9 and was characterized using radiotelemetry and measures of renal function and circadian rhythm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;SS&lt;sup&gt;Per1-/-&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; rats had similar mean arterial pressure when fed a normal 0.4% NaCl diet but developed augmented hypertension after three weeks on a high-salt (4% NaCl) diet. Despite being maintained on a normal 12:12 light:dark cycle, &lt;em&gt;SS&lt;sup&gt;Per1-/-&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; rats exhibited desynchrony mean arterial pressure rhythms on a high-salt diet, as evidenced by increased variability in the time of peak mean arterial pressure. &lt;em&gt;SS&lt;sup&gt;Per1-/-&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; rats excrete less sodium after three weeks on the high-salt diet. Furthermore, &lt;em&gt;SS&lt;sup&gt;Per1-/-&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; rats exhibited decreased creatinine clearance, a measurement of renal function, as well as increased signs of kidney tissue damage. &lt;em&gt;SS&lt;sup&gt;Per1-/-&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; rats also exhibited higher plasma aldosterone levels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; Altogether, our findings demonstrate that loss of PER1 in Dahl SS rats causes an array of deleterious effects, including exacerbation of the development of salt-sensitive hypertension and renal damage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Activation of long non-coding RNA NEAT1 leads to survival advantage of multiple myeloma cells by supporting a positive regulatory loop with DNA repair proteins</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36073514/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36073514/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Long non-coding RNA NEAT1 is the core structural component of the nuclear paraspeckle (PS) organelles and it has been found to be deregulated in multiple myeloma (MM) patients. Experimental evidence indicated that NEAT1 silencing negatively impacts proliferation and viability of MM cells, both in vitro and in vivo, suggesting a role in DNA damage repair (DDR). In order to elucidate the biological and molecular relevance of NEAT1 upregulation in MM disease we exploited the CRISPR/Cas9 synergistic activation mediator genome editing system to engineer the AMO-1 MM cell line and generate two clones that para-physiologically transactivate NEAT1 at different levels. NEAT1 overexpression is associated with oncogenic and prosurvival advantages in MM cells exposed to nutrient starvation or a hypoxic microenvironment, which are stressful conditions often associated with more aggressive disease phases. Furthermore, we highlighted the NEAT1 involvement in virtually all DDR processes through, at least, two different mechanisms. On one side NEAT1 positively regulates the posttranslational stabilization of essential PS proteins, which are involved in almost all DDR systems, thus increasing their availability within cells. On the other hand, NEAT1 plays a crucial role as a major regulator of a molecular axis that includes ATM and the catalytic subunit of DNA-PK kinase proteins, and their direct targets pRPA32 and pCHK2. Overall, we provided novel important insightsthe role of NEAT1 in supporting MM cells adaptation to stressful conditions by improving the maintenance of DNA integrity. Taken together, our results suggest that NEAT1, and probably PS organelles, could represent a potential therapeutic target for MM treatment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tetrahedral DNA framework based CRISPR electrochemical biosensor for amplification-free miRNA detection</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36122469/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36122469/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;microRNA (miRNA) is a kind of small non-coding RNA that has been regarded as potential biomarkers for cancers. Sensitive and specific detection of miRNA at low expression levels is highly desirable but remains challenging, especially for amplification-free and portable point of care (POC) diagnostics. The clustered regularly interspaced short palindromic repeats (CRISPR)/Cas13a has been recently discovered and used in the field of RNA detection. Nonetheless, most CRISPR/Cas13a-based methods were burdened with expensive equipment, time-consuming procedures, and complicated operations which were not suitable for POC analysis. In this work, we constructed a three-dimensional tetrahedral DNA framework based CRISPR-electrochemical biosensor (CRISPR-E). By combining tetrahedral DNA framework, CRISPR, and electrochemical biosensor, the process of activation, cleavage of Cas13a, and signal readout were all finished on the chip, and a simple, amplification-free and sensitive detection of miRNA-19b was realized. Under the optimal experimental conditions, a linear range from 10 pM to 104 pM with detection limit of 10 pM for miRNA-19b in buffer solution was achieved. Selectivity analysis indicated that our CRISPR-E had good distinguishing ability between miRNA-19b and miRNA-197. The results of miRNA-19b detection in mimic serum samples were consistent with that of the buffer solution. This all-on-chip strategy of our CRISPR-E is very suitable for POC testing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The retroelement Lx9 puts a brake on the immune response to virus infection</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35948641/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35948641/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The notion that mobile units of nucleic acid known as transposable elements can operate as genomic controlling elements was put forward over six decades ago. However, it was not until the advancement of genomic sequencing technologies that the abundance and repertoire of transposable elements were revealed, and they are now known to constitute up to two-thirds of mammalian genomes. The presence of DNA regulatory regions including promoters, enhancers and transcription-factor-binding sites within transposable elements has led to the hypothesis that transposable elements have been co-opted to regulate mammalian gene expression and cell phenotype. Mammalian transposable elements include recent acquisitions and ancient transposable elements that have been maintained in the genome over evolutionary time. The presence of ancient conserved transposable elements correlates positively with the likelihood of a regulatory function, but functional validation remains an essential step to identify transposable element insertions that have a positive effect on fitness. Here we show that CRISPR-Cas9-mediated deletion of a transposable element-namely the LINE-1 retrotransposon Lx9c11-in mice results in an exaggerated and lethal immune response to virus infection. Lx9c11 is critical for the neogenesis of a non-coding RNA (Lx9c11-RegoS) that regulates genes of the Schlafen family, reduces the hyperinflammatory phenotype and rescues lethality in virus-infected Lx9c11-/- mice. These findings provide evidence that a transposable element can control the immune system to favour host survival during virus infection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In Vivo Genome-Wide CRISPR Activation Screening Identifies Functionally Important Long Noncoding RNAs in Hepatocellular Carcinoma</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35944892/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35944892/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background &amp;amp; aims:&lt;/em&gt; Long noncoding RNAs (lncRNAs) are found to have profound impacts on diverse cellular processes. Although high-throughput sequencing studies have shown the differential lncRNA expression profiles between hepatocellular carcinoma (HCC) and nontumor livers, the functional impacts of lncRNAs on HCC development await further investigation. Herein, we sought to address the functional roles of lncRNAs in HCC pathogenesis by in vivo functional screening.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; We performed genome-wide clustered regularly interspaced short palindromic repeats (CRISPR)/dead CRISPR-associated protein 9 (dCas9) lncRNA activation screening in HCC xenografts. We characterized the clinical relevance of positively selected lncRNAs using transcriptomic data sets. We used CRISPR-based gene activation and knockdown approaches to show the functional roles of positively selected lncRNAs including Cancer Susceptibility 11 (CASC11) in HCC. RNA sequencing and chromatin isolation by RNA purification sequencing were used to investigate the molecular mechanisms of CASC11 in HCC progression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; The in vivo functional screening identified 1603 positively selected lncRNAs, 538 of which were overexpressed in HCC patients. Systematic transcriptomic data analysis and clinical investigation showed that patients with high expression of these lncRNA candidates correlated with aggressive tumor behaviors. Overexpression of these lncRNAs aggravated HCC cell growth. Detailed characterization of a lncRNA candidate, CASC11, showed its pivotal role in cell proliferation and tumor growth. Mechanistically, chromatin isolation by RNA purification sequencing showed that CASC11 was bound to the CASC11/MYC proto-oncogene shared promoter region on chromosome 8q24. CASC11 modulated the transcriptional activity of MYC in a cis-regulatory manner, which affected the expression of MYC downstream target genes, consequently promoting G1/S progression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; Our study showed the power of in vivo CRISPR screening, which comprehensively investigated the functionality of lncRNAs in HCC progression, providing a rationale for targeting these lncRNAs clinically.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nanozyme-catalysed CRISPR assay for preamplification-free detection of non-coding RNAs</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35927321/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35927321/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CRISPR-based diagnostics enable specific sensing of DNA and RNA biomarkers associated with human diseases. This is achieved through the binding of guide RNAs to a complementary sequence that activates Cas enzymes to cleave reporter molecules. Currently, most CRISPR-based diagnostics rely on target preamplification to reach sufficient sensitivity for clinical applications. This limits quantification capability and adds complexity to the reaction chemistry. Here we show the combination of a CRISPR-Cas-based reaction with a nanozyme-linked immunosorbent assay, which allows for the quantitative and colorimetric readout of Cas13-mediated RNA detection through catalytic metallic nanoparticles at room temperature (CrisprZyme). We demonstrate that CrisprZyme is easily adaptable to a lateral-flow-based readout and different Cas enzymes and enables the sensing of non-coding RNAs including microRNAs, long non-coding RNAs and circular RNAs. We utilize this platform to identify patients with acute myocardial infarction and to monitor cellular differentiation in vitro and in tissue biopsies from prostate cancer patients. We anticipate that CrisprZyme will serve as a universally applicable signal catalyst for CRISPR-based diagnostics, which will expand the spectrum of targets for preamplification-free, quantitative detection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Screening circular RNAs with functional potential using the RfxCas13d/BSJ-gRNA system</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35831613/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35831613/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Circular RNAs (circRNAs) are covalently enclosed, single-stranded RNAs produced by back-splicing of pre-mRNA exons that have recently emerged as an important class of molecules in gene expression regulation. circRNAs share overlapping sequences with their cognate linear mRNAs except the back-splicing junction (BSJ) sites. This feature makes it difficult to discriminate between the functions of circRNAs and their cognate mRNAs. We previously reported that the programmable RNA-guided, RNA-targeting CRISPR-Cas13 (RfxCas13d) system effectively and specifically discriminates circRNAs from mRNAs by using guide RNAs (gRNAs) targeting sequences across BSJ sites. Here, we describe a detailed protocol based on this RfxCas13d/BSJ-gRNA system for large-scale functional circRNA screening in human cell lines. The protocol includes gRNA library design, construction and transduction, analysis of screening results and validation of functional circRNA candidates. In total, it takes ~3-4 months of collaborative work between a well-trained molecular biologist and a bioinformatic expert. This protocol can be applied both in cells and in vivo to identify highly expressed circRNAs affecting cell growth, either in unperturbed conditions or under environmental stimulation, without disturbing their cognate linear mRNAs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fast and sensitive detection of SARS-CoV-2 RNA using suboptimal protospacer adjacent motifs for Cas12a</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35314803/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35314803/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CRISPR-based assays for the detection of nucleic acids are highly specific, yet they are not fast, sensitive or easy to use. Here we report a one-step fluorescence assay for the detection of severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 (SARS-CoV-2) RNA in nasopharyngeal samples, with a sample-to-answer time of less than 20 minutes and a sensitivity comparable to that of quantitative real-time PCR with reverse transcription (RT-qPCR). The assay uses suboptimal protospacer adjacent motifs, allowing for flexibility in the design of CRISPR RNAs and slowing down the kinetics of Cas12a-mediated collateral cleavage of fluorescent DNA reporters and cis cleavage of substrates, which leads to stronger fluorescence owing to the accumulation of amplicons generated by isothermal recombinase polymerase amplification. In a set of 204 nasopharyngeal samples with RT-qPCR cycle thresholds ranging from 18.1 to 35.8, the assay detected SARS-CoV-2 with a sensitivity of 94.2% and a specificity of 100%, without the need for RNA extraction. Rapid and sensitive assays for nucleic acid testing in one pot that allow for flexibility in assay design may aid the development of reliable point-of-care nucleic acid testing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Copper induces cell death by targeting lipoylated TCA cycle proteins</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35298263/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35298263/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Erratum in:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.abq4855&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Copper induces cell death by targeting lipoylated TCA cycle proteins&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Copper is an essential cofactor for all organisms, and yet it becomes toxic if concentrations exceed a threshold maintained by evolutionarily conserved homeostatic mechanisms. How excess copper induces cell death, however, is unknown. Here, we show in human cells that copper-dependent, regulated cell death is distinct from known death mechanisms and is dependent on mitochondrial respiration. We show that copper-dependent death occurs by means of direct binding of copper to lipoylated components of the tricarboxylic acid (TCA) cycle. This results in lipoylated protein aggregation and subsequent iron-sulfur cluster protein loss, which leads to proteotoxic stress and ultimately cell death. These findings may explain the need for ancient copper homeostatic mechanisms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Copper induces cell death&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cell death is an essential, finely tuned process that is critical for the removal of damaged and superfluous cells. Multiple forms of programmed and nonprogrammed cell death have been identified, including apoptosis, ferroptosis, and necroptosis. Tsvetkov et al. investigated whether abnormal copper ion elevations may sensitize cells toward a previously unidentified death pathway (see the Perspective by Kahlson and Dixon). By performing CRISPR/Cas9 screens, several genes were identified that could protect against copper-induced cell killing. Using genetically modified cells and a mouse model of a copper overload disorder, the researchers report that excess copper promotes the aggregation of lipoylated proteins and links mitochondrial metabolism to copper-dependent death.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Genome-wide screens identify specific drivers of mutant hTERT promoters</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35027447/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35027447/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Significance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mutations in &lt;em&gt;hTERT&lt;/em&gt; promoter are seen in over 19% of human cancers, irrespective of the cancer type. Understanding the molecular players that regulate Mut-&lt;em&gt;hTERT&lt;/em&gt; promoters may help the design of effective targeting strategies to inhibit telomerase reactivation specifically in cancer cells. Our work uses genome-wide functional screens to identify 30 specific regulators of Mut-&lt;em&gt;hTERT&lt;/em&gt; promoters. These candidates identified from the screening serve as an excellent resource to understand how telomerase is reactivated and as targets for making inhibitors to telomerase, a key driver of cancer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cancer-specific &lt;em&gt;hTERT&lt;/em&gt; promoter mutations reported in 19% of cancers result in enhanced telomerase activity. Understanding the distinctions between transcriptional regulation of wild-type (WT) and mutant (Mut) &lt;em&gt;hTERT&lt;/em&gt; promoters may open up avenues for development of inhibitors which specially block &lt;em&gt;hTERT&lt;/em&gt; expression in cancer cells. To comprehensively identify physiological regulators of WT- or Mut-&lt;em&gt;hTERT&lt;/em&gt; promoters, we generated several isogenic reporter cells driven by endogenous &lt;em&gt;hTERT&lt;/em&gt; loci. Genome-wide CRISPR-Cas9 and small interfering RNA screens using these isogenic reporter lines identified specific regulators of Mut-&lt;em&gt;hTERT&lt;/em&gt; promoters. We validate and characterize one of these hits, namely, MED12, a kinase subunit of mediator complex. We demonstrate that MED12 specifically drives expression of &lt;em&gt;hTERT&lt;/em&gt; from the Mut-&lt;em&gt;hTERT&lt;/em&gt; promoter by mediating long-range chromatin interaction between the proximal Mut-&lt;em&gt;hTERT&lt;/em&gt; promoter and &lt;em&gt;T-INT1&lt;/em&gt; distal regulatory region 260 kb upstream. Several hits identified in our screens could serve as potential therapeutic targets, inhibition of which may specifically block Mut-&lt;em&gt;hTERT&lt;/em&gt; promoter driven telomerase reactivation in cancers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Genome-wide CRISPRi/a screens in human neurons link lysosomal failure to ferroptosis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34031600/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34031600/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Single-cell transcriptomics provide a systematic map of gene expression in different human cell types. The next challenge is to systematically understand cell-type-specific gene function. The integration of CRISPR-based functional genomics and stem cell technology enables the scalable interrogation of gene function in differentiated human cells. Here we present the first genome-wide CRISPR interference and CRISPR activation screens in human neurons. We uncover pathways controlling neuronal response to chronic oxidative stress, which is implicated in neurodegenerative diseases. Unexpectedly, knockdown of the lysosomal protein prosaposin strongly sensitizes neurons, but not other cell types, to oxidative stress by triggering the formation of lipofuscin, a hallmark of aging, which traps iron, generating reactive oxygen species and triggering ferroptosis. We also determine transcriptomic changes in neurons after perturbation of genes linked to neurodegenerative diseases. To enable the systematic comparison of gene function across different human cell types, we establish a data commons named &lt;a href=&#34;https://crisprbrain.org&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CRISPRbrain&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://crisprbrain.org&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CRISPRbrain&lt;/a&gt; is a data commons organizing results from genetic screens for different phenotypes in different human cell types, by different research groups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A genome-wide CRISPR screen identifies UFMylation and TRAMP-like complexes as host factors required for hepatitis A virus infection</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33730579/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33730579/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A genome-wide CRISPR screen identifies host factors important for hepatitis A virus&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;UFMylation of the ribosomal protein RPL26 enhances viral translation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PAPD5/7-ZCCHC14 TRAMP-like complexes are important for hepatitis A virus&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pharmacological inhibition of PAPD5/7 reduces hepatitis A virus replication&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Summary&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hepatitis A virus (HAV) is a positive-sense RNA virus causing acute inflammation of the liver. Here, using a genome-scale CRISPR screen, we provide a comprehensive picture of the cellular factors that are exploited by HAV. We identify genes involved in sialic acid/ganglioside biosynthesis and members of the eukaryotic translation initiation factor complex, corroborating their putative roles for HAV. Additionally, we uncover all components of the cellular machinery for UFMylation, a ubiquitin-like protein modification. We show that HAV translation specifically depends on UFM1 conjugation of the ribosomal protein RPL26. Furthermore, we find that components related to the yeast Trf4/5-Air1/2-Mtr4 polyadenylation (TRAMP) complex are required for viral translation independent of controlling viral poly(A) tails or RNA stability. Finally, we demonstrate that pharmacological inhibition of the TRAMP-like complex decreases HAV replication in hepatocyte cells and human liver organoids, thus providing a strategy for host-directed therapy of HAV infection&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>High-throughput functional variant screens via in vivo production of single-stranded DNA</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33906944/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33906944/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Creating and characterizing individual genetic variants remains limited in scale, compared to the tremendous variation both existing in nature and envisioned by genome engineers. Here we introduce retron library recombineering (RLR), a methodology for high-throughput functional screens that surpasses the scale and specificity of CRISPR-Cas methods. We use the targeted reverse-transcription activity of retrons to produce single-stranded DNA (ssDNA) in vivo, incorporating edits at &amp;gt;90% efficiency and enabling multiplexed applications. RLR simultaneously introduces many genomic variants, producing pooled and barcoded variant libraries addressable by targeted deep sequencing. We use RLR for pooled phenotyping of synthesized antibiotic resistance alleles, demonstrating quantitative measurement of relative growth rates. We also perform RLR using the sheared genomic DNA of an evolved bacterium, experimentally querying millions of sequences for causal variants, demonstrating that RLR is uniquely suited to utilize large pools of natural variation. Using ssDNA produced in vivo for pooled experiments presents avenues for exploring variation across the genome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Significance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We report a methodology for the pooled construction of mutants bearing precise genomic sequence variations and multiplex phenotypic characterization of these mutants using next-generation sequencing (NGS). Unlike existing techniques depending on CRISPR-Cas–directed genomic breaks for genome editing, this strategy instead uses single-stranded DNA produced by a retron element for recombineering. This enables libraries of millions of elements to be constructed and offers relaxed design constraints which permit natural DNA or random variation to be used as inputs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Screening for functional circular RNAs using the CRISPR-Cas13 system</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33288960/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33288960/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Circular RNAs (circRNAs) produced from back-spliced exons are widely expressed, but individual circRNA functions remain poorly understood owing to the lack of adequate methods for distinguishing circRNAs from cognate messenger RNAs with overlapping exons. Here, we report that CRISPR-RfxCas13d can effectively discriminate circRNAs from mRNAs by using guide RNAs targeting sequences spanning back-splicing junction (BSJ) sites featured in RNA circles. Using a lentiviral library that targets sequences across BSJ sites of highly expressed human circRNAs, we show that a group of circRNAs are important for cell growth mostly in a cell-type-specific manner and that a common oncogenic circRNA, circFAM120A, promotes cell proliferation by preventing the mRNA for family with sequence similarity 120A (FAM120A) from binding the translation inhibitor IGF2BP2. Further application of RfxCas13d-BSJ-gRNA screening has uncovered circMan1a2, which has regulatory potential in mouse embryo preimplantation development. Together, these results establish CRISPR-RfxCas13d as a useful tool for the discovery and functional study of circRNAs at both individual and large-scale levels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Genome-wide ER-phagy Screen Highlights Key Roles of Mitochondrial Metabolism and ER-Resident UFMylation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32160526/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32160526/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Selective autophagy of organelles is critical for cellular differentiation, homeostasis, and organismal health. Autophagy of the ER (ER-phagy) is implicated in human neuropathy but is poorly understood beyond a few autophagosomal receptors and remodelers. By using an ER-phagy reporter and genome-wide CRISPRi screening, we identified 200 high-confidence human ER-phagy factors. Two pathways were unexpectedly required for ER-phagy. First, reduced mitochondrial metabolism represses ER-phagy, which is opposite of general autophagy and is independent of AMPK. Second, ER-localized UFMylation is required for ER-phagy to repress the unfolded protein response via IRE1α. The UFL1 ligase is brought to the ER surface by DDRGK1 to UFMylate RPN1 and RPL26 and preferentially targets ER sheets for degradation, analogous to PINK1-Parkin regulation during mitophagy. Our data provide insight into the cellular logic of ER-phagy, reveal parallels between organelle autophagies, and provide an entry point to the relatively unexplored process of degrading the ER network.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A bacteriophage nucleus-like compartment shields DNA from CRISPR nucleases</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/31819262/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/31819262/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All viruses require strategies to inhibit or evade the immune pathways of cells that they infect. The viruses that infect bacteria, bacteriophages (phages), must avoid immune pathways that target nucleic acids, such as CRISPR-Cas and restriction-modification systems, to replicate efficiently1. Here we show that jumbo phage ΦKZ segregates its DNA from immunity nucleases of its host, &lt;em&gt;Pseudomonas aeruginosa&lt;/em&gt;, by constructing a proteinaceous nucleus-like compartment. ΦKZ is resistant to many immunity mechanisms that target DNA &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt;, including two subtypes of CRISPR-Cas3, Cas9, Cas12a and the restriction enzymes HsdRMS and EcoRI. Cas proteins and restriction enzymes are unable to access the phage DNA throughout the infection, but engineering the relocalization of EcoRI inside the compartment enables targeting of the phage and protection of host cells. Moreover, ΦKZ is sensitive to Cas13a-a CRISPR-Cas enzyme that targets RNA-probably owing to phage mRNA localizing to the cytoplasm. Collectively, we propose that Pseudomonas jumbo phages evade a broad spectrum of DNA-targeting nucleases through the assembly of a protein barrier around their genome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A genome-wide long noncoding RNA CRISPRi screen identifies PRANCR as a novel regulator of epidermal homeostasis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/31804951/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/31804951/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Genome-wide association studies indicate that many disease susceptibility regions reside in non-protein-coding regions of the genome. Long noncoding RNAs (lncRNAs) are a major component of the noncoding genome, but their biological impacts are not fully understood. Here, we performed a CRISPR interference (CRISPRi) screen on 2263 epidermis-expressed lncRNAs and identified nine novel candidate lncRNAs regulating keratinocyte proliferation. We further characterized a top hit from the screen, progenitor renewal associated non-coding RNA (&lt;em&gt;PRANCR&lt;/em&gt;), using RNA interference-mediated knockdown and phenotypic analysis in organotypic human tissue. PRANCR regulates keratinocyte proliferation, cell cycle progression, and clonogenicity. &lt;em&gt;PRANCR&lt;/em&gt;-deficient epidermis displayed impaired stratification with reduced expression of differentiation genes that are altered in human skin diseases, including keratins 1 and 10, filaggrin, and loricrin. Transcriptome analysis showed that &lt;em&gt;PRANCR&lt;/em&gt; controls the expression of 1136 genes, with strong enrichment for late cell cycle genes containing a CHR promoter element. In addition, _PRANCR _depletion led to increased levels of both total and nuclear CDKN1A (also known as p21), which is known to govern both keratinocyte proliferation and differentiation. Collectively, these data show that &lt;em&gt;PRANCR&lt;/em&gt; is a novel lncRNA regulating epidermal homeostasis and identify other lncRNA candidates that may have roles in this process as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Programmable Inhibition and Detection of RNA Viruses Using Cas13</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/31607545/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/31607545/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The CRISPR effector Cas13 could be an effective antiviral for single-stranded RNA (ssRNA) viruses because it programmably cleaves RNAs complementary to its CRISPR RNA (crRNA). Here, we computationally identify thousands of potential Cas13 crRNA target sites in hundreds of ssRNA viral species that can potentially infect humans. We experimentally demonstrate Cas13&amp;rsquo;s potent activity against three distinct ssRNA viruses: lymphocytic choriomeningitis virus (LCMV); influenza A virus (IAV); and vesicular stomatitis virus (VSV). Combining this antiviral activity with Cas13-based diagnostics, we develop Cas13-assisted restriction of viral expression and readout (CARVER), an end-to-end platform that uses Cas13 to detect and destroy viral RNA. We further screen hundreds of crRNAs along the LCMV genome to evaluate how conservation and target RNA nucleotide content influence Cas13&amp;rsquo;s antiviral activity. Our results demonstrate that Cas13 can be harnessed to target a wide range of ssRNA viruses and CARVER&amp;rsquo;s potential broad utility for rapid diagnostic and antiviral drug development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Functional CRISPR screening identifies the ufmylation pathway as a regulator of SQSTM1/p62</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/27351204/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/27351204/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SQSTM1 is an adaptor protein that integrates multiple cellular signaling pathways and whose expression is tightly regulated at the transcriptional and post-translational level. Here, we describe a forward genetic screening paradigm exploiting CRISPR-mediated genome editing coupled to a cell selection step by FACS to identify regulators of SQSTM1. Through systematic comparison of pooled libraries, we show that CRISPR is superior to RNAi in identifying known SQSTM1 modulators. A genome-wide CRISPR screen exposed MTOR signalling and the entire macroautophagy machinery as key regulators of SQSTM1 and identified several novel modulators including HNRNPM, SLC39A14, SRRD, PGK1 and the ufmylation cascade. We show that ufmylation regulates SQSTM1 by eliciting a cell type-specific ER stress response which induces SQSTM1 expression and results in its accumulation in the cytosol. This study validates pooled CRISPR screening as a powerful method to map the repertoire of cellular pathways that regulate the fate of an individual target protein.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
