<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>African Swine Fever Virus | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/african-swine-fever-virus/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/african-swine-fever-virus/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>African Swine Fever Virus</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>African Swine Fever Virus</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/african-swine-fever-virus/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Splenic-targeting biomimetic nanovaccine for elevating protective immunity against virus infection</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36463277/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36463277/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; The prevalence of viral infectious diseases has become a serious threat to public safety, economic and social development. Vaccines have been served as the most effective platform to prevent virus transmission via the activation of host immune responses, while the low immunogenicity or safety, the high cost of production, storage, transport limit their effective clinical application. Therefore, there is a need to develop a promising strategy to improve the immunogenicity and safety of vaccines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; We developed a splenic-targeting biomimetic nanovaccine (NV) that can boost protective humoral and cellular immunity against african swine fever virus (ASFV) infection. The universal PLGA nanoparticles (CMR-PLGA/p54 NPs) coated with mannose and CpG (TLR9 agonist) co-modified red blood cell (RBC) membrane were prepared, which comprised a viral antigen (p54) and can be served as a versatile nanovaccine for elevating protective immunity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; CMR-PLGA/p54 NVs could be effectively uptaken by BMDC and promoted BMDC maturation in vitro. After subcutaneous immunization, antigen could be effectively delivered to the splenic dendritic cells (DCs) due to the splenic homing ability of RBC and DC targeting capacity of mannose, which promoted antigen presentation and DCs maturation, and further elicited higher levels of cytokines secretion and specific IgG titers, CD4+ and CD8+ T cells activation and B maturation. Moreover, NVs demonstrated notable safety during the immunization period.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; This study demonstrates the high potential of CMR-PLGA NPs as vaccine delivery carriers to promote humoral and cellular immune responses, and it provides a promising strategy to develop safe and effective vaccines against viral infectious diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MGF360-9L Is a Major Virulence Factor Associated with the African Swine Fever Virus by Antagonizing the JAK/STAT Signaling Pathway</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35076286/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35076286/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;African swine fever (ASF)-an aggressive infectious disease caused by the African swine fever virus (ASFV)-is significantly unfavorable for swine production. ASFV has a complex structure and encodes 150-167 proteins; however, the function of most of these proteins is unknown. This study identified ASFV MGF360-9L as a negative regulator of the interferon (IFN)-β signal. Further evidence showed that MGF360-9L interacts with signal transducer and activator of transcription (STAT) 1 and STAT2 and degrades STAT1 and STAT2 through apoptosis and ubiquitin-proteasome pathways, respectively. Subsequently, the activation of IFN-β signaling was inhibited. Naturally isolated or genetically manipulated live attenuated viruses are known to protect against the virulent parental ASFV strains. Therefore, through homologous recombination, we deleted MGF360-9L from the virulent ASFV CN/GS/2018 strain to construct a recombinant strain, ASFV-Δ360-9L. Compared with the parent ASFV CN/GS/2018 strain, the replication level of ASFV-Δ360-9L decreased in primary porcine alveolar macrophage cultures at 24 h postinfection, but the difference is unlikely to be biologically relevant. Notably, ASFV-Δ360-9L was partially attenuated in pigs. To our knowledge, this study is the first to uncover the function of MGF360-9L during ASFV infection. MGF360-9L inhibits IFN-β signaling through the targeted degradation of STAT1 and STAT2. Furthermore, MGF360-9L is a key virulence gene of ASFV. Our findings reveal a new mechanism by which ASFV inhibits host antiviral response; this might facilitate the development of live attenuated ASFV vaccines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Importance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;African swine fever-an acute, febrile, hemorrhagic, highly contacting, and highly lethal disease caused by African swine fever virus (ASFV)-jeopardizes the global pig industry. Understanding the mechanism ASFV employs to evade host defense during infection is essential for developing targeted drugs and vaccines against ASFV. To our knowledge, this study identifies the mechanism of innate immunity against by MGF360-9L and the effect of MGF360-9L on ASFV pathogenicity. The results showed that MGF360-9L may help ASFV escape the host immunity by degrading STAT1 and STAT2 and thus inhibiting IFN-β signaling. MGF360-9L is also an important virulence factor of ASFV. The deletion of MGF360-9L reduces ASFV virulence in pigs. This study explored a new mechanism of ASFV against innate immunity and identified a new ASFV virulence factor; these findings may guide the development of live attenuated ASFV vaccines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>African Swine Fever Virus E120R Protein Inhibits Interferon Beta Production by Interacting with IRF3 To Block Its Activation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34190598/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34190598/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;African swine fever is a devastating disease of swine caused by African swine fever virus (ASFV). The pathogenesis of the disease remains largely unknown, leaving the spread of the disease uncontrolled in many countries and regions. Here, we identified E120R, a structural protein of ASFV, as a key virulence factor and late-phase-expressed protein of the virus. E120R revealed an activity to suppress the host antiviral response through blocking beta interferon (IFN-β) production, and the amino acids (aa) at sites 72 and 73 (amino acids 72-73) in the C-terminal domain were essential for this function. E120R interacted with interferon regulatory factor 3 (IRF3) and interfered with the recruitment of IRF3 to TANK-binding kinase 1 (TBK1), which in turn suppressed IRF3 phosphorylation, decreasing interferon production. A recombinant mutant ASFV was further constructed to confirm the claimed mechanism. The ASFV lacking the complete E120R region could not be rescued, whereas the virus could tolerate the deletion of the 72nd and 73rd residues in E120R (ASFV E120R-Δ72-73aa). ASFV E120R with the two-amino-acid deletion failed to interact with IRF3 during ASFV E120R-Δ72-73aa infection, and the viral infection activated IRF3 phosphorylation highly and induced more robust type I interferon production than its parental ASFV. An unbiased transcriptome-wide analysis of gene expression also confirmed that considerably more IFN-stimulated genes (ISGs) were detected in ASFV E120R-Δ72-73aa-infected porcine alveolar macrophages (PAMs) than in wild-type ASFV-infected PAMs. Together, our findings have identified a novel mechanism evolved by ASFV to inhibit the host antiviral response, and they provide a new target for guiding the development of ASFV live-attenuated vaccine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Importance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;African swine fever is a highly contagious animal disease affecting the pig industry worldwide, which has brought enormous economic losses. Infection by the causative agent, African swine fever virus (ASFV), causes severe immunosuppression during viral infection, contributing to serious clinical manifestations. Therefore, identification of the viral proteins involved in immunosuppression is critical for ASFV vaccine design and development. Here, for the first time, we demonstrated that E120R protein, a structural protein of ASFV, played an important role in suppression of interferon regulatory factor 3 (IRF3) phosphorylation and type I interferon production by binding to IRF3 and blocking the recruitment of IRF3 to TANK-binding kinase 1 (TBK1). Deletion of the crucial binding sites in E120R critically increased the interferon response during ASFV infection. This study explored a novel antagonistic mechanism of ASFV, which is critical for guiding the development of ASFV live-attenuated vaccines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
