<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>African Swine Fever Virus | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/african-swine-fever-virus/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/african-swine-fever-virus/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>African Swine Fever Virus</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>African Swine Fever Virus</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/african-swine-fever-virus/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>African Swine Fever Virus E120R Protein Inhibits Interferon Beta Production by Interacting with IRF3 To Block Its Activation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34190598/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34190598/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;African swine fever is a devastating disease of swine caused by African swine fever virus (ASFV). The pathogenesis of the disease remains largely unknown, leaving the spread of the disease uncontrolled in many countries and regions. Here, we identified E120R, a structural protein of ASFV, as a key virulence factor and late-phase-expressed protein of the virus. E120R revealed an activity to suppress the host antiviral response through blocking beta interferon (IFN-β) production, and the amino acids (aa) at sites 72 and 73 (amino acids 72-73) in the C-terminal domain were essential for this function. E120R interacted with interferon regulatory factor 3 (IRF3) and interfered with the recruitment of IRF3 to TANK-binding kinase 1 (TBK1), which in turn suppressed IRF3 phosphorylation, decreasing interferon production. A recombinant mutant ASFV was further constructed to confirm the claimed mechanism. The ASFV lacking the complete E120R region could not be rescued, whereas the virus could tolerate the deletion of the 72nd and 73rd residues in E120R (ASFV E120R-Δ72-73aa). ASFV E120R with the two-amino-acid deletion failed to interact with IRF3 during ASFV E120R-Δ72-73aa infection, and the viral infection activated IRF3 phosphorylation highly and induced more robust type I interferon production than its parental ASFV. An unbiased transcriptome-wide analysis of gene expression also confirmed that considerably more IFN-stimulated genes (ISGs) were detected in ASFV E120R-Δ72-73aa-infected porcine alveolar macrophages (PAMs) than in wild-type ASFV-infected PAMs. Together, our findings have identified a novel mechanism evolved by ASFV to inhibit the host antiviral response, and they provide a new target for guiding the development of ASFV live-attenuated vaccine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Importance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;African swine fever is a highly contagious animal disease affecting the pig industry worldwide, which has brought enormous economic losses. Infection by the causative agent, African swine fever virus (ASFV), causes severe immunosuppression during viral infection, contributing to serious clinical manifestations. Therefore, identification of the viral proteins involved in immunosuppression is critical for ASFV vaccine design and development. Here, for the first time, we demonstrated that E120R protein, a structural protein of ASFV, played an important role in suppression of interferon regulatory factor 3 (IRF3) phosphorylation and type I interferon production by binding to IRF3 and blocking the recruitment of IRF3 to TANK-binding kinase 1 (TBK1). Deletion of the crucial binding sites in E120R critically increased the interferon response during ASFV infection. This study explored a novel antagonistic mechanism of ASFV, which is critical for guiding the development of ASFV live-attenuated vaccines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
