<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Heart | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/heart/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/heart/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Heart</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Heart</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/heart/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interdependent Nuclear Co-Trafficking of ASPP1 and p53 Aggravates Cardiac Ischemia/Reperfusion Injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/23-01-01-10-14/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/23-01-01-10-14/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;OBJECTIVE:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ASPP1 (apoptosis stimulating of p53 protein 1) is critical in regulating cell apoptosis as a cofactor of p53 to promote its transcriptional activity in the nucleus. However, whether cytoplasmic ASPP1 affects p53 nuclear trafficking and its role in cardiac diseases remains unknown. This study aims to explore the mechanism by which ASPP1 modulates p53 nuclear trafficking and the subsequent contribution to cardiac ischemia/reperfusion (I/R) injury.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;METHODS AND RESULTS:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The immunofluorescent staining showed that under normal condition ASPP1 and p53 colocalized in the cytoplasm of neonatal mouse ventricular cardiomyocytes, while they were both upregulated and translocated to the nuclei upon hypoxia/reoxygenation treatment. The nuclear translocation of ASPP1 and p53 was interdependent, as knockdown of either ASPP1 or p53 attenuated nuclear translocation of the other one. Inhibition of importin-β1 resulted in the cytoplasmic sequestration of both p53 and ASPP1 in neonatal mouse ventricular cardiomyocytes with hypoxia/reoxygenation stimulation. Overexpression of ASPP1 potentiated, whereas knockdown of ASPP1 inhibited the expression of Bax (Bcl2-associated X), PUMA (p53 upregulated modulator of apoptosis), and Noxa, direct apoptosis-associated targets of p53. ASPP1 was also increased in the I/R myocardium. Cardiomyocyte-specific transgenic overexpression of ASPP1 aggravated I/R injury as indicated by increased infarct size and impaired cardiac function. Conversely, knockout of ASPP1 mitigated cardiac I/R injury. The same qualitative data were observed in neonatal mouse ventricular cardiomyocytes exposed to hypoxia/reoxygenation injury. Furthermore, inhibition of p53 significantly blunted the proapoptotic activity and detrimental effects of ASPP1 both in vitro and in vivo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;CONCLUSIONS:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Binding of ASPP1 to p53 triggers their nuclear cotranslocation via importin-β1 that eventually exacerbates cardiac I/R injury. The findings imply that interfering the expression of ASPP1 or the interaction between ASPP1 and p53 to block their nuclear trafficking represents an important therapeutic strategy for cardiac I/R injury.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Liver-heart cross-talk mediated by coagulation factor XI protects against heart failure</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36137043/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36137043/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tissue-tissue communication by endocrine factors is a vital mechanism for physiologic homeostasis. A systems genetics analysis of transcriptomic and functional data from a cohort of diverse, inbred strains of mice predicted that coagulation factor XI (FXI), a liver-derived protein, protects against diastolic dysfunction, a key trait of heart failure with preserved ejection fraction. This was confirmed using gain- and loss-of-function studies, and FXI was found to activate the bone morphogenetic protein (BMP)-SMAD1/5 pathway in the heart. The proteolytic activity of FXI is required for the cleavage and activation of extracellular matrix-associated BMP7 in the heart, thus inhibiting genes involved in inflammation and fibrosis. Our results reveal a protective role of FXI in heart injury that is distinct from its role in coagulation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CircRNA Samd4 induces cardiac repair after myocardial infarction by blocking mitochondria-derived ROS output</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35791879/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35791879/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reactive oxygen species (ROS) derived from oxygen-dependent mitochondrial metabolism are the essential drivers of cardiomyocyte (CM) cell-cycle arrest in adulthood. Mitochondria-localized circular RNAs (circRNAs) play important roles in regulating mitochondria-derived ROS production, but their functions in cardiac regeneration are still unknown. Herein, we investigated the functions and underlying mechanism of mitochondria-localized circSamd4 in cardiac regeneration. We found that circSamd4 was selectively expressed in fetal and neonatal CMs. The transcription factor Nrf2 controlled circSamd4 expression by binding to the promoter of circSamd4 host gene. CircSamd4 overexpression reduced while circSamd4 silenced increased mitochondrial oxidative stress and subsequent oxidative DNA damage. Moreover, circSamd4 overexpression induced CM proliferation and prevented CM apoptosis, which reduced the size of the fibrotic area and improved cardiac function after myocardial infarction (MI). Mechanistically, circSamd4 reduced oxidative stress generation and maintained mitochondrial dynamics by inducing the mitochondrial translocation of the Vcp protein, which downregulated Vdac1 expression and prevented the mitochondrial permeability transition pore (mPTP) from opening. Our findings suggest that circSamd4 is a novel therapeutic target for heart failure after MI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Circular RNA CircFndc3b modulates cardiac repair after myocardial infarction via FUS/VEGF-A axis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/31541092/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/31541092/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Circular RNAs are generated from many protein-coding genes, but their role in cardiovascular health and disease states remains unknown. Here we report identification of circRNA transcripts that are differentially expressed in post myocardial infarction (MI) mouse hearts including circFndc3b which is significantly down-regulated in the post-MI hearts. Notably, the human circFndc3b ortholog is also significantly down-regulated in cardiac tissues of ischemic cardiomyopathy patients. Overexpression of circFndc3b in cardiac endothelial cells increases vascular endothelial growth factor-A expression and enhances their angiogenic activity and reduces cardiomyocytes and endothelial cell apoptosis. Adeno-associated virus 9 -mediated cardiac overexpression of circFndc3b in post-MI hearts reduces cardiomyocyte apoptosis, enhances neovascularization and improves left ventricular functions. Mechanistically, circFndc3b interacts with the RNA binding protein Fused in Sarcoma to regulate VEGF expression and signaling. These findings highlight a physiological role for circRNAs in cardiac repair and indicate that modulation of circFndc3b expression may represent a potential strategy to promote cardiac function and remodeling after MI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gata6&#43; Pericardial Cavity Macrophages Relocate to the Injured Heart and Prevent Cardiac Fibrosis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/31315031/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/31315031/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Macrophages play an important role in structural cardiac remodeling and the transition to heart failure following myocardial infarction (MI). Previous research has focused on the impact of blood-derived monocytes on cardiac repair. Here we examined the contribution of resident cavity macrophages located in the pericardial space adjacent to the site of injury. We found that disruption of the pericardial cavity accelerated maladaptive post-MI cardiac remodeling. Gata6&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; macrophages in mouse pericardial fluid contributed to the reparative immune response. Following experimental MI, these macrophages invaded the epicardium and lost Gata6 expression but continued to perform anti-fibrotic functions. Loss of this specialized macrophage population enhanced interstitial fibrosis after ischemic injury. Gata6+ macrophages were present in human pericardial fluid, supporting the notion that this reparative function is relevant in human disease. Our findings uncover an immune cardioprotective role for the pericardial tissue compartment and argue for the reevaluation of surgical procedures that remove the pericardium.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>S100a8/a9 Signaling Causes Mitochondrial Dysfunction and Cardiomyocyte Death in Response to Ischemic/Reperfusion Injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/31220942/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/31220942/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Myocardial ischemia-reperfusion (MI/R) injury is a significant clinical problem without effective therapy. Unbiased omics approaches may reveal key MI/R mediators to initiate MI/R injury.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; We used a dynamic transcriptome analysis of mouse heart exposed to various MI/R periods to identify S100a8/a9 as an early mediator. Using loss/gain-of-function approaches to understand the role of S100a8/a9 in MI/R injury, we explored the mechanisms through transcriptome and functional experiment. Dynamic serum S100a8/a9 levels were measured in patients with acute myocardial infarction before and after percutaneous coronary intervention. Patients were prospectively followed for the occurrence of major adverse cardiovascular events.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; S100a8/a9 was identified as the most significantly upregulated gene during the early reperfusion stage. Knockout of S100a9 markedly decreased cardiomyocyte death and improved heart function, whereas hematopoietic overexpression of S100a9 exacerbated MI/R injury. Transcriptome/functional studies revealed that S100a8/a9 caused mitochondrial respiratory dysfunction in cardiomyocytes. Mechanistically, S100a8/a9 downregulated NDUF gene expression with subsequent mitochondrial complex I inhibition via Toll-like receptor 4/Erk-mediated Pparg coactivator 1 alpha/nuclear respiratory factor 1 signaling suppression. Administration of S100a9 neutralizing antibody significantly reduced MI/R injury and improved cardiac function. Finally, we demonstrated that serum S100a8/a9 levels were significantly increased 1 day after percutaneous coronary intervention in patients with acute myocardial infarction, and elevated S100a8/a9 levels were associated with the incidence of major adverse cardiovascular events.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; Our study identified S100a8/a9 as a master regulator causing cardiomyocyte death in the early stage of MI/R injury via the suppression of mitochondrial function. Targeting S100a8/a9-intiated signaling may represent a novel therapeutic intervention against MI/R injury.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-renewing resident cardiac macrophages limit adverse remodeling following myocardial infarction</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/30538339/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/30538339/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Erratum in:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Publisher Correction: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nature.com/articles/s41590-019-0363-8&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Self-renewing resident cardiac macrophages limit adverse remodeling following myocardial infarction&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Macrophages promote both injury and repair after myocardial infarction, but discriminating functions within mixed populations remains challenging. Here we used fate mapping, parabiosis and single-cell transcriptomics to demonstrate that at steady state, TIMD4&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt;LYVE1&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt;MHC-II&lt;sup&gt;lo&lt;/sup&gt;CCR2&lt;sup&gt;-&lt;/sup&gt; resident cardiac macrophages self-renew with negligible blood monocyte input. Monocytes partially replaced resident TIMD4&lt;sup&gt;-&lt;/sup&gt;LYVE1&lt;sup&gt;-&lt;/sup&gt;MHC-II&lt;sup&gt;hi&lt;/sup&gt;CCR2&lt;sup&gt;-&lt;/sup&gt; macrophages and fully replaced TIMD4&lt;sup&gt;-&lt;/sup&gt;LYVE1&lt;sup&gt;-&lt;/sup&gt;MHC-II&lt;sup&gt;hi&lt;/sup&gt;CCR2&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; macrophages, revealing a hierarchy of monocyte contribution to functionally distinct macrophage subsets. Ischemic injury reduced TIMD4&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; and TIMD4&lt;sup&gt;-&lt;/sup&gt; resident macrophage abundance, whereas CCR2&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; monocyte-derived macrophages adopted multiple cell fates within infarcted tissue, including those nearly indistinguishable from resident macrophages. Recruited macrophages did not express TIMD4, highlighting the ability of TIMD4 to track a subset of resident macrophages in the absence of fate mapping. Despite this similarity, inducible depletion of resident macrophages using a Cx3cr1-based system led to impaired cardiac function and promoted adverse remodeling primarily within the peri-infarct zone, revealing a nonredundant, cardioprotective role of resident cardiac macrophages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
