<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Heart | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/heart/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/heart/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Heart</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Heart</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/heart/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exosomes as perioperative therapeutics to limit organ injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36682935/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36682935/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perioperative organ injury is a frequent and major complication for the ∼240 million people undergoing surgery worldwide annually. Ischaemic preconditioning is a powerful technique that reduces organ injury in experimental models of heart, lung, gut, brain, and kidney ischaemia-reperfusion injury. However, ischaemic preconditioning has been a challenge to translate into clinical practice. We describe how utilising isolated pre-conditioned exosomes (secreted vesicles containing many cell-survival mediators), some of the translational hurdles of ischaemic preconditioning can be overcome. Delivery of exosomes in the perioperative period could become a promising new therapeutic strategy to prevent perioperative organ injury.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Circadian Biology of Heart Failure</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/36656971/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/36656971/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Driven by autonomous molecular clocks that are synchronized by a master pacemaker in the suprachiasmatic nucleus, cardiac physiology fluctuates in diurnal rhythms that can be partly or entirely circadian. Cardiac contractility, metabolism, and electrophysiology, all have diurnal rhythms, as does the neurohumoral control of cardiac and kidney function. In this review, we discuss the evidence that circadian biology regulates cardiac function, how molecular clocks may relate to the pathogenesis of heart failure, and how chronotherapeutics might be applied in heart failure. Disrupting molecular clocks can lead to heart failure in animal models, and the myocardial response to injury seems to be conditioned by the time of day. Human studies are consistent with these findings, and they implicate the clock and circadian rhythms in the pathogenesis of heart failure. Certain circadian rhythms are maintained in patients with heart failure, a factor that can guide optimal timing of therapy. Pharmacologic and nonpharmacologic manipulation of circadian rhythms and molecular clocks show promise in the prevention and treatment of heart failure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Circular RNAs at the intersection of cancer and heart disease: potential therapeutic targets in cardio-oncology</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/36651915/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/36651915/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Considerable progress has been made for managing cancer, however, with these advancements, comes the discovery of previously unknown adverse events. In particular, the prolonged lifespan of patients has uncovered severe cardiotoxic side effects of widely used anticancer therapies, which restrict their administration and thus compromise the success of the seemingly most suitable treatments in large cancer patient cohorts. Vice versa, cardiovascular diseases can also promote both the onset and progression of different cancers, highlighting that both conditions are deeply interlinked. Recognizing these close interactions, the novel interdisciplinary field of cardio-oncology has emerged to closely study these uniquely correlating diseases. In this regard, non-coding RNAs are gaining increasing attention since they constitute crucial regulators in many physiological but also pathological signaling pathways, including those of cancer and cardiac dysfunction. In this review, we focus on the new subtype of non-coding RNA, circular RNAs, in their distinct exchange within cardio-oncology and discuss their suitability as potent targets for the simultaneous treatment of cardiac dysfunction and cancer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adaptor protein HIP-55-mediated signalosome protects against ferroptosis in myocardial infarction</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36639542/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36639542/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ischemic heart disease is a leading cause of death worldwide. Myocardial infarction (MI) results in cardiac damage due to cell death and insufficient cardiomyocyte self-renewal. Ferroptosis, a novel type of cell death, has recently been shown as a key cause of cardiomyocyte death after MI. However, the complicated regulation mechanisms involved in ferroptosis, especially how ferroptosis is integrated into classical cell survival/death pathways, are still unclear. Here, we discovered that HIP-55, a novel adaptor protein, acts as a hub protein for the integration of the ferroptosis mechanism into the classical AKT cell survival and MAP4K1 cell death pathways for MI injury. The expression of HIP-55 is induced in MI. Genetic deletion of HIP-55 increased cardiomyocyte ferroptosis and MI injury, whereas cardiac-specific overexpression of HIP-55 significantly alleviated cardiomyocyte ferroptosis and MI injury. Mechanistically, HIP-55 was identified as a new AKT substrate. AKT phosphorylates HIP-55 at S269/T291 sites and further HIP-55 directs AKT signaling to negatively regulate the MAP4K1 pathway against MI injury in a site-specific manner. S269A/T291A-mutated HIP-55 (HIP-55AA), which is defective in AKT phosphorylation and significantly decreases the interaction between HIP-55 and MAP4K1, failed to inhibit the MAP4K1/GPX4 ferroptosis pathway. In line with this mechanism, cardiac-specific overexpression of HIP-55WT mice, but not cardiac-specific overexpression of HIP-55AA mice, protected cardiomyocytes against MI-induced ferroptosis and cardiac injury in vivo. These findings suggest that HIP-55 rewired the classical AKT (cell survival) and MAPK (cell death) pathways into ferroptosis mechanism in MI injury. HIP-55 may be a new therapeutic target for myocardial damage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anti-angiogenic effect of exo-LncRNA TUG1 in myocardial infarction and modulation by remote ischemic conditioning</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36635484/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36635484/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The successful use of exosomes in therapy after myocardial infarction depends on an improved understanding of their role in cardiac signaling and regulation. Here, we report that exosomes circulating after myocardial infarction (MI) carry LncRNA TUG1 which downregulates angiogenesis by disablement of the HIF-1α/VEGF-α axis and that this effect can be counterbalanced by remote ischemic conditioning (RIC). Rats with MI induced through left coronary artery ligation without (MI model) and with reperfusion (ischemia/reperfusion I/R model) were randomized to RIC, or MI (I/R) or sham-operated (SO) control. Data from one cohort study and one randomized-controlled trial of humans with MI were also utilized, the former involving patients who had not received percutaneous coronary intervention (PCI) and the latter patients with PCI. Exosome concentrations did not differ between intervention groups (RIC vs. control) in rats (MI and I/R model) as well as humans (with and without PCI). However, MI and I/R exosomes attenuated HIF-1α, VEGF-α, and endothelial function. LncRNA TUG1 was increased in MI and I/R exosomes, but decreased in SO and RIC exosomes. HIF-1α expression was downregulated with MI and I/R exosomes but increased with RIC exosomes. Exosome inhibition suppressed HIF-1α upregulation through RIC exosomes. VEGF-α was identified as HIF-1α-regulated target gene. Knockdown of HIF-1α decreased VEGF-α, endothelial cell capability, and tube formation. Overexpression of HIF-1α exerted opposite effects. Transfection and co-transfection of 293 T cells with exosome-inhibitor GW4869 and HIF-1α inhibitor si-HIF-1α confirmed the exosomal-LncRNA TUG1/HIF-1α/VEGF-α pathway. LncRNA TUG1 is a potential therapeutic target after MI with or without reperfusion through PCI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TREM2hi resident macrophages protect the septic heart by maintaining cardiomyocyte homeostasis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36635449/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36635449/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sepsis-induced cardiomyopathy (SICM) is common in septic patients with a high mortality and is characterized by an abnormal immune response. Owing to cellular heterogeneity, understanding the roles of immune cell subsets in SICM has been challenging. Here we identify a unique subpopulation of cardiac-resident macrophages termed CD163&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt;RETNLA&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; (Mac1), which undergoes self-renewal during sepsis and can be targeted to prevent SICM. By combining single-cell RNA sequencing with fate mapping in a mouse model of sepsis, we demonstrate that the Mac1 subpopulation has distinct transcriptomic signatures enriched in endocytosis and displays high expression of TREM2 (TREM2&lt;sup&gt;hi&lt;/sup&gt;). TREM2&lt;sup&gt;hi&lt;/sup&gt; Mac1 cells actively scavenge cardiomyocyte-ejected dysfunctional mitochondria. &lt;em&gt;Trem2&lt;/em&gt; deficiency in macrophages impairs the self-renewal capability of the Mac1 subpopulation and consequently results in defective elimination of damaged mitochondria, excessive inflammatory response in cardiac tissue, exacerbated cardiac dysfunction and decreased survival. Notably, intrapericardial administration of TREM2&lt;sup&gt;hi&lt;/sup&gt; Mac1 cells prevents SICM. Our findings suggest that the modulation of TREM2&lt;sup&gt;hi&lt;/sup&gt; Mac1 cells could serve as a therapeutic strategy for SICM.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The oral microbiome in the pathophysiology of cardiovascular disease</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/36624275/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/36624275/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite advances in our understanding of the pathophysiology of many cardiovascular diseases (CVDs) and expansion of available therapies, the global burden of CVD-associated morbidity and mortality remains unacceptably high. Important gaps remain in our understanding of the mechanisms of CVD and determinants of disease progression. In the past decade, much research has been conducted on the human microbiome and its potential role in modulating CVD. With the advent of high-throughput technologies and multiomics analyses, the complex and dynamic relationship between the microbiota, their ‘theatre of activity’ and the host is gradually being elucidated. The relationship between the gut microbiome and CVD is well established. Much less is known about the role of disruption (dysbiosis) of the oral microbiome; however, interest in the field is growing, as is the body of literature from basic science and animal and human investigations. In this Review, we examine the link between the oral microbiome and CVD, specifically coronary artery disease, stroke, peripheral artery disease, heart failure, infective endocarditis and rheumatic heart disease. We discuss the various mechanisms by which oral dysbiosis contributes to CVD pathogenesis and potential strategies for prevention and treatment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Key points&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The incidence and prevalence of cardiovascular diseases (CVDs) are increasing despite advances in our understanding of their pathophysiology and an expanded arsenal of treatment options.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An association between the oral microbiome (or oralome) and cardiovascular inflammation and CVD is supported by a growing body of epidemiological studies, systematic reviews and basic science investigations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Validated links exist between oral dysbiosis and CVDs, including atherosclerotic diseases, heart failure, infective endocarditis and rheumatic heart disease.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The mechanisms by which oral dysbiosis contributes to CVD include immunomodulation; endothelial dysfunction; molecular mimicry and antibody cross-reactivity; protein citrullination; platelet activation, aggregation and thrombogenesis; arterial invasion; and systemic inflammation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Targeting oral dysbiosis in a clinical setting could be an important component of CVD management.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TMBIM6 prevents VDAC1 multimerization and improves mitochondrial quality control to reduce sepsis-related myocardial injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36603706/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36603706/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The regulatory mechanisms involved in mitochondrial quality control (MQC) dysfunction during septic cardiomyopathy (SCM) remain incompletely characterized. Transmembrane BAX inhibitor motif containing 6 (TMBIM6) is an endoplasmic reticulum protein with Ca2+ leak activity that modulates cellular responses to various cellular stressors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this study, we evaluated the role of TMBIM6 in SCM using cardiomyocyte-specific TMBIM6 knockout (TMBIM6CKO) and TMBIM6 transgenic (TMBIM6TG) mice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Myocardial TMBIM6 transcription and expression were significantly downregulated in wild-type mice upon LPS exposure, along with characteristic alterations in myocardial systolic/diastolic function, cardiac inflammation, and cardiomyocyte death. Notably, these alterations were further exacerbated in LPS-treated TMBIM6CKO mice, and largely absent in TMBIM6TG mice. In LPS-treated primary cardiomyocytes, TMBIM6 deficiency further impaired mitochondrial respiration and ATP production, while defective MQC was suggested by enhanced mitochondrial fission, impaired mitophagy, and disrupted mitochondrial biogenesis. Structural protein analysis, Co-IP, mutant TMBIM6 plasmid transfection, and molecular docking assays subsequently indicated that TMBIM6 exerts cardioprotection against LPS-induced sepsis by interacting with and preventing the oligomerization of voltage-dependent anion channel-1 (VDAC1), the major route of mitochondrial Ca2+ uptake.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We conclude that the TMBIM6-VDAC1 interaction prevents VDAC1 oligomerization and thus sustains mitochondrial Ca2+ homeostasis as well as MQC, contributing to improved myocardial function in SCM.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interdependent Nuclear Co-Trafficking of ASPP1 and p53 Aggravates Cardiac Ischemia/Reperfusion Injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36656967/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36656967/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;OBJECTIVE:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ASPP1 (apoptosis stimulating of p53 protein 1) is critical in regulating cell apoptosis as a cofactor of p53 to promote its transcriptional activity in the nucleus. However, whether cytoplasmic ASPP1 affects p53 nuclear trafficking and its role in cardiac diseases remains unknown. This study aims to explore the mechanism by which ASPP1 modulates p53 nuclear trafficking and the subsequent contribution to cardiac ischemia/reperfusion (I/R) injury.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;METHODS AND RESULTS:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The immunofluorescent staining showed that under normal condition ASPP1 and p53 colocalized in the cytoplasm of neonatal mouse ventricular cardiomyocytes, while they were both upregulated and translocated to the nuclei upon hypoxia/reoxygenation treatment. The nuclear translocation of ASPP1 and p53 was interdependent, as knockdown of either ASPP1 or p53 attenuated nuclear translocation of the other one. Inhibition of importin-β1 resulted in the cytoplasmic sequestration of both p53 and ASPP1 in neonatal mouse ventricular cardiomyocytes with hypoxia/reoxygenation stimulation. Overexpression of ASPP1 potentiated, whereas knockdown of ASPP1 inhibited the expression of Bax (Bcl2-associated X), PUMA (p53 upregulated modulator of apoptosis), and Noxa, direct apoptosis-associated targets of p53. ASPP1 was also increased in the I/R myocardium. Cardiomyocyte-specific transgenic overexpression of ASPP1 aggravated I/R injury as indicated by increased infarct size and impaired cardiac function. Conversely, knockout of ASPP1 mitigated cardiac I/R injury. The same qualitative data were observed in neonatal mouse ventricular cardiomyocytes exposed to hypoxia/reoxygenation injury. Furthermore, inhibition of p53 significantly blunted the proapoptotic activity and detrimental effects of ASPP1 both in vitro and in vivo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;CONCLUSIONS:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Binding of ASPP1 to p53 triggers their nuclear cotranslocation via importin-β1 that eventually exacerbates cardiac I/R injury. The findings imply that interfering the expression of ASPP1 or the interaction between ASPP1 and p53 to block their nuclear trafficking represents an important therapeutic strategy for cardiac I/R injury.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CD44 promotes angiogenesis in myocardial infarction through regulating plasma exosome uptake and further enhancing FGFR2 signaling transduction</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36463112/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36463112/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since angiogenesis occurs as the pathological process following myocardial infarction to alleviate ischemia, therapeutic angiogenesis has been proposed to be a cardioprotective strategy. CD44 has been implicated in endothelial cell functions and its role has been well established in angiogenesis for years. Although recent studies indicate the close correlation between CD44 and exosome, as well as the two being implicated in myocardial ischemia pathological processes, the effect and the underlying mechanism of CD44 and its regulated plasma exosome in pathological angiogenesis post-myocardial infarction have not been fully elucidated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this study, we used CD44 knockout mice to study the in vivo impacts of CD44 on ischemic angiogenesis in myocardial infarction. Mouse cardiac function was measured by echocardiography, histological changes were observed by Evans Blue and TTC-double staining and Masson’s trichrome staining, and molecular changes were detected by immunofluorescence. In the in vitro study, CD44 knockout HUVECs were generated and CD44 inhibitor was used to study the mechanism of CD44 on angiogenesis. We performed the immunoprecipitation, proximity ligation assay, and super-resolution imaging to study the mechanistic regulation of FGFR2 signaling transduction by CD44. Importantly, we also isolated plasma exosomes from myocardial infarction model mice and studied the effect of plasma exosomes on the activation of the FGFR2 signaling pathway and the related phenotypic alterations, including exosomes uptake and angiogenic function in primary mouse microvascular endothelial cells, and further discovered the regulation mechanism of exosomal miRNAs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We observed that the expression of CD44 in the border zone of the infarcted heart was tightly related to pathological angiogenesis following myocardial ischemia. The depletion of CD44 impaired angiogenesis and impacts biogenesis and proangiogenic function of plasma exosomes. Subsequently, we found that CD44 mediated the activation of the FGFR2 signaling pathway as well as the caveolin 1-dependent uptake of exosomes in vascular endothelial cells. Most importantly, the proangiogenic therapeutic effect of plasma exosomal miRNAs depended upon the participation of CD44/FGFR2 signaling transduction in vascular endothelial cells.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CD44 and its regulated plasma exosomes have crucial potent angiogenic activity. Our studies elucidate that CD44 plays a key role in plasma exosomal miRNA-enhanced angiogenic FGFR2 singling transduction and ischemic angiogenesis in the early stage of myocardial infarction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tropoelastin Improves Post-Infarct Cardiac Function</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36453283/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36453283/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Myocardial infarction (MI) is among the leading causes of death worldwide. Following MI, necrotic cardiomyocytes are replaced by a stiff collagen-rich scar. Compared to collagen, the extracellular matrix protein elastin has high elasticity and may have more favorable properties within the cardiac scar. We sought to improve post-MI healing by introducing tropoelastin, the soluble subunit of elastin, to alter scar mechanics early after MI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods and results:&lt;/em&gt; We developed an ultrasound-guided direct intramyocardial injection method to administer tropoelastin directly into the left ventricular anterior wall of rats subjected to induced MI. Experimental groups included shams and infarcted rats injected with either PBS vehicle control or tropoelastin. Compared to vehicle treated controls, echocardiography assessments showed tropoelastin significantly improved left ventricular ejection fraction (64.7±4.4% versus 46.0±3.1% control) and reduced left ventricular dyssynchrony (11.4±3.5 ms versus 31.1±5.8 ms control) 28 days post-MI. Additionally, tropoelastin reduced post-MI scar size (8.9±1.5% versus 20.9±2.7% control) and increased scar elastin (22±5.8% versus 6.2±1.5% control) as determined by histological assessments. RNA sequencing (RNAseq) analyses of rat infarcts showed that tropoelastin injection increased genes associated with elastic fiber formation 7 days post-MI and reduced genes associated with immune response 11 days post-MI. To show translational relevance, we performed immunohistochemical analyses on human ischemic heart disease cardiac samples and showed an increase in tropoelastin within fibrotic areas. Using RNA-seq we also demonstrated the tropoelastin gene ELN is upregulated in human ischemic heart disease and during human cardiac fibroblast-myofibroblast differentiation. Furthermore, we showed by immunocytochemistry that human cardiac fibroblast synthesize increased elastin in direct response to tropoelastin treatment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; We demonstrate for the first time that purified human tropoelastin can significantly repair the infarcted heart in a rodent model of MI and that human cardiac fibroblast synthesize elastin. Since human cardiac fibroblasts are primarily responsible for post-MI scar synthesis, our findings suggest exciting future clinical translation options designed to therapeutically manipulate this synthesis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cannabinoid Receptor 2-Centric Molecular Feedback Loop Drives Necroptosis in Diabetic Heart Injuries</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36448459/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36448459/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Diabetic heart dysfunction is a common complication of diabetes. Cell death is a core event that leads to diabetic heart dysfunction. However, the time sequence of cell death pathways and the precise time to intervene of particular cell death type remain largely unknown in the diabetic heart. This study aims to identify the particular cell death type that is responsible for diabetic heart dysfunction and to propose a promising therapeutic strategy by intervening in the cell death pathway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; Type 2 diabetes models were established using db/db leptin receptor-deficient mice and high-fat diet/streptozotocin-induced mice. The type 1 diabetes model was established in streptozotocin-induced mice. Apoptosis and programmed cell necrosis (necroptosis) were detected in diabetic mouse hearts at different ages. G protein-coupled receptor-targeted drug library was searched to identify potential receptors regulating the key cell death pathway. Pharmacological and genetic approaches that modulate the expression of targets were used. Stable cell lines and a homemade phosphorylation antibody were prepared to conduct mechanistic studies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; Necroptosis was activated after apoptosis at later stages of diabetes and was functionally responsible for cardiac dysfunction. Cannabinoid receptor 2 (CB2R) was a key regulator of necroptosis. Mechanically, during normal glucose levels, CB2R inhibited S6 kinase-mediated phosphorylation of BACH2 at serine 520, thereby leading to BACH2 translocation to the nucleus, where BACH2 transcriptionally repressed the necroptosis genes Rip1, Rip3, and Mlkl. Under hyperglycemic conditions, high glucose induced CB2R internalization in a β-arrestin 2-dependent manner; thereafter, MLKL (mixed lineage kinase domain-like), but not receptor-interacting protein kinase 1 or 3, phosphorylated CB2R at serine 352 and promoted CB2R degradation by ubiquitin modification. Cardiac re-expression of CB2R rescued diabetes-induced cardiomyocyte necroptosis and heart dysfunction, whereas cardiac knockout of Bach2 diminished CB2R-mediated beneficial effects. In human diabetic hearts, both CB2R and BACH2 were negatively associated with diabetes-induced myocardial injuries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; CB2R transcriptionally repressed necroptosis through interaction with BACH2; in turn, MLKL formed a negative feedback to phosphorylate CB2R. Our study provides the integrative view of a novel molecular mechanism loop for regulation of necroptosis centered by CB2R, which represents a promising alternative strategy for controlling diabetic heart dysfunction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blocking MG53S255 Phosphorylation Protects Diabetic Heart From Ischemic Injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36337049/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36337049/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; As an integral component of cell membrane repair machinery, MG53 (mitsugumin 53) is important for cardioprotection induced by ischemia preconditioning and postconditioning. However, it also impairs insulin signaling via its E3 ligase activity-mediated ubiquitination-dependent degradation of IR (insulin receptor) and IRS1 (insulin receptor substrate 1) and its myokine function-induced allosteric blockage of IR. Here, we sought to develop MG53 into a cardioprotection therapy by separating its detrimental metabolic effects from beneficial actions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; Using immunoprecipitation-mass spectrometry, site-specific mutation, in vitro kinase assay, and in vivo animal studies, we investigated the role of MG53 phosphorylation at serine 255 (S255). In particular, utilizing recombinant proteins and gene knock-in approaches, we evaluated the potential therapeutic effect of MG53-S255A mutant in treating cardiac ischemia/reperfusion injury in diabetic mice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; We identified S255 phosphorylation as a prerequisite for MG53 E3 ligase activity. Furthermore, MG53S255 phosphorylation was mediated by GSK3β (glycogen synthase kinase 3 beta) and markedly elevated in the animal models with metabolic disorders. Thus, IR-IRS1-GSK3β-MG53 formed a vicious cycle in the pathogenesis of metabolic disorders where aberrant insulin signaling led to hyper-activation of GSK3β, which in turn, phosphorylated MG53 and enhanced its E3 ligase activity, and further impaired insulin sensitivity. Importantly, S255A mutant eliminated the E3 ligase activity while retained cell protective function of MG53. Consequently, the S255A mutant, but not the wild type MG53, protected the heart against ischemia/reperfusion injury in db/db mice with advanced diabetes, although both elicited cardioprotection in normal mice. Moreover, in S255A knock-in mice, S255A mutant also mitigated ischemia/reperfusion-induced myocardial damage in the diabetic setting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; S255 phosphorylation is a biased regulation of MG53 E3 ligase activity. The MG53-S255A mutant provides a promising approach for the treatment of acute myocardial injury, especially in patients with metabolic disorders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dusp6 deficiency attenuates neutrophil-mediated cardiac damage in the acute inflammatory phase of myocardial infarction</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36335128/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36335128/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dual-specificity phosphatase 6 (DUSP6) serves a specific and conserved function on the dephosphorylation of extracellular signal-regulated kinase 1/2 (ERK1/2). We previously identified Dusp6 as a regenerative repressor during zebrafish heart regeneration, therefore we propose to investigate the role of this repressor in mammalian cardiac repair. Utilizing a rat strain harboring Dusp6 nonsense mutation, rat neutrophil-cardiomyocyte co-culture, bone marrow transplanted rats and neutrophil-specific Dusp6 knockout mice, we find that Dusp6 deficiency improves cardiac outcomes by predominantly attenuating neutrophil-mediated myocardial damage in acute inflammatory phase after myocardial infarction. Mechanistically, Dusp6 is transcriptionally activated by p38-C/EBPβ signaling and acts as an effector for maintaining p-p38 activity by down-regulating pERK and p38-targeting phosphatases DUSP1/DUSP16. Our findings provide robust animal models and novel insights for neutrophil-mediated cardiac damage and demonstrate the potential of DUSP6 as a therapeutic target for post-MI cardiac remodeling and other relevant inflammatory diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>circHIPK3 prevents cardiac senescence by acting as a scaffold to recruit ubiquitin ligase to degrade HuR</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36438474/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36438474/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rational:&lt;/em&gt; Senescence is a major aging process that contributes to the development of cardiovascular diseases, but the underlying molecular mechanisms remain largely unknown. One reason is due to the lack of suitable animal models. We aimed to generate a cardiomyocyte (CM)-specific senescent animal model, uncover the underlying mechanisms, and develop new therapies for aging associated cardiac dysfunction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; The gain/loss of circHIPK3 approach was used to explore the role of circHIPK3 in cardiomyocyte (CM) senescence. To investigate the mechanisms of circHIPK3 function in cardiac senescence, we generated CM-specific tamoxifen-induced circHIPK3 knockout (CKO) mice. We also applied various analyses including PCR, Western blot, nuclear and cytoplasmic protein extraction, immunofluorescence, echocardiography, RNA immunoprecipitation assay, RNA-pulldown assay, and co-immunoprecipitation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; Our novel CKO mice exhibited worse cardiac function, decreased circHIPK3 expression and telomere length shortening in the heart. The level of the senescence-inducer p21 in the hearts of CKO mice was significantly increased and survival was poor compared with control mice. In vitro, the level of p21 in CMs was significantly decreased by circHIPK3 overexpression, but increased by circHIPK3 silencing. We showed that circHIPK3 was a scaffold for p21 mRNA-binding protein HuR and E3 ubiquitin ligase β-TrCP. circHIPK3 silencing weakened the interaction between HuR and β-TrCP, reduced HuR ubiquitination, and enhanced the interaction between HuR and p21 mRNA. Moreover, we found that mice injected with human umbilical cord mesenchymal stem cell-derived exosomes (UMSC-Exos) showed increased circHIPK3 levels, decreased levels of p21, longer telomere length, and good cardiac function. However, these beneficial effects exerted by UMSC-Exos were inhibited by silencing circHIPK3.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; We successfully generated CM-specific CKO mice for aging research. Our results showed that deletion of circHIPK3 led to exaggerated CM senescence and decreased cardiac function. As a scaffold, circHIPK3 enhanced the binding of E3 ubiquitin ligase β-TrCP and HuR in the cytoplasm, leading to the ubiquitination and degradation of HuR and reduced p21 activity. In addition, UMSC-Exos exerted an anti-senescence and cardio-protective effect by delivering circHIPK3. These findings pave the way to the development of new therapies for aging associated cardiac dysfunction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Histone Lactylation Boosts Reparative Gene Activation Post-Myocardial Infarction</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36268709/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36268709/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Inflammation resolution and cardiac repair initiation after myocardial infarction (MI) require timely activation of reparative signals. Histone lactylation confers macrophage homeostatic gene expression signatures via transcriptional regulation. However, the role of histone lactylation in the repair response post-MI remains unclear. We aimed to investigate whether histone lactylation induces reparative gene expression in monocytes early and remotely post-MI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; Single-cell transcriptome data indicated that reparative genes were activated early and remotely in bone marrow and circulating monocytes before cardiac recruitment. Western blotting and immunofluorescence staining revealed increases in histone lactylation levels, including the previously identified histone H3K18 lactylation in monocyte-macrophages early post-MI. Through joint CUT&amp;amp;Tag and RNA-sequencing analyses, we identified Lrg1, Vegf-a, and IL-10 as histone H3K18 lactylation target genes. The increased modification and expression levels of these target genes post-MI were verified by chromatin immunoprecipitation-qPCR and reverse transcription-qPCR.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; We demonstrated that histone lactylation regulates the anti-inflammatory and pro-angiogenic dual activities of monocyte-macrophages by facilitating reparative gene transcription and confirmed that histone lactylation favors a reparative environment and improves cardiac function post-MI. Furthermore, we explored the potential positive role of monocyte histone lactylation in reperfused MI. Mechanistically, we provided new evidence that monocytes undergo metabolic reprogramming in the early stage of MI and demonstrated that dysregulated glycolysis and MCT1 (monocarboxylate transporter 1)-mediated lactate transport promote histone lactylation. Finally, we revealed the catalytic effect of IL (interleukin)-1β-dependent GCN5 (general control non-depressible 5) recruitment on histone H3K18 lactylation and elucidated its potential role as an upstream regulatory element in the regulation of monocyte histone lactylation and downstream reparative gene expression post-MI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; Histone lactylation promotes early remote activation of the reparative transcriptional response in monocytes, which is essential for the establishment of immune homeostasis and timely activation of the cardiac repair process post-MI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gallic, ellagic acids and their oral combined administration induce kidney, lung, and heart injury after acute exposure in Wistar rats</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36272503/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36272503/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gallic (GA) and ellagic (EA) acids are present in foods, medicinal plants, teas, and dietary supplements. An acute toxicological study was conducted by oral administration of both compounds alone (200, 1000, and 2000 mg/kg) and combined (2000 mg/kg) and their effects on the electron transport chain (ETC) and the ROS production in kidney mitochondria further evaluated. All treatments induced a dose-dependent heart, lung, and kidney injury. However, the intensity of these effects varied according to the substance, with greater cardiac and renal toxicity for EA and pulmonary injury for GA, while the combination attenuated the toxicity of the isolated molecules. All substances inhibited the activity of complexes II, III, and IV of the ETC from renal mitochondria. However, no changes were observed regarding mitochondrial ROS production. These compounds have a non-negligible inherent deleterious potential, so their uncontrolled use at high doses (≥200 mg/kg) could cause undesirable effects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Liver-heart cross-talk mediated by coagulation factor XI protects against heart failure</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36137043/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36137043/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tissue-tissue communication by endocrine factors is a vital mechanism for physiologic homeostasis. A systems genetics analysis of transcriptomic and functional data from a cohort of diverse, inbred strains of mice predicted that coagulation factor XI (FXI), a liver-derived protein, protects against diastolic dysfunction, a key trait of heart failure with preserved ejection fraction. This was confirmed using gain- and loss-of-function studies, and FXI was found to activate the bone morphogenetic protein (BMP)-SMAD1/5 pathway in the heart. The proteolytic activity of FXI is required for the cleavage and activation of extracellular matrix-associated BMP7 in the heart, thus inhibiting genes involved in inflammation and fibrosis. Our results reveal a protective role of FXI in heart injury that is distinct from its role in coagulation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multi-species meta-analysis identifies transcriptional signatures associated with cardiac endothelial responses in the ischaemic heart</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36082978/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36082978/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Aim:&lt;/em&gt; Myocardial infarction remains the leading cause of heart failure. The adult human heart lacks the capacity to undergo endogenous regeneration. New blood vessel growth is integral to regenerative medicine necessitating a comprehensive understanding of the pathways that regulate vascular regeneration. We sought to define the transcriptomic dynamics of coronary endothelial cells following ischaemic injuries in the developing and adult mouse and human heart and to identify new mechanistic insights and targets for cardiovascular regeneration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods and results:&lt;/em&gt; We carried out a comprehensive meta-analysis of integrated single cell RNA-sequencing data of coronary vascular endothelial cells from the developing and adult mouse and human heart spanning healthy and acute and chronic ischaemic cardiac disease. We identified species-conserved gene regulatory pathways aligned to endogenous neovascularisation. We annotated injury-associated temporal shifts of the endothelial transcriptome and validated four genes: VEGF-C, KLF4, EGR1 and ZFP36. Moreover, we showed that ZFP36 regulates human coronary endothelial cell proliferation and defined that VEGF-C administration in vivo enhances clonal expansion of the cardiac vasculature post-myocardial infarction. Finally, we constructed a coronary endothelial cell meta-atlas, CrescENDO, to empower future in-depth research to target pathways associated with coronary neovascularisation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/em&gt; We present a high-resolution single cell meta-atlas of healthy and injured coronary endothelial cells in the mouse and human heart, revealing a suite of novel targets with great potential to promote vascular regeneration, and providing a rich resource for therapeutic development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Translational perspective:&lt;/em&gt; Myocardial infarction is the leading cause of heart failure, a condition with high morbidity and mortality. Vascular regeneration is vital to tissue survival and functional restoration while a comprehensive understanding of the underpinning mechanisms is lacking. We show that the meta-analysis of single cell RNA-sequencing data excels at deciphering multi-faceted vascular responses conserved between mouse and human following ischaemic injury. We envision that these data will inform future strategies and accelerate therapeutic development for promoting vascular regeneration in the ischaemic heart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Molecular Mechanisms of Ferroptosis and Relevance to Cardiovascular Disease</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/36078133/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/36078133/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ferroptosis has recently been demonstrated to be a novel regulated non-apoptotic cell death characterized by iron-dependence and the accumulation of lipid peroxidation that results in membrane damage. Excessive iron induces ferroptosis by promoting the generation of both soluble and lipid ROS via an iron-dependent Fenton reaction and lipoxygenase (LOX) enzyme activity. Cytosolic glutathione peroxidase 4 (cGPX4) pairing with ferroptosis suppressor protein 1 (FSP1) and mitochondrial glutathione peroxidase 4 (mGPX4) pairing with dihydroorotate dehydrogenase (DHODH) serve as two separate defense systems to detoxify lipid peroxidation in the cytoplasmic as well as the mitochondrial membrane, thereby defending against ferroptosis in cells under normal conditions. However, disruption of these defense systems may cause ferroptosis. Emerging evidence has revealed that ferroptosis plays an essential role in the development of diverse cardiovascular diseases (CVDs), such as hemochromatosis-associated cardiomyopathy, doxorubicin-induced cardiotoxicity, ischemia/reperfusion (I/R) injury, heart failure (HF), atherosclerosis, and COVID-19-related arrhythmias. Iron chelators, antioxidants, ferroptosis inhibitors, and genetic manipulations may alleviate the aforementioned CVDs by blocking ferroptosis pathways. In conclusion, ferroptosis plays a critical role in the pathogenesis of various CVDs and suppression of cardiac ferroptosis is expected to become a potential therapeutic option. Here, we provide a comprehensive review on the molecular mechanisms involved in ferroptosis and its implications in cardiovascular disease.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inhibition of the cardiac fibroblast-enriched histone methyltransferase Dot1L prevents cardiac fibrosis and cardiac dysfunction</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35986422/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35986422/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Cardiac fibrosis is characterized by excessive extracellular matrix deposition that contributes to compromised cardiac function and potentially heart failure. Disruptor of telomeric silencing 1-like (Dot1L) is the catalytic enzyme required for histone H3K79 methylation which has been demonstrated to play a role in transcriptional activation. However, the functions of Dot1L in the process of cardiac fibrosis still remain unknown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; In the present study, we found that endogenous Dot1L is upregulated in cardiac fibroblasts (CFs) treated with angiotensin II (Ang II) or transforming growth factor (TGF)-β1, along with elevated extracellular matrix (ECM) such as fibronectin, collagen I and III. Silencing or inhibiting Dot1L mitigated Ang II-induced myofibroblast generation and fibrogenesis. We identified the transcription factor-forkhead box O (FoxO) 3a as a novel substrate of Dot1L, the transcriptional activating mark H3K79me3 level on the promoter of FoxO3a was increase in activated-CFs, and inhibition of Dot1L markedly decreased FoxO3a transcription accompanied by a significant decrease in the expression of fibrogenic gene. Knockdown of FoxO3a could alleviate ECM deposition induced by Ang II, on the contrary, overexpression FoxO3a resulting in CFs activation. Consistently, in vivo Dot1L ablation rescued myocardial ischemia-induced cardiac fibrosis and improved cardiac function.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; Our findings conclude that upregulation of Dot1L results in activation of the cardiac fibroblasts to promote profibrotic gene, eventually causes cardiac fibrosis. Pharmacological targeting for Dot1L might represent a promising therapeutic approach for the treatment of human cardiac fibrosis and other fibrotic diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ischemia-Selective Cardioprotection by Malonate for Ischemia/Reperfusion Injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35959683/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35959683/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Inhibiting SDH (succinate dehydrogenase), with the competitive inhibitor malonate, has shown promise in ameliorating ischemia/reperfusion injury. However, key for translation to the clinic is understanding the mechanism of malonate entry into cells to enable inhibition of SDH, its mitochondrial target, as malonate itself poorly permeates cellular membranes. The possibility of malonate selectively entering the at-risk heart tissue on reperfusion, however, remains unexplored.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; C57BL/6J mice, C2C12 and H9c2 myoblasts, and HeLa cells were used to elucidate the mechanism of selective malonate uptake into the ischemic heart upon reperfusion. Cells were treated with malonate while varying pH or together with transport inhibitors. Mouse hearts were either perfused ex vivo (Langendorff) or subjected to in vivo left anterior descending coronary artery ligation as models of ischemia/reperfusion injury. Succinate and malonate levels were assessed by liquid chromatography-tandem mass spectrometry LC-MS/MS, in vivo by mass spectrometry imaging, and infarct size by TTC (2,3,5-triphenyl-2H-tetrazolium chloride) staining.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; Malonate was robustly protective against cardiac ischemia/reperfusion injury, but only if administered at reperfusion and not when infused before ischemia. The extent of malonate uptake into the heart was proportional to the duration of ischemia. Malonate entry into cardiomyocytes in vivo and in vitro was dramatically increased at the low pH (≈6.5) associated with ischemia. This increased uptake of malonate was blocked by selective inhibition of MCT1 (monocarboxylate transporter 1). Reperfusion of the ischemic heart region with malonate led to selective SDH inhibition in the at-risk region. Acid-formulation greatly enhances the cardioprotective potency of malonate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; Cardioprotection by malonate is dependent on its entry into cardiomyocytes. This is facilitated by the local decrease in pH that occurs during ischemia, leading to its selective uptake upon reperfusion into the at-risk tissue, via MCT1. Thus, malonate&amp;rsquo;s preferential uptake in reperfused tissue means it is an at-risk tissue-selective drug that protects against cardiac ischemia/reperfusion injury.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mitochondrial quality control in cardiac ischemia/reperfusion injury: new insights into mechanisms and implications</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/35951200/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/35951200/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The current effective method for the treatment of myocardial infarction is timely restoration of the blood supply to the ischemic area of the heart. Although reperfusion is essential for reestablishing oxygen and nutrient supplies, it often leads to additional myocardial damage, creating an important clinical dilemma. Reports from long-term studies have confirmed that mitochondrial damage is the critical mechanism in cardiac ischemia/reperfusion (I/R) injury. Mitochondria are dynamic and possess a quality control system that targets mitochondrial quantity and quality by modifying mitochondrial fusion, fission, mitophagy, and biogenesis and protein homeostasis to maintain a healthy mitochondrial network. The system of mitochondrial quality control involves complex molecular machinery that is highly interconnected and associated with pathological changes such as oxidative stress, calcium overload, and endoplasmic reticulum (ER) stress. Because of the critical role of the mitochondrial quality control systems, many reports have suggested that defects in this system are among the molecular mechanisms underlying myocardial reperfusion injury. In this review, we briefly summarize the important role of the mitochondrial quality control in cardiomyocyte function and focus on the current understanding of the regulatory mechanisms and molecular pathways involved in mitochondrial quality control in cardiac I/R damage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spatial multi-omic map of human myocardial infarction</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35948637/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35948637/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Myocardial infarction is a leading cause of death worldwide1. Although advances have been made in acute treatment, an incomplete understanding of remodelling processes has limited the effectiveness of therapies to reduce late-stage mortality2. Here we generate an integrative high-resolution map of human cardiac remodelling after myocardial infarction using single-cell gene expression, chromatin accessibility and spatial transcriptomic profiling of multiple physiological zones at distinct time points in myocardium from patients with myocardial infarction and controls. Multi-modal data integration enabled us to evaluate cardiac cell-type compositions at increased resolution, yielding insights into changes of the cardiac transcriptome and epigenome through the identification of distinct tissue structures of injury, repair and remodelling. We identified and validated disease-specific cardiac cell states of major cell types and analysed them in their spatial context, evaluating their dependency on other cell types. Our data elucidate the molecular principles of human myocardial tissue organization, recapitulating a gradual cardiomyocyte and myeloid continuum following ischaemic injury. In sum, our study provides an integrative molecular map of human myocardial infarction, represents an essential reference for the field and paves the way for advanced mechanistic and therapeutic studies of cardiac disease.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Origin and function of activated fibroblast states during zebrafish heart regeneration</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35864193/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35864193/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The adult zebrafish heart has a high capacity for regeneration following injury. However, the composition of the regenerative niche has remained largely elusive. Here, we dissected the diversity of activated cell states in the regenerating zebrafish heart based on single-cell transcriptomics and spatiotemporal analysis. We observed the emergence of several transient cell states with fibroblast characteristics following injury, and we outlined the proregenerative function of collagen-12-expressing fibroblasts. To understand the cascade of events leading to heart regeneration, we determined the origin of these cell states by high-throughput lineage tracing. We found that activated fibroblasts were derived from two separate sources: the epicardium and the endocardium. Mechanistically, we determined Wnt signalling as a regulator of the endocardial fibroblast response. In summary, our work identifies specialized activated fibroblast cell states that contribute to heart regeneration, thereby opening up possible approaches to modulating the regenerative capacity of the vertebrate heart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wildfires and extracellular vesicles: Exosomal MicroRNAs as mediators of cross-tissue cardiopulmonary responses to biomass smoke</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35863239/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35863239/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Multiple wildfire-relevant exposure conditions were tested in mice.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Extracellular vesicles (EVs) were evaluated in circulating plasma.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Exposures altered EV-encapsulated microRNAs involved in cell stress and hypoxia.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Exposures disrupted cell stress and hypoxia pathways in lung and heart tissues.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enhanced responses occurred from flaming vs. smoldering burn conditions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Introduction:&lt;/em&gt; Wildfires are a threat to public health world-wide that are growing in intensity and prevalence. The biological mechanisms that elicit wildfire-associated toxicity remain largely unknown. The potential involvement of cross-tissue communication via extracellular vesicles (EVs) is a new mechanism that has yet to be evaluated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; Female CD-1 mice were exposed to smoke condensate samples collected from the following biomass burn scenarios: flaming peat; smoldering peat; flaming red oak; and smoldering red oak, representing lab-based simulations of wildfire scenarios. Lung tissue, bronchoalveolar lavage fluid (BALF) samples, peripheral blood, and heart tissues were collected 4 and 24 h post-exposure. Exosome-enriched EVs were isolated from plasma, physically characterized, and profiled for microRNA (miRNA) expression. Pathway-level responses in the lung and heart were evaluated through RNA sequencing and pathway analyses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; Markers of cardiopulmonary tissue injury and inflammation from BALF samples were significantly altered in response to exposures, with the greatest changes occurring from flaming biomass conditions. Plasma EV miRNAs relevant to cardiovascular disease showed exposure-induced expression alterations, including miR-150, miR-183, miR-223-3p, miR-30b, and miR-378a. Lung and heart mRNAs were identified with differential expression enriched for hypoxia and cell stress-related pathways. Flaming red oak exposure induced the greatest transcriptional response in the heart, a large portion of which were predicted as regulated by plasma EV miRNAs, including miRNAs known to regulate hypoxia-induced cardiovascular injury. Many of these miRNAs had published evidence supporting their transfer across tissues. A follow-up analysis of miR-30b showed that it was increased in expression in the heart of exposed mice in the absence of changes to its precursor molecular, pri-miR-30b, suggesting potential transfer from external sources (e.g., plasma).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Discussion:&lt;/em&gt; This study posits a potential mechanism through which wildfire exposures induce cardiopulmonary responses, highlighting the role of circulating plasma EVs in intercellular and systems-level communication between tissues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AAV capsid engineering identified two novel variants with improved in vivo tropism for cardiomyocytes</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35810332/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35810332/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AAV vectors are promising delivery tools for human gene therapy. However, broad tissue tropism and pre-existing immunity against natural serotypes limit their clinical use. We identified two AAV capsid variants, AAV2-THGTPAD and AAV2-NLPGSGD, by in vivo AAV2 peptide display library screening in a murine model of pressure overload-induced cardiac hypertrophy. Both variants showed significantly improved efficacy in in vivo cardiomyocyte transduction compared with the parental serotype AAV2 as indicated by a higher number of AAV vector episomes in the nucleus and significant improved transduction efficiency. Both variants also outcompeted the reference serotype AAV9 regarding cardiomyocyte tropism, reaching comparable cardiac transduction efficiencies accompanied with liver de-targeting and decreased transduction efficiency of non-cardiac cells. Capsid modification influenced immunogenicity as sera of mice treated with AAV2-THGTPAD and AAV2-NLPGSGD demonstrated a poor neutralization capacity for the parental serotype and the novel variants. In a therapeutic setting, using the long non-coding RNA H19 in low vector dose conditions, novel AAV variants mediated superior anti-hypertrophic effects and revealed a further improved target-to-noise ratio, i.e., cardiomyocyte tropism. In conclusion, AAV2-THGTPAD and AAV2-NLPGSGD are promising novel tools for cardiac-directed gene therapy outperforming AAV9 regarding the specificity and therapeutic efficiency of in vivo cardiomyocyte transduction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WDR62 variants contribute to congenital heart disease by inhibiting cardiomyocyte proliferation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35808830/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35808830/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Congenital heart disease (CHD) is the most common birth defect and has high heritability. Although some susceptibility genes have been identified, the genetic basis underlying the majority of CHD cases is still undefined.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; A total of 1320 unrelated CHD patients were enrolled in our study. Exome-wide association analysis between 37 tetralogy of Fallot (TOF) patients and 208 Han Chinese controls from the 1000 Genomes Project was performed to identify the novel candidate gene WD repeat-containing protein 62 (&lt;em&gt;WDR62&lt;/em&gt;). &lt;em&gt;WDR62&lt;/em&gt; variants were searched in another expanded set of 200 TOF patients by Sanger sequencing. Rescue experiments in zebrafish were conducted to observe the effects of &lt;em&gt;WDR62&lt;/em&gt; variants. The roles of WDR62 in heart development were examined in mouse models with &lt;em&gt;Wdr62&lt;/em&gt; deficiency. &lt;em&gt;WDR62&lt;/em&gt; variants were investigated in an additional 1083 CHD patients with similar heart phenotypes to knockout mice by multiplex PCR-targeting sequencing. The cellular phenotypes of &lt;em&gt;WDR62&lt;/em&gt; deficiency and variants were tested in cardiomyocytes, and the molecular mechanisms were preliminarily explored by RNA-seq and co-immunoprecipitation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; Seven &lt;em&gt;WDR62&lt;/em&gt; coding variants were identified in the 237 TOF patients and all were indicated to be loss of function variants. A total of 25 coding and 22 non-coding &lt;em&gt;WDR62&lt;/em&gt; variants were identified in 80 (6%) of the 1320 CHD cases sequenced, with a higher proportion of &lt;em&gt;WDR62&lt;/em&gt; variation (8%) found in the ventricular septal defect (VSD) cohort. &lt;em&gt;WDR62&lt;/em&gt; deficiency resulted in a series of heart defects affecting the outflow tract and right ventricle in mouse models, including VSD as the major abnormality. Cell cycle arrest and an increased number of cells with multipolar spindles that inhibited proliferation were observed in cardiomyocytes with variants or knockdown of &lt;em&gt;WDR62&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;em&gt;WDR62&lt;/em&gt; deficiency weakened the association between WDR62 and the cell cycle-regulated kinase AURKA on spindle poles, reduced the phosphorylation of AURKA, and decreased expression of target genes related to cell cycle and spindle assembly shared by WDR62 and AURKA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;WDR62&lt;/em&gt; was identified as a novel susceptibility gene for CHD with high variant frequency. WDR62 was shown to participate in the cardiac development by affecting spindle assembly and cell cycle pathway in cardiomyocytes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CircRNA Samd4 induces cardiac repair after myocardial infarction by blocking mitochondria-derived ROS output</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35791879/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35791879/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reactive oxygen species (ROS) derived from oxygen-dependent mitochondrial metabolism are the essential drivers of cardiomyocyte (CM) cell-cycle arrest in adulthood. Mitochondria-localized circular RNAs (circRNAs) play important roles in regulating mitochondria-derived ROS production, but their functions in cardiac regeneration are still unknown. Herein, we investigated the functions and underlying mechanism of mitochondria-localized circSamd4 in cardiac regeneration. We found that circSamd4 was selectively expressed in fetal and neonatal CMs. The transcription factor Nrf2 controlled circSamd4 expression by binding to the promoter of circSamd4 host gene. CircSamd4 overexpression reduced while circSamd4 silenced increased mitochondrial oxidative stress and subsequent oxidative DNA damage. Moreover, circSamd4 overexpression induced CM proliferation and prevented CM apoptosis, which reduced the size of the fibrotic area and improved cardiac function after myocardial infarction (MI). Mechanistically, circSamd4 reduced oxidative stress generation and maintained mitochondrial dynamics by inducing the mitochondrial translocation of the Vcp protein, which downregulated Vdac1 expression and prevented the mitochondrial permeability transition pore (mPTP) from opening. Our findings suggest that circSamd4 is a novel therapeutic target for heart failure after MI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A circular RNA derived from the insulin receptor locus protects against doxorubicin-induced cardiotoxicity</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35758064/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35758064/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Aims:&lt;/em&gt; Cardiotoxicity leading to heart failure (HF) is a growing problem in many cancer survivors. As specific treatment strategies are not available, RNA discovery pipelines were employed and a new and powerful circular RNA (circRNA)-based therapy was developed for the treatment of doxorubicin-induced HF.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods and results:&lt;/em&gt; The circRNA sequencing was applied and the highly species-conserved circRNA insulin receptor (Circ-INSR) was identified, which participates in HF processes, including those provoked by cardiotoxic anti-cancer treatments. Chemotherapy-provoked cardiotoxicity leads to the down-regulation of Circ-INSR in rodents and patients, which mechanistically contributes to cardiomyocyte cell death, cardiac dysfunction, and mitochondrial damage. In contrast, Circ-INSR overexpression prevented doxorubicin-mediated cardiotoxicity in both rodent and human cardiomyocytes in vitro and in a mouse model of chronic doxorubicin cardiotoxicity. Breast cancer type 1 susceptibility protein (Brca1) was identified as a regulator of Circ-INSR expression. Detailed transcriptomic and proteomic analyses revealed that Circ-INSR regulates apoptotic and metabolic pathways in cardiomyocytes. Circ-INSR physically interacts with the single-stranded DNA-binding protein (SSBP1) mediating its cardioprotective effects under doxorubicin stress. Importantly, in vitro transcribed and circularized Circ-INSR mimics also protected against doxorubicin-induced cardiotoxicity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/em&gt; Circ-INSR is a highly conserved non-coding RNA which is down-regulated during cardiotoxicity and cardiac remodelling. Adeno-associated virus and circRNA mimics-based Circ-INSR overexpression prevent and reverse doxorubicin-mediated cardiomyocyte death and improve cardiac function. The results of this study highlight a novel and translationally important Circ-INSR-based therapeutic approach for doxorubicin-induced cardiac dysfunction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Liquiritigenin protects against myocardial ischemic by inhibiting oxidative stress, apoptosis, and L-type Ca2&#43; channels</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35747908/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35747908/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Liquiritigenin (Lq) offers cytoprotective effects against various cardiac injuries, but its beneficial effects on myocardial ischemic (MI) injury and the related mechanisms remain unclear. In the in vivo study, an animal model of MI was induced by intraperitoneal injection of isoproterenol (Iso, 85 mg/kg). ECG, heart rate, serum levels of CK and CK-MB, histopathological changes, and reactive oxygen species (ROS) levels were all measured. In vitro, H9c2 cells were divided into four groups and treated for 24 hr with liquiritigenin (30 μmol/L and 100 μmol/L) followed with CoCl&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; (800 μmol/L) for another 24 hr. Cell viability, apoptosis, mitochondrial membrane potential, and intracellular Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt; concentration ([Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt; ]&lt;sub&gt;i&lt;/sub&gt;) were then assessed. The L-type Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt; current (I&lt;sub&gt;Ca-L&lt;/sub&gt;) was detected using a patch clamp technique on isolated rat ventricular myocytes. The myocyte contraction and Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt; transients were measured using an IonOptix detection system. The remarkable cardiac injury and generation of intracellular ROS induced by Iso were alleviated via treatment with Lq. CoCl&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; administration induced cell apoptosis, mitochondrial dysfunction, and Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt; overload in H9c2; Lq reduces these deleterious effects of CoCl&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;. Meanwhile, Lq blocked I&lt;sub&gt;Ca-L&lt;/sub&gt; in a dose-dependent manner. The half-maximal inhibitory concentration of Lq was 110.87 μmol/L. Lq reversibly reduced the amplitude of cell contraction as well as the Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt; transients. The results show that Lq protects against MI injury by antioxidation, antiapoptosis, counteraction mitochondrial dysfunction, and inhibition of I&lt;sub&gt;Ca-L&lt;/sub&gt;, thus damping intracellular Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Whole transcriptome sequencing analysis revealed key RNA profiles and toxicity in mice after chronic exposure to microplastics</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35718033/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35718033/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Investigating the long-term effects of microplastics (MPs) in vivo is necessary for evaluating its biological toxicity. Previously, we showed that MPs elicit vascular dysfunctions in atherosclerotic mice. However, the effects of long-term treatment with environmental levels of MPs on biological functions and RNA expression profiles in wild-type mice are unknown. Here, C57BL/6 mice were administered 1000 μg/L MPs through their drinking water for 180 days. Transcriptomic analyses, biochemical analysis, and histopathological examination were conducted to determine the key signals and molecular mechanisms triggered by MPs in vivo using whole transcriptome sequencing, enzyme-linked immunosorbent assay, and histopathological analysis. Notably, our data revealed that MPs aggravated vascular lesions and organ injuries, particularly liver, kidney, and heart injuries. Additionally, MPs exacerbated oxidative injuries by inhibiting the activities of antioxidant enzymes and increasing the levels of the serum biochemistry indicator of organ damage. RNA sequencing of vascular tissues showed that 674 mRNAs, 39 lncRNAs, 196 miRNAs, and 565 circRNAs were abnormally expressed in MPs-treated mice compared with the untreated group. Pathway enrichment analyses identified pathways linked to the toxicity of MPs, including lysosomal, NOD-like receptor, and peroxisome proliferator-activated receptor pathways. Additionally, competing endogenous RNA networks were constructed and hub RNAs were identified using bioinformatics analysis. Taken together, our data suggested that toxicity induced by long-term exposure to MPs continually presents with extensive changes in biological features and global gene expression profiles. Our data provides new insights into the biological toxicity of MPs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MG53 Inhibits Necroptosis Through Ubiquitination-Dependent RIPK1 Degradation for Cardiac Protection Following Ischemia/Reperfusion Injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35711363/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35711363/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rationale:&lt;/em&gt; While reactive oxygen species (ROS) has been recognized as one of the main causes of cardiac injury following myocardial infarction, the clinical application of antioxidants has shown limited effects on protecting hearts against ischemia-reperfusion (I/R) injury. Thus, the precise role of ROS following cardiac injury remains to be fully elucidated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Objective:&lt;/em&gt; We investigated the role of mitsugumin 53 (MG53) in regulating necroptosis following I/R injury to the hearts and the involvement of ROS in MG53-mediated cardioprotection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods and results:&lt;/em&gt; Antioxidants were used to test the role of ROS in MG53-mediated cardioprotection in the mouse model of I/R injury and induced human pluripotent stem cells (hiPSCs)-derived cardiomyocytes subjected to hypoxia or re-oxygenation (H/R) injury. Western blotting and co-immunoprecipitation were used to identify potential cell death pathways that MG53 was involved in. CRISPR/Cas 9-mediated genome editing and mutagenesis assays were performed to further identify specific interaction amino acids between MG53 and its ubiquitin E3 ligase substrate. We found that MG53 could protect myocardial injury via inhibiting the necroptosis pathway. Upon injury, the generation of ROS in the infarct zone of the hearts promoted interaction between MG53 and receptor-interacting protein kinase 1 (RIPK1). As an E3 ubiquitin ligase, MG53 added multiple ubiquitin chains to RIPK1 at the sites of K316, K604, and K627 for proteasome-mediated RIPK1 degradation and inhibited necroptosis. The application of N-acetyl cysteine (NAC) disrupted the interaction between MG53 and RIPK1 and abolished MG53-mediated cardioprotective effects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; Taken together, this study provided a molecular mechanism of a potential beneficial role of ROS following acute myocardial infarction. Thus, fine-tuning ROS levels might be critical for cardioprotection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Effects of intracardiac delivery of aldehyde dehydrogenase 2 gene in myocardial salvage</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35606494/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35606494/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Intrinsic activity of aldehyde dehydrogenase (ALDH)2, a cardiac mitochondrial enzyme, is vital in detoxifying 4-hydroxy-2-nonenal (4HNE) like cellular reactive carbonyl species (RCS) and thereby conferring cardiac protection against pathological stress. It was also known that a single point mutation (E487K) in ALDH2 (prevalent in East Asians) known as ALDH2&lt;em&gt;2 reduces its activity intrinsically and was associated with increased cardiovascular diseases. We and others have shown that ALDH2 activity is reduced in several pathologies in WT animals as well. Thus, exogenous augmentation of ALDH2 activity is a good strategy to protect the myocardium from pathologies. In this study, we will test the efficacy of intracardiac injections of the ALDH2 gene in mice. We injected both wild type (WT) and ALDH2&lt;/em&gt;2 knock-in mutant mice with ALDH2 constructs, AAv9-cTNT-hALDH2-HA tag-P2A-eGFP or their control constructs, AAv9-cTNT-eGFP. We found that intracardiac ALDH2 gene transfer increased myocardial levels of ALDH2 compared to GFP alone after 1 and 3 weeks. When we subjected the hearts of these mice to 30 min global ischemia and 90 min reperfusion (I-R) using the Langendorff perfusion system, we found reduced infarct size in the hearts of mice with ALDH2 gene vs GFP alone. A single time injection has shown increased myocardial ALDH2 activity for at least 3 weeks and reduced myocardial 4HNE adducts and infarct size along with increased contractile function of the hearts while subjected to I-R. Thus, ALDH2 overexpression protected the myocardium from I-R injury by reducing 4HNE protein adducts implicating increased 4HNE detoxification by ALDH2. In conclusion, intracardiac ALDH2 gene transfer is an effective strategy to protect the myocardium from pathological insults.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gene set enrichment analysis: a knowledge-based approach for interpreting genome-wide expression profiles</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35673580/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35673580/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background and Purpose:&lt;/em&gt; Myocardial infarction (MI) in diabetic patients results in higher mortality and morbidity. We and others have previously shown that bone marrow-endothelial progenitor cells (EPCs) promote cardiac neovascularization and attenuate ischemic injury. Lately, small extracellular vesicles (EVs) have emerged as major paracrine effectors mediating the benefits of stem cell therapy. Modest clinical outcomes of autologous cell-based therapies suggest diabetes-induced EPC dysfunction and may also reflect their EV derivatives. Moreover, studies suggest that post-translational histone modifications promote diabetes-induced vascular dysfunctions. Therefore, we tested the hypothesis that diabetic EPC-EVs may lose their post-injury cardiac reparative function by modulating histone modification in endothelial cells (ECs).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; We collected EVs from the culture medium of EPCs isolated from non-diabetic (db/+) and diabetic (db/db) mice and examined their effects on recipient ECs and cardiomyocytes &lt;em&gt;in vitro&lt;/em&gt;, and their reparative function in permanent ligation of left anterior descending (LAD) coronary artery and ischemia/reperfusion (I/R) myocardial ischemic injuries &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; Compared to db/+ EPC-EVs, db/db EPC-EVs promoted EC and cardiomyocyte apoptosis and repressed tube-forming capacity of ECs. &lt;em&gt;In vivo&lt;/em&gt;, db/db EPC-EVs depressed cardiac function, reduced capillary density, and increased fibrosis compared to db/+ EPC-EV treatments after MI. Moreover, in the I/R MI model, db/+ EPC-EV-mediated acute cardio-protection was lost with db/db EPC-EVs, and db/db EPC-EVs increased immune cell infiltration, infarct area, and plasma cardiac troponin-I. Mechanistically, histone 3 lysine 9 acetylation (H3K9Ac) was significantly decreased in cardiac ECs treated with db/db EPC-EVs compared to db/+ EPC-EVs. The H3K9Ac chromatin immunoprecipitation sequencing (ChIP-Seq) results further revealed that db/db EPC-EVs reduced H3K9Ac level on angiogenic, cell survival, and proliferative genes in cardiac ECs. We found that the histone deacetylase (HDAC) inhibitor, valproic acid (VPA), partly restored diabetic EPC-EV-impaired H3K9Ac levels, tube formation and viability of ECs, and enhanced cell survival and proliferative genes, &lt;em&gt;Pdgfd&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Sox12&lt;/em&gt;, expression. Moreover, we observed that VPA treatment improved db/db EPC-mediated post-MI cardiac repair and functions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; Our findings unravel that diabetes impairs EPC-EV reparative function in the ischemic heart, at least partially, through HDACs-mediated H3K9Ac downregulation leading to transcriptional suppression of angiogenic, proliferative and cell survival genes in recipient cardiac ECs. Thus, HDAC inhibitors may potentially be used to restore the function of diabetic EPC and other stem cells for autologous cell therapy applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HDAC6 modulates myofibril stiffness and diastolic function of the heart</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35575093/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35575093/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Passive stiffness of the heart is determined largely by extracellular matrix and titin, which functions as a molecular spring within sarcomeres. Titin stiffening is associated with the development of diastolic dysfunction (DD), while augmented titin compliance appears to impair systolic performance in dilated cardiomyopathy. We found that myofibril stiffness was elevated in mice lacking histone deacetylase 6 (HDAC6). Cultured adult murine ventricular myocytes treated with a selective HDAC6 inhibitor also exhibited increased myofibril stiffness. Conversely, HDAC6 overexpression in cardiomyocytes led to decreased myofibril stiffness, as did ex vivo treatment of mouse, rat, and human myofibrils with recombinant HDAC6. Modulation of myofibril stiffness by HDAC6 was dependent on 282 amino acids encompassing a portion of the PEVK element of titin. HDAC6 colocalized with Z-disks, and proteomics analysis suggested that HDAC6 functions as a sarcomeric protein deacetylase. Finally, increased myofibril stiffness in HDAC6-deficient mice was associated with exacerbated DD in response to hypertension or aging. These findings define a role for a deacetylase in the control of myofibril function and myocardial passive stiffness, suggest that reversible acetylation alters titin compliance, and reveal the potential of targeting HDAC6 to manipulate the elastic properties of the heart to treat cardiac diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SEC is an antiangiogenic virulence factor that promotes Staphylococcus aureus endocarditis independent of superantigen activity</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35544579/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35544579/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The superantigen staphylococcal enterotoxin C (SEC) is critical for &lt;em&gt;Staphylococcus aureus&lt;/em&gt; infective endocarditis (SAIE) in rabbits. Superantigenicity, its hallmark function, was proposed to be a major underlying mechanism driving SAIE but was not directly tested. With the use of S. aureus MW2 expressing SEC toxoids, we show that superantigenicity does not sufficiently account for vegetation growth, myocardial inflammation, and acute kidney injury in the rabbit model of native valve SAIE. These results highlight the critical contribution of an alternative function of superantigens to SAIE. In support of this, we provide evidence that SEC exerts antiangiogenic effects by inhibiting branching microvessel formation in an ex vivo rabbit aortic ring model and by inhibiting endothelial cell expression of one of the most potent mediators of angiogenesis, VEGF-A. SEC&amp;rsquo;s ability to interfere with tissue revascularization and remodeling after injury serves as a mechanism to promote SAIE and its life-threatening systemic pathologies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extracellular vesicles enclosed-miR-421 suppresses air pollution (PM2.5)-induced cardiac dysfunction via ACE2 signalling</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35536587/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35536587/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Air pollution, via ambient PM&lt;sub&gt;2.5&lt;/sub&gt;, is a big threat to public health since it associates with increased hospitalisation, incidence rate and mortality of cardiopulmonary injury. However, the potential mediators of pulmonary injury in PM&lt;sub&gt;2.5&lt;/sub&gt;-induced cardiovascular disorder are not fully understood. To investigate a potential cross talk between lung and heart upon PM&lt;sub&gt;2.5&lt;/sub&gt; exposure, intratracheal instillation in vivo, organ culture ex vivo and human bronchial epithelial cells (Beas-2B) culture in vitro experiments were performed respectively. The exposed supernatants of Beas-2B were collected to treat primary neonatal rat cardiomyocytes (NRCMs). Upon intratracheal instillation, subacute PM&lt;sub&gt;2.5&lt;/sub&gt; exposure caused cardiac dysfunction, which was time-dependent secondary to lung injury in mice, thereby demonstrating a cross-talk between lungs and heart potentially mediated via small extracellular vesicles (sEV). We isolated sEV from PM&lt;sub&gt;2.5&lt;/sub&gt;-exposed mice serum and Beas-2B supernatants to analyse the change of sEV subpopulations in response to PM&lt;sub&gt;2.5&lt;/sub&gt;. Single particle interferometric reflectance imaging sensing analysis (SP-IRIS) demonstrated that PM&lt;sub&gt;2.5&lt;/sub&gt; increased CD63/CD81/CD9 positive particles. Our results indicated that respiratory system-derived sEV containing miR-421 contributed to cardiac dysfunction post-PM&lt;sub&gt;2.5&lt;/sub&gt; exposure. Inhibition of miR-421 by AAV9-miR421-sponge could significantly reverse PM&lt;sub&gt;2.5&lt;/sub&gt;-induced cardiac dysfunction in mice. We identified that cardiac angiotensin converting enzyme 2 (ACE2) was a downstream target of sEV-miR421, and induced myocardial cell apoptosis and cardiac dysfunction. In addition, we observed that GW4869 (an inhibitor of sEV release) or diminazene aceturate (DIZE, an activator of ACE2) treatment could attenuate PM&lt;sub&gt;2.5&lt;/sub&gt;-induced cardiac dysfunction in vivo. Taken together, our results suggest that PM&lt;sub&gt;2.5&lt;/sub&gt; exposure promotes sEV-linked miR421 release after lung injury and hereby contributes to PM&lt;sub&gt;2.5&lt;/sub&gt;-induced cardiac dysfunction via suppressing ACE2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Galectin-3 interferes with tissue repair and promotes cardiac dysfunction and comorbidities in a genetic heart failure model</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35441327/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35441327/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Galectin-3, a biomarker for heart failure (HF), has been associated with myocardial fibrosis. However, its causal involvement in HF pathogenesis has been questioned in certain models of cardiac injury-induced HF. To address this, we used desmin-deficient mice (&lt;em&gt;des&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt;), a model of progressive HF characterized by cardiomyocyte death, spontaneous inflammatory responses sustaining fibrosis, and galectin-3 overexpression. Genetic ablation or pharmacological inhibition of galectin-3 led to improvement of cardiac function and adverse remodeling features including fibrosis. Over the course of development of &lt;em&gt;des&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; cardiomyopathy, monitored for a period of 12 months, galectin-3 deficiency specifically ameliorated the decline in systolic function accompanying the acute inflammatory phase (4-week-old mice), whereas a more pronounced protective effect was observed in older mice, including the preservation of diastolic function. Interestingly, the cardiac repair activities during the early inflammatory phase were restored under galectin-3 deficiency by increasing the proliferation potential and decreasing apoptosis of fibroblasts, while galectin-3 absence modulated macrophage-fibroblast coupled functions and suppressed both pro-fibrotic activation of cardiac fibroblasts and pro-fibrotic gene expression in the &lt;em&gt;des&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; heart. In addition, galectin-3 also affected the emphysema-like comorbid pathology observed in the &lt;em&gt;des&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; mice, as its absence partially normalized lung compliance. Collectively galectin-3 was found to be causally involved in cardiac adverse remodeling, inflammation, and failure by affecting functions of cardiac fibroblasts and macrophages. In concordance with this role, the effectiveness of pharmacological inhibition in ameliorating cardiac pathology features establishes galectin-3 as a valid intervention target for HF, with additive benefits for treatment of associated comorbidities, such as pulmonary defects. Schematic illustrating top to bottom, the detrimental role of galectin-3 (Gal3) in heart failure progression: desmin deficiency-associated spontaneous myocardial inflammation accompanying cardiac cell death (reddish dashed border) is characterized by infiltration of macrophages (round cells) and up-regulation of Lgals3 (encoding secretable galectin-3, green) and detrimental macrophage-related genes (Ccr2 and Arg1). In this galectin-3-enriched milieu, the early up-regulation of profibrotic gene expression (Tgfb1, Acta2, Col1a1), in parallel to the suppression of proliferative activities and a potential of senescence induction by cardiac fibroblasts (spindle-like cells), collectively promote &lt;em&gt;des&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; cardiac fibrosis and dysfunction establishing heart failure (left panel). Additionally, galectin-3+ macrophage-enrichment accompanies the development of emphysema-like lung comorbidities. In the absence of galectin-3 (right panel), the effect of macrophage-fibroblast dipole and associated events are modulated (grey color depicts reduced expression or activities) leading to attenuated cardiac pathology in the &lt;em&gt;des&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; Lgals3&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt;_ mice. Pulmonary comorbidities are also limited.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Effects of mango and mint pod-based e-cigarette aerosol inhalation on inflammatory states of the brain, lung, heart, and colon in mice</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35411847/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35411847/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While health effects of conventional tobacco are well defined, data on vaping devices, including one of the most popular e-cigarettes which have high nicotine levels, are less established. Prior acute e-cigarette studies have demonstrated inflammatory and cardiopulmonary physiology changes while chronic studies have demonstrated extra-pulmonary effects, including neurotransmitter alterations in reward pathways. In this study we investigated the impact of inhalation of aerosols produced from pod-based, flavored e-cigarettes (JUUL) aerosols three times daily for 3 months on inflammatory markers in the brain, lung, heart, and colon. JUUL aerosol exposure induced upregulation of cytokine and chemokine gene expression and increased HMGB1 and RAGE in the nucleus accumbens in the central nervous system. Inflammatory gene expression increased in the colon, while gene expression was more broadly altered by e-cigarette aerosol inhalation in the lung. Cardiopulmonary inflammatory responses to acute lung injury with lipopolysaccharide were exacerbated in the heart. Flavor-specific findings were detected across these studies. Our findings suggest that daily e-cigarette use may cause neuroinflammation, which may contribute to behavioral changes and mood disorders. In addition, e-cigarette use may cause gut inflammation, which has been tied to poor systemic health, and cardiac inflammation, which leads to cardiovascular disease.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inhibition of BKCa channels protects neonatal hearts against myocardial ischemia and reperfusion injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35393410/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35393410/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BK&lt;sub&gt;Ca&lt;/sub&gt; channels are large-conductance calcium and voltage-activated potassium channels that are heterogeneously expressed in a wide array of cells. Activation of BK&lt;sub&gt;Ca&lt;/sub&gt; channels present in mitochondria of adult ventricular cardiomyocytes is implicated in cardioprotection against ischemia-reperfusion (IR) injury. However, the BK&lt;sub&gt;Ca&lt;/sub&gt; channel&amp;rsquo;s activity has never been detected in the plasma membrane of adult ventricular cardiomyocytes. In this study, we report the presence of the BK&lt;sub&gt;Ca&lt;/sub&gt; channel in the plasma membrane and mitochondria of neonatal murine and rodent cardiomyocytes, which protects the heart on inhibition but not activation. Furthermore, K+ currents measured in neonatal cardiomyocyte (NCM) was sensitive to iberiotoxin (IbTx), suggesting the presence of BK&lt;sub&gt;Ca&lt;/sub&gt; channels in the plasma membrane. Neonatal hearts subjected to IR when post-conditioned with NS1619 during reoxygenation increased the myocardial infarction whereas IbTx reduced the infarct size. In agreement, isolated NCM also presented increased apoptosis on treatment with NS1619 during hypoxia and reoxygenation, whereas IbTx reduced TUNEL-positive cells. In NCMs, activation of BK&lt;sub&gt;Ca&lt;/sub&gt; channels increased the intracellular reactive oxygen species post HR injury. Electrophysiological characterization of NCMs indicated that NS1619 increased the beat period, field, and action potential duration, and decreased the conduction velocity and spike amplitude. In contrast, IbTx had no impact on the electrophysiological properties of NCMs. Taken together, our data established that inhibition of plasma membrane BK&lt;sub&gt;Ca&lt;/sub&gt; channels in the NCM protects neonatal heart/cardiomyocytes from IR injury. Furthermore, the functional disparity observed towards the cardioprotective activity of BK&lt;sub&gt;Ca&lt;/sub&gt; channels in adults compared to neonatal heart could be attributed to their differential localization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neurologic Prognostication After Cardiac Arrest Using Brain Biomarkers: A Systematic Review and Meta-analysis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35226054/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35226054/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Importance:&lt;/em&gt; Brain injury biomarkers released into circulation from the injured neurovascular unit are important prognostic tools in patients with cardiac arrest who develop hypoxic ischemic brain injury (HIBI) after return of spontaneous circulation (ROSC).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Objective:&lt;/em&gt; To assess the neuroprognostic utility of bloodborne brain injury biomarkers in patients with cardiac arrest with HIBI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Data sources:&lt;/em&gt; Studies in electronic databases from inception to September 15, 2021. These databases included MEDLINE, Embase, Evidence-Based Medicine Reviews, CINAHL, Cochrane Database of Systematic Reviews, and the World Health Organization Global Health Library.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Study selection:&lt;/em&gt; Articles included in this systmatic review and meta-analysis were independently assessed by 2 reviewers. We included studies that investigated neuron-specific enolase, S100 calcium-binding protein β, glial fibrillary acidic protein, neurofilament light, tau, or ubiquitin carboxyl hydrolase L1 in patients with cardiac arrest aged 18 years and older for neurologic prognostication. We excluded studies that did not (1) dichotomize neurologic outcome as favorable vs unfavorable, (2) specify the timing of blood sampling or outcome determination, or (3) report diagnostic test accuracy or biomarker concentration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Data extraction and synthesis:&lt;/em&gt; Data on the study design, inclusion and exclusion criteria, brain biomarkers levels, diagnostic test accuracy, and neurologic outcome were recorded. This study was conducted in accordance with the Preferred Reporting Items for Systematic Reviews and Meta-Analyses (PRISMA) guideline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Main outcomes and measures:&lt;/em&gt; Summary receiver operating characteristic curve analysis was used to calculate the area under the curve, sensitivity, specificity, and optimal thresholds for each biomarker. Risk of bias and concerns of applicability were assessed with the Quality Assessment of Diagnostic Accuracy Studies (QUADAS-2) tool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; We identified 2953 studies, of which 86 studies with 10 567 patients (7777 men [73.6] and 2790 women [26.4]; pooled mean [SD] age, 62.8 [10.2] years) were included. Biomarker analysis at 48 hours after ROSC demonstrated that neurofilament light had the highest predictive value for unfavorable neurologic outcome, with an area under the curve of 0.92 (95% CI, 0.84-0.97). Subgroup analyses of patients treated with targeted temperature management and those who specifically had an out-of-hospital cardiac arrest showed similar results (targeted temperature management, 0.92 [95% CI, 0.86-0.95] and out-of-hospital cardiac arrest, 0.93 [95% CI, 0.86-0.97]).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions and relevance:&lt;/em&gt; Neurofilament light, which reflects white matter damage and axonal injury, yielded the highest accuracy in predicting neurologic outcome in patients with HIBI at 48 hours after ROSC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A nitric oxide-eluting and REDV peptide-conjugated coating promotes vascular healing</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35366606/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35366606/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Drug-eluting stents (DESs) placement remarkably reduces the over-proliferation of smooth muscle cells (SMCs) and thus neointimal hyperplasia. However, the pharmacological agent also slows down the re-endothelization, delays injury vascular healing and increases the risk of in-stent restenosis (ISR). Here, inspired by mussel foot proteins (Mfps), a mimicking endothelium functional stent coating was efficiently fabricated by thiol-ene &amp;ldquo;click&amp;rdquo; reaction, consisting of catechol grafted chitosan (CS-C), zinc sulfate, and Arg-Glu-Asp-Val (REDV) peptide. The mimicking endothelium coating could continuously catalyze endogenous nitric oxide (NO) gas and maintain the bioactivity of REDV peptide. Compared with bare stents, the mimicking coatings significantly inhibited the acute thrombosis for the first 1-week, accelerated re-endothelization and decreased in-stent restenosis for 1- and 3-month after implantation. In addition, the synergistic effect of NO and REDV peptide also regulated inflammation response and promoted the expression of muscle fiber.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mechanisms and clinical implications of endothelium-dependent vasomotor dysfunction in coronary microvasculature</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/35333122/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/35333122/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coronary microvascular disease (CMD), which affects the arterioles and capillary endothelium that regulate myocardial perfusion, is an increasingly recognized source of morbidity and mortality, particularly in the setting of metabolic syndrome. The coronary endothelium plays a pivotal role in maintaining homeostasis, though factors such as diabetes, hypertension, hyperlipidemia, and obesity can contribute to endothelial injury and consequently arteriolar vasomotor dysfunction. These disturbances in the coronary microvasculature clinically manifest as diminished coronary flow reserve, which is a known independent risk factor for cardiac death, even in the absence of macrovascular atherosclerotic disease. Therefore, a growing body of literature has examined the molecular mechanisms by which coronary microvascular injury occurs at the level of the endothelium and the consequences on arteriolar vasomotor responses. This review will begin with an overview of normal coronary microvascular physiology, modalities of measuring coronary microvascular function, and clinical implications of CMD. These introductory topics will be followed by a discussion of recent advances in the understanding of the mechanisms by which inflammation, oxidative stress, insulin resistance, hyperlipidemia, hypertension, shear stress, endothelial cell senescence, and tissue ischemia dysregulate coronary endothelial homeostasis and arteriolar vasomotor function.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Association of SGLT2 inhibitors with cardiovascular, kidney, and safety outcomes among patients with diabetic kidney disease: a meta-analysis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35321742/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35321742/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; We conducted a systematic review and meta-analysis of the cardiovascular, kidney, and safety outcomes of sodium-glucose cotransporter 2 inhibitors (SGLT2i) among patients with diabetic kidney disease (DKD).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; We searched electronic databases for major randomized placebo-controlled clinical trials published up to September 30, 2021 and reporting on cardiovascular and kidney outcomes of SGLT2i in patients with DKD. DKD was defined as chronic kidney disease in individuals with type 2 diabetes. Random-effects meta-analysis models were used to estimate pooled hazard ratios (HR) and 95% confidence intervals (CI) for clinical outcomes including major adverse cardiovascular events (MACE: myocardial infarction [MI], stroke, and cardiovascular death), kidney composite outcomes (a combination of worsening kidney function, end-stage kidney disease, or death from renal or cardiovascular causes), hospitalizations for heart failure (HHF), deaths and safety events (mycotic infections, diabetic ketoacidosis [DKA], volume depletion, amputations, fractures, urinary tract infections [UTI], acute kidney injury [AKI], and hyperkalemia).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; A total of 26,106 participants with DKD from 8 large-scale trials were included (median age: 65.2 years, 29.7-41.8% women, 53.2-93.2% White, median follow-up: 2.5 years). SGLT2i were associated with reduced risks of MACE (HR 0.83, 95% CI 0.75-0.93), kidney composite outcomes (HR 0.66, 95% CI 0.58-0.75), HHF (HR 0.62, 95% CI 0.55-0.71), cardiovascular death (HR 0.84, 95% CI 0.74-0.96), MI (HR 0.78, 95% CI 0.67-0.92), stroke (HR 0.76, 95% CI 0.59-0.97), and all-cause death (HR 0.86, 95% CI 0.77-0.96), with no significant heterogeneity detected. Similar results were observed among participants with reduced estimated glomerular filtration rate (eGFR: &amp;lt; 60 mL/min/1.73m&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;). The relative risks (95% CI) for adverse events were 3.89 (1.42-10.62) and 2.50 (1.32-4.72) for mycotic infections in men and women respectively, 3.54 (0.82-15.39) for DKA, and 1.29 (1.13-1.48) for volume depletion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; Among adults with DKD, SGLT2i were associated with reduced risks of MACE, kidney outcomes, HHF, and death. With a few exceptions of more clear safety signals, we found overall limited data on the associations between SGLT2i and safety outcomes. More research is needed on the safety profile of SGLT2i in this population.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Loss of NPPA-AS1 promotes heart regeneration by stabilizing SFPQ-NONO heteromer-induced DNA repair</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35247074/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35247074/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The role of long non-coding RNA (lncRNA) in endogenous cardiac regeneration remains largely elusive. The mammalian cardiomyocyte is capable of regeneration for a brief period after birth. This fact allows the exploration of the roles of critical lncRNAs in the regulation of cardiac regeneration. Through a cardiac regeneration model by apical resection (AR) of the left ventricle in neonatal mice, we identified an lncRNA named natriuretic peptide A antisense RNA 1 (NPPA-AS1), which negatively regulated cardiomyocyte proliferation. In neonates, NPPA-AS1 deletion did not affect heart development, but was sufficient to prolong the postnatal window of regeneration after AR. In adult mice, NPPA-AS1 deletion improved cardiac function and reduced infarct size after myocardial infarction (MI), associated with a significant improvement in cardiomyocyte proliferation. Further analysis showed that NPPA-AS1 interacted with DNA repair-related molecule splicing factor, proline- and glutamine-rich (SFPQ). A heteromer of SFPQ and non-POU domain-containing octamer-binding protein (NONO) was required for double-strand DNA break repair, but NPPA-AS1 was competitively bound with SFPQ due to the overlapped binding sites of SFPQ and NONO. NPPA-AS1 deletion promoted the binding of SFPQ-NONO heteromer, decreased DNA damage, and activated cardiomyocyte cell cycle re-entry. Together, loss of NPPA-AS1 promoted cardiomyocyte proliferation by stabilizing SFPQ-NONO heteromer-induced DNA repair and exerted a therapeutic effect against MI in adult mice. Consequently, NPPA-AS1 may be a novel target for stimulating cardiac regeneration to treat MI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plasma EFEMP1 Is Associated with Brain Aging and Dementia: The Framingham Heart Study</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34958018/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34958018/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Epidermal growth factor containing fibulin extracellular matrix protein-1 (EFEMP1) has been associated with increased white matter hyperintensities (WMH) burden and disorders of premature aging and may have a shared pathophysiological role in the development of WMH and dementia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Objective:&lt;/em&gt; To determine the association between plasma EFEMP1 levels and MRI markers of vascular brain injury and incident all-cause and Alzheimer&amp;rsquo;s disease (AD) dementia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; We measured plasma EFEMP1 levels in 1597 [53% women, mean age 68.7 (SD 5.7) years] dementia-free Framingham Offspring cohort participants between 1998-2001 and subsequently followed them for incident dementia. Secondary outcomes included stroke, structural MRI brain measures and neurocognitive test performance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; During a median 11.8 [Q1, Q3 : 7.1, 13.3] year follow-up, 131 participants developed dementia. The highest quintile of plasma EFEMP1, compared to the bottom four quintiles, was associated with an increased risk of time to incident all-cause dementia (HR 1.77, 95% CI 1.18-2.64) and AD dementia (HR 1.76, 95% CI 1.11-2.81) but not with markers of vascular brain injury (WMH, covert brain infarcts or stroke). Higher circulating EFEMP1 concentrations were also cross-sectionally associated with lower total brain (β±SE, -0.28±0.11, &lt;em&gt;p&lt;/em&gt; = 0.01) and hippocampal volumes (-0.006±0.003, &lt;em&gt;p&lt;/em&gt; = 0.04) and impaired abstract reasoning (Similarities test, -0.18±0.08, &lt;em&gt;p&lt;/em&gt; = 0.018 per standard deviation increment in EFEMP1).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/em&gt; Elevated circulating EFEMP1 is associated with an increased risk of all-cause and AD dementia, smaller hippocampal and total brain volumes, and poorer cognitive performance. EFEMP1 may play an important biological role in the development of AD dementia. Further studies to validate these findings are warranted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Acute cardiovascular effects of inhaled ambient particulate matter: Chemical composition-related oxidative stress, endothelin-1, blood pressure, and ST-segment changes in Wistar rats</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35157883/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35157883/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Experimental evidence of particle composition as cardiovascular potency determinant.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ambient particle inhalation, ROS/RNS-related perturbations in endothelin isoforms.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PM-related molecular-level and relevant physiological/functional level changes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Particle composition-led key mechanistic events explain BP/S-T segment changes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Short-term increases in particulate matter (PM) are associated with heightened morbidity and mortality from cardiovascular causes. Inhalation of PM is known to increase endothelin (ET)-1 levels. Yet, less is known about particle composition-related changes at the molecular level including the endothelinergic system and relationship with cardiovascular function changes. In this work, adult Wistar male rats were exposed for 4 h by nose-only inhalation to clean air, Ottawa urban particles (EHC-93, 48 mg/m&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;) and water-leached (EHC-93L, 49 mg/m&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;) particles, to examine the effect of particle compositional changes on oxidative stress, circulating ETs, blood pressure, and heart electrophysiology. Particle deposition in the respiratory compartment was estimated at 85 μg (25 ng/cm&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;). Lung cell proliferation was low in both treatment groups, indicating absence of acute injury. Inhalation of EHC-93 caused statistically significant elevations (&lt;em&gt;p&lt;/em&gt; &amp;lt; 0.05) of oxidative stress markers, ET-1, ET-3, blood pressure, and a decrease of ST-segment duration in the ECG at 1.5 days post-exposure. Leached particles (EHC-93L) caused rapid but transient elevation (&lt;em&gt;p&lt;/em&gt; &amp;lt; 0.05) of oxidative stress, ET-1, ET-2, and ET-3 at earlier time points, with no changes in blood pressure or ST-segment. These results demonstrate that inhalation of urban particles at an internal dose inadequate to cause acute lung injury can induce oxidative stress, enhance vasoactive endothelins, leading to vasopressor response, affecting cardiac electrophysiology in Wistar rats, consistent with the cardiovascular impacts of ambient particles in human populations. Change in particle potency after removal of soluble species, notably cadmium, zinc and polar organics suggests that the toxicodynamics of cardiovascular effects can be modified by physicochemical properties of particles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Roles of Mineralocorticoid Receptors in Cardiovascular and Cardiorenal Diseases</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/35143332/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/35143332/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mineralocorticoid receptor (MR) activation in the heart and vessels leads to pathological effects, such as excessive extracellular matrix accumulation, oxidative stress, and sustained inflammation. In these organs, the MR is expressed in cardiomyocytes, fibroblasts, endothelial cells, smooth muscle cells, and inflammatory cells. We review the accumulating experimental and clinical evidence that pharmacological MR antagonism has a positive impact on a battery of cardiac and vascular pathological states, including heart failure, myocardial infarction, arrhythmic diseases, atherosclerosis, vascular stiffness, and cardiac and vascular injury linked to metabolic comorbidities and chronic kidney disease. Moreover, we present perspectives on optimization of the use of MR antagonists in patients more likely to respond to such therapy and review the evidence suggesting that novel nonsteroidal MR antagonists offer an improved safety profile while retaining their cardiovascular protective effects. Finally, we highlight future therapeutic applications of MR antagonists in cardiovascular injury.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Patient-Specific TBX5-G125R Variant Induces Profound Transcriptional Deregulation and Atrial Dysfunction</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35113653/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35113653/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; The pathogenic missense variant p.G125R in TBX5 (T-box transcription factor 5) causes Holt-Oram syndrome (also known as hand-heart syndrome) and early onset of atrial fibrillation. Revealing how an altered key developmental transcription factor modulates cardiac physiology in vivo will provide unique insights into the mechanisms underlying atrial fibrillation in these patients.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; We analyzed ECGs of an extended family pedigree of Holt-Oram syndrome patients. Next, we introduced the TBX5-p.G125R variant in the mouse genome (Tbx5G125R) and performed electrophysiologic analyses (ECG, optical mapping, patch clamp, intracellular calcium measurements), transcriptomics (single-nuclei and tissue RNA sequencing), and epigenetic profiling (assay for transposase-accessible chromatin using sequencing, H3K27ac [histone H3 lysine 27 acetylation] CUT&amp;amp;RUN [cleavage under targets and release under nuclease sequencing]).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; We discovered high incidence of atrial extra systoles and atrioventricular conduction disturbances in Holt-Oram syndrome patients. &lt;em&gt;Tbx5&lt;sup&gt;G125R/+&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; mice were morphologically unaffected and displayed variable RR intervals, atrial extra systoles, and susceptibility to atrial fibrillation, reminiscent of TBX5-p.G125R patients. Atrial conduction velocity was not affected but systolic and diastolic intracellular calcium concentrations were decreased and action potentials were prolonged in isolated cardiomyocytes of &lt;em&gt;Tbx5&lt;sup&gt;G125R/+&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; mice compared with controls. Transcriptional profiling of atria revealed the most profound transcriptional changes in cardiomyocytes versus other cell types, and identified over a thousand coding and noncoding transcripts that were differentially expressed. Epigenetic profiling uncovered thousands of TBX5-p.G125R-sensitive, putative regulatory elements (including enhancers) that gained accessibility in atrial cardiomyocytes. The majority of sites with increased accessibility were occupied by Tbx5. The small group of sites with reduced accessibility was enriched for DNA-binding motifs of members of the SP (specificity protein) and KLF (Krüppel-like factor) families of transcription factors. These data show that Tbx5-p.G125R induces changes in regulatory element activity, alters transcriptional regulation, and changes cardiomyocyte behavior, possibly caused by altered DNA binding and cooperativity properties.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; Our data reveal that a disease-causing missense variant in TBX5 induces profound changes in the atrial transcriptional regulatory network and epigenetic state in vivo, leading to arrhythmia reminiscent of those seen in human TBX5-p.G125R variant carriers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;What Is New?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A pathogenic variant in the fifth exon of TBX5 ([T-box transcription factor 5] p.G125R) found in a Dutch, atypical Holt–Oram syndrome family with early onset atrial fibrillation was modeled in mice.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This is the first human pathogenic variant based on a patient family in this key cardiac transcription factor explored in vivo.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We identify widespread electrophysiologic, transcriptional, and epigenetic changes (including coding and noncoding RNA, chromatin accessibility, and H3K27ac [histone H3 lysine 27 acetylation] association) in the atria of Tbx5-p.G125R heterozygous mice distinct from the changes in atria of Tbx5 insufficiency models.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;What Are the Clinical Implications?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The characterization of the Tbx5 p.G125R mouse model indicates that a patient-specific pathogenic variant in TBX5 induces changes in regulatory element activity, altered balance in the regulatory network of atrial cardiomyocytes, and clinically relevant changes in cardiomyocyte function.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;These findings shed light on the target and off-target genes of Tbx5-p.G125R because of its altered properties, which are at the basis of distinct electrophysiologic changes observed in a subset of Holt–Oram syndrome patients with atrial fibrillation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This work may provide insight into the epigenetic changes and transcriptional underpinning of arrhythmia in the general population caused by small increases in TBX5-expression caused by common variants predisposing to atrial fibrillation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>H2 Inhibits the Formation of Neutrophil Extracellular Traps</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35257042/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35257042/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;NETs have been implicated as therapeutic targets to address inflammation and thrombotic tissue damage in conditions such as sepsis, acute respiratory disease syndrome, COVID-19, and CVDs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; has been clinically and experimentally proven to ameliorate inflammation; however, the underlying molecular mechanisms remain elusive.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Compared with control neutrophils, PMA-stimulated human neutrophils exposed to H2 exhibited reduced citrullination of histones and release of NET components; mechanistically, H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;-mediated neutralization of HOCl produced during oxidative bursts suppresses DNA damage.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Inhalation of H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; inhibited the formation and release of NET components in the blood and BAL of the LPS-induced sepsis in mice and aged mini pigs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; therapy is potentially a new therapeutic strategy for inflammatory diseases involving NETs associated with excessive neutrophil activation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Neutrophil extracellular traps (NETs) contribute to inflammatory pathogenesis in numerous conditions, including infectious and cardiovascular diseases, and have attracted attention as potential therapeutic targets. H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; acts as an antioxidant and has been clinically and experimentally proven to ameliorate inflammation. This study was performed to investigate whether H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; could inhibit NET formation and excessive neutrophil activation. Neutrophils isolated from the blood of healthy volunteers were stimulated with phorbol-12-myristate-13-acetate (PMA) or the calcium ionophore A23187 in H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;-exposed or control media. Compared with control neutrophils, PMA- or A23187-stimulated human neutrophils exposed to H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; exhibited reduced neutrophil aggregation, citrullination of histones, membrane disruption by chromatin complexes, and release of NET components. CXCR4&lt;sup&gt;high&lt;/sup&gt; neutrophils are highly prone to NETs, and H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; suppressed Ser-139 phosphorylation in H2AX, a marker of DNA damage, thereby suppressing the induction of CXCR4 expression. H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; suppressed both myeloperoxidase chlorination activity and production of reactive oxygen species to the same degree as N-acetylcysteine and ascorbic acid, while showing a more potent ability to inhibit NET formation than these antioxidants do in PMA-stimulated neutrophils. Although A23187 formed NETs in a reactive oxygen species-independent manner, H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; inhibited A23187-induced NET formation, probably via direct inhibition of peptidyl arginine deiminase 4-mediated histone citrullination. Inhalation of H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; inhibited the formation and release of NET components in the blood and bronchoalveolar lavage fluid in animal models of lipopolysaccharide-induced sepsis (mice and aged mini pigs). Thus, H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; therapy can be a novel therapeutic strategy for NETs associated with excessive neutrophil activation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hypoxia Increases the Potential for Neutrophil-mediated Endothelial Damage in Chronic Obstructive Pulmonary Disease</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35044899/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35044899/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rationale:&lt;/em&gt; Patients with chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD) experience excess cardiovascular morbidity and mortality, and exacerbations further increase the risk of such events. COPD is associated with persistent blood and airway neutrophilia and systemic and tissue hypoxia. Hypoxia augments neutrophil elastase release, enhancing capacity for tissue injury.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Objective:&lt;/em&gt; To determine whether hypoxia-driven neutrophil protein secretion contributes to endothelial damage in COPD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; The healthy human neutrophil secretome generated under normoxic or hypoxic conditions was characterized by quantitative mass spectrometry, and the capacity for neutrophil-mediated endothelial damage was assessed. Histotoxic protein concentrations were measured in normoxic versus hypoxic neutrophil supernatants and plasma from patients experiencing COPD exacerbation and healthy control subjects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Measurements and Main Results:&lt;/em&gt; Hypoxia promoted PI3Kγ-dependent neutrophil elastase secretion, with greater release seen in neutrophils from patients with COPD. Supernatants from neutrophils incubated under hypoxia caused pulmonary endothelial cell damage, and identical supernatants from COPD neutrophils increased neutrophil adherence to endothelial cells. Proteomics revealed differential neutrophil protein secretion under hypoxia and normoxia, and hypoxia augmented secretion of a subset of histotoxic granule and cytosolic proteins, with significantly greater release seen in COPD neutrophils. The plasma of patients with COPD had higher content of hypoxia-upregulated neutrophil-derived proteins and protease activity, and vascular injury markers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; Hypoxia drives a destructive &amp;ldquo;hypersecretory&amp;rdquo; neutrophil phenotype conferring enhanced capacity for endothelial injury, with a corresponding signature of neutrophil degranulation and vascular injury identified in plasma of patients with COPD. Thus, hypoxic enhancement of neutrophil degranulation may contribute to increased cardiovascular risk in COPD. These insights may identify new therapeutic opportunities for endothelial damage in COPD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pandemic Influenza Infection Promotes Streptococcus pneumoniae Infiltration, Necrotic Damage, and Proteomic Remodeling in the Heart</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35089061/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35089061/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For over a century, it has been reported that primary influenza infection promotes the development of a lethal form of bacterial pulmonary disease. More recently, pneumonia events caused by both viruses and bacteria have been directly associated with cardiac damage. Importantly, it is not known whether viral-bacterial synergy extends to extrapulmonary organs such as the heart. Using label-free quantitative proteomics and molecular approaches, we report that primary infection with pandemic influenza A virus leads to increased Streptococcus pneumoniae translocation to the myocardium, leading to general biological alterations. We also observed that each infection alone led to proteomic changes in the heart, and these were exacerbated in the secondary bacterial infection (SBI) model. Gene ontology analysis of significantly upregulated proteins showed increased innate immune activity, oxidative processes, and changes to ion homeostasis during SBI. Immunoblots confirmed increased complement and antioxidant activity in addition to increased expression of angiotensin-converting enzyme 2. Using an &lt;em&gt;in vitro&lt;/em&gt; model of sequential infection in human cardiomyocytes, we observed that influenza enhances S. pneumoniae cytotoxicity by promoting oxidative stress enhancing bacterial toxin-induced necrotic cell death. Influenza infection was found to increase receptors that promote bacterial adhesion, such as polymeric immunoglobulin receptor and fibronectin leucine-rich transmembrane protein 1 in cardiomyocytes. Finally, mice deficient in programmed necrosis (i.e., necroptosis) showed enhanced innate immune responses, decreased virus-associated pathways, and promotion of mitochondrial function upon SBI. The presented results provide the first &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt; evidence that influenza infection promotes S. pneumoniae infiltration, necrotic damage, and proteomic remodeling of the heart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Importance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adverse cardiac events are a common complication of viral and bacterial pneumonia. For over a century, it has been recognized that influenza infection promotes severe forms of pulmonary disease mainly caused by the bacterium Streptococcus pneumoniae. The extrapulmonary effects of secondary bacterial infections to influenza virus are not known. In the present study, we used a combination of quantitative proteomics and molecular approaches to assess the underlying mechanisms of how influenza infection promotes bacteria-driven cardiac damage and proteome remodeling. We further observed that programmed necrosis (i.e., necroptosis) inhibition leads to reduced damage and proteome changes associated with health.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Renal and Cerebral Hypoxia and Inflammation During Cardiopulmonary Bypass</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34964119/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34964119/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cardiac surgery-associated acute kidney injury and brain injury remain common despite ongoing efforts to improve both the equipment and procedures deployed during cardiopulmonary bypass (CPB). The pathophysiology of injury of the kidney and brain during CPB is not completely understood. Nevertheless, renal (particularly in the medulla) and cerebral hypoxia and inflammation likely play critical roles. Multiple practical factors, including depth and mode of anesthesia, hemodilution, pump flow, and arterial pressure can influence oxygenation of the brain and kidney during CPB. Critically, these factors may have differential effects on these two vital organs. Systemic inflammatory pathways are activated during CPB through activation of the complement system, coagulation pathways, leukocytes, and the release of inflammatory cytokines. Local inflammation in the brain and kidney may be aggravated by ischemia (and thus hypoxia) and reperfusion (and thus oxidative stress) and activation of resident and infiltrating inflammatory cells. Various strategies, including manipulating perfusion conditions and administration of pharmacotherapies, could potentially be deployed to avoid or attenuate hypoxia and inflammation during CPB. Regarding manipulating perfusion conditions, based on experimental and clinical data, increasing standard pump flow and arterial pressure during CPB appears to offer the best hope to avoid hypoxia and injury, at least in the kidney. Pharmacological approaches, including use of anti-inflammatory agents such as dexmedetomidine and erythropoietin, have shown promise in preclinical models but have not been adequately tested in human trials. However, evidence for beneficial effects of corticosteroids on renal and neurological outcomes is lacking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Long non-coding RNA MALAT1 modulates myocardial ischemia-reperfusion injury through the PI3K/Akt/eNOS pathway by sponging miRNA-133a-3p to target IGF1R expression</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34968461/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34968461/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The mechanism of myocardial ischemia-reperfusion injury (MIRI) is a complex pathophysiological process that can lead to poor patient outcomes. Although LncRNA metastasis-associated lung adenocarcinoma transcript 1 (MALAT1) is reported to be highly expressed in myocardial ischemia reperfusion (IR) injury, the specific mechanism remains largely unknown. This study aimed to elucidate the roles and possible mechanism of MALAT1 in myocardial IR injury. IR model was established in rats by ligation of the anterior descending artery in vivo, and H9c2 and HL-1 cells were treated by hypoxia/reoxygenation (HR) to construct the model in vitro. The small interfering RNA (siRNA) for MALAT1 and miR-133a-3p mimics, inhibitor was used to transfect the cells. The expression of MALAT1, miR-133a-3p in MIRI were evaluated using real-time quantitative polymerase chain reaction (qRT-PCR)，immunohistochemistry (IHC) and western blot (WB). Relationships between MALAT1, insulin-like growth factor 1 receptor (IGF1R) with miR-133a-3p were confirmed by luciferase reporter assay. Annexin V-FITC/PI double-labeled flow cytometry, terminal dexynucleotidyl transferase-mediated dUTP nick end labeling (TUNEL), Cell Counting Kit-8 (CCK-8), serum creatine kinase MB (CK-MB), and lactate dehydrogenase (LDH) were evaluated to examine the impact of MALAT1 on MIRI. Our results revealed that MALAT1 was highly expressed, while miR-133a-3p and IGF1R were repressed in IR and HR groups. Knockdown of MALAT1 alleviate the pro-apoptotic effect and myocardial injury in vitro and in vivo. Systematically, MALAT1 may serve as a sponge for miR-133a-3p to suppress IGF1R, which a direct target of miR-133a-3p, then inhibit the PI3K/Akt/eNOS survival pathway. Mechanistically, our study demonstrated that MALAT1 regulates PI3K/Akt/eNOS signaling via miR-133a-3p. In summary, these results suggest that MALAT1 and miR-133a-3p play important roles in MIRI. MALAT1 regulates miR-133a-3p /IGF1R axis. These results show light on the underlying mechanisms of MIRI and provide potential therapeutic targets for MIRI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hypertension-Mediated Organ Damage: Prevalence, Correlates, and Prognosis in the Community</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35138872/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35138872/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Guidelines emphasize screening people with elevated BP for the presence of end-organ damage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; We characterized the prevalence, correlates, and prognosis of hypertension-mediated organ damage (HMOD) in the community-based Framingham Study. 7898 participants (mean age 51.6 years, 54% women) underwent assessment for the following HMOD: electrocardiographic and echocardiographic left ventricular hypertrophy, abnormal brain imaging findings consistent with vascular injury, increased carotid intima-media thickness, elevated carotid-femoral pulse wave velocity, reduced kidney function, microalbuminuria, and low ankle-brachial index. We characterized HMOD prevalence according to blood pressure (BP) categories defined by four international BP guidelines. Participants were followed up for incidence of cardiovascular disease.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; The prevalence of HMOD varied positively with systolic BP and pulse pressure but negatively with diastolic BP; it increased with age, was similar in both sexes, and varied across BP guidelines based on their thresholds defining hypertension. Among participants with hypertension, elevated carotid-femoral pulse wave velocity was the most prevalent HMOD (40%-60%), whereas low ankle-brachial index was the least prevalent (&amp;lt;5%). Left ventricular hypertrophy, reduced kidney function, microalbuminuria, increased carotid intima-media thickness, and abnormal brain imaging findings had an intermediate prevalence (20%-40%). HMOD frequently clustered within individuals. On follow-up (median, 14.1 years), there were 384 cardiovascular disease events among 5865 participants with concurrent assessment of left ventricular mass, carotid-femoral pulse wave velocity, kidney function, and microalbuminuria. For every BP category above optimal (referent group), the presence of HMOD increased cardiovascular disease risk compared with its absence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; The prevalence of HMOD varies across international BP guidelines based on their different thresholds for defining hypertension. The presence of HMOD confers incremental prognostic information regarding cardiovascular disease risk at every BP category.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cardioprotective mechanism of SGLT2 inhibitor against myocardial infarction is through reduction of autosis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33417139/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33417139/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sodium-glucose cotransporter 2 (SGLT2) inhibitors reduce cardiovascular mortality in patients with diabetes mellitus but the protective mechanism remains elusive. Here we demonstrated that the SGLT2 inhibitor, Empagliflozin (EMPA), suppresses cardiomyocytes autosis (autophagic cell death) to confer cardioprotective effects. Using myocardial infarction (MI) mouse models with and without diabetes mellitus, EMPA treatment significantly reduced infarct size, and myocardial fibrosis, thereby leading to improved cardiac function and survival. In the context of ischemia and nutritional glucose deprivation where autosis is already highly stimulated, EMPA directly inhibits the activity of the Na+/H+ exchanger 1 (NHE1) in the cardiomyocytes to regulate excessive autophagy. Knockdown of NHE1 significantly rescued glucose deprivation-induced autosis. In contrast, overexpression of NHE1 aggravated the cardiomyocytes death in response to starvation, which was effectively rescued by EMPA treatment. Furthermore, in vitro and in vivo analysis of NHE1 and Beclin 1 knockout mice validated that EMPA&amp;rsquo;s cardioprotective effects are at least in part through downregulation of autophagic flux. These findings provide new insights for drug development, specifically targeting NHE1 and autosis for ventricular remodeling and heart failure after MI in both diabetic and non-diabetic patients.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upregulation of Rubicon promotes autosis during myocardial ischemia/reperfusion injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32364533/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32364533/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although autophagy is generally protective, uncontrolled or excessive activation of autophagy can be detrimental. However, it is often difficult to distinguish death by autophagy from death with autophagy, and whether autophagy contributes to death in cardiomyocytes (CMs) is still controversial. Excessive activation of autophagy induces a morphologically and biochemically defined form of cell death termed autosis. Whether autosis is involved in tissue injury induced under pathologically relevant conditions is poorly understood. In the present study, myocardial ischemia/reperfusion (I/R) induced autosis in CMs, as evidenced by cell death with numerous vacuoles and perinuclear spaces, and ﻿depleted intracellular membranes. Autosis was observed frequently after 6 hours of reperfusion, accompanied by upregulation of Rubicon, attenuation of autophagic flux, and marked accumulation of autophagosomes. Genetic downregulation of Rubicon inhibited autosis and reduced I/R injury, whereas stimulation of autosis during the late phase of I/R with Tat-Beclin 1 exacerbated injury. Suppression of autosis by ouabain, a cardiac glycoside, in humanized ﻿Na+,K+-ATPase-knockin mice reduced I/R injury. Taken together, these results demonstrate that autosis is significantly involved in I/R injury in the heart and triggered by dysregulated accumulation of autophagosomes due to upregulation of Rubicon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Circular RNA CircFndc3b modulates cardiac repair after myocardial infarction via FUS/VEGF-A axis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/31541092/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/31541092/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Circular RNAs are generated from many protein-coding genes, but their role in cardiovascular health and disease states remains unknown. Here we report identification of circRNA transcripts that are differentially expressed in post myocardial infarction (MI) mouse hearts including circFndc3b which is significantly down-regulated in the post-MI hearts. Notably, the human circFndc3b ortholog is also significantly down-regulated in cardiac tissues of ischemic cardiomyopathy patients. Overexpression of circFndc3b in cardiac endothelial cells increases vascular endothelial growth factor-A expression and enhances their angiogenic activity and reduces cardiomyocytes and endothelial cell apoptosis. Adeno-associated virus 9 -mediated cardiac overexpression of circFndc3b in post-MI hearts reduces cardiomyocyte apoptosis, enhances neovascularization and improves left ventricular functions. Mechanistically, circFndc3b interacts with the RNA binding protein Fused in Sarcoma to regulate VEGF expression and signaling. These findings highlight a physiological role for circRNAs in cardiac repair and indicate that modulation of circFndc3b expression may represent a potential strategy to promote cardiac function and remodeling after MI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gata6&#43; Pericardial Cavity Macrophages Relocate to the Injured Heart and Prevent Cardiac Fibrosis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/31315031/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/31315031/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Macrophages play an important role in structural cardiac remodeling and the transition to heart failure following myocardial infarction (MI). Previous research has focused on the impact of blood-derived monocytes on cardiac repair. Here we examined the contribution of resident cavity macrophages located in the pericardial space adjacent to the site of injury. We found that disruption of the pericardial cavity accelerated maladaptive post-MI cardiac remodeling. Gata6&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; macrophages in mouse pericardial fluid contributed to the reparative immune response. Following experimental MI, these macrophages invaded the epicardium and lost Gata6 expression but continued to perform anti-fibrotic functions. Loss of this specialized macrophage population enhanced interstitial fibrosis after ischemic injury. Gata6+ macrophages were present in human pericardial fluid, supporting the notion that this reparative function is relevant in human disease. Our findings uncover an immune cardioprotective role for the pericardial tissue compartment and argue for the reevaluation of surgical procedures that remove the pericardium.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>S100a8/a9 Signaling Causes Mitochondrial Dysfunction and Cardiomyocyte Death in Response to Ischemic/Reperfusion Injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/31220942/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/31220942/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Myocardial ischemia-reperfusion (MI/R) injury is a significant clinical problem without effective therapy. Unbiased omics approaches may reveal key MI/R mediators to initiate MI/R injury.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; We used a dynamic transcriptome analysis of mouse heart exposed to various MI/R periods to identify S100a8/a9 as an early mediator. Using loss/gain-of-function approaches to understand the role of S100a8/a9 in MI/R injury, we explored the mechanisms through transcriptome and functional experiment. Dynamic serum S100a8/a9 levels were measured in patients with acute myocardial infarction before and after percutaneous coronary intervention. Patients were prospectively followed for the occurrence of major adverse cardiovascular events.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; S100a8/a9 was identified as the most significantly upregulated gene during the early reperfusion stage. Knockout of S100a9 markedly decreased cardiomyocyte death and improved heart function, whereas hematopoietic overexpression of S100a9 exacerbated MI/R injury. Transcriptome/functional studies revealed that S100a8/a9 caused mitochondrial respiratory dysfunction in cardiomyocytes. Mechanistically, S100a8/a9 downregulated NDUF gene expression with subsequent mitochondrial complex I inhibition via Toll-like receptor 4/Erk-mediated Pparg coactivator 1 alpha/nuclear respiratory factor 1 signaling suppression. Administration of S100a9 neutralizing antibody significantly reduced MI/R injury and improved cardiac function. Finally, we demonstrated that serum S100a8/a9 levels were significantly increased 1 day after percutaneous coronary intervention in patients with acute myocardial infarction, and elevated S100a8/a9 levels were associated with the incidence of major adverse cardiovascular events.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; Our study identified S100a8/a9 as a master regulator causing cardiomyocyte death in the early stage of MI/R injury via the suppression of mitochondrial function. Targeting S100a8/a9-intiated signaling may represent a novel therapeutic intervention against MI/R injury.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wnt/β-catenin signaling mediates both heart and kidney injury in type 2 cardiorenal syndrome</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/30770217/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/30770217/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Erratum in:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Corrigendum to Zhao Y, Wang C, Hong X, et al. &lt;a href=&#34;https://linkinghub.elsevier.com/retrieve/pii/S0085253822006226&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Wnt/β-catenin signaling mediates both heart and kidney injury in type 2 cardiorenal syndrome&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Kidney Int. 2019;95:815-829.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In type 2 cardiorenal syndrome, chronic heart failure is thought to cause or promote chronic kidney disease; however, the underlying mechanisms remain poorly understood. We investigated the role of Wnt signaling in heart and kidney injury in a mouse model of cardiac hypertrophy and heart failure induced by transverse aortic constriction (TAC). At 8 weeks after TAC, cardiac hypertrophy, inflammation, and fibrosis were prominent, and echocardiography confirmed impaired cardiac function. The cardiac lesions were accompanied by upregulation of multiple Wnt ligands and activation of β-catenin, as well as activation of the renin-angiotensin system (RAS). Wnt3a induced multiple components of the RAS in primary cardiomyocytes and cardiac fibroblasts in vitro. TAC also caused proteinuria and kidney fibrosis, accompanied by klotho depletion and β-catenin activation in the kidney. Pharmacologic blockade of β-catenin with a small molecule inhibitor or the RAS with losartan ameliorated cardiac injury, restored heart function, and mitigated the renal lesions. Serum from TAC mice was sufficient to activate β-catenin and trigger tubular cell injury in vitro, indicating a role for circulating factors. Multiple inflammatory cytokines were upregulated in the circulation of TAC mice, and tumor necrosis factor-α was able to inhibit klotho, induce β-catenin activation, and cause tubular cell injury in vitro. These studies identify Wnt/β-catenin signaling as a common pathogenic mediator of heart and kidney injury in type 2 cardiorenal syndrome after TAC. Targeting this pathway could be a promising therapeutic strategy to protect both organs in cardiorenal syndrome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-renewing resident cardiac macrophages limit adverse remodeling following myocardial infarction</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/30538339/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/30538339/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Erratum in:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Publisher Correction: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nature.com/articles/s41590-019-0363-8&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Self-renewing resident cardiac macrophages limit adverse remodeling following myocardial infarction&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Macrophages promote both injury and repair after myocardial infarction, but discriminating functions within mixed populations remains challenging. Here we used fate mapping, parabiosis and single-cell transcriptomics to demonstrate that at steady state, TIMD4&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt;LYVE1&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt;MHC-II&lt;sup&gt;lo&lt;/sup&gt;CCR2&lt;sup&gt;-&lt;/sup&gt; resident cardiac macrophages self-renew with negligible blood monocyte input. Monocytes partially replaced resident TIMD4&lt;sup&gt;-&lt;/sup&gt;LYVE1&lt;sup&gt;-&lt;/sup&gt;MHC-II&lt;sup&gt;hi&lt;/sup&gt;CCR2&lt;sup&gt;-&lt;/sup&gt; macrophages and fully replaced TIMD4&lt;sup&gt;-&lt;/sup&gt;LYVE1&lt;sup&gt;-&lt;/sup&gt;MHC-II&lt;sup&gt;hi&lt;/sup&gt;CCR2&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; macrophages, revealing a hierarchy of monocyte contribution to functionally distinct macrophage subsets. Ischemic injury reduced TIMD4&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; and TIMD4&lt;sup&gt;-&lt;/sup&gt; resident macrophage abundance, whereas CCR2&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; monocyte-derived macrophages adopted multiple cell fates within infarcted tissue, including those nearly indistinguishable from resident macrophages. Recruited macrophages did not express TIMD4, highlighting the ability of TIMD4 to track a subset of resident macrophages in the absence of fate mapping. Despite this similarity, inducible depletion of resident macrophages using a Cx3cr1-based system led to impaired cardiac function and promoted adverse remodeling primarily within the peri-infarct zone, revealing a nonredundant, cardioprotective role of resident cardiac macrophages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
