<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Epigenetics | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/epigenetics/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/epigenetics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Epigenetics</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 24 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Epigenetics</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/epigenetics/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>UHRF1-mediated ferroptosis promotes pulmonary fibrosis via epigenetic repression of GPX4 and FSP1 genes</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36566325/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36566325/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pulmonary fibrosis (PF), as an end-stage clinical phenotype of interstitial lung diseases (ILDs), is frequently initiated after alveolar injury, in which ferroptosis has been identified as a critical event aggravating the pathophysiological progression of this disease. Here in, a comprehensive analysis of two mouse models of pulmonary fibrosis developed in our lab demonstrated that lung damage-induced ferroptosis of alveolar epithelial Type2 cells (AEC2) significantly accumulates during the development of pulmonary fibrosis while ferroptosis suppressor genes GPX4 and FSP1 are dramatically inactivated. Mechanistically, upregulation of de novo methylation regulator Uhrf1 sensitively elevates CpG site methylation levels in promoters of both GPX4 and FSP1 genes and induces the epigenetic repression of both genes, subsequently leading to ferroptosis in chemically interfered AEC2 cells. Meanwhile, specific inhibition of UHRF1 highly arrests the ferroptosis formation and blocks the progression of pulmonary fibrosis in both of our research models. This study first, to our knowledge, identified the involvement of Uhrf1 in mediating the ferroptosis of chemically injured AEC2s via de novo promoter-specific methylation of both GPX4 and FSP1 genes, which consequently accelerates the process of pulmonary fibrosis. The above findings also strongly suggested Uhrf1 as a novel potential target in the treatment of pulmonary fibrosis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Histone Lactylation Boosts Reparative Gene Activation Post-Myocardial Infarction</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36268709/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36268709/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Inflammation resolution and cardiac repair initiation after myocardial infarction (MI) require timely activation of reparative signals. Histone lactylation confers macrophage homeostatic gene expression signatures via transcriptional regulation. However, the role of histone lactylation in the repair response post-MI remains unclear. We aimed to investigate whether histone lactylation induces reparative gene expression in monocytes early and remotely post-MI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; Single-cell transcriptome data indicated that reparative genes were activated early and remotely in bone marrow and circulating monocytes before cardiac recruitment. Western blotting and immunofluorescence staining revealed increases in histone lactylation levels, including the previously identified histone H3K18 lactylation in monocyte-macrophages early post-MI. Through joint CUT&amp;amp;Tag and RNA-sequencing analyses, we identified Lrg1, Vegf-a, and IL-10 as histone H3K18 lactylation target genes. The increased modification and expression levels of these target genes post-MI were verified by chromatin immunoprecipitation-qPCR and reverse transcription-qPCR.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; We demonstrated that histone lactylation regulates the anti-inflammatory and pro-angiogenic dual activities of monocyte-macrophages by facilitating reparative gene transcription and confirmed that histone lactylation favors a reparative environment and improves cardiac function post-MI. Furthermore, we explored the potential positive role of monocyte histone lactylation in reperfused MI. Mechanistically, we provided new evidence that monocytes undergo metabolic reprogramming in the early stage of MI and demonstrated that dysregulated glycolysis and MCT1 (monocarboxylate transporter 1)-mediated lactate transport promote histone lactylation. Finally, we revealed the catalytic effect of IL (interleukin)-1β-dependent GCN5 (general control non-depressible 5) recruitment on histone H3K18 lactylation and elucidated its potential role as an upstream regulatory element in the regulation of monocyte histone lactylation and downstream reparative gene expression post-MI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; Histone lactylation promotes early remote activation of the reparative transcriptional response in monocytes, which is essential for the establishment of immune homeostasis and timely activation of the cardiac repair process post-MI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spatially resolved epigenomic profiling of single cells in complex tissues</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36272405/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36272405/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Epigenomic MERFISH enables spatially resolved single-cell epigenomic profiling&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Epigenomic MERFISH maps active promoters and putative enhancers in mouse brain&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Epigenomic MERFISH reveals putative enhancer hubs in embryonic mouse brain&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Epigenomic MERFISH images show sub-nuclear distributions of epigenetic loci&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The recent development of spatial omics methods has enabled single-cell profiling of the transcriptome and 3D genome organization with high spatial resolution. Expanding the repertoire of spatial omics tools, a spatially resolved single-cell epigenomics method will accelerate understanding of the spatial regulation of cell and tissue functions. Here, we report a method for spatially resolved epigenomic profiling of single cells using in situ tagmentation and transcription followed by multiplexed imaging. We demonstrated the ability to profile histone modifications marking active promoters, putative enhancers, and silent promoters in individual cells, and generated high-resolution spatial atlas of hundreds of active promoters and putative enhancers in embryonic and adult mouse brains. Our results suggested putative promoter-enhancer pairs and enhancer hubs regulating developmentally important genes. We envision this approach will be generally applicable to spatial profiling of epigenetic modifications and DNA-binding proteins, advancing our understanding of how gene expression is spatiotemporally regulated by the epigenome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lactate induces metabolic and epigenetic reprogramming of pro-inflammatory Th17 cells</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36215678/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36215678/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Increased lactate levels in the tissue microenvironment are a well-known feature of chronic inflammation. However, the role of lactate in regulating T cell function remains controversial. Here, we demonstrate that extracellular lactate predominantly induces deregulation of the Th17-specific gene expression program by modulating the metabolic and epigenetic status of Th17 cells. Following lactate treatment, Th17 cells significantly reduced their IL-17A production and upregulated Foxp3 expression through ROS-driven IL-2 secretion. Moreover, we observed increased levels of genome-wide histone H3K18 lactylation, a recently described marker for active chromatin in macrophages, in lactate-treated Th17 cells. In addition, we show that high lactate concentrations suppress Th17 pathogenicity during intestinal inflammation in mice. These results indicate that lactate is capable of reprogramming pro-inflammatory T cell phenotypes into regulatory T cells.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SARS-CoV-2 disrupts host epigenetic regulation via histone mimicry</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36198800/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36198800/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 (SARS-CoV-2) emerged at the end of 2019 and caused the devastating global pandemic of coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19), in part because of its ability to effectively suppress host cell responses. In rare cases, viral proteins dampen antiviral responses by mimicking critical regions of human histone proteins, particularly those containing post-translational modifications required for transcriptional regulation. Recent work has demonstrated that SARS-CoV-2 markedly disrupts host cell epigenetic regulation. However, how SARS-CoV-2 controls the host cell epigenome and whether it uses histone mimicry to do so remain unclear. Here we show that the SARS-CoV-2 protein encoded by ORF8 (ORF8) functions as a histone mimic of the ARKS motifs in histone H3 to disrupt host cell epigenetic regulation. ORF8 is associated with chromatin, disrupts regulation of critical histone post-translational modifications and promotes chromatin compaction. Deletion of either the ORF8 gene or the histone mimic site attenuates the ability of SARS-CoV-2 to disrupt host cell chromatin, affects the transcriptional response to infection and attenuates viral genome copy number. These findings demonstrate a new function of ORF8 and a mechanism through which SARS-CoV-2 disrupts host cell epigenetic regulation. Further, this work provides a molecular basis for the finding that SARS-CoV-2 lacking ORF8 is associated with decreased severity of COVID-19.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Macrophage-specific inhibition of the histone demethylase JMJD3 decreases STING and pathologic inflammation in diabetic wound repair</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36127466/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36127466/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Macrophage plasticity is critical for normal tissue repair following injury. In pathologic states such as diabetes, macrophage plasticity is impaired, and macrophages remain in a persistent proinflammatory state; however, the reasons for this are unknown. Here, using single-cell RNA sequencing of human diabetic wounds, we identified increased JMJD3 in diabetic wound macrophages, resulting in increased inflammatory gene expression. Mechanistically, we report that in wound healing, JMJD3 directs early macrophage-mediated inflammation via JAK1,3/STAT3 signaling. However, in the diabetic state, we found that IL-6, a cytokine increased in diabetic wound tissue at later time points post-injury, regulates JMJD3 expression in diabetic wound macrophages via the JAK1,3/STAT3 pathway and that this late increase in JMJD3 induces NFκB-mediated inflammatory gene transcription in wound macrophages via an H3K27me3 mechanism. Interestingly, RNA sequencing of wound macrophages isolated from mice with JMJD3-deficient myeloid cells (Jmjd3&lt;sup&gt;f/f&lt;/sup&gt;Lyz2&lt;sup&gt;Cre+&lt;/sup&gt;) identified that the STING gene (Tmem173) is regulated by JMJD3 in wound macrophages. STING limits inflammatory cytokine production by wound macrophages during healing. However, in diabetic mice, its role changes to limit wound repair and enhance inflammation. This finding is important since STING is associated with chronic inflammation, and we found STING to be elevated in human and murine diabetic wound macrophages at late time points. Finally, we demonstrate that macrophage-specific, nanoparticle inhibition of JMJD3 in diabetic wounds significantly improves diabetic wound repair by decreasing inflammatory cytokines and STING. Taken together, this work highlights the central role of JMJD3 in tissue repair and identifies cell-specific targeting as a viable therapeutic strategy for nonhealing diabetic wounds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Copper-olsalazine metal-organic frameworks as a nanocatalyst and epigenetic modulator for efficient inhibition of colorectal cancer growth and metastasis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36087871/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36087871/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite the extensive explorations of nanoscale metal-organic frameworks (nanoMOFs) in drug delivery, the intrinsic bioactivity of nanoMOFs, such as anticancer activity, is severely underestimated owing to the overlooked integration of the hierarchical components including nanosized MOFs and molecular-level organic ligands and metal-organic complexes. Herein, we propose a de novo design of multifunctional bioactive nanoMOFs ranging from molecular to nanoscale level, and demonstrate this proof-of-concept by a copper-olsalazine (Olsa, a clinically approved drug for inflammatory bowel disease, here as a bioactive linker and DNA hypomethylating agent) nanoMOF displaying a multifaceted anticancer mechanism: (1) Cu-Olsa nanoMOF-mediated redox dyshomeostasis for enhanced catalytic tumor therapy, (2) targeting downregulation of cyclooxygenase-2 by the organic complex of Cu&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt; and Olsa, and (3) Olsa-mediated epigenetic regulation. Cu-Olsa nanoMOF displayed an enzyme-like catalytic activity to generate cancericidal species ·OH and &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; from rich H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; in tumors, improved the expression of tumor suppressors TIMP3 and AXIN2 by epigenetic modulation, and fulfilled selective inhibition of colorectal cancer cells over normal cells. The hyaluronic acid-modified nanoMOF further verified the efficient suppression of CT26 colorectal tumor growth and metastasis in murine models. Overall, these results suggest that Olsa-based MOF presents a platform of epigenetic therapy-synergized nanomedicine for efficient cancer treatment and provides a powerful strategy for the design of intrinsically bioactive nanoMOFs. STATEMENT OF SIGNIFICANCE: Metal-organic frameworks (MOFs) with intrinsic bioactivities such as anticancer and antibacterial activity are of great interest. Herein, we reported a bioactive copper-olsalazine (Cu-Olsa) nanoMOF as a nanodrug for colorectal cancer treatment. This nanoMOF per se displayed enzyme-like catalytic activity to generate cancericidal species ·OH and &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; from rich H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; in tumors for nanocatalytic tumor therapy. Upon dissociation into small molecular copper-organic complex and olsalazine in cancer cells, COX-2 inhibition and epigenetic modulation were fulfilled for selective inhibition of colorectal cancer growth and metastasis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prenatal Lipopolysaccharides Exposure Induces Transgenerational Inheritance of Hypertension</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36004643/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36004643/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Adverse environmental exposure during the prenatal period can lead to diseases in the offspring, including hypertension. Whether or not the hypertensive phenotype can be transgenerationally transmitted is not known.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; Pregnant Sprague Dawley rats were intraperitoneally injected with lipopolysaccharide (LPS) on gestation days 6, 8, 10, and 12 to generate the prenatal LPS exposure model. Blood pressure was monitored by both telemetry and tail-cuff method. RNA sequencing was performed to analyze transcriptome alteration in the kidney of the third generation. Tempol and spironolactone were used to test the potential preventative and therapeutic effect of targeting reactive oxygen species and mineralocorticoid receptor signaling, respectively. Molecular biological experiments were performed to illustrate the mechanism of epigenetic and transcription regulation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; Prenatal LPS exposure can impair the ability to excrete a salt load and induce hypertension from the first to the third generations, with the fourth and fifth generations, inducing salt-sensitive hypertension. Compared with control pups, the transcriptome in the kidney of the hypertensive third-generation prenatal LPS-exposed offspring have upregulation of the Ras-related C3 botulinum toxin substrate 1 (&lt;em&gt;Rac1&lt;/em&gt;) gene and activation of mineralocorticoid receptor signaling. Furthermore, we found that LPS exposure during pregnancy triggered oxidative stress that upregulated KDM3B (histone lysine demethylase 3B) in the oocytes of first-generation female rats, leading to an inheritable low level of H3K9me2 (histone H3 lysine 9 dimethylation), resulting in the transgenerational upregulation of &lt;em&gt;Rac1&lt;/em&gt;. Based on these findings, we treated the LPS-exposed pregnant rats with the reactive oxygen species scavenger, tempol, which successfully prevented hypertension in the first-generation offspring and the transgenerational inheritance of hypertension.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; These findings show that adverse prenatal exposure induces transgenerational hypertension through an epigenetic-regulated mechanism and identify potentially preventive and therapeutic strategies for hypertension.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Epigenetics, DNA damage, and aging</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/35968782/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/35968782/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the course of a human lifespan, genome integrity erodes, leading to an increased abundance of several types of chromatin changes. The abundance of DNA lesions (chemical perturbations to nucleotides) increases with age, as does the number of genomic mutations and transcriptional disruptions caused by replication or transcription of those lesions, respectively. At the epigenetic level, precise DNA methylation patterns degrade, likely causing increasingly stochastic variations in gene expression. Similarly, the tight regulation of histone modifications begins to unravel. The genomic instability caused by these mechanisms allows transposon element reactivation and remobilization, further mutations, gene dysregulation, and cytoplasmic chromatin fragments. This cumulative genomic instability promotes cell signaling events that drive cell fate decisions and extracellular communications known to disrupt tissue homeostasis and regeneration. In this Review, we focus on age-related epigenetic changes and their interactions with age-related genomic changes that instigate these events.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Histone demethylase JMJD3 downregulation protects against aberrant force-induced osteoarthritis through epigenetic control of NR4A1</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35831280/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35831280/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Osteoarthritis (OA) is a prevalent joint disease with no effective treatment strategies. Aberrant mechanical stimuli was demonstrated to be an essential factor for OA pathogenesis. Although multiple studies have detected potential regulatory mechanisms underlying OA and have concentrated on developing novel treatment strategies, the epigenetic control of OA remains unclear. Histone demethylase JMJD3 has been reported to mediate multiple physiological and pathological processes, including cell differentiation, proliferation, autophagy, and apoptosis. However, the regulation of JMJD3 in aberrant force-related OA and its mediatory effect on disease progression are still unknown. In this work, we confirmed the upregulation of JMJD3 in aberrant force-induced cartilage injury in vitro and in vivo. Functionally, inhibition of JMJD3 by its inhibitor, GSK-J4, or downregulation of JMJD3 by adenovirus infection of sh-JMJD3 could alleviate the aberrant force-induced chondrocyte injury. Mechanistic investigation illustrated that aberrant force induces JMJD3 expression and then demethylates H3K27me3 at the NR4A1 promoter to promote its expression. Further experiments indicated that NR4A1 can regulate chondrocyte apoptosis, cartilage degeneration, extracellular matrix degradation, and inflammatory responses. In vivo, anterior cruciate ligament transection (ACLT) was performed to construct an OA model, and the therapeutic effect of GSK-J4 was validated. More importantly, we adopted a peptide-siRNA nanoplatform to deliver si-JMJD3 into articular cartilage, and the severity of joint degeneration was remarkably mitigated. Taken together, our findings demonstrated that JMJD3 is flow-responsive and epigenetically regulates OA progression. Our work provides evidences for JMJD3 inhibition as an innovative epigenetic therapy approach for joint diseases by utilizing p5RHH-siRNA nanocomplexes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DBC1 is a key positive regulator of enhancer epigenomic writers KMT2D and p300</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35801925/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35801925/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Histone modification is a key epigenetic mechanism for regulation of chromatin dynamics and gene expression. Deleted in breast cancer 1 (DBC1) has been shown to act as a negative regulator of epigenetic modifiers and as a co-activator for nuclear receptors and other transcription factors. However, little is known about the role of DBC1 in the regulation of histone modifications and chromatin landscapes. Here, we analyzed genome-wide profiles of active enhancer and promoter marks in colorectal cancer cells and report DBC1 as a critical positive regulator of histone epigenetic writers KMT2D (H3K4 methyltransferase) and p300 (histone acetyltransferase). DBC1 is required for establishing the landscape of active enhancers, for genome-wide chromatin binding and enhancer recruitment of KMT2D and p300, and for gene activation involved in colorectal cancer progression. DBC1 interacts directly with KMT2D and p300, and enhances KMT2D-mediated histone H3K4 methylation (H3K4me1/2/3) and p300-mediated H3 acetylation. Importantly, DBC1 contributes to super-enhancer formation and function by facilitating the recruitment of KMT2D and p300 and by enhancing their functional interaction and cooperative cross-talk. Our results highlight the critical role of DBC1 as a key positive regulator of KMT2D and p300, and provide insights into regulatory mechanisms underlying the interplay between the enhancer epigenomic writers in enhancer activation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Epigenomic analysis reveals a dynamic and context-specific macrophage enhancer landscape associated with innate immune activation and tolerance</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35751107/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35751107/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Chromatin states and enhancers associate gene expression, cell identity and disease. Here, we systematically delineate the acute innate immune response to endotoxin in terms of human macrophage enhancer activity and contrast with endotoxin tolerance, profiling the coding and non-coding transcriptome, chromatin accessibility and epigenetic modifications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; We describe the spectrum of enhancers under acute and tolerance conditions and the regulatory networks between these enhancers and biological processes including gene expression, splicing regulation, transcription factor binding and enhancer RNA signatures. We demonstrate that the vast majority of differentially regulated enhancers on acute stimulation are subject to tolerance and that expression quantitative trait loci, disease-risk variants and eRNAs are enriched in these regulatory regions and related to context-specific gene expression. We find enrichment for context-specific eQTL involving endotoxin response and specific infections and delineate specific differential regions informative for GWAS variants in inflammatory bowel disease and multiple sclerosis, together with a context-specific enhancer involving a bacterial infection eQTL for KLF4. We show enrichment in differential enhancers for tolerance involving transcription factors NFκB-p65, STATs and IRFs and prioritize putative causal genes directly linking genetic variants and disease risk enhancers. We further delineate similarities and differences in epigenetic landscape between stem cell-derived macrophages and primary cells and characterize the context-specific enhancer activities for key innate immune response genes KLF4, SLAMF1 and IL2RA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; Our study demonstrates the importance of context-specific macrophage enhancers in gene regulation and utility for interpreting disease associations, providing a roadmap to link genetic variants with molecular and cellular functions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Methyltransferase-like 3 leads to lung injury by up-regulation of interleukin 24 through N6-methyladenosine-dependent mRNA stability and translation efficiency in mice exposed to fine particulate matter 2.5</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35718042/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35718042/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Long-term fine particulate matter 2.5 (PM2.5) exposure induces lung injury.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PM2.5 increases the global RNA m&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;A modification in vivo and in vitro.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PM2.5 alters the expression of m&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;A modulators including METTL3 and YTHDF1.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;YTHDF1 can bind &lt;em&gt;IL24&lt;/em&gt; mRNA.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;METTL3 and YTHDF1 regulate the expression of IL24 via m&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;A modification.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fine particulate matter 2.5 (PM2.5) exposure leads to the progress of pulmonary disease. It has been reported that N6-methyladenosine (m&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;A) modification was involved in various biological processes and diseases. However, the critical role of m&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;A modification in pulmonary disease during PM2.5 exposure remains elusive. Here, we revealed that lung inflammation and mucus production caused by PM2.5 were associated with m&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;A modification. Both &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;in vitro&lt;/em&gt; assays demonstrated that PM2.5 exposure elevated the total level of m&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;A modification as well as the methyltransferase like 3 (METTL3) expression. Integration analysis of m&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;A RNA immunoprecipitation-seq (meRIP-seq) and RNA-seq discovered that METTL3 up-regulated the expression level and the m&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;A modification of Interleukin 24 (IL24). Importantly, we explored that the stability of &lt;em&gt;IL24&lt;/em&gt; mRNA was enhanced due to the increased m&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;A modification. Moreover, the data from qRT-PCR showed that PM2.5 also increased &lt;em&gt;YTH&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;N&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;-Methyladenosine RNA Binding Protein 1&lt;/em&gt; (&lt;em&gt;YTHDF1&lt;/em&gt;) expression, and the up-regulated YTHDF1 augmented &lt;em&gt;IL24&lt;/em&gt; mRNA translation efficiency. Down-regulation of Mettl3 reduced Il24 expression and ameliorated the pulmonary inflammation and mucus secretion in mice exposed to PM2.5. Taken together, our finding provided a comprehensive insight for revealing the significant role of m&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;A regulators in the lung injury via METTL3/YTHDF1-coupled epitranscriptomal regulation of &lt;em&gt;IL24&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>METTL3-Mediated N6-Methyladenosine Modification of Trim59 mRNA Protects Against Sepsis-Induced Acute Respiratory Distress Syndrome</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35693774/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35693774/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;N6-methyladenosine (m&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;A) RNA modification is a fundamental determinant of mRNA metabolism in eukaryotic cells and is involved in numerous physiological and pathological processes. However, the specific role of m&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;A modification in sepsis-induced acute respiratory distress syndrome(ARDS) remains unknown. Here, we show that the levels of m&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;A RNA were significantly decreased in septic lungs and that METTL3 was the main regulator involved in the absence of m&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;A RNA modification. Pulmonary endothelial barrier damage is a critical process in the pathogenesis of acute lung injury during sepsis. METTL3 regulated endothelial barrier dysfunction and inflammatory responses in sepsis-induced ARDS &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;in vitro&lt;/em&gt;. Furthermore, we identified tripartite motif-containing (Trim)59 as a key m&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;A effector and Trim59 deficiency exacerbated lung injury. Mechanistically, METTL3 inhibited endothelial injury in sepsis-induced ARDS through Trim59-associated NF-κB inactivation. Our findings revealed novel insights into epitranscriptional mechanisms in sepsis-induced ARDS via m&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;A modifications, which has important application value in the diagnosis, prognosis, and molecular-targeted therapy of sepsis-associated lung injury.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Perspectives of using microRNA-loaded nanocarriers for epigenetic reprogramming of drug resistant colorectal cancers</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/35623562/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/35623562/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Epigenetic regulation by microRNAs (miRs) demonstrated a promising therapeutic potential of these molecules to regulate genetic activity in different cancers, including colorectal cancers (CRCs). The RNA-based therapy does not change genetic codes in tumor cells but can silence oncogenes and/or reactivate inhibited tumor suppressor genes. In many cancers, specific miRs were shown to promote or stop tumor progression. Among confirmed and powerful epigenetic regulators of colon carcinogenesis and development of resistance are onco-miRs, which include let-7, miR-21, miR-22, miR-23a, miR-27a, miR-34, miR-92, miR-96, miR-125b, miR-135b, miR-182, miR-200c, miR-203, miR-221, miR-421, miR-451, and others. Moreover, various tumor-suppressor miRs (miR-15b-5b, miR-18a, miR-20b, miR-22, miR-96, miR-139-5p, miR-145, miR-149, miR-197, miR-199b, miR-203, miR-214, miR-218, miR-320, miR-375-3p, miR-409-3p, miR-450b-5p, miR-494, miR-577, miR-874, and others) were found silenced in drug-resistant CRCs. Re-expression of tumor suppressor miR is complicated by the chemical nature of miRs that are not long-lasting compounds and require protection from the enzymatic degradation. Several recent studies explored application of miRs using nanocarrier complexes. This study critically describes the most successfully tested nanoparticle complexes used for intracellular delivery of nuclear acids and miRs, including micelles, liposomes, inorganic and polymeric NPs, dendrimers, and aptamers. Nanocarriers shield incorporated miRs and improve the agent stability in circulation. Attachment of antibodies and/or specific peptide or ligands facilitates cell-targeted miR delivery. Addressing in vivo challenges, a broad spectrum of non-toxic materials has been tested and indicated reliable advantages of lipid-based (lipoplexes) and polymer-based liposomes. Recent cutting-edge developments indicated that lipid-based complexes with multiple cargo, including several miRs, are the most effective approach to eradicate drug-resistant tumors. Focusing on CRC-specific miRs, this review provides a guidance and insights towards the most promising direction to achieve dramatic reduction in tumor growth and metastasis using miR-nanocarrier complexes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zinc finger protein 280C contributes to colorectal tumorigenesis by maintaining epigenetic repression at H3K27me3-marked loci</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35605119/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35605119/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Significance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This study uncovered the role of ZNF280C, a known DNA damage response protein, as a tumorigenic transcription regulator that contributes to colorectal tumorigenesis and metastasis through maintaining an epigenetic repression program at key cancer gene loci. These findings identified a contributor with potential prognostic value to colorectal pathogenesis and provide mechanistic insight to the essential function of transcription factor in fine-tuning the activity of chromatin regulators for proper transcription control.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dysregulated epigenetic and transcriptional programming due to abnormalities of transcription factors (TFs) contributes to and sustains the oncogenicity of cancer cells. Here, we unveiled the role of zinc finger protein 280C (ZNF280C), a known DNA damage response protein, as a tumorigenic TF in colorectal cancer (CRC), required for colitis-associated carcinogenesis and Apc deficiency–driven intestinal tumorigenesis in mice. Consistently, ZNF280C silencing in human CRC cells inhibited proliferation, clonogenicity, migration, xenograft growth, and liver metastasis. As a C2H2 (Cys2-His2) zinc finger-containing TF, ZNF280C occupied genomic intervals with both transcriptionally active and repressive states and coincided with CCCTC-binding factor (CTCF) and cohesin binding. Notably, ZNF280C was crucial for the repression program of trimethylation of histone H3 at lysine 27 (H3K27me3)-marked genes and the maintenance of both focal and broad H3K27me3 levels. Mechanistically, ZNF280C counteracted CTCF/cohesin activities and condensed the chromatin environment at the cis elements of certain tumor suppressor genes marked by H3K27me3, at least partially through recruiting the epigenetic repressor structural maintenance of chromosomes flexible hinge domain-containing 1 (SMCHD1). In clinical relevance, ZNF280C was highly expressed in primary CRCs and distant metastases, and a higher ZNF280C level independently predicted worse prognosis of CRC patients. Thus, our study uncovered a contributor with good prognostic value to CRC pathogenesis and also elucidated the essence of DNA-binding TFs in orchestrating the epigenetic programming of gene regulation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Xist-mediated silencing requires additive functions of SPEN and Polycomb together with differentiation-dependent recruitment of SmcHD1</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35584662/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35584662/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SPEN and PRC1 pathways function in parallel to establish gene silencing by Xist RNA&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Removal of both pathways abolishes gene silencing and disrupts Xist localization&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Differentiation is required to achieve maximal X-linked gene silencing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Differentiation-dependent SmcHD1 recruitment contributes to silencing of many genes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;X chromosome inactivation (XCI) is mediated by the non-coding RNA Xist, which directs chromatin modification and gene silencing in cis. The RNA binding protein SPEN and associated corepressors have a central role in Xist-mediated gene silencing. Other silencing factors, notably the Polycomb system, have been reported to function downstream of SPEN. In recent work, we found that SPEN has an additional role in correct localization of Xist RNA in cis, indicating that its contribution to chromatin-mediated gene silencing needs to be reappraised. Making use of a SPEN separation-of-function mutation, we show that SPEN and Polycomb pathways, in fact, function in parallel to establish gene silencing. We also find that differentiation-dependent recruitment of the chromosomal protein SmcHD1 is required for silencing many X-linked genes. Our results provide important insights into the mechanism of X inactivation and the coordination of chromatin-based gene regulation with cellular differentiation and development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Antisense-mediated repression of SAGA-dependent genes involves the HIR histone chaperone</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35474134/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35474134/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eukaryotic genomes are pervasively transcribed by RNA polymerase II (RNAPII), and transcription of long non-coding RNAs often overlaps with coding gene promoters. This might lead to coding gene repression in a process named Transcription Interference (TI). In Saccharomyces cerevisiae, TI is mainly driven by antisense non-coding transcription and occurs through re-shaping of promoter Nucleosome-Depleted Regions (NDRs). In this study, we developed a genetic screen to identify new players involved in Antisense-Mediated Transcription Interference (AMTI). Among the candidates, we found the HIR histone chaperone complex known to be involved in de novo histone deposition. Using genome-wide approaches, we reveal that HIR-dependent histone deposition represses the promoters of SAGA-dependent genes via antisense non-coding transcription. However, while antisense transcription is enriched at promoters of SAGA-dependent genes, this feature is not sufficient to define the mode of gene regulation. We further show that the balance between HIR-dependent nucleosome incorporation and transcription factor binding at promoters directs transcription into a SAGA- or TFIID-dependent regulation. This study sheds light on a new connection between antisense non-coding transcription and the nature of coding transcription initiation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BAP1 shapes the bone marrow niche for lymphopoiesis by fine-tuning epigenetic profiles in endosteal mesenchymal stromal cells</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35473985/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35473985/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hematopoiesis occurs within a unique bone marrow (BM) microenvironment, which consists of various niche cells, cytokines, growth factors, and extracellular matrix components. These multiple components directly or indirectly regulate the maintenance and differentiation of hematopoietic stem cells (HSCs). Here we report that BAP1 in BM mesenchymal stromal cells (MSCs) is critical for the maintenance of HSCs and B lymphopoiesis. Mice lacking BAP1 in MSCs show aberrant differentiation of hematopoietic stem and progenitor cells, impaired B lymphoid differentiation, and expansion of myeloid lineages. Mechanistically, BAP1 loss in distinct endosteal MSCs, expressing PRX1 but not LEPR, leads to aberrant expression of genes affiliated with BM niche functions. BAP1 deficiency leads to a reduced expression of pro-hematopoietic factors such as Scf caused by increased H2AK119-ub1 and H3K27-me3 levels on the promoter region of these genes. On the other hand, the expression of myelopoiesis stimulating factors including Csf3 was increased by enriched H3K4-me3 and H3K27-ac levels on their promoter, causing myeloid skewing. Notably, loss of BAP1 substantially blocks B lymphopoiesis and skews the differentiation of hematopoietic precursors toward myeloid lineages in vitro, which is reversed by G-CSF neutralization. Thus, our study uncovers a key role for BAP1 expressed in endosteal MSCs in controlling normal hematopoiesis in mice by modulating expression of various niche factors governing lymphopoiesis and myelopoiesis via histone modifications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inhaled tire-wear microplastic particles induced pulmonary fibrotic injury via epithelial cytoskeleton rearrangement</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35486965/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35486965/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tire wear microplastic particles (TWMPs) are emerging microplastic pollutants that have gained increasing attention lately. However, the health effect of inhaled airborne TWMPs has never been explored before and may already be included in particulate matter morbidity and mortality. Here, we endeavored to address the preliminary study of TWMP inhalation-induced pulmonary toxic effects and its epigenetic mechanisms in C57BL/6 mice. As a result, restricted ventilatory dysfunction and fibrotic pathological changes were observed in TWMP-treaded mice. Further research found that attenuation of miR-1a-3p plays an important role in TWMP-induced lung injury. Results from in vitro study confirmed that cytoskeleton regulatory gene twinfilin-1 was one of the target genes of miR-1a-3p, and involved in cytoskeleton rearrangement caused by TWMP exposure. Mechanistically, miR-1a-3p inhibited the F-actin formation by targeting cytoskeletal regulatory proteins twinfilin-1, leading to TWMP-induced pulmonary fibrotic injury. While we are in the very early stages of explaining the role of epigenetics in TWMP-induced lung injury, the potential for the use of epigenetic marks as biomarkers is high and discoveries made in this field will likely bring us closer to better understanding this crucial mechanism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The nuclear receptor THRB facilitates differentiation of human PSCs into more mature hepatocytes</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35452598/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35452598/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;THRB motif enrichment in regulomes is lower in PSC-hepatocytes than in primary hepatocytes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;THRB regulates &lt;em&gt;CYP3A4&lt;/em&gt; expression by binding to the proximal enhancer of &lt;em&gt;CYP3A4&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The pBAF component PBRM1 binds THRB and is required for THRB regulation of &lt;em&gt;CYP3A4&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;T3 promotes maturation and engraftment of in vitro differentiated hPSC-hepatocytes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To understand the mechanisms regulating the &lt;em&gt;in vitro&lt;/em&gt; maturation of hPSC-derived hepatocytes, we developed a 3D differentiation system and compared gene regulatory elements in human primary hepatocytes with those in hPSC-hepatocytes that were differentiated in 2D or 3D conditions by RNA-seq, ATAC-seq, and H3K27Ac ChIP-seq. Regulome comparisons showed a reduced enrichment of thyroid receptor THRB motifs in accessible chromatin and active enhancers without a reduced transcription of THRB. The addition of thyroid hormone T3 increased the binding of THRB to the &lt;em&gt;CYP3A4&lt;/em&gt; proximal enhancer, restored the super-enhancer status and gene expression of &lt;em&gt;NFIC&lt;/em&gt;, and reduced the expression of &lt;em&gt;AFP&lt;/em&gt;. The resultant hPSC-hepatocytes showed gene expression, epigenetic status, and super-enhancer landscape closer to primary hepatocytes and activated regulatory regions including non-coding SNPs associated with liver-related diseases. Transplanting the hPSC-hepatocytes resulted in the engraftment of human hepatocytes into the mouse liver without disrupting normal liver histology. This work implicates the environmental factor-nuclear receptor axis in regulating the maturation of hPSC-hepatocytes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bone tissue engineering using 3D silk scaffolds and human dental pulp stromal cells epigenetic reprogrammed with the selective histone deacetylase inhibitor MI192</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35362831/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35362831/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Epigenetics plays a critical role in regulating mesenchymal stem cells&amp;rsquo; (MSCs) fate for tissue repair and regeneration. There is increasing evidence that the inhibition of histone deacetylase (HDAC) isoform 3 can enhance MSC osteogenesis. This study investigated the potential of using a selective HDAC2 and 3 inhibitor, MI192, to promote human dental pulp stromal cells (hDPSCs) bone-like tissue formation in vitro and in vivo within porous Bombyx Mori silk scaffolds. Both 2 and 5 wt% silk scaffolds were fabricated and characterised. The 5 wt% scaffolds possess thicker internal lamellae, reduced scaffold swelling and degradation rates, whilst increased compressive modulus in comparison to the 2 wt% silk scaffold. MI192 pre-treatment of hDPSCs on 5 wt% silk scaffold significantly enhanced hDPSCs alkaline phosphatase activity (ALP). The expression of osteoblast-related genes (RUNX2, ALP, Col1a, OCN) was significantly upregulated in the MI192 pre-treated cells. Histological analysis confirmed that the MI192 pre-treated hDPSCs-silk scaffold constructs promoted bone extracellular matrix (ALP, Col1a, OCN) deposition and mineralisation compared to the untreated group. Following 6 weeks of subcutaneous implantation in nude mice, the MI192 pre-treated hDPSCs-silk scaffold constructs enhanced the vascularisation and extracellular matrix mineralisation compared to untreated control. In conclusion, these findings demonstrate the potential of using epigenetic reprogramming and silk scaffolds to promote hDPSCs bone formation efficacy, which provides evidence for clinical translation of this technology for bone augmentation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Epigenetic regulation of EIF4A1 through DNA methylation and an oncogenic role of eIF4A1 through BRD2 signaling in prostate cancer</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35361883/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35361883/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In prostate cancers, elongation initiation factor 4A1 (eIF4A1) supports an oncogenic translation program and is highly expressed, but its role remains elusive. By the use of human specimens and cell models, we addressed the role of eIF4A1 in prostate cancer &lt;em&gt;in vitro&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;em&gt;EIF4A1&lt;/em&gt; expression, as determined by mRNA and protein levels, was higher in primary prostate cancers relative to normal prostate tissue. Also, for primary prostate cancers, elevated mRNA levels of &lt;em&gt;EIF4A1&lt;/em&gt; correlated with DNA hypomethylation levels in the CpG-rich island of &lt;em&gt;EIF4A1&lt;/em&gt;. Using a DNMT3a CRISPR-Cas9-based tool for specific targeting of DNA methylation, we characterized, in human prostate cancer cells, the epigenetic regulation of &lt;em&gt;EIF4A1&lt;/em&gt; transcripts through DNA methylation in the CpG-rich island of &lt;em&gt;EIF4A1&lt;/em&gt;. Next, we investigated the oncogenic effect of &lt;em&gt;EIF4A1&lt;/em&gt; on cancer cell proliferation &lt;em&gt;in vitro&lt;/em&gt; and tumor growth &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt;. For prostate cancer cells, &lt;em&gt;EIF4A1&lt;/em&gt; heterozygous knockout or knockdown inhibited protein translation and tumor growth. In addition, using RNA immunoprecipitation with RNA sequencing, we discovered the eIF4A1-mediated translational regulation of the oncogene &lt;em&gt;BRD2&lt;/em&gt;, which contains the most enriched eIF4A1-binding motifs in its 5&amp;rsquo; untranslated region, establishing an eIF4A1-BRD2 axis for oncogenic translation. Finally, we found a positive correlation between expression levels of &lt;em&gt;eIF4A1&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;BRD2&lt;/em&gt; in primary prostate cancers. Our results demonstrate, for prostate cancer cells, epigenetic regulation of &lt;em&gt;EIF4A1&lt;/em&gt; transcripts through DNA methylation and an oncogenic role of eIF4A1 through BRD2 signaling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inhibition of bromodomain extraterminal histone readers alleviates skin fibrosis in experimental models of scleroderma</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35349485/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35349485/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Binding of the bromodomain and extraterminal domain proteins (BETs) to acetylated histone residues is critical for gene transcription. We sought to determine the antifibrotic efficacy and potential mechanisms of BET inhibition in systemic sclerosis (SSc). Blockade of BETs was done using a pan-BET inhibitor, JQ1; BRD2 inhibitor, BIC1; or BRD4 inhibitors AZD5153 or ARV825. BET inhibition, specifically BRD4 blockade, showed antifibrotic effects in an animal model of SSc and in patient-derived diffuse cutaneous SSc (dcSSc) fibroblasts. Transcriptome analysis of JQ1-treated dcSSc fibroblasts revealed differentially expressed genes related to extracellular matrix, cell cycle, and calcium (Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt;) signaling. The antifibrotic effect of BRD4 inhibition was mediated at least in part by downregulation of Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt;/calmodulin-dependent protein kinase II α and reduction of intracellular Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt; concentrations. On the basis of these results, we propose targeting Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt; pathways or BRD4 as potentially novel therapeutic approaches for progressive tissue fibrosis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Epigenetic regulation of CXCR4 signaling in cancer pathogenesis and progression</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/35346802/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/35346802/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Signaling involving chemokine receptor CXCR4 and its ligand SDF-1/CXL12 has been investigated for many years for its possible role in cancer progression and pathogenesis. Evidence emerging from clinical studies in recent years has further established diagnostic as well as prognostic importance of CXCR4 signaling. CXCR4 and SDF-1 are routinely reported to be elevated in tumors, distant metastases, which correlates with poor survival of patients. These findings have kindled interest in the mechanisms that regulate CXCR4/SDF-1 expression. Of note, there is a particular interest in the epigenetic regulation of CXCR4 signaling that may be responsible for upregulated CXCR4 in primary as well as metastatic cancers. This review first lists the clinical evidence supporting CXCR4 signaling as putative cancer diagnostic and/or prognostic biomarker, followed by a discussion on reported epigenetic mechanisms that affect CXCR4 expression. These mechanisms include regulation by non-coding RNAs, such as, microRNAs, long non-coding RNAs and circular RNAs. Additionally, we also discuss the regulation of CXCR4 expression through methylation and acetylation. Better understanding and appreciation of epigenetic regulation of CXCR4 signaling can invariably lead to identification of novel therapeutic targets as well as therapies to regulate this oncogenic signaling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Histone Extraction from Human Articular Cartilage for the Study of Epigenetic Regulation in Osteoarthritis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35328777/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35328777/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Osteoarthritis (OA) is a chronic disease that affects articular cartilage, causing its degeneration. Although OA is one of the most prevalent pathologies globally, there are no definitive treatments available. Recently, research has focused on elucidating the complex interplay that takes place between inflammatory processes and epigenetic regulation, showing that histone post-translational modifications (PTMs) can exert a pronounced effect on the expression of OA-related genes. OA chondrocytes enhance the production of interleukin 1β (IL-1β) and interleukin 8 (IL-8), which are epigenetically regulated. These cytokines upregulate the synthesis of matrix metalloproteinases (MMPs) and aggrecanases, which promote the extracellular matrix (ECM) destruction. This motivates the study of histone PTMs to investigate the epigenetic regulation of proinflammatory molecules, but the absence of specific protocols to extract histones from human articular cartilage has complicated this task. The lack of effective methods can be explained by the structural complexity and low cellularity of this tissue, which are responsible for the biomechanical properties that allow the movement of the joint but also complicate histone isolation. Here, we provide a histone extraction procedure specifically adapted for cryopreserved human articular cartilage that can be useful to understand epigenetic regulation in OA and accelerate the search for novel strategies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Regulation of Dystroglycan Gene Expression in Early Myoblast Differentiation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35330913/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35330913/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dystroglycan, a component of the dystrophin-associated glycoprotein complex, connects the extracellular matrix and cytoskeleton to maintain muscle membrane integrity. As such, abnormalities of dystroglycan are linked to different types of muscular dystrophies. In an effort to develop therapeutic approaches to re-establish signal integration for muscle repair and homeostasis, we have previously determined that a clinically approved agonist of retinoid X receptor enhances myoblast differentiation through direct regulation of gene expression of the muscle master regulator MyoD. Using comprehensive omics and molecular analyses, we found that dystroglycan gene expression is responsive to retinoid X receptor-selective signaling in early myoblast differentiation. In addition, the dystroglycan gene is a MyoD target, and residue-specific histone acetylation coincides with the occupancy of histone acetyltransferase p300 at the MyoD binding sites. Consequently, the p300 function is important for rexinoid-augmented dystroglycan gene expression. Finally, dystroglycan plays a role in myoblast differentiation. Our study sheds new light on dystroglycan regulation and function in myoblast differentiation and presents a potential avenue for re-establishing signal integration of a specific chromatin state pharmacologically to overcome muscle pathology and identify additional myogenic interactions for therapeutic applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Epigenetic modifications in spinal ligament aging</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/35218968/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/35218968/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spinal ligament aging is a complex process involving genetic, epigenetic, and environmental factors.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;DNA methylation, histone modifications and ncRNAs exert vital functions in spinal ligament aging.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Epigenetic alterations provide promising diagnostic and therapeutic targets for spinal ligament aging.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spinal stenosis is a common degenerative spine disorder in the aged population and the spinal ligament aging is a main contributor to this chronic disease. However, the underlying mechanisms of spinal ligament aging remain unclear. Epigenetics is the study of heritable and reversible changes in the function of a gene or genome that occur without any alteration in the primary DNA sequence. Epigenetic alterations have been demonstrated to play crucial roles in age-related diseases and conditions, and they are recently studied as biomarkers and therapeutic targets in the field of cancer research. The main epigenetic modifications, including DNA methylation alteration, histone modifications as well as dysregulated noncoding RNA modulation, have all been implicated in spinal ligament aging diseases. DNA methylation modulates the expression of critical genes including WNT5A, GDNF, ACSM5, miR-497 and miR-195 during spinal ligament degeneration. Histone modifications widely affect gene expression and obvious histone modification abnormalities have been found in spinal ligament aging. MicroRNAs (miRNAs), long noncoding RNAs (lncRNAs) and circular RNAs (circRNAs) exert crucial regulating effects on spinal ligament aging conditions via targeting various osteogenic or fibrogenic differentiation related genes. To our knowledge, there is no systematic review yet to summarize the involvement of epigenetic mechanisms of spinal ligament aging in degenerative spinal diseases. In this study, we systematically discussed the different epigenetic modifications and their potential functions in spinal ligament aging process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Epigenomic and enhancer dysregulation in uterine leiomyomas</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/35199155/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/35199155/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Uterine leiomyomas, also known as uterine fibroids or myomas, are the most common benign gynecological tumors and are found in women of reproductive and postmenopausal age. There is an exceptionally high prevalence of this tumor in women by the age of 50 years. Black women are particularly affected, with an increased incidence, earlier age of onset, larger and faster growing fibroids and greater severity of symptoms as compared to White women. Although advances in identifying genetic and environmental factors to delineate these fibroids have already been made, only recently has the role of epigenomics in the pathogenesis of this disease been considered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Objective and rationale:&lt;/em&gt; Over recent years, studies have identified multiple epigenomic aberrations that may contribute to leiomyoma development and growth. This review will focus on the most recent discoveries in three categories of epigenomic changes found in uterine fibroids, namely aberrant DNA methylation, histone tail modifications and histone variant exchange, and their translation into altered target gene architecture and transcriptional outcome. The findings demonstrating how the altered 3D shape of the enhancer can regulate gene expression from millions of base pairs away will be discussed. Additionally, translational implications of these discoveries and potential roadblocks in leiomyoma treatment will be addressed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Search methods:&lt;/em&gt; A comprehensive PubMed search was performed to identify published articles containing keywords relevant to the focus of the review, such as: uterine leiomyoma, uterine fibroids, epigenetic alterations, epigenomics, stem cells, chromatin modifications, extracellular matrix [ECM] organization, DNA methylation, enhancer, histone post-translational modifications and dysregulated gene expression. Articles until September 2021 were explored and evaluated to identify relevant updates in the field. Most of the articles focused on in the discussion were published between 2015 and 2021, although some key discoveries made before 2015 were included for background information and foundational purposes. We apologize to the authors whose work was not included because of space restrictions or inadvertent omission.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Outcomes:&lt;/em&gt; Chemical alterations to the DNA structure and of nucleosomal histones, without changing the underlying DNA sequence, have now been implicated in the phenotypic manifestation of uterine leiomyomas. Genome-wide DNA methylation analysis has revealed subsets of either suppressed or overexpressed genes accompanied by aberrant promoter methylation. Furthermore, differential promoter access resulting from altered 3D chromatin structure and histone modifications plays a role in regulating transcription of key genes thought to be involved in leiomyoma etiology. The dysregulated genes function in tumor suppression, apoptosis, angiogenesis, ECM formation, a variety of cancer-related signaling pathways and stem cell differentiation. Aberrant DNA methylation or histone modification is also observed in altering enhancer architecture, which leads to changes in enhancer-promoter contact strength, producing novel explanations for the overexpression of high mobility group AT-hook 2 and gene dysregulation found in mediator complex subunit 12 mutant fibroids. While many molecular mechanisms and epigenomic features have been investigated, the basis for the racial disparity observed among those in the Black population remains unclear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Wider implications:&lt;/em&gt; A comprehensive understanding of the exact pathogenesis of uterine leiomyoma is lacking and requires attention as it can provide clues for prevention and viable non-surgical treatment. These findings will widen our knowledge of the role epigenomics plays in the mechanisms related to uterine leiomyoma development and highlight novel approaches for the prevention and identification of epigenome targets for long-term non-invasive treatment options of this significantly common disease.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Loss of IκBζ Drives Dentin Formation via Altered H3K4me3 Status</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35193410/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35193410/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enforced enrichment of the active promoter marks trimethylation of histone H3 lysine 4 (H3K4me3) and acetylation of histone H3 lysine 27 (H3K27ac) by inhibiting histone demethylases and deacetylases is positively associated with hard tissue formation through the induction of osteo/odontogenic differentiation. However, the key endogenous epigenetic modulator of odontoblasts to regulate the expression of genes coding dentin extracellular matrix (ECM) proteins has not been identified. We focused on nuclear factor (NF)-κB inhibitor ζ (IκBζ), which was originally identified as the transcriptional regulator of NF-κB and recently regarded as the NF-κB-independent epigenetic modulator, and found that IκBζ null mice exhibit a thicker dentin width and narrower pulp chamber, with aged mice having more marked phenotypes. At 6 mo of age, dentin fluorescent labeling revealed significantly accelerated dentin synthesis in the incisors of IκBζ null mice. In the molars of IκBζ null mice, marked tertiary dentin formation adjacent to the pulp horn was observed. Mechanistically, the expression of COL1A2 and COL1A1 collagen genes increased more in the odontoblast-rich fraction of IκBζ null mice than in wild type in vivo, similar to human odontoblast-like cells transfected with small interfering RNA for IκBζ compared with cells transfected with control siRNA in vitro. Furthermore, the direct binding of IκBζ to the COL1A2 promoter suppressed COL1A2 expression and the local active chromatin status marked by H3K4me3. Based on whole-genome identification of H3K4me3 enrichment, ECM and ECM organization-related gene loci were selectively activated by the knockdown of IκBζ, which consistently resulted in the upregulation of these genes. Collectively, this study suggested that IκBζ is the key negative regulator of dentin formation in odontoblasts by inhibiting dentin ECM- and ECM organization-related gene expression through an altered local chromatin status marked by H3K4me3. Therefore, IκBζ is a potential target for epigenetically improving the clinical outcomes of dentin regeneration therapies such as pulp capping.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Epigenetic regulation in antiviral innate immunity</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/33964027/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/33964027/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Emerging life-threatening viruses have posed great challenges to public health. It is now increasingly clear that epigenetics plays a role in shaping host-virus interactions and there is a great need for a more thorough understanding of these intricate interactions through the epigenetic lens, which may represent potential therapeutic opportunities in the clinic. In this review, we highlight the current understanding of the roles of key epigenetic regulators - chromatin remodeling and histone modification - in modulating chromatin openness during host defense against virus. We also discuss how the RNA modification m6A (N6-methyladenosine) affects fundamental aspects of host-virus interactions. We conclude with future directions for uncovering more detailed functions that epigenetic regulation exerts on both host cells and viruses during infection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transcriptomic and epigenetic mechanisms underlying myeloid diversity in the lung</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/31959980/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/31959980/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The lung is inhabited by resident alveolar and interstitial macrophages as well as monocytic cells that survey lung tissues. Each cell type plays distinct functional roles under homeostatic and inflammatory conditions, but mechanisms establishing their molecular identities and functional potential remain poorly understood. In the present study, systematic evaluation of transcriptomes and open chromatin of alveolar macrophages (AMs), interstitial macrophages (IMs) and lung monocytes from two mouse strains enabled inference of common and cell-specific transcriptional regulators. We provide evidence that these factors drive selection of regulatory landscapes that specify distinct phenotypes of AMs and IMs and entrain qualitatively different responses to toll-like receptor 4 signaling in vivo. These studies reveal a striking divergence in a fundamental innate immune response pathway in AMs and establish a framework for further understanding macrophage diversity in the lung.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LncRNA PTPRE-AS1 modulates M2 macrophage activation and inflammatory diseases by epigenetic promotion of PTPRE</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/31844669/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/31844669/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Long noncoding RNAs (lncRNAs) are important regulators of diverse biological processes; however, their function in macrophage activation is undefined. We describe a new regulatory mechanism, where an unreported lncRNA, &lt;em&gt;PTPRE-AS1&lt;/em&gt;, targets receptor-type tyrosine protein phosphatase ε (PTPRE) to regulate macrophage activation. &lt;em&gt;PTPRE-AS1&lt;/em&gt; was selectively expressed in IL-4-stimulated macrophages, and its knockdown promoted M2 macrophage activation via MAPK/ERK 1/2 pathway. In vivo, PTPRE-AS1 deficiency enhanced IL-4-mediated M2 macrophage activation and accelerated pulmonary allergic inflammation while reducing chemical-induced colitis. Mechanistically, &lt;em&gt;PTPRE-AS1&lt;/em&gt; bound WDR5 directly, modulating H3K4me3 of the &lt;em&gt;PTPRE&lt;/em&gt; promoter to regulate &lt;em&gt;PTPRE&lt;/em&gt;-dependent signaling during M2 macrophage activation. Further, the expression of &lt;em&gt;PTPRE-AS1&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;PTPRE&lt;/em&gt; was significantly lower in peripheral blood mononuclear cells from patients with allergic asthma. These results provide evidence supporting the importance of &lt;em&gt;PTPRE-AS1&lt;/em&gt; in controlling macrophage function and the potential utility of &lt;em&gt;PTPRE-AS1&lt;/em&gt; as a target for controlling inflammatory diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Key Role of Epigenetics in Human Disease Prevention and Mitigation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/29617578/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/29617578/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No abstract available&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
