<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Epigenetics | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/epigenetics/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/epigenetics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Epigenetics</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Epigenetics</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/epigenetics/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>LncRNA PTPRE-AS1 modulates M2 macrophage activation and inflammatory diseases by epigenetic promotion of PTPRE</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/31844669/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/31844669/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Long noncoding RNAs (lncRNAs) are important regulators of diverse biological processes; however, their function in macrophage activation is undefined. We describe a new regulatory mechanism, where an unreported lncRNA, &lt;em&gt;PTPRE-AS1&lt;/em&gt;, targets receptor-type tyrosine protein phosphatase ε (PTPRE) to regulate macrophage activation. &lt;em&gt;PTPRE-AS1&lt;/em&gt; was selectively expressed in IL-4-stimulated macrophages, and its knockdown promoted M2 macrophage activation via MAPK/ERK 1/2 pathway. In vivo, PTPRE-AS1 deficiency enhanced IL-4-mediated M2 macrophage activation and accelerated pulmonary allergic inflammation while reducing chemical-induced colitis. Mechanistically, &lt;em&gt;PTPRE-AS1&lt;/em&gt; bound WDR5 directly, modulating H3K4me3 of the &lt;em&gt;PTPRE&lt;/em&gt; promoter to regulate &lt;em&gt;PTPRE&lt;/em&gt;-dependent signaling during M2 macrophage activation. Further, the expression of &lt;em&gt;PTPRE-AS1&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;PTPRE&lt;/em&gt; was significantly lower in peripheral blood mononuclear cells from patients with allergic asthma. These results provide evidence supporting the importance of &lt;em&gt;PTPRE-AS1&lt;/em&gt; in controlling macrophage function and the potential utility of &lt;em&gt;PTPRE-AS1&lt;/em&gt; as a target for controlling inflammatory diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
