<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Metabolism | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/metabolism/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/metabolism/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Metabolism</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Metabolism</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/metabolism/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gut commensal Parabacteroides distasonis alleviates inflammatory arthritis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36604114/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36604114/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Objective:&lt;/em&gt; Gut microbiota dysbiosis is closely linked to the pathogenesis of rheumatoid arthritis (RA). We aimed to identify potential probiotic gut microbes that can ameliorate the development of RA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Design:&lt;/em&gt; Microbiota profiling in patients with RA and healthy individuals was investigated via 16S rDNA bacterial gene sequencing and shotgun metagenomics. Collagen-induced arthritic mice and TNF-α transgenic mice were used to evaluate the roles of the gut commensal &lt;em&gt;Parabacteroides distasonis&lt;/em&gt; in RA. The effects of &lt;em&gt;P. distasonis&lt;/em&gt;-derived microbial metabolites on the differentiation of CD4&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T cells and macrophage polarisation were also investigated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; The relative abundance of &lt;em&gt;P. distasonis&lt;/em&gt; in new-onset patients with RA and patients with RA with history of the disease was downregulated and this decrease was negatively correlated with Disease Activity Score-28 (DAS28). Oral treatment of arthritic mice with live &lt;em&gt;P. distasonis&lt;/em&gt; (LPD) considerably ameliorated RA pathogenesis. LPD-derived lithocholic acid (LCA), deoxycholic acid (DCA), isolithocholic acid (isoLCA) and 3-oxolithocholic acid (3-oxoLCA) had similar and synergistic effects on the treatment of RA. In addition to directly inhibiting the differentiation of Th17 cells, 3-oxoLCA and isoLCA were identified as TGR5 agonists that promoted the M2 polarisation of macrophages. A specific synthetic inhibitor of bile salt hydrolase attenuated the antiarthritic effects of LPD by reducing the production of these four bile acids. The natural product ginsenoside Rg2 exhibited its anti-RA effects by promoting the growth of &lt;em&gt;P. distasonis&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;P. distasonis&lt;/em&gt; and ginsenoside Rg2 might represent probiotic and prebiotic agents in the treatment of RA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Metabolic enzyme UAP1 mediates IRF3 pyrophosphorylation to facilitate innate immune response</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36603579/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36603579/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;UAP1 is a positive regulator of type I interferon signaling&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;UAP1 catalyzes IRF3 pyrophosphorylation at serine 386&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;UAP1 pyrophosphorylates IRF3 at S386 to promote antiviral responses&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Summary&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Post-translational modifications (PTMs) of proteins are crucial to guarantee the proper biological functions in immune responses. Although protein phosphorylation has been extensively studied, our current knowledge of protein pyrophosphorylation, which occurs based on phosphorylation, is very limited. Protein pyrophosphorylation is originally considered to be a non-enzymatic process, and its function in immune signaling is unknown. Here, we identify a metabolic enzyme, UDP-N-acetylglucosamine pyrophosphorylase 1 (UAP1), as a pyrophosphorylase for protein serine pyrophosphorylation, by catalyzing the pyrophosphorylation of interferon regulatory factor 3 (IRF3) at serine (Ser) 386 to promote robust type I interferon (IFN) responses. Uap1 deficiency significantly impairs the activation of both DNA- and RNA-viruse-induced type I IFN pathways, and the Uap1-deficient mice are highly susceptible to lethal viral infection. Our findings demonstrate the function of protein pyrophosphorylation in the regulation of antiviral responses and provide insights into the crosstalk between metabolism and innate immunity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Diurnal transcriptome landscape of a multi-tissue response to time-restricted feeding in mammals</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36599299/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36599299/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;80% of genes are differentially expressed or rhythmic under TRF in at least one tissue&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;TRF decreases genes involved in inflammatory signaling and glycerolipid metabolism&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;TRF increases genes involved in RNA processing, protein folding, and autophagy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;TRF causes multi-tissue rewiring of BCAA, glucose, and lipid metabolism&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Summary&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Time-restricted feeding (TRF) is an emerging behavioral nutrition intervention that involves a daily cycle of feeding and fasting. In both animals and humans, TRF has pleiotropic health benefits that arise from multiple organ systems, yet the molecular basis of TRF-mediated benefits is not well understood. Here, we subjected mice to isocaloric &lt;em&gt;ad libitum&lt;/em&gt; feeding (ALF) or TRF of a western diet and examined gene expression changes in samples taken from 22 organs and brain regions collected every 2 h over a 24-h period. We discovered that TRF profoundly impacts gene expression. Nearly 80% of all genes show differential expression or rhythmicity under TRF in at least one tissue. Functional annotation of these changes revealed tissue- and pathway-specific impacts of TRF. These findings and resources provide a critical foundation for future mechanistic studies and will help to guide human time-restricted eating (TRE) interventions to treat various disease conditions with or without pharmacotherapies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lactylome analysis suggests lactylation-dependent mechanisms of metabolic adaptation in hepatocellular carcinoma</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36593272/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36593272/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enhanced glycolysis and accumulation of lactate is a common feature in various types of cancer. Intracellular lactate drives a recently described type of posttranslational modification, lysine lactylation (Kla), on core histones. However, the impact of lactylation on biological processes of tumour cells remains largely unknown. Here we show a global lactylome profiling on a prospectively collected hepatitis B virus-related hepatocellular carcinoma (HCC) cohort. Integrative lactylome and proteome analysis of the tumours and adjacent livers identifies 9,275 Kla sites, with 9,256 sites on non-histone proteins, indicating that Kla is a prevalent modification beyond histone proteins and transcriptional regulation. Notably, Kla preferentially affects enzymes involved in metabolic pathways, including the tricarboxylic acid cycle, and carbohydrate, amino acid, fatty acid and nucleotide metabolism. We further verify that lactylation at K28 inhibits the function of adenylate kinase 2, facilitating the proliferation and metastasis of HCC cells. Our study therefore reveals that Kla plays an important role in regulating cellular metabolism and may contribute to HCC progression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The lipid flippase SLC47A1 blocks metabolic vulnerability to ferroptosis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36575162/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36575162/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ferroptosis is a type of regulated necrosis caused by unrestricted lipid peroxidation and subsequent plasma membrane rupture. However, the lipid remodeling mechanism that determines sensitivity to ferroptosis remains poorly understood. Here, we report a previously unrecognized role for the lipid flippase solute carrier family 47 member 1 (SLC47A1) as a regulator of lipid remodeling and survival during ferroptosis. Among 49 phospholipid scramblases, flippases, and floppases we analyzed, only SLC47A1 had mRNA that was selectively upregulated in multiple cancer cells exposed to ferroptotic inducers. Large-scale lipidomics and functional analyses revealed that the silencing of SLC47A1 increased RSL3- or erastin-induced ferroptosis by favoring ACSL4-SOAT1-mediated production of polyunsaturated fatty acid cholesterol esters. We identified peroxisome proliferator activated receptor alpha (PPARA) as a transcription factor that transactivates SLC47A1. The depletion of PPARA and SLC47A1 similarly sensitized cells to ferroptosis induction, whereas transfection-enforced re-expression of SLC47A1 restored resistance to ferroptosis in PPARA-deficient cells. Pharmacological or genetic blockade of the PPARA-SLC47A1 pathway increased the anticancer activity of a ferroptosis inducer in mice. These findings establish a direct molecular link between ferroptosis and lipid transporters, which may provide metabolic targets for overcoming drug resistance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Study on the protective effect of berberine treatment on sepsis based on gut microbiota and metabolomic analysis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36601077/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36601077/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Introduction:&lt;/em&gt; Sepsis, an infection with multiorgan dysfunction, is a serious burden on human health. Berberine (BBR), a bioactive component, has a protective effect on sepsis and the effect may be related to gut microbiota. However, studies on the role of BBR with gut microbiota in sepsis are lacking. Therefore, this study investigated the ameliorative effects and the underlying mechanisms of BBR on cecal ligature and puncture (CLP) rats.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; This study has observed the effect of BBR on pathological injury, Inflammation, intestinal barrier function, gut microbiota, and metabolite change in CLP rats by Hematoxylin-eosin staining, enzyme-linked immunosorbent assays, flow cytometry, 16S rDNA, and metabolomics analyses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; The inhibition effects of BBR treatment on the histological damage of the lung, kidney, and ileum, the interleukin (IL)-1b, IL-6, IL-17A, and monocyte chemokine-1 levels in serum in CLP rats were proved. Also, the BBR inhibited the diamine-oxidase and fluorescein isothiocyanate-dextran 40 levels, suggesting it can improve intestinal barrier function disorders. The cluster of differentiation (CD) 4&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt;, CD8&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt;, and CD25&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; Forkhead box protein P3 (Foxp3) &lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T lymphocytes in splenocytes were up-regulated by BBR, while the IL-17A&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt;CD4&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; cell level was decreased. The abundance of gut microbiota in CLP rats was significantly different from that of the sham and BBR treatment rats. The significantly changed metabolites in the serum mainly included carbohydrates, phenols, benzoic acids, alcohols, vitamins et al. Additionally, this study predicted that the biological mechanism of BBR to ameliorate sepsis involves glycolysis-, nucleotide-, and amino acid-related metabolic pathways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Discussion: This study proved the strong correlation between the improvement effect of BBR on sepsis and gut microbiota and analyzed by metabolomics that gut microbiota may improve CLP rats through metabolites, providing a scientific basis for BBR to improve sepsis and a new direction for the study of the biological mechanism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integrative analysis and identification of key elements and pathways regulated by Traditional Chinese Medicine (Yiqi Sanjie formula) in colorectal cancer</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36582529/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36582529/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Introduction:&lt;/em&gt; The clinical efficacy of Yiqi Sanjie (YQSJ) formula in the treatment of stage III colorectal cancer (CRC) has been demonstrated. However, the underlying antitumor mechanisms remain poorly understood.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Materials and methods:&lt;/em&gt; The aim of the present study was to comprehensively characterize the molecular and microbiota changes in colon tissues and fecal samples from CRC mice and in CRC cell lines treated with YQSJ or its main active component, peiminine. Integrative tandem mass tag-based proteomics and ultra-performance liquid chromatography coupled with time-of-flight tandem mass spectrometry metabolomics were used to analyze azoxymethane/dextran sulfate sodium-induced CRC mouse colon tissues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; The results showed that 0.8% (57/7568) of all detected tissue proteins and 3.2% (37/1141) of all detected tissue metabolites were significantly changed by YQSJ treatment, with enrichment in ten and six pathways associated with colon proteins and metabolites, respectively. The enriched pathways were related to inflammation, sphingolipid metabolism, and cholesterol metabolism. Metabolomics analysis of fecal samples from YQSJ-treated mice identified 121 altered fecal metabolites and seven enriched pathways including protein digestion and absorption pathway. 16S rRNA sequencing analysis of fecal samples indicated that YQSJ restored the CRC mouse microbiota structure by increasing the levels of beneficial bacteria such as Ruminococcus_1 and Prevotellaceae_UCG_001. In HCT-116 cells treated with peiminine, data-independent acquisition-based proteomics analysis showed that 1073 of the 7152 identified proteins were significantly altered and involved in 33 pathways including DNA damage repair, ferroptosis, and TGF-β signaling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/em&gt; The present study identified key regulatory elements (proteins/metabolites/bacteria) and pathways involved in the antitumor mechanisms of YQSJ, suggesting new potential therapeutic targets in CRC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intracellular galectin-3 is a lipopolysaccharide sensor that promotes glycolysis through mTORC1 activation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36481721/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36481721/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How the carbohydrate binding protein galectin-3 might act as a diabetogenic and tumorogenic factor remains to be investigated. Here we report that intracellular galectin-3 interacts with Rag GTPases and Ragulator on lysosomes. We show that galectin-3 senses lipopolysaccharide (LPS) to facilitate the interaction of Rag GTPases and Ragulator, leading to the activation of mTORC1. We find that the lipopolysaccharide/galectin-3-Rag GTPases/Ragulator-mTORC1 axis regulates a cohort of genes including GLUT1, and HK2, and PKM2 that are critically involved in glucose uptake and glycolysis. Indeed, galectin-3 deficiency severely compromises LPS-promoted glycolysis. Importantly, the expression of HK2 is significantly reduced in diabetes patients. In multiple types of cancer including hepatocellular carcinoma (HCC), galectin-3 is highly expressed, and its level of expression is positively correlated with that of HK2 and PKM2 and negatively correlated with the prognosis of HCC patients. Our study unravels that galectin-3 is a sensor of LPS, an important modulator of the mTORC1 signaling, and a critical regulator of glucose metabolism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lipid-laden lung mesenchymal cells foster breast cancer metastasis via metabolic reprogramming of tumor cells and natural killer cells</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36476935/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36476935/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lung mesenchymal cells (MCs) store neutral lipids during breast cancer progression&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IL-1β elicits neutral lipid accumulation in lung MCs to foster metastasis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lipid-laden MCs metabolically reprogram both tumor cells and NK cells&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Targeting lipid-laden MCs improves the efficacy of NK cell-based immunotherapy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Summary&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the distant organ environment is known to support metastasis of primary tumors, its metabolic roles in this process remain underdetermined. Here, in breast cancer models, we found lung-resident mesenchymal cells (MCs) accumulating neutral lipids at the pre-metastatic stage. This was partially mediated by interleukin-1β (IL-1β)-induced hypoxia-inducible lipid droplet-associated (HILPDA) that subsequently represses adipose triglyceride lipase (ATGL) activity in lung MCs. MC-specific ablation of the ATGL or HILPDA genes in mice reinforced and reduced lung metastasis of breast cancer respectively, suggesting a metastasis-promoting effect of lipid-laden MCs. Mechanistically, lipid-laden MCs transported their lipids to tumor cells and natural killer (NK) cells via exosome-like vesicles, leading to heightened tumor cell survival and proliferation and NK cell dysfunction. Blockage of IL-1β, which was effective singly, improved the efficacy of adoptive NK cell immunotherapy in mitigating lung metastasis. Collectively, lung MCs metabolically regulate tumor cells and anti-tumor immunity to facilitate breast cancer lung metastasis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mannose metabolism normalizes gut homeostasis by blocking the TNF-α-mediated proinflammatory circuit</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36471112/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36471112/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mannose is a naturally occurring sugar widely consumed in the daily diet; however, mechanistic insights into how mannose metabolism affects intestinal inflammation remain lacking. Herein, we reported that mannose supplementation ameliorated colitis development and promoted colitis recovery. Macrophage-secreted inflammatory cytokines, particularly TNF-α, induced pathological endoplasmic reticulum stress (ERS) in intestinal epithelial cells (IECs), which was prevented by mannose via normalization of protein N-glycosylation. By preserving epithelial integrity, mannose reduced the inflammatory activation of colonic macrophages. On the other hand, mannose directly suppressed macrophage TNF-α production translationally by reducing the glyceraldehyde 3-phosphate level, thus promoting GAPDH binding to TNF-α mRNA. Additionally, we found dysregulated mannose metabolism in the colonic mucosa of patients with inflammatory bowel disease. Finally, we revealed that activating PMM2 activity with epalrestat, a clinically approved drug for the treatment of diabetic neuropathy, elicited further sensitization to the therapeutic effect of mannose. Therefore, mannose metabolism prevents TNF-α-mediated pathogenic crosstalk between IECs and intestinal macrophages, thereby normalizing aberrant immunometabolism in the gut.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Epsin Nanotherapy Regulates Cholesterol Transport to Fortify Atheroma Regression</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36444722/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36444722/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Excess cholesterol accumulation in lesional macrophages elicits complex responses in atherosclerosis. Epsins, a family of endocytic adaptors, fuel the progression of atherosclerosis; however, the underlying mechanism and therapeutic potential of targeting Epsins remains unknown. In this study, we determined the role of Epsins in macrophage-mediated metabolic regulation. We then developed an innovative method to therapeutically target macrophage Epsins with specially designed S2P-conjugated lipid nanoparticles, which encapsulate small-interfering RNAs to suppress Epsins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; We used single-cell RNA sequencing with our newly developed algorithm MEBOCOST to study cell-cell communications mediated by metabolites from sender cells and sensor proteins on receiver cells. Biomedical, cellular, and molecular approaches were utilized to investigate the role of macrophage Epsins in regulating lipid metabolism and transport. We performed this study using myeloid-specific Epsin double knockout (LysM-DKO) mice and mice with a genetic reduction of ABCG1 (ATP-binding cassette subfamily G member 1; LysM-DKO-ABCG1&lt;sup&gt;fl/+&lt;/sup&gt;). The nanoparticles targeting lesional macrophages were developed to encapsulate interfering RNAs to treat atherosclerosis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; We revealed that Epsins regulate lipid metabolism and transport in atherosclerotic macrophages. Inhibiting Epsins by nanotherapy halts inflammation and accelerates atheroma resolution. Harnessing lesional macrophage-specific nanoparticle delivery of Epsin small-interfering RNAs, we showed that silencing of macrophage Epsins diminished atherosclerotic plaque size and promoted plaque regression. Mechanistically, we demonstrated that Epsins bound to CD36 to facilitate lipid uptake by enhancing CD36 endocytosis and recycling. Conversely, Epsins promoted ABCG1 degradation via lysosomes and hampered ABCG1-mediated cholesterol efflux and reverse cholesterol transport. In a LysM-DKO-ABCG1&lt;sup&gt;fl/+&lt;/sup&gt; mouse model, enhanced cholesterol efflux and reverse transport due to Epsin deficiency was suppressed by the reduction of ABCG1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; Our findings suggest that targeting Epsins in lesional macrophages may offer therapeutic benefits for advanced atherosclerosis by reducing CD36-mediated lipid uptake and increasing ABCG1-mediated cholesterol efflux.
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GPSM1 impairs metabolic homeostasis by controlling a pro-inflammatory pathway in macrophages</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36434066/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36434066/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;G-protein-signaling modulator 1 (GPSM1) exhibits strong genetic association with Type 2 diabetes (T2D) and Body Mass Index in population studies. However, how GPSM1 carries out such control and in which types of cells are poorly understood. Here, we demonstrate that myeloid GPSM1 promotes metabolic inflammation to accelerate T2D and obesity development. Mice with myeloid-specific GPSM1 ablation are protected against high fat diet-induced insulin resistance, glucose dysregulation, and liver steatosis via repression of adipose tissue pro-inflammatory states. Mechanistically, GPSM1 deficiency mainly promotes TNFAIP3 transcription via the Gαi3/cAMP/PKA/CREB axis, thus inhibiting TLR4-induced NF-κB signaling in macrophages. In addition, we identify a small-molecule compound, AN-465/42243987, which suppresses the pro-inflammatory phenotype by inhibiting GPSM1 function, which could make it a candidate for metabolic therapy. Furthermore, GPSM1 expression is upregulated in visceral fat of individuals with obesity and is correlated with clinical metabolic traits. Overall, our findings identify macrophage GPSM1 as a link between metabolic inflammation and systemic homeostasis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cellular functions of cGAS-STING signaling</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/36437149/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/36437149/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cyclic GMP-AMP (cGAMP) synthase (cGAS) senses misplaced genomic, mitochondrial, and microbial double-stranded DNA (dsDNA) to synthesize 2&#39;3&amp;rsquo;-cGAMP that mobilizes stimulator of interferon genes (STING) to unleash innate immune responses, constituting a ubiquitous and effective surveillance system against tissue damage and pathogen invasion. However, imbalanced cGAS-STING signaling tethers considerably in infectious, autoimmune, malignant, fibrotic, and neurodegenerative diseases. Recently, multifaceted roles for cGAS-STING signaling at the cellular scale have emerged; these include autophagy, translation, metabolism homeostasis, cellular condensation, DNA damage repair, senescence, and cell death. These dominances adaptively shape cellular physiologies and impact disease pathogenesis. However, understanding how DNA sensing-initiated responses trigger these diverse cellular processes remains an outstanding challenge. In this review we discuss recent developments of cellular physiological states controlled by cGAS-STING machinery, as well as their disease relevance and underlying mechanisms, canonical or noncanonical. Ultimately, exploiting these cellular functions and mechanisms may represent promising targets for disease therapeutics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chronic exposure to carbon black ultrafine particles reprograms macrophage metabolism and accelerates lung cancer</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36383649/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36383649/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chronic exposure to airborne carbon black ultrafine (nCB) particles generated from incomplete combustion of organic matter drives IL-17A–dependent emphysema. However, whether and how they alter the immune responses to lung cancer remains unknown. Here, we show that exposure to nCB particles increased PD-L1&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; PD-L2&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; CD206&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; antigen-presenting cells (APCs), exhausted T cells, and Treg cells. Lung macrophages that harbored nCB particles showed selective mitochondrial structure damage and decreased oxidative respiration. Lung macrophages sustained the HIF1α axis that increased glycolysis and lactate production, culminating in an immunosuppressive microenvironment in multiple mouse models of non–small cell lung cancers. Adoptive transfer of lung APCs from nCB-exposed wild type to susceptible mice increased tumor incidence and caused early metastasis. Our findings show that nCB exposure metabolically rewires lung macrophages to promote immunosuppression and accelerates the development of lung cancer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AMPK directly phosphorylates TBK1 to integrate glucose sensing into innate immunity</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36384137/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36384137/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Viral infection induces acute blood glucose decline in rodents that activates AMPK&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;AMPK directly phosphorylates TBK1 at S511 to prime antiviral sensing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;AMPK-TBK1 couples glucose deficiency sensing and innate immune surveillance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Targeting the AMPK-TBK1 axis compromises innate antiviral immunity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nutrient sensing and damage sensing are two fundamental processes in living organisms. While hyperglycemia is frequently linked to diabetes-related vulnerability to microbial infection, how body glucose levels affect innate immune responses to microbial invasion is not fully understood. Here, we surprisingly found that viral infection led to a rapid and dramatic decrease in blood glucose levels in rodents, leading to robust AMPK activation. AMPK, once activated, directly phosphorylates TBK1 at S511, which triggers IRF3 recruitment and the assembly of MAVS or STING signalosomes. Consistently, ablation or inhibition of AMPK, knockin of TBK1-S511A, or increased glucose levels compromised nucleic acid sensing, while boosting AMPK-TBK1 cascade by AICAR or TBK1-S511E knockin improves antiviral immunity substantially in various animal models. Thus, we identify TBK1 as an AMPK substrate, reveal the molecular mechanism coupling a dual sensing of glucose and nuclei acids, and report its physiological necessity in antiviral defense.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The NLRP3 inflammasome: regulation by metabolic signalss</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/36371361/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/36371361/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Glycolytic enzymes differentially regulate NLRP3 inflammasome activation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Itaconate post-translationally modifies kelch-like ECH-associated protein 1 (KEAP1), NLRP3, and gasdermin D (GSDMD) proteins to dampen both the NLRP3 inflammasome and pyroptosis.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Succination of GSDMD and GSDME blocks pyroptosis and apoptosis, respectively.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fatty acid synthesis and fatty acid oxidation regulate the priming and activation of the NLRP3 inflammasome.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Significance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Several metabolic pathways are instrumental in modulating myeloid cell responses to inflammation and new findings are revealing further molecular details regarding inflammasome regulation. By targeting various proteins, itaconate – a metabolite derived from the TCA cycle – is gaining significant attention because it can dampen the NLRP3 inflammasome and lower pyroptotic cell death.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Macrophages undergo profound metabolic reprogramming upon sensing infectious and sterile stimuli. This metabolic shift supports and regulates essential innate immune functions, including activation of the NLRP3 inflammasome. Within distinct metabolic networks, key enzymes play pivotal roles to control flux restraining detrimental inflammasome signaling. However, depending on the metabolic cues, specific enzymes and metabolites result in inflammasome activation outcomes which contrast other metabolic steps in the pathway. We posit that understanding which metabolic steps commit to discrete inflammasome fates will broaden our understanding of metabolic checkpoints to maintain homeostasis and offer better therapeutic options in human disease.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SLC7A8 is a key amino acids supplier for the metabolic programs that sustain homeostasis and activation of type 2 innate lymphoid cells</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36343258/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36343258/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Significance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Metabolic adaptations enable immune responses. While much is known about how metabolism underlies T cell function, a metabolic framework for innate lymphoid cells (ILCs) is just developing. Group 2 ILCs (ILC2s), the innate counterparts of Th2, require arginine and branched-chain amino acids for proliferation and activation. How these amino acids reach the intracellular ILC2 compartment is unknown. Here, we show that SLC7A8 is the key amino acid transporter in ILC2s. &lt;em&gt;Slc7a8&lt;/em&gt; deletion in lymphocytes reduced ILC2s and attenuated responses to helminth infection and house dust mite allergens. &lt;em&gt;Slc7a8&lt;/em&gt; deficiency compromised mitochondrial OXPHOS and mammalian target of rapamycin and c-Myc pathways in ILC2s. Thus, SLC7A8 is a promising target for therapies aiming at attenuating immune inflammation in allergies and asthma.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Group 2 innate lymphoid cells (ILC2) are innate counterparts of T helper 2 (Th2) cells that maintain tissue homeostasis and respond to injuries through rapid interleukin (IL)-5 and IL-13 secretion. ILC2s depend on availability of arginine and branched-chain amino acids for sustaining cellular fitness, proliferation, and cytokine secretion in both steady state and upon activation. However, the contribution of amino acid transporters to ILC2 functions is not known. Here, we found that ILC2s selectively express &lt;em&gt;Slc7a8&lt;/em&gt;, encoding a transporter for arginine and large amino acids. &lt;em&gt;Slc7a8&lt;/em&gt; was expressed in ILC2s in a tissue-specific manner in steady state and was further increased upon activation. Genetic ablation of &lt;em&gt;Slc7a8&lt;/em&gt; in lymphocytes reduced the frequency of ILC2s, suppressed IL-5 and IL-13 production upon stimulation, and impaired type 2 immune responses to helminth infection. Consistent with this, &lt;em&gt;Slc7a8&lt;/em&gt;-deficient ILC2s also failed to induce cytokine production and recruit eosinophils in a model of allergic lung inflammation. Mechanistically, reduced amino acid availability due to &lt;em&gt;Slc7a8&lt;/em&gt; deficiency led to compromised mitochondrial oxidative phosphorylation, as well as impaired activation of mammalian target of rapamycin and c-Myc signaling pathways. These findings identify &lt;em&gt;Slc7a8&lt;/em&gt; as a key supplier of amino acids for the metabolic programs underpinning fitness and activation of ILC2s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HIF1A-dependent induction of alveolar epithelial PFKFB3 dampens acute lung injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36326834/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36326834/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acute lung injury (ALI) is a severe form of lung inflammation causing acute respiratory distress syndrome in patients. ALI pathogenesis is closely linked to uncontrolled alveolar inflammation. We hypothesize that specific enzymes of the glycolytic pathway could function as key regulators of alveolar inflammation. Therefore, we screened isolated alveolar epithelia from mice exposed to ALI induced by injurious ventilation to assess their metabolic responses. These studies pointed us toward a selective role for isoform 3 of the 6-phosphofructo-2-kinase/fructose-2,6-bisphosphatase (PFKFB3). Pharmacologic inhibition or genetic deletion of Pfkfb3 in alveolar epithelia (Pfkfb3loxP/loxP SPC-ER-Cre+ mice) was associated with profound increases in ALI during injurious mechanical ventilation or acid instillation. Studies in genetic models linked Pfkfb3 expression and function to Hif1a. Not only did intratracheal pyruvate instillation reconstitute Pfkfb3loxP/loxP or Hif1aloxP/loxP SPC-ER-Cre+ mice, but pyruvate was also effective in ALI treatment of wild-type mice. Finally, proof-of-principle studies in human lung biopsies demonstrated increased PFKFB3 staining in injured lungs and colocalized PFKFB3 to alveolar epithelia. These studies reveal a specific role for PFKFB3 in counterbalancing alveolar inflammation and lay the groundwork for novel metabolic therapeutic approaches during ALI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ferroptosis inhibitor liproxstatin-1 alleviates metabolic dysfunction-associated fatty liver disease in mice: potential involvement of PANoptosis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36323829/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36323829/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ferroptosis is a new form of regulated cell death characterized by excessive iron accumulation and uncontrollable lipid peroxidation. The role of ferroptosis in metabolic dysfunction-associated fatty liver disease (MAFLD) is not fully elucidated. In this study we compared the therapeutic effects of ferroptosis inhibitor liproxstatin-1 (LPT1) and iron chelator deferiprone (DFP) in MAFLD mouse models. This model was established in mice by feeding a high-fat diet with 30% fructose in water (HFHF) for 16 weeks. The mice then received LPT1 (10 mg·kg&lt;sup&gt;-1&lt;/sup&gt;·d&lt;sup&gt;-1&lt;/sup&gt;, ip) or DFP (100 mg·kg&lt;sup&gt;-1&lt;/sup&gt;·d&lt;sup&gt;-1&lt;/sup&gt;, ig) for another 2 weeks. We showed that both LPT1 and DFP treatment blocked the ferroptosis markers ACSL4 and ALOX15 in MAFLD mice. Furthermore, LPT1 treatment significantly reduced the liver levels of triglycerides and cholesterol, lipid peroxidation markers 4-hydroxynonenal (4-HNE) and malondialdehyde (MDA), and ameliorated the expression of lipid synthesis/oxidation genes (Pparα, Scd1, Fasn, Hmgcr and Cpt1a), insulin resistance, mitochondrial ROS content and liver fibrosis. Importantly, LPT1 treatment potently inhibited hepatic apoptosis (Bax/Bcl-xL ratio and TUNEL+ cell number), pyroptosis (cleavages of Caspase-1 and GSDMD) and necroptosis (phosphorylation of MLKL). Moreover, LPT1 treatment markedly inhibited cleavages of PANoptosis-related caspase-8 and caspase-6 in MAFLD mouse liver. In an in vitro MAFLD model, treatment with LPT1 (100 nM) prevented cultured hepatocyte against cell death induced by pro-PANoptosis molecules (TNF-α, LPS and nigericin) upon lipid stress. On the contrary, DFP treatment only mildly attenuated hepatic inflammation but failed to alleviate lipid deposition, insulin resistance, apoptosis, pyroptosis and necroptosis in MAFLD mice. We conclude that ferroptosis inhibitor LPT1 protects against steatosis and steatohepatitis in MAFLD mice, which may involve regulation of PANoptosis, a coordinated cell death pathway that involves apoptosis, pyroptosis and necroptosis. These results suggest a potential link between ferroptosis and PANoptosis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Long-Term Dietary Lycium ruthenicum Murr. Anthocyanins Intake Alleviated Oxidative Stress-Mediated Aging-Related Liver Injury and Abnormal Amino Acid Metabolism</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36359989/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36359989/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In recent years, the relationship between Lycium ruthenicum Murr. anthocyanins (LRA) and health has attracted increasing attention. The purpose of this study is to investigate the anti-aging effect and mechanism of LRA through a D-galactose (DG)-induced aging rat model. Our results showed that the long-term intake of LRA, for 8 weeks, improved motor function, reduced serum aging markers, promoted the endogenous antioxidant system, and suppressed the serum inflammatory cytokines in aging rats. Besides, the LRA treatment alleviated DG-induced liver injuries by relieving the inflammation and inhibiting Fas/FasL-mediated cell death. More importantly, the abnormal serum metabolome profiles of the aging rats were restored by the LRA, relating to 38 metabolites and 44 pathways. Specifically, the LRA significantly affected the amino acid and protein-related metabolic pathways by regulating the levels of L-threonine, L-aspartic acid, glycine, L-histidine, D-homocysteine, L-homocitrulline, L-homoserine, guanidineacetic acid, and kynurenine. These results have important implications for the development of LRA as an anti-aging and liver-protective ingredient.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Circular RNAs: Emerging regulators of glucose metabolism in cancer</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/36283584/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/36283584/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aberrant glucose metabolism is one of the most striking characteristics of metabolic reprogramming in cancer. Thus, clarifying the regulatory mechanism of glucose metabolism is crucial to understanding tumor progression and developing novel therapeutic strategies for cancer patients. Recent developments in circular RNAs have explained the regulatory mechanism of glucose metabolism from a new dimension. In this review, we briefly summarize the recent advances in circRNA research on cancer glucose metabolism and emphasize the different regulatory mechanisms, including acting as miRNA sponges, interacting with proteins and being translated into proteins. Additionally, we discuss the future research directions of circular RNAs in the field of glucose metabolism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rhein ameliorates septic lung injury and intervenes in macrophage metabolic reprogramming in the inflammatory state by Sirtuin 1</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36279970/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36279970/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rhein prevented the progression of acute lung injury.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The metabolism in sepsis pathological state was changed after Rhein treatment.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rhein inhibited the over activation of macrophages by affecting metabolic reprogramming.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rhein preconditioning up-regulated and activated SIRT1 signal pathway.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Aims:&lt;/em&gt; Sepsis is an organ dysfunction syndrome caused by the maladjustment of response to infection. Acute lung injury (ALI) appears the earliest, with urgent onset and limited treatments. Previous pharmacological studies have found that rhein (RH), an active ingredient rich in rhubarb, has multiple pharmacological activities such as anti-inflammatory, anti-infection and metabolic regulation. This research aimed to explore whether RH alleviates septic acute lung injury and probe possible mechanisms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Main methods:&lt;/em&gt; In this study, the septic ALI mouse model was established by cecal ligation and perforation (CLP). LPS-induced RAW264.7 model was selected to further explore the protective mechanism of RH. H&amp;amp;E staining, Western blot, qRT-PCR, and 1H NMR analysis were used to verify the protective effect of RH on ALI &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;in vitro&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Key findings:&lt;/em&gt; RH could relieve pathological lung injury and pulmonary edema, reduce the serum LPS and inhibit inflammatory response in CLP mice. Further studies displayed that RH affected the metabolism &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt;, with significant changes in serum and lung metabolomics. &lt;em&gt;In vitro&lt;/em&gt; results demonstrated that RH inhibited the expression of inflammatory mediators and factors in macrophages by affecting metabolic reprogramming and upregulating the expression of Sirtuin 1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Significance:&lt;/em&gt; RH improved the overall metabolic condition of sepsis mice by up-regulating and activating SIRT1, and inhibited the over activation of macrophages by regulating metabolism. These findings reveal the therapeutic mechanism of RH on sepsis ALI from the perspective of metabolism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The metabolomics of human aging: Advances, challenges, and opportunities</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/36260671/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/36260671/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the global population becomes older, understanding the impact of aging on health and disease becomes paramount. Recent advancements in multiomic technology have allowed for the high-throughput molecular characterization of aging at the population level. Metabolomics studies that analyze the small molecules in the body can provide biological information across a diversity of aging processes. Here, we review the growing body of population-scale metabolomics research on aging in humans, identifying the major trends in the field, implicated biological pathways, and how these pathways relate to health and aging. We conclude by assessing the main challenges in the research to date, opportunities for advancing the field, and the outlook for precision health applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lactate induces metabolic and epigenetic reprogramming of pro-inflammatory Th17 cells</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36215678/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36215678/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Increased lactate levels in the tissue microenvironment are a well-known feature of chronic inflammation. However, the role of lactate in regulating T cell function remains controversial. Here, we demonstrate that extracellular lactate predominantly induces deregulation of the Th17-specific gene expression program by modulating the metabolic and epigenetic status of Th17 cells. Following lactate treatment, Th17 cells significantly reduced their IL-17A production and upregulated Foxp3 expression through ROS-driven IL-2 secretion. Moreover, we observed increased levels of genome-wide histone H3K18 lactylation, a recently described marker for active chromatin in macrophages, in lactate-treated Th17 cells. In addition, we show that high lactate concentrations suppress Th17 pathogenicity during intestinal inflammation in mice. These results indicate that lactate is capable of reprogramming pro-inflammatory T cell phenotypes into regulatory T cells.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Single-cell spatial transcriptomics reveals a dynamic control of metabolic zonation and liver regeneration by endothelial cell Wnt2 and Wnt9b</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36220068/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36220068/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Conserved expression of Wnt2 and Wnt9b in liver endothelial cells is identified&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wnt2 and Wnt9b deletion from endothelial cells affects gene expression in zone 3&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Endothelial Wnt2 and Wnt9b deletion affects liver regeneration after hepatectomy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Late treatment with Wnt agonist rescues regeneration after acetaminophen overdose&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Summary&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The conclusive identity of Wnts regulating liver zonation (LZ) and regeneration (LR) remains unclear despite an undisputed role of β-catenin. Using single-cell analysis, we identified a conserved Wnt2 and Wnt9b expression in endothelial cells (ECs) in zone 3. EC-elimination of Wnt2 and Wnt9b led to both loss of β-catenin targets in zone 3, and re-appearance of zone 1 genes in zone 3, unraveling dynamicity in the LZ process. Impaired LR observed in the knockouts phenocopied models of defective hepatic Wnt signaling. Administration of a tetravalent antibody to activate Wnt signaling rescued LZ and LR in the knockouts and induced zone 3 gene expression and LR in controls. Administration of the agonist also promoted LR in acetaminophen overdose acute liver failure (ALF) fulfilling an unmet clinical need. Overall, we report an unequivocal role of EC-Wnt2 and Wnt9b in LZ and LR and show the role of Wnt activators as regenerative therapy for ALF.
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Serine metabolism orchestrates macrophage polarization by regulating the IGF1-p38 axis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36180780/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36180780/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Serine metabolism is reportedly involved in immune cell functions, but whether and how serine metabolism regulates macrophage polarization remain largely unknown. Here, we show that suppressing serine metabolism, either by inhibiting the activity of the key enzyme phosphoglycerate dehydrogenase in the serine biosynthesis pathway or by exogenous serine and glycine restriction, robustly enhances the polarization of interferon-γ-activated macrophages (M(IFN-γ)) but suppresses that of interleukin-4-activated macrophages (M(IL-4)) both in vitro and in vivo. Mechanistically, serine metabolism deficiency increases the expression of IGF1 by reducing the promoter abundance of S-adenosyl methionine-dependent histone H3 lysine 27 trimethylation. IGF1 then activates the p38-dependent JAK-STAT1 axis to promote M(IFN-γ) polarization and suppress STAT6-mediated M(IL-4) activation. This study reveals a new mechanism by which serine metabolism orchestrates macrophage polarization and suggests the manipulation of serine metabolism as a therapeutic strategy for macrophage-mediated immune diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Liang-Ge decoction ameliorates acute lung injury in septic model rats through reducing inflammatory response, oxidative stress, apoptosis, and modulating host metabolism</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36188538/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36188538/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Liang-Ge decoction (LG) has been used in the treatment of early stage of spesis and can ameliorate sepsis-associated lung injury. However, the mechanism of LG on sepsis-associated lung injury remains unknown. In this study, we established a rat model of sepsis-associated lung injury using the cecal ligation and puncture (CLP) method, and investigated the therapeutic effects of LG on lung injury in rats with sepsis. In addition, the anti-inflammatory, anti-oxidative and anti-apoptotic effects of LG on sepsis-associated lung injury model rats were evaluated. Besides, untargeted metabolomics was used to investigate the regulation of metabolites in rats with sepsis-associated lung injury after LG treatment. Our results showed that LG could decrease the wet/dry (W/D) ratio in lung and the total cell count and total protein concentration in bronchoalveolar lavage fluid (BALF) in septic model rats. Hematoxylin and eosin (HE) staining showed that LG reduced the infiltration of pro-inflammatory cells in lung. In addition, LG treatmment down-regulated the gene and protein expression of pro-inflammatory cytokins in lung tissue and BALF. The activities of superoxide dismutase (SOD) and glutathione peroxidase (GSH-Px) were increased and the level of methane dicarboxylic aldehyde (MDA) was decreased in lung tissue homogenate in septic model rats after LG treament. Moreover, the numbers of apoptotic cells in lung were reduced and the activity of lactic dehydrogenase (LDH) in BALF was decreased in septic model rats after LG treament. Untargeted metabolomics analysis showed that LG treatment affected the levels of 23 metabolites in lung in septic model rats such as citric acid, methionine, threonine, alpha-ketoglutaric acid, and inositol, these metabolites were associated with the glycine, serine and threonine metabolism, cysteine and methionine metabolism, inositol phosphate metabolism and citrate cycle (TCA cycle) pathways. In conclusion, our study demonstrated the therapeutic effetcts of LG on sepsis-associated lung injury model rats. Moreover, LG could inhibit the inflammatory response, oxidative stress, apoptosis and regulate metabolites related to glycine, serine and threonine metabolism, cysteine and methionine metabolism, inositol phosphate metabolism and TCA cycle in lung in sepsis-associated lung injury model rats.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Total flavonoids of Inula japonica alleviated the inflammatory response and oxidative stress in LPS-induced acute lung injury via inhibiting the sEH activity: Insights from lipid metabolomics</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36150346/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36150346/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Acute lung injury (ALI) is a severe respiratory disease characterized by diffuse lung interstitial and respiratory distress and pulmonary edema with a mortality rate of 35%-40%. Inula japonica Thunb., known as &amp;ldquo;Xuan Fu Hua&amp;rdquo; in Chinese, is a traditional Chinese medicine Inulae Flos to use for relieving cough, eliminating expectorant, and preventing bacterial infections in the clinic, and possesses an anti-pulmonary fibrosis effect. However, the effect and action mechanism of I. japonica on ALI is still unclear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Purpose:&lt;/em&gt; This study aimed to investigate the protective effect and underlying mechanism of total flavonoids of I. japonica (TFIJ) in the treatment of ALI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Study design and methods:&lt;/em&gt; A mouse ALI model was established through administration of LPS by the intratracheal instillation. Protective effects of TFIJ in the inflammation and oxidative stress were studied in LPS-induced ALI mice based on inflammatory and oxidative stress factors, including MDA, MPO, SOD, and TNF-α. Lipid metabolomics, bioinformatics, Western blot, quantitative real-time PCR, and immunohistochemistry were performed to reveal the potential mechanism of TFIJ in the treatment of ALI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; TFIJ significantly alleviated the interstitial infiltration of inflammatory cells and the collapse of the alveoli in LPS-induced ALI mice. Lipid metabolomics demonstrated that TFIJ could significantly affect the CYP2J/sEH-mediated arachidonic acid metabolism, such as 11,12-EET, 14,15-EET, 8,9-DHET, 11,12-DHET, and 14,15-DHET, revealing that sEH was the potential target of TFIJ, which was further supported by the recombinant sEH-mediated the substrate hydrolysis in vitro (IC50 = 1.18 μg/ml). Inhibition of sEH by TFIJ alleviated the inflammatory response and oxidative stress via the MAPK, NF-κB, and Nrf2 signaling pathways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/em&gt; These results demonstrated that TFIJ could suppress the sEH activity to stabilize the level of EETs, allowing the alleviation of the pathological course of lung injury in LPS-treated mice, which suggested that TFIJ could serve as the potential agents in the treatment of ALI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Energy homeostasis mediated by the LcSnRK1α-LcbZIP1/3 signaling pathway modulates litchi fruit senescence</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35634876/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35634876/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cellular energy status is a key factor deciding the switch-on of the senescence of horticultural crops. Despite the established significance of the conserved energy master regulator sucrose non-fermenting 1 (SNF1)-related protein kinase 1 (SnRK1) in plant development, its working mechanism and related signaling pathway in the regulation of fruit senescence remain enigmatic. Here, we demonstrate that energy deficit accelerates fruit senescence, whereas exogenous ATP treatment delays it. The transient suppression of &lt;em&gt;LcSnRK1α&lt;/em&gt; in litchi (&lt;em&gt;Litchi chinensis&lt;/em&gt; Sonn.) fruit inhibited the expression of energy metabolism-related genes, while its ectopic expression in tomato (&lt;em&gt;Solanum lycopersicum&lt;/em&gt;) promoted ripening and a high energy level. Biochemical analyses revealed that LcSnRK1α interacted with and phosphorylated the transcription factors LcbZIP1 and LcbZIP3, which directly bound to the promoters to activate the expression of &lt;em&gt;DARK-INDUCIBLE 10&lt;/em&gt; (&lt;em&gt;LcDIN10&lt;/em&gt;), &lt;em&gt;ASPARAGINE SYNTHASE 1&lt;/em&gt; (&lt;em&gt;LcASN1&lt;/em&gt;), and &lt;em&gt;ANTHOCYANIN SYNTHASE&lt;/em&gt; (&lt;em&gt;LcANS&lt;/em&gt;), thereby fine-tuning the metabolic reprogramming to ensure energy and redox homeostasis. Altogether, these observations reveal a post-translational modification mechanism by which &lt;em&gt;LcSnRK1α&lt;/em&gt;-mediated phosphorylation of LcbZIP1 and LcbZIP3 regulates the expression of metabolic reprogramming-related genes, consequently modulating litchi fruit senescence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mucus sialylation determines intestinal host-commensal homeostasis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35303419/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35303419/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A local sialyltransferase dominantly controls intestinal protein sialylation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sialylation protects intestinal mucus integrity from bacterial degradation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mucus sialylation is critical for commensalism and bacterial metabolite homeostasis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Treatment with sialylated mucins ameliorates gut inflammation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Summary&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Intestinal mucus forms the first line of defense against bacterial invasion while providing nutrition to support microbial symbiosis. How the host controls mucus barrier integrity and commensalism is unclear. We show that terminal sialylation of glycans on intestinal mucus by ST6GALNAC1 (ST6), the dominant sialyltransferase specifically expressed in goblet cells and induced by microbial pathogen-associated molecular patterns, is essential for mucus integrity and protecting against excessive bacterial proteolytic degradation. Glycoproteomic profiling and biochemical analysis of ST6 mutations identified in patients show that decreased sialylation causes defective mucus proteins and congenital inflammatory bowel disease (IBD). Mice harboring a patient ST6 mutation have compromised mucus barriers, dysbiosis, and susceptibility to intestinal inflammation. Based on our understanding of the ST6 regulatory network, we show that treatment with sialylated mucin or a Foxo3 inhibitor can ameliorate IBD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Therapeutic potential of traditional Chinese medicine for the treatment of NAFLD: A promising drug Potentilla discolor Bunge</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/36176915/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/36176915/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nonalcoholic fatty liver disease (NAFLD) is characterized by excessive accumulation of hepatic lipids and metabolic stress-induced liver injury. There are currently no approved effective pharmacological treatments for NAFLD. Traditional Chinese medicine (TCM) has been used for centuries to treat patients with chronic liver diseases without clear disease types and mechanisms. More recently, TCM has been shown to have unique advantages in the treatment of NAFLD. We performed a systematic review of the medical literature published over the last two decades and found that many TCM formulas have been reported to be beneficial for the treatment of metabolic dysfunctions, including &lt;em&gt;Potentilla discolor&lt;/em&gt; Bunge (PDB). PDB has a variety of active compounds, including flavonoids, terpenoids, organic acids, steroids and tannins. Many compounds have been shown to exhibit a series of beneficial effects for the treatment of NAFLD, including anti-oxidative and anti-inflammatory functions, improvement of lipid metabolism and reversal of insulin resistance. In this review, we summarize potential therapeutic effects of TCM formulas for the treatment of NAFLD, focusing on the medicinal properties of natural active compounds from PDB and their underlying mechanisms. We point out that PDB can be classified as a novel candidate for the treatment and prevention of NAFLD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Functional metabolomics revealed functional metabolic-characteristics of chronic hepatitis that is significantly differentiated from acute hepatitis in mice</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35537579/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35537579/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Diagnosis and therapeutics of acute- and chronic- hepatitis (A-H and C-H) cannot be distinguished during clinical practice because functional molecular-characteristics of two conditions remains elusive. Here, we employed a functional metabolomics strategy to discover functional metabolites that can readily distinguish C-H from A-H in CCl&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; treated mice. Metabolic-differentiation between A-H and C-H was identified as A-H was largely characterized by the dysregulated purine cycle and amino acid metabolism, while the disorders of hepatic taurine-conjugated bile acids and glycerolipid biosynthesis were observed with C-H. Excitingly, we found that the enhanced conversation of C&lt;sub&gt;18-22&lt;/sub&gt; PUFA-containing TAGs to MUFA-containing TAGs promoted the development of C-H, which was also closely associated with the changes of TCA intermediates regulated by gut microbiota (Muribaculaceae and Prevotellaceae). Such metabolic discovery on hepatitis was validated by the functional annotation of metabolic genes, as the decreased expressions of Slc27a2, Acaa1a and Acaa1b mostly account for the dysregulation of purine degradation with AH, then the lowered expressions of Cyp2e1, Cat, Slc27a5 and Klb are significantly related to the dysregulated bile acids with C-H. Collecting clinical samples from the patients with hepatitis to compare serum metabolomes with A-H and C-H mice, the determinant functional metabolites were identified to significantly distinguish C-H from A-H in both experimental and clinical settings, suggesting metabolic discovery with CCl&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; treated mice could be further efficiently explored to guide clinical research of A-H and C-H. Collectively, our study is providing novel insight into distinctive metabolic-characteristics of A-H and C-H underlying the innovative diagnosis and therapeutics of hepatitis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Circadian clock, diurnal glucose metabolic rhythm, and dawn phenomenon</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/35466006/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/35466006/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Autophagy is an intracellular self-digestion mechanism, by which cellular components are sorted into double-membrane autophagosomes and delivered to lysosomes for degradation. Cells use autophagy to dispose of wastes and eliminate hazards, while recycling nutrients and tuning metabolism in the process. Through these functions, autophagy promotes cell fitness, genome integrity, tissue homeostasis, and cell survival and growth under stress. Both autophagy upregulation and downregulation have been found in human cancers, suggesting a complex role in tumor development. Accumulating results from autophagy-deficient mice and mouse models of human cancers have demonstrated that autophagy generally suppresses tumor initiation, but promotes tumor progression, in a manner that is dependent on timing and context and modified by specific tumorigenic events. Given the role of autophagy in facilitating tumor growth, autophagy inhibition has gained wide attention as a potential anticancer therapy. Here, we summarize relevant genetic, preclinical, and clinical studies and discuss the multifaceted role of autophagy in cancer, as well as the prospects of autophagy inhibition for cancer therapy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Positive feedback regulation of microglial glucose metabolism by histone H4 lysine 12 lactylation in Alzheimer&#39;s disease</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35303422/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35303422/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Histone lactylation is elevated in the brains of 5XFAD model mice and AD patients&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;H4K12la activates transcription of glycolytic genes in AD microglia&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A glycolysis/H4K12la/PKM2 positive feedback loop exacerbates microglial dysfunction&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interruption of this loop ameliorates microglial dysfunction and Aβ pathology&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The pro-inflammatory activation of microglia is a hallmark of Alzheimer&amp;rsquo;s disease (AD), and this process involves a switch from oxidative phosphorylation (OXPHOS) toward glycolysis. Here, we show how a positive feedback loop in microglia drives AD pathogenesis, and we demonstrate that inhibiting this cycle in microglia can ameliorate Aβ burden and cognitive deficits in an AD mouse model (5XFAD). After first detecting elevated histone lactylation in brain samples from both 5XFAD mice and individuals with AD, we observed that H4K12la levels are elevated in Aβ plaque-adjacent microglia. This lactate-dependent histone modification is enriched at the promoters of glycolytic genes and activates transcription, thereby increasing glycolytic activity. Ultimately, the glycolysis/H4K12la/PKM2 positive feedback loop exacerbates microglial dysfunction in AD. Pharmacologic inhibition of PKM2 attenuated microglial activation, and microglia-specific ablation of Pkm2 improved spatial learning and memory in AD mice. Thus, our study illustrates that disruption of the positive feedback loop may be a potential therapeutic approach for the treatment of AD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intestinal butyrate-metabolizing species contribute to autoantibody production and bone erosion in rheumatoid arthritis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35148177/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35148177/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The imbalance between pathogenic and beneficial species of the intestinal microbiome and metabolism in rheumatoid arthritis (RA) remains unclarified. Here, using shotgun-based metagenome sequencing for a treatment-naïve patient cohort and a &amp;ldquo;quasi-paired cohort&amp;rdquo; method, we observed a deficiency of butyrate-producing species and an overwhelming number of butyrate consumers in RA patients. These outcomes mainly occurred in patients with positive ACPA, with a mean AUC of 0.94. This panel was also validated in established RA with an AUC of 0.986 in those with joint deformity. In addition, we showed that butyrate promoted T&lt;sub&gt;regs&lt;/sub&gt;, while suppressing T&lt;sub&gt;convs&lt;/sub&gt; and osteoclasts, due to potentiation of the reduction in HDAC expression and down-regulation of proinflammatory cytokine genes. Dietary butyrate supplementation conferred anti-inflammatory benefits in a mouse model by rebalancing T&lt;sub&gt;FH&lt;/sub&gt; cells and T&lt;sub&gt;regs&lt;/sub&gt;, as well as reducing antibody production. These findings reveal the critical role of butyrate-metabolizing species and suggest the potential of butyrate-based therapies for RA patients.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mitochondrial and metabolic dysfunction in ageing and age-related diseases</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/35145250/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/35145250/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Organismal ageing is accompanied by progressive loss of cellular function and systemic deterioration of multiple tissues, leading to impaired function and increased vulnerability to death. Mitochondria have become recognized not merely as being energy suppliers but also as having an essential role in the development of diseases associated with ageing, such as neurodegenerative and cardiovascular diseases. A growing body of evidence suggests that ageing and age-related diseases are tightly related to an energy supply and demand imbalance, which might be alleviated by a variety of interventions, including physical activity and calorie restriction, as well as naturally occurring molecules targeting conserved longevity pathways. Here, we review key historical advances and progress from the past few years in our understanding of the role of mitochondria in ageing and age-related metabolic diseases. We also highlight emerging scientific innovations using mitochondria-targeted therapeutic approaches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Berberine Relieves Metabolic Syndrome in Mice by Inhibiting Liver Inflammation Caused by a High-Fat Diet and Potential Association With Gut Microbiota</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35095784/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35095784/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whether berberine mediates its anti-inflammatory and blood sugar and lipid-lowering effects solely by adjusting the structure of the gut microbiota or by first directly regulating the expression of host pro-inflammatory proteins and activation of macrophages and subsequently acting on gut microbiota, is currently unclear. To clarify the mechanism of berberine-mediated regulation of metabolism, we constructed an obese mouse model using SPF-grade C57BL/6J male mice and conducted a systematic study of liver tissue pathology, inflammatory factor expression, and gut microbiota structure. We screened the gut microbiota targets of berberine and showed that the molecular mechanism of berberine-mediated treatment of metabolic syndrome involves the regulation of gut microbiota structure and the expression of inflammatory factors. Our results revealed that a high-fat diet (HFD) significantly changed mice gut microbiota, thereby probably increasing the level of toxins in the intestine, and triggered the host inflammatory response. The HFD also reduced the proportion of short-chain fatty acid (SCFA)-producing genes, thereby hindering mucosal immunity and cell nutrition, and increased the host inflammatory response and liver fat metabolism disorders. Further, berberine could improve the chronic HFD-induced inflammatory metabolic syndrome to some extent and effectively improved the metabolism of high-fat foods in mice, which correlated with the gut microbiota composition. Taken together, our study may improve our understanding of host-microbe interactions during the treatment of metabolic diseases and provide useful insights into the action mechanism of berberine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>gutMGene: a comprehensive database for target genes of gut microbes and microbial metabolites</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34500458/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34500458/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://bio-annotation.cn/gutmgene&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;gutMGene&lt;/a&gt;, a manually curated database, aims at providing a comprehensive resource of target genes of gut microbes and microbial metabolites in humans and mice. Metagenomic sequencing of fecal samples has identified 3.3 × 106 non-redundant microbial genes from up to 1500 different species. One of the contributions of gut microbiota to host biology is the circulating pool of bacterially derived small-molecule metabolites. It has been estimated that 10% of metabolites found in mammalian blood are derived from the gut microbiota, where they can produce systemic effects on the host through activating or inhibiting gene expression. The current version of &lt;a href=&#34;http://bio-annotation.cn/gutmgene&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;gutMGene&lt;/a&gt; documents 1331 curated relationships between 332 gut microbes, 207 microbial metabolites and 223 genes in humans, and 2349 curated relationships between 209 gut microbes, 149 microbial metabolites and 544 genes in mice. Each entry in the &lt;a href=&#34;http://bio-annotation.cn/gutmgene&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;gutMGene&lt;/a&gt; contains detailed information on a relationship between gut microbe, microbial metabolite and target gene, a brief description of the relationship, experiment technology and platform, literature reference and so on. &lt;a href=&#34;http://bio-annotation.cn/gutmgene&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;gutMGene&lt;/a&gt; provides a user-friendly interface to browse and retrieve each entry using gut microbes, disorders and intervention measures. It also offers the option to download all the entries and submit new experimentally validated associations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Targeting cancer metabolism in the era of precision oncology</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/34862480/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/34862480/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One hundred years have passed since Warburg discovered alterations in cancer metabolism, more than 70 years since Sidney Farber introduced anti-folates that transformed the treatment of childhood leukaemia, and 20 years since metabolism was linked to oncogenes. However, progress in targeting cancer metabolism therapeutically in the past decade has been limited. Only a few metabolism-based drugs for cancer have been successfully developed, some of which are in - or en route to - clinical trials. Strategies for targeting the intrinsic metabolism of cancer cells often did not account for the metabolism of non-cancer stromal and immune cells, which have pivotal roles in tumour progression and maintenance. By considering immune cell metabolism and the clinical manifestations of inborn errors of metabolism, it may be possible to isolate undesirable off-tumour, on-target effects of metabolic drugs during their development. Hence, the conceptual framework for drug design must consider the metabolic vulnerabilities of non-cancer cells in the tumour immune microenvironment, as well as those of cancer cells. In this Review, we cover the recent developments, notable milestones and setbacks in targeting cancer metabolism, and discuss the way forward for the field.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Impact of intracellular innate immune receptors on immunometabolism</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/34697412/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/34697412/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Immunometabolism, which is the metabolic reprogramming of anaerobic glycolysis, oxidative phosphorylation, and metabolite synthesis upon immune cell activation, has gained importance as a regulator of the homeostasis, activation, proliferation, and differentiation of innate and adaptive immune cell subsets that function as key factors in immunity. Metabolic changes in epithelial and other stromal cells in response to different stimulatory signals are also crucial in infection, inflammation, cancer, autoimmune diseases, and metabolic disorders. The crosstalk between the PI3K–AKT–mTOR and LKB1–AMPK signaling pathways is critical for modulating both immune and nonimmune cell metabolism. The bidirectional interaction between immune cells and metabolism is a topic of intense study. Toll-like receptors (TLRs), cytokine receptors, and T and B cell receptors have been shown to activate multiple downstream metabolic pathways. However, how intracellular innate immune sensors/receptors intersect with metabolic pathways is less well understood. The goal of this review is to examine the link between immunometabolism and the functions of several intracellular innate immune sensors or receptors, such as nucleotide-binding and leucine-rich repeat-containing receptors (NLRs, or NOD-like receptors), absent in melanoma 2 (AIM2)-like receptors (ALRs), and the cyclic dinucleotide receptor stimulator of interferon genes (STING). We will focus on recent advances and describe the impact of these intracellular innate immune receptors on multiple metabolic pathways. Whenever appropriate, this review will provide a brief contextual connection to pathogenic infections, autoimmune diseases, cancers, metabolic disorders, and/or inflammatory bowel diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First we eat, then we do everything else: The dynamic metabolic regulation of efferocytosis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/34433074/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/34433074/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clearance of apoptotic cells, or &amp;ldquo;efferocytosis,&amp;rdquo; is essential for diverse processes including embryonic development, tissue turnover, organ regeneration, and immune cell development. The human body is estimated to remove approximately 1% of its body mass via apoptotic cell clearance daily. This poses several intriguing cell metabolism problems. For instance, phagocytes such as macrophages must induce or suppress metabolic pathways to find, engulf, and digest apoptotic cells. Then, phagocytes must manage the potentially burdensome biomass of the engulfed apoptotic cell. Finally, phagocytes reside in complex tissue architectures that vary in nutrient availability, the types of dying cells or debris that require clearance, and the neighboring cells they interact with. Here, we review advances in our understanding of these three key areas of phagocyte metabolism. We end by proposing a model of efferocytosis that integrates recent findings and establishes a new paradigm for testing how efferocytosis prevents chronic inflammatory disease and autoimmunity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A graph neural network model to estimate cell-wise metabolic flux using single-cell RNA-seq data</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34301623/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34301623/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The metabolic heterogeneity and metabolic interplay between cells are known as significant contributors to disease treatment resistance. However, with the lack of a mature high-throughput single-cell metabolomics technology, we are yet to establish systematic understanding of the intra-tissue metabolic heterogeneity and cooperative mechanisms. To mitigate this knowledge gap, we developed a novel computational method, namely, single-cell flux estimation analysis (scFEA), to infer the cell-wise fluxome from single-cell RNA-sequencing (scRNA-seq) data. scFEA is empowered by a systematically reconstructed human metabolic map as a factor graph, a novel probabilistic model to leverage the flux balance constraints on scRNA-seq data, and a novel graph neural network-based optimization solver. The intricate information cascade from transcriptome to metabolome was captured using multilayer neural networks to capitulate the nonlinear dependency between enzymatic gene expressions and reaction rates. We experimentally validated scFEA by generating an scRNA-seq data set with matched metabolomics data on cells of perturbed oxygen and genetic conditions. Application of scFEA on this data set showed the consistency between predicted flux and the observed variation of metabolite abundance in the matched metabolomics data. We also applied scFEA on five publicly available scRNA-seq and spatial transcriptomics data sets and identified context- and cell group-specific metabolic variations. The cell-wise fluxome predicted by scFEA empowers a series of downstream analyses including identification of metabolic modules or cell groups that share common metabolic variations, sensitivity evaluation of enzymes with regards to their impact on the whole metabolic flux, and inference of cell-tissue and cell-cell metabolic communications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cancer metabolism: looking forward</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/34272515/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/34272515/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tumour initiation and progression requires the metabolic reprogramming of cancer cells. Cancer cells autonomously alter their flux through various metabolic pathways in order to meet the increased bioenergetic and biosynthetic demand as well as mitigate oxidative stress required for cancer cell proliferation and survival. Cancer driver mutations coupled with environmental nutrient availability control flux through these metabolic pathways. Metabolites, when aberrantly accumulated, can also promote tumorigenesis. The development and application of new technologies over the last few decades has not only revealed the heterogeneity and plasticity of tumours but also allowed us to uncover new metabolic pathways involved in supporting tumour growth. The tumour microenvironment (TME), which can be depleted of certain nutrients, forces cancer cells to adapt by inducing nutrient scavenging mechanisms to sustain cancer cell proliferation. There is growing appreciation that the metabolism of cell types other than cancer cells within the TME, including endothelial cells, fibroblasts and immune cells, can modulate tumour progression. Because metastases are a major cause of death of patients with cancer, efforts are underway to understand how metabolism is harnessed by metastatic cells. Additionally, there is a new interest in exploiting cancer genetic analysis for patient stratification and/or dietary interventions in combination with therapies that target metabolism. In this Perspective, we highlight these main themes that are currently under investigation in the context of in vivo tumour metabolism, specifically emphasizing questions that remain unanswered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Identification and Characterization of Robust Hepatocellular Carcinoma Prognostic Subtypes Based on an Integrative Metabolite-Protein Interaction Network</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34247449/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34247449/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Metabolite-protein interactions (MPIs) play key roles in cancer metabolism. However, our current knowledge about MPIs in cancers remains limited due to the complexity of cancer cells. Herein, the authors construct an integrative MPI network and propose a MPI network based hepatocellular carcinoma (HCC) subtyping and mechanism exploration workflow. Based on the expressions of hub proteins on the MPI network, two prognosis-distinctive HCC subtypes are identified. Meanwhile, multiple interdependent features of the poor prognostic subtype are observed, including hypoxia, DNA hypermethylation of metabolic pathways, fatty acid accumulation, immune pathway up-regulation, and exhausted T-cell infiltration. Notably, the immune pathway up-regulation is probably induced by accumulated unsaturated fatty acids which are predicted to interact with multiple immune regulators like SRC and TGFB1. Moreover, based on tumor microenvironment compositions, the poor prognostic subtype is further divided into two sub-populations showing remarkable differences in metabolism. The subtyping shows a strong consistency across multiple HCC cohorts including early-stage HCC. Overall, the authors redefine robust HCC prognosis subtypes and identify potential MPIs linking metabolism to immune regulations, thus promoting understanding and clinical applications about HCC metabolism heterogeneity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Metabolic modeling of single Th17 cells reveals regulators of autoimmunity</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34216539/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34216539/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Compass enables studying cellular metabolism based on single-cell transcriptomes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Compass links the pathogenic potential of Th17 cells with their metabolic programs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Th17 pathogenicity is associated with a switch between glycolysis and beta oxidation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The polyamine pathway is required for Th17 induction and restriction of a Treg profile&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Summary&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Metabolism is a major regulator of immune cell function, but it remains difficult to study the metabolic status of individual cells. Here, we present Compass, an algorithm to characterize cellular metabolic states based on single-cell RNA sequencing and flux balance analysis. We applied Compass to associate metabolic states with T helper 17 (Th17) functional variability (pathogenic potential) and recovered a metabolic switch between glycolysis and fatty acid oxidation, akin to known Th17/regulatory T cell (Treg) differences, which we validated by metabolic assays. Compass also predicted that Th17 pathogenicity was associated with arginine and downstream polyamine metabolism. Indeed, polyamine-related enzyme expression was enhanced in pathogenic Th17 and suppressed in Treg cells. Chemical and genetic perturbation of polyamine metabolism inhibited Th17 cytokines, promoted Foxp3 expression, and remodeled the transcriptome and epigenome of Th17 cells toward a Treg-like state. In vivo perturbations of the polyamine pathway altered the phenotype of encephalitogenic T cells and attenuated tissue inflammation in CNS autoimmunity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intestinal MYC modulates obesity-related metabolic dysfunction</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34211180/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34211180/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MYC is a transcription factor with broad biological functions, notably in the control of cell proliferation. Here, we show that intestinal MYC regulates systemic metabolism. We find that MYC expression is increased in ileum biopsies from individuals with obesity and positively correlates with body mass index. Intestine-specific reduction of MYC in mice improves high-fat-diet-induced obesity, insulin resistance, hepatic steatosis and steatohepatitis. Mechanistically, reduced expression of MYC in the intestine promotes glucagon-like peptide-1 (GLP-1) production and secretion. Moreover, we identify Cers4, encoding ceramide synthase 4, catalysing de novo ceramide synthesis, as a MYC target gene. Finally, we show that administration of the MYC inhibitor 10058-F4 has beneficial effects on high-fat-diet-induced metabolic disorders, and is accompanied by increased GLP-1 and reduced ceramide levels in serum. This study positions intestinal MYC as a putative drug target against metabolic diseases, including non-alcoholic fatty liver disease and non-alcoholic steatohepatitis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The metabolite α-KG induces GSDMC-dependent pyroptosis through death receptor 6-activated caspase-8</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34012073/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34012073/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pyroptosis is a form of regulated cell death mediated by gasdermin family members, among which the function of GSDMC has not been clearly described. Herein, we demonstrate that the metabolite α-ketoglutarate (α-KG) induces pyroptosis through caspase-8-mediated cleavage of GSDMC. Treatment with DM-αKG, a cell-permeable derivative of α-KG, elevates ROS levels, which leads to oxidation of the plasma membrane-localized death receptor DR6. Oxidation of DR6 triggers its endocytosis, and then recruits both pro-caspase-8 and GSDMC to a DR6 receptosome through protein-protein interactions. The DR6 receptosome herein provides a platform for the cleavage of GSDMC by active caspase-8, thereby leading to pyroptosis. Moreover, this α-KG-induced pyroptosis could inhibit tumor growth and metastasis in mouse models. Interestingly, the efficiency of α-KG in inducing pyroptosis relies on an acidic environment in which α-KG is reduced by MDH1 and converted to L-2HG that further boosts ROS levels. Treatment with lactic acid, the end product of glycolysis, builds an improved acidic environment to facilitate more production of L-2HG, which makes the originally pyroptosis-resistant cancer cells more susceptible to α-KG-induced pyroptosis. This study not only illustrates a pyroptotic pathway linked with metabolites but also identifies an unreported principal axis extending from ROS-initiated DR6 endocytosis to caspase-8-mediated cleavage of GSDMC for potential clinical application in tumor therapy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Metabolomics in cancer research and emerging applications in clinical oncology</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/33982817/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/33982817/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cancer has myriad effects on metabolism that include both rewiring of intracellular metabolism to enable cancer cells to proliferate inappropriately and adapt to the tumor microenvironment, and changes in normal tissue metabolism. With the recognition that fluorodeoxyglucose-positron emission tomography imaging is an important tool for the management of many cancers, other metabolites in biological samples have been in the spotlight for cancer diagnosis, monitoring, and therapy. Metabolomics is the global analysis of small molecule metabolites that like other -omics technologies can provide critical information about the cancer state that are otherwise not apparent. Here, the authors review how cancer and cancer therapies interact with metabolism at the cellular and systemic levels. An overview of metabolomics is provided with a focus on currently available technologies and how they have been applied in the clinical and translational research setting. The authors also discuss how metabolomics could be further leveraged in the future to improve the management of patients with cancer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Serine metabolism antagonizes antiviral innate immunity by preventing ATP6V0d2-mediated YAP lysosomal degradation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33798471/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33798471/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Serine metabolism promotes tumor oncogenesis and regulates immune cell functions, but whether it also contributes to antiviral innate immunity is unknown. Here, we demonstrate that virus-infected macrophages display decreased expression of serine synthesis pathway (SSP) enzymes. Suppressing the SSP key enzyme phosphoglycerate dehydrogenase (PHGDH) by genetic approaches or by treatment with the pharmaceutical inhibitor CBR-5884 and by exogenous serine restriction enhanced IFN-β-mediated antiviral innate immunity in vitro and in vivo. Mechanistic experiments showed that virus infection or serine metabolism deficiency increased the expression of the V-ATPase subunit ATP6V0d2 by inhibiting S-adenosyl methionine-dependent H3K27me3 occupancy at the promoter. ATP6V0d2 promoted YAP lysosomal degradation to relieve YAP-mediated blockade of the TBK1-IRF3 axis and, thus, enhance IFN-β production. These findings implicate critical functions of PHGDH and the key immunometabolite serine in blunting antiviral innate immunity and also suggest manipulation of serine metabolism as a therapeutic strategy against virus infection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adaptive immunity at the crossroads of autophagy and metabolism</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/33785844/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/33785844/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The function of lymphocytes is dependent on their plasticity, particularly their adaptation to energy availability and environmental stress, and their protein synthesis machinery. Lymphocytes are constantly under metabolic stress, and macroautophagy/autophagy is the primary metabolic pathway that helps cells overcome stressors. The intrinsic role of autophagy in regulating the metabolism of adaptive immune cells has recently gained increasing attention. In this review, we summarize and discuss the versatile roles of autophagy in regulating cellular metabolism and the implications of autophagy for immune cell function and fate, especially for T and B lymphocytes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modification of Proteins by Metabolites in Immunity</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/33220233/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/33220233/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Immunometabolism has emerged as a key focus for immunologists, with metabolic change in immune cells becoming as important a determinant for specific immune effector responses as discrete signaling pathways. A key output for these changes involves post-translational modification (PTM) of proteins by metabolites. Products of glycolysis and Krebs cycle pathways can mediate these events, as can lipids, amino acids, and polyamines. A rich and diverse set of PTMs in macrophages and T cells has been uncovered, altering phenotype and modulating immunity and inflammation in different contexts. We review the recent findings in this area and speculate whether they could be of use in the effort to develop therapeutics for immune-related diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Metabolic Underpinnings of Ferroptosis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/33217331/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/33217331/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acute or chronic cellular stress resulting from aberrant metabolic and biochemical processes may trigger a pervasive non-apoptotic form of cell death, generally known as ferroptosis. Ferroptosis is unique among the different cell death modalities, as it has been mostly linked to pathophysiological conditions and because several metabolic pathways, such as (seleno)thiol metabolism, fatty acid metabolism, iron handling, mevalonate pathway, and mitochondrial respiration, directly impinge on the cells&amp;rsquo; sensitivity toward lipid peroxidation and ferroptosis. Additionally, key cellular redox systems, such as selenium-dependent glutathione peroxidase 4 and the NAD(P)H/ferroptosis suppressor protein-1/ubiquinone axis, are at play that constantly surveil and neutralize oxidative damage to cellular membranes. Since this form of cell death emerges to be the root cause of a number of diseases and since it offers various pharmacologically tractable nodes for therapeutic intervention, there has been overwhelming interest in the last few years aiming for a better molecular understanding of the ferroptotic death process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lipid Metabolism in Regulation of Macrophage Functions</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/33036870/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/33036870/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Macrophages are cells of the innate immune system that regulate the maintenance of tissue homeostasis, host defense during pathogen infection, and tissue repair in response to tissue injury. Recent studies indicate that macrophage functions are influenced by cellular metabolism, including lipid metabolism. Here, we review how macrophage lipid metabolism can be dynamically altered in different physiological and pathophysiological contexts and the key regulators involved. We also describe how alterations in lipid metabolism are integrated with the signaling pathways that specify macrophage functions, allowing for coordinated control of macrophage biology. Finally, we discuss how dysregulated lipid metabolism contributes to perturbed macrophage functions in settings such as atherosclerosis and pathogen infections.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IL-1 induces mitochondrial translocation of IRAK2 to suppress oxidative metabolism in adipocytes</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32778760/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32778760/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chronic inflammation is a common feature of obesity, with elevated cytokines such as interleukin-1 (IL-1) in the circulation and tissues. Here, we report an unconventional IL-1R–MyD88–IRAK2–PHB/OPA1 signaling axis that reprograms mitochondrial metabolism in adipocytes to exacerbate obesity. IL-1 induced recruitment of IRAK2 Myddosome to mitochondria outer membranes via recognition by TOM20, followed by TIMM50-guided translocation of IRAK2 into mitochondria inner membranes, to suppress oxidative phosphorylation and fatty acid oxidation, thereby attenuating energy expenditure. Adipocyte-specific MyD88 or IRAK2 deficiency reduced high-fat-diet-induced weight gain, increased energy expenditure and ameliorated insulin resistance, associated with a smaller adipocyte size and increased cristae formation. IRAK2 kinase inactivation also reduced high-fat diet-induced metabolic diseases. Mechanistically, IRAK2 suppressed respiratory super-complex formation via interaction with PHB1 and OPA1 upon stimulation of IL-1. Taken together, our results suggest that the IRAK2 Myddosome functions as a critical link between inflammation and metabolism, representing a novel therapeutic target for patients with obesity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Circadian rhythms and obesity: Timekeeping governs lipid metabolism</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/32656907/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/32656907/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Almost all living organisms have evolved autoregulatory transcriptional-translational feedback loops that produce oscillations with a period of approximately 24-h. These endogenous time keeping mechanisms are called circadian clocks. The main function of these circadian clocks is to drive overt circadian rhythms in the physiology of the organisms to ensure that main physiological functions are in synchrony with the external environment. Disruption of circadian rhythms caused by genetic or environmental factors has long-term consequences for metabolic health. Of relevance, host circadian rhythmicity and lipid metabolism are increasingly recognized to cross-regulate and the circadian clock-lipid metabolism interplay may involve in the development of obesity. Multiple systemic and molecular mechanisms, such as hormones (ie, melatonin, leptin, and glucocorticoid), the gut microbiome, and energy metabolism, link the circadian clock and lipid metabolism, and predictably, the deregulation of circadian clock-lipid metabolism interplay can increase the risk of obesity, which in turn may exacerbate circadian disorganization. Feeding time and dietary nutrients are two of key environmental Zeitgebers affecting the circadian rhythm-lipid metabolism interplay, and the influencing mechanisms in obesity development are highlighted in this review. Together, the characterization of the clock machinery in lipid metabolism aimed at producing a healthy circadian lifestyle may improve obesity care.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paraventricular hypothalamus mediates diurnal rhythm of metabolism</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32732906/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32732906/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Defective rhythmic metabolism is associated with high-fat high-caloric diet (HFD) feeding, ageing and obesity; however, the neural basis underlying HFD effects on diurnal metabolism remains elusive. Here we show that deletion of BMAL1, a core clock gene, in paraventricular hypothalamic (PVH) neurons reduces diurnal rhythmicity in metabolism, causes obesity and diminishes PVH neuron activation in response to fast-refeeding. Animal models mimicking deficiency in PVH neuron responsiveness, achieved through clamping PVH neuron activity at high or low levels, both show obesity and reduced diurnal rhythmicity in metabolism. Interestingly, the PVH exhibits BMAL1-controlled rhythmic expression of GABA-A receptor γ2 subunit, and dampening rhythmicity of GABAergic input to the PVH reduces diurnal rhythmicity in metabolism and causes obesity. Finally, BMAL1 deletion blunts PVH neuron responses to external stressors, an effect mimicked by HFD feeding. Thus, BMAL1-driven PVH neuron responsiveness in dynamic activity changes involving rhythmic GABAergic neurotransmission mediates diurnal rhythmicity in metabolism and is implicated in diet-induced obesity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amino Assets: How Amino Acids Support Immunity</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/32649859/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/32649859/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amino acids are fundamental building blocks supporting life. Their role in protein synthesis is well defined, but they contribute to a host of other intracellular metabolic pathways, including ATP generation, nucleotide synthesis, and redox balance, to support cellular and organismal function. Immune cells critically depend on such pathways to acquire energy and biomass and to reprogram their metabolism upon activation to support growth, proliferation, and effector functions. Amino acid metabolism plays a key role in this metabolic rewiring, and it supports various immune cell functions beyond increased protein synthesis. Here, we review the mechanisms by which amino acid metabolism promotes immune cell function, and how these processes could be targeted to improve immunity in pathological conditions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Classical and Nonclassical Intercellular Communication in Senescence and Ageing</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/32505550/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/32505550/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Intercellular communication is a key feature in physiological and pathological conditions. We hypothesize that several means of intercellular communication occur either simultaneously or in succession.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The most studied means of intercellular communication are soluble factors. However, important alternative means are emerging.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Senescent cells are highly proactive and communicate with neighboring cells via various means of intercellular communication including but not limited to the senescence-associated secretory phenotype (SASP).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Most studies of pharmacological drugs preventing the release of soluble factors oversee the influence of these drugs on other means of communication.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Intercellular communication refers to the different ways through which cells communicate with each other and transfer a variety of messages. These communication methods involve a number of different processes that occur individually or simultaneously, which change depending on the physiological or pathological context. The best characterized means of intercellular communication is the release of soluble factors that affect the function of neighboring cells. However, there are many other ways by which cells can communicate with each other. Here, we review the different means of intercellular communication including soluble factors in the context of senescence, ageing, and age-related diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nuclear receptor PXR targets AKR1B7 to protect mitochondrial metabolism and renal function in AKI</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32404507/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32404507/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acute kidney injury (AKI) is a worldwide public health problem with no specific and satisfactory therapies in clinic. The nuclear pregnane X receptor (PXR) is involved in the progression of multiple diseases, including metabolic diseases, atherosclerosis, hypertension, liver injury, etc. However, its role in kidney injury remains to be understood. In this study, we have investigated the role of PXR in AKI and underlying mechanism(s) involved in its function. PXR was robustly down-regulated and negatively correlated with renal dysfunction in human and animal kidneys with AKI. Silencing PXR in rats enhanced cisplatin-induced AKI and induced severe mitochondrial abnormalities, whereas activating PXR protected against AKI. Using luciferase reporter assays, genomic manipulation, and proteomics data analysis on the kidneys of PXR&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt; rats, we determined that PXR targeted Aldo-keto reductase family 1, member B7 (AKR1B7) to improve mitochondrial function, thereby ameliorating AKI. We confirmed the protective role of PXR against kidney injury using genomic and pharmacologic approaches in an ischemia/reperfusion model of AKI. These findings demonstrate that disabling the PXR/AKR1B7/mitochondrial metabolism axis is an important factor that can contribute to AKI, whereas reestablishing this axis can be useful for treating AKI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Glycogen metabolism regulates macrophage-mediated acute inflammatory responses</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32286295/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32286295/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our current understanding of how sugar metabolism affects inflammatory pathways in macrophages is incomplete. Here, we show that glycogen metabolism is an important event that controls macrophage-mediated inflammatory responses. IFN-γ/LPS treatment stimulates macrophages to synthesize glycogen, which is then channeled through glycogenolysis to generate G6P and further through the pentose phosphate pathway to yield abundant NADPH, ensuring high levels of reduced glutathione for inflammatory macrophage survival. Meanwhile, glycogen metabolism also increases UDPG levels and the receptor P2Y&lt;sub&gt;14&lt;/sub&gt; in macrophages. The UDPG/P2Y&lt;sub&gt;14&lt;/sub&gt; signaling pathway not only upregulates the expression of STAT1 via activating RARβ but also promotes STAT1 phosphorylation by downregulating phosphatase TC45. Blockade of this glycogen metabolic pathway disrupts acute inflammatory responses in multiple mouse models. Glycogen metabolism also regulates inflammatory responses in patients with sepsis. These findings show that glycogen metabolism in macrophages is an important regulator and indicate strategies that might be used to treat acute inflammatory diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Association to Causality: the Role of the Gut Microbiota and Its Functional Products on Host Metabolism</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/32234490/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/32234490/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many genomic studies have revealed associations between the gut microbiota composition and host metabolism. These observations led to the idea that a causal relationship could exist between the microbiota and metabolic diseases, a concept supported by studies showing compositional changes in the microbial community in metabolic diseases and transmissibility of host phenotype via microbiota transfer. Accumulating data suggest that the microbiota may affect host metabolic phenotypes through the production of metabolites. These bioactive microbial metabolites, sensitive fingerprints of microbial function, can act as inter-kingdom signaling messengers via penetration into host blood circulation and tissues. These fingerprints may be used for diagnostic purposes, and increased understanding of strain specificity in producing microbial metabolites can identify bacterial strains or specific metabolites that can be used for therapeutic purposes. Here, we will review data supporting the causal role of the gut microbiota in metabolism and discuss mechanisms and potential clinical implications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Signaling networks in immunometabolism</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/32203134/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/32203134/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adaptive immunity is essential for pathogen and tumor eradication, but may also trigger uncontrolled or pathological inflammation. T cell receptor, co-stimulatory and cytokine signals coordinately dictate specific signaling networks that trigger the activation and functional programming of T cells. In addition, cellular metabolism promotes T cell responses and is dynamically regulated through the interplay of serine/threonine kinases, immunological cues and nutrient signaling networks. In this review, we summarize the upstream regulators and signaling effectors of key serine/threonine kinase-mediated signaling networks, including PI3K-AGC kinases, mTOR and LKB1-AMPK pathways that regulate metabolism, especially in T cells. We also provide our perspectives about the pending questions and clinical applicability of immunometabolic signaling. Understanding the regulators and effectors of immunometabolic signaling networks may uncover therapeutic targets to modulate metabolic programming and T cell responses in human disease.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Genome-wide ER-phagy Screen Highlights Key Roles of Mitochondrial Metabolism and ER-Resident UFMylation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32160526/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32160526/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Selective autophagy of organelles is critical for cellular differentiation, homeostasis, and organismal health. Autophagy of the ER (ER-phagy) is implicated in human neuropathy but is poorly understood beyond a few autophagosomal receptors and remodelers. By using an ER-phagy reporter and genome-wide CRISPRi screening, we identified 200 high-confidence human ER-phagy factors. Two pathways were unexpectedly required for ER-phagy. First, reduced mitochondrial metabolism represses ER-phagy, which is opposite of general autophagy and is independent of AMPK. Second, ER-localized UFMylation is required for ER-phagy to repress the unfolded protein response via IRE1α. The UFL1 ligase is brought to the ER surface by DDRGK1 to UFMylate RPN1 and RPL26 and preferentially targets ER sheets for degradation, analogous to PINK1-Parkin regulation during mitophagy. Our data provide insight into the cellular logic of ER-phagy, reveal parallels between organelle autophagies, and provide an entry point to the relatively unexplored process of degrading the ER network.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Metabolic regulation of gene expression by histone lactylation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/31645732/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/31645732/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Warburg effect, which originally described increased production of lactate in cancer, is associated with diverse cellular processes such as angiogenesis, hypoxia, polarization of macrophages and activation of T cells. This phenomenon is intimately linked to several diseases including neoplasia, sepsis and autoimmune diseases1,2. Lactate, which is converted from pyruvate in tumour cells, is widely known as an energy source and metabolic by-product. However, its non-metabolic functions in physiology and disease remain unknown. Here we show that lactate-derived lactylation of histone lysine residues serves as an epigenetic modification that directly stimulates gene transcription from chromatin. We identify 28 lactylation sites on core histones in human and mouse cells. Hypoxia and bacterial challenges induce the production of lactate by glycolysis, and this acts as a precursor that stimulates histone lactylation. Using M1 macrophages that have been exposed to bacteria as a model system, we show that histone lactylation has different temporal dynamics from acetylation. In the late phase of M1 macrophage polarization, increased histone lactylation induces homeostatic genes that are involved in wound healing, including Arg1. Collectively, our results suggest that an endogenous ‘lactate clock’ in bacterially challenged M1 macrophages turns on gene expression to promote homeostasis. Histone lactylation thus represents an opportunity to improve our understanding of the functions of lactate and its role in diverse pathophysiological conditions, including infection and cancer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comparative Flavivirus-Host Protein Interaction Mapping Reveals Mechanisms of Dengue and Zika Virus Pathogenesis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/30550790/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/30550790/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mosquito-borne flaviviruses, including dengue virus (DENV) and Zika virus (ZIKV), are a growing public health concern. Systems-level analysis of how flaviviruses hijack cellular processes through virus-host protein-protein interactions (PPIs) provides information about their replication and pathogenic mechanisms. We used affinity purification-mass spectrometry (AP-MS) to compare flavivirus-host interactions for two viruses (DENV and ZIKV) in two hosts (human and mosquito). Conserved virus-host PPIs revealed that the flavivirus NS5 protein suppresses interferon stimulated genes by inhibiting recruitment of the transcription complex PAF1C and that chemical modulation of SEC61 inhibits DENV and ZIKV replication in human and mosquito cells. Finally, we identified a ZIKV-specific interaction between NS4A and ANKLE2, a gene linked to hereditary microcephaly, and showed that ZIKV NS4A causes microcephaly in Drosophila in an ANKLE2-dependent manner. Thus, comparative flavivirus-host PPI mapping provides biological insights and, when coupled with in vivo models, can be used to unravel pathogenic mechanisms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Infection-Induced Peroxisome Biogenesis Is a Metabolic Strategy for Herpesvirus Replication</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/30269970/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/30269970/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Viral proteins have evolved to target cellular organelles and usurp their functions for virus replication. Despite the knowledge of these critical functions for several organelles, little is known about peroxisomes during infection. Peroxisomes are primarily metabolic organelles with important functions in lipid metabolism. Here, we discovered that the enveloped viruses human cytomegalovirus (HCMV) and herpes simplex virus type 1 (HSV-1) induce the biogenesis of and unique morphological changes to peroxisomes to support their replication. Targeted proteomic quantification revealed a global virus-induced upregulation of peroxisomal proteins. Mathematical modeling and microscopy structural analysis show that infection triggers peroxisome growth and fission, leading to increased peroxisome numbers and irregular disc-like structures. HCMV-induced peroxisome biogenesis increased the phospholipid plasmalogen, thereby enhancing virus production. Peroxisome regulation and dependence were not observed for the non-enveloped adenovirus. Our findings uncover a role of peroxisomes in viral pathogenesis, with likely implications for multiple enveloped viruses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An orthogonal proteomic survey uncovers novel Zika virus host factors</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/30177828/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/30177828/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zika virus (ZIKV) has recently emerged as a global health concern owing to its widespread diffusion and its association with severe neurological symptoms and microcephaly in newborns. However, the molecular mechanisms that are responsible for the pathogenicity of ZIKV remain largely unknown. Here we use human neural progenitor cells and the neuronal cell line SK-N-BE2 in an integrated proteomics approach to characterize the cellular responses to viral infection at the proteome and phosphoproteome level, and use affinity proteomics to identify cellular targets of ZIKV proteins. Using this approach, we identify 386 ZIKV-interacting proteins, ZIKV-specific and pan-flaviviral activities as well as host factors with known functions in neuronal development, retinal defects and infertility. Moreover, our analysis identified 1,216 phosphorylation sites that are specifically up- or downregulated after ZIKV infection, indicating profound modulation of fundamental signalling pathways such as AKT, MAPK-ERK and ATM-ATR and thereby providing mechanistic insights into the proliferation arrest elicited by ZIKV infection. Functionally, our integrative study identifies ZIKV host-dependency factors and provides a comprehensive framework for a system-level understanding of ZIKV-induced perturbations at the levels of proteins and cellular pathways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>High-Definition Analysis of Host Protein Stability during Human Cytomegalovirus Infection Reveals Antiviral Factors and Viral Evasion Mechanisms</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/30122656/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/30122656/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Human cytomegalovirus (HCMV) is an important pathogen with multiple immune evasion strategies, including virally facilitated degradation of host antiviral restriction factors. Here, we describe a multiplexed approach to discover proteins with innate immune function on the basis of active degradation by the proteasome or lysosome during early-phase HCMV infection. Using three orthogonal proteomic/transcriptomic screens to quantify protein degradation, with high confidence we identified 35 proteins enriched in antiviral restriction factors. A final screen employed a comprehensive panel of viral mutants to predict viral genes that target &amp;gt;250 human proteins. This approach revealed that helicase-like transcription factor (HLTF), a DNA helicase important in DNA repair, potently inhibits early viral gene expression but is rapidly degraded during infection. The functionally unknown HCMV protein UL145 facilitates HLTF degradation by recruiting the Cullin4 E3 ligase complex. Our approach and data will enable further identifications of innate pathways targeted by HCMV and other viruses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ferroptosis: A Regulated Cell Death Nexus Linking Metabolism, Redox Biology, and Disease</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/28985560/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/28985560/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ferroptosis is a form of regulated cell death characterized by the iron-dependent accumulation of lipid hydroperoxides to lethal levels. Emerging evidence suggests that ferroptosis represents an ancient vulnerability caused by the incorporation of polyunsaturated fatty acids into cellular membranes, and cells have developed complex systems that exploit and defend against this vulnerability in different contexts. The sensitivity to ferroptosis is tightly linked to numerous biological processes, including amino acid, iron, and polyunsaturated fatty acid metabolism, and the biosynthesis of glutathione, phospholipids, NADPH, and coenzyme Q&lt;sub&gt;10&lt;/sub&gt;. Ferroptosis has been implicated in the pathological cell death associated with degenerative diseases (i.e., Alzheimer&amp;rsquo;s, Huntington&amp;rsquo;s, and Parkinson&amp;rsquo;s diseases), carcinogenesis, stroke, intracerebral hemorrhage, traumatic brain injury, ischemia-reperfusion injury, and kidney degeneration in mammals and is also implicated in heat stress in plants. Ferroptosis may also have a tumor-suppressor function that could be harnessed for cancer therapy. This Primer reviews the mechanisms underlying ferroptosis, highlights connections to other areas of biology and medicine, and recommends tools and guidelines for studying this emerging form of regulated cell death.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emerging Roles for the Lysosome in Lipid Metabolism</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/28838620/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/28838620/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Precise regulation of lipid biosynthesis, transport, and storage is key to the homeostasis of cells and organisms. Cells rely on a sophisticated but poorly understood network of vesicular and nonvesicular transport mechanisms to ensure efficient delivery of lipids to target organelles. The lysosome stands at the crossroads of this network due to its ability to process and sort exogenous and endogenous lipids. The lipid-sorting function of the lysosome is intimately connected to its recently discovered role as a metabolic command-and-control center, which relays multiple nutrient cues to the master growth regulator, mechanistic target of rapamycin complex (mTORC)1 kinase. In turn, mTORC1 potently drives anabolic processes, including de novo lipid synthesis, while inhibiting lipid catabolism. Here, we describe the dual role of the lysosome in lipid transport and biogenesis, and we discuss how integration of these two processes may play important roles both in normal physiology and in disease.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Metabolic Instruction of Immunity</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/28475890/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/28475890/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Choices have consequences. Immune cells survey and migrate throughout the body and sometimes take residence in niche environments with distinct communities of cells, extracellular matrix, and nutrients that may differ from those in which they matured. Imbedded in immune cell physiology are metabolic pathways and metabolites that not only provide energy and substrates for growth and survival, but also instruct effector functions, differentiation, and gene expression. This review of immunometabolism will reference the most recent literature to cover the choices that environments impose on the metabolism and function of immune cells and highlight their consequences during homeostasis and disease.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>mTOR Signaling in Growth, Metabolism, and Disease</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/28283069/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/28283069/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The mechanistic target of rapamycin (mTOR) coordinates eukaryotic cell growth and metabolism with environmental inputs, including nutrients and growth factors. Extensive research over the past two decades has established a central role for mTOR in regulating many fundamental cell processes, from protein synthesis to autophagy, and deregulated mTOR signaling is implicated in the progression of cancer and diabetes, as well as the aging process. Here, we review recent advances in our understanding of mTOR function, regulation, and importance in mammalian physiology. We also highlight how the mTOR signaling network contributes to human disease and discuss the current and future prospects for therapeutically targeting mTOR in the clinic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commensal microbiota from patients with inflammatory bowel disease produce genotoxic metabolites</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36302024/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jun 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36302024/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Introduction&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gut microbiota can potentially contribute to the development and progression of colorectal cancer (CRC) by producing small-molecule genotoxins. For example, select commensal &lt;em&gt;Escherichia coli&lt;/em&gt; strains produce the canonical microbiota-derived genotoxin colibactin, which engenders the formation of DNA double-strand breaks (DSBs) in intestinal epithelial cells and exacerbates CRC in mouse models. Furthermore, human CRCs harbor colibactin-associated mutational signatures, implying a direct role for microbiota-induced DNA damage in CRC. However, the impacts of microbiota-derived genotoxins beyond colibactin remain largely unexplored.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rationale&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given the extensive diversity of small-molecule metabolites produced by bacteria, we hypothesized that additional taxa from the human gut microbiome might produce previously undiscovered small molecules that cause DNA damage in host cells. Identifying and characterizing such genotoxins and their respective biosynthetic pathways may reveal causal roles of gut microbes in shaping host biology and disease susceptibility. Thus, we designed a large-scale electrophoresis-based DNA damage screening pipeline to evaluate the genotoxicity of a collection of more than 100 gut commensals isolated from patients with inflammatory bowel disease (IBD).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We identified diverse bacteria from the human microbiota whose small-molecule metabolites caused genotoxicity in both cell-free and cell-based DNA damage assays. For example, small-molecule metabolites from gram-positive bacteria (including &lt;em&gt;Clostridium perfringens&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Clostridium ramosum&lt;/em&gt; strains) and gram-negative bacteria (including multiple &lt;em&gt;Morganella morganii&lt;/em&gt; strains) directly damaged DNA in cell-free assays and induced the expression of the DSB marker γ-H2AX and cell-cycle arrest in epithelial cells. However, the DNA damage patterns caused by these metabolites were distinct from colibactin-induced cross-links, and these isolates lacked the biosynthetic machinery to produce colibactin or other known genotoxins. These data thus implied the existence of previously unrecognized microbiota-derived genotoxins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;M. morganii&lt;/em&gt; is enriched in the gut microbiota of both IBD and CRC patients. Using a combination of comparative metabolomics and bioactivity-guided natural product-discovery techniques, we discovered a family of &lt;em&gt;M. morganii&lt;/em&gt;-derived small-molecule genotoxins—termed the indolimines—that elicited DNA damage in cell-based and cell-free assays. Furthermore, we identified a previously uncharacterized bacterial decarboxylase (annotated as an aspartate aminotransferase encoded by the &lt;em&gt;aat&lt;/em&gt; gene) that was essential for indolimine synthesis and constructed an isogenic aat mutant &lt;em&gt;M. morganii&lt;/em&gt; that lacked genotoxicity in both cell-free and cell-based DNA damage assays.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Compared with the non–indolimine-producing mutant, wild-type &lt;em&gt;M. morganii&lt;/em&gt; caused increased intestinal permeability and induced transcriptional signatures associated with abnormal DNA replication and intestinal epithelial cell proliferation in gnotobiotic mice. Furthermore, indolimine-producing &lt;em&gt;M. morganii&lt;/em&gt; induced increased colonic tumor burden in the context of a mock microbial community in a mouse model of CRC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By leveraging function-based assessments of the microbiome, we uncovered the existence of a broader universe of microbiota-derived small-molecule genotoxins. We found that diverse bacterial strains isolated from IBD patients exhibited DNA-damaging activities and discovered a previously undescribed family of genotoxins, termed the indolimines, produced by the IBD- and CRC-associated species &lt;em&gt;M. morganii&lt;/em&gt;. Indolimine-producing &lt;em&gt;M. morganii&lt;/em&gt; caused increased intestinal permeability and exacerbated colon tumorigenesis in gnotobiotic mice. Overall, these studies imply an expanded role for microbiota-derived genotoxins in shaping host biology and disease susceptibility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
