<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>cccDNA | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/cccdna/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/cccdna/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>cccDNA</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>cccDNA</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/cccdna/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Discovery of a first-in-class orally available HBV cccDNA inhibitor</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36587899/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36587899/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background &amp;amp; Aims&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The persistence of covalently closed circular DNA (cccDNA) in infected hepatocytes is the major barrier preventing viral eradication with existing therapies in patients with chronic hepatitis B (CHB). Therapeutic agents that can eliminate cccDNA are urgently needed to achieve virus eradication and thus HBV cure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A phenotypic assay with HBV-infected primary human hepatocytes (PHHs) was employed to screen for novel cccDNA inhibitors. A HBVcircle mouse model and a urokinase-type plasminogen activator-severe combined immunodeficiency (uPA-SCID) humanized liver mouse model were used to evaluate the anti-HBV efficacy of the discovered cccDNA inhibitors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Potent and dose-dependent reductions in extracellular HBV DNA, HBsAg, and HBeAg levels were achieved upon the initiation of ccc_R08 treatment two days after the HBV infection of PHHs. More importantly, the level of cccDNA was specifically reduced by ccc_R08, while it did not obviously affect mitochondrial DNA. Additionally, ccc_R08 showed no significant cytotoxicity in PHHs or in multiple proliferating cell lines. The twice daily oral administration of ccc_R08 to HBVcircle model mice, which contained surrogate cccDNA molecules, significantly decreased the serum levels of HBV DNA and antigens, and these effects were sustained during the off-treatment follow-up period. Moreover, at the end of the follow-up, the levels of surrogate cccDNA molecules in the livers of ccc_R08-treated HBVcircle mice were reduced to below the lower limit of quantification (LLOQ).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have discovered a small molecule cccDNA inhibitor that reduces HBV cccDNA levels. cccDNA inhibitors potentially represent a new approach to completely cure patients chronically infected with HBV.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Impact and Implications&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;cccDNA persistence in HBV-infected hepatocytes is the root cause of chronic hepatitis B. We discovered a novel small molecule cccDNA inhibitor that can specifically reduce cccDNA levels in HBV infected hepatocytes. This type of molecule offers a new approach to completely cure patients chronically infected with HBV.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
