<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Guide/Consensus | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/guide/consensus/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/guide/consensus/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Guide/Consensus</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Guide/Consensus</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/guide/consensus/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>A guide to naming eukaryotic circular RNAs</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36658223/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36658223/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alternative splicing of eukaryotic messenger RNA transcripts often leads to the production of several mature RNAs — including linear RNAs and circular RNAs (circRNAs) — from a single gene locus. The names given to circRNAs are often ambiguous and lack consistency across studies. This Comment calls on the community to embrace a common nomenclature for naming circRNAs to ensure clarity and reproducibility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A researcher&#39;s guide to preclinical mouse NASH models</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/36539621/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/36539621/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Non-alcoholic fatty liver disease (NAFLD) and its inflammatory form, non-alcoholic steatohepatitis (NASH), have quickly risen to become the most prevalent chronic liver disease in the Western world and are risk factors for the development of hepatocellular carcinoma (HCC). HCC is not only one of the most common cancers but is also highly lethal. Nevertheless, there are currently no clinically approved drugs for NAFLD, and NASH-induced HCC poses a unique metabolic microenvironment that may influence responsiveness to certain treatments. Therefore, there is an urgent need to better understand the pathogenesis of this rampant disease to devise new therapies. In this line, preclinical mouse models are crucial tools to investigate mechanisms as well as novel treatment modalities during the pathogenesis of NASH and subsequent HCC in preparation for human clinical trials. Although, there are numerous genetically induced, diet-induced and toxin-induced models of NASH, not all of these models faithfully phenocopy and mirror the human pathology very well. In this Perspective, we shed some light onto the most widely used mouse models of NASH and highlight some of the key advantages and disadvantages of the various models with an emphasis on &amp;lsquo;Western diets&amp;rsquo;, which are increasingly recognized as some of the best models in recapitulating the human NASH pathology and comorbidities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A brief guideline for studies of phase-separated biomolecular condensates</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/36400991/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/36400991/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cells are exquisitely compartmentalized to achieve precise spatiotemporal regulation of myriad processes and pathways. Phase separation offers one way to achieve territorial organization in the cellular context, via the creation of membrane-less organelles (MLOs). MLOs formed through phase separation are associated with numerous critical biological functions. Although hundreds of publications on related topics are produced each year, robust criteria for the determination of biologically meaningful phase separation are yet to be well established. Here we present some principles and propose a few guidelines for phase-separation studies in biology. Specifically, we provide an in-depth experiment pipeline for phase-separation studies, including mechanisms of the molecular driving forces, ways to correlate in vivo and in vitro observations, and strategies to relate the phase-separation phenomenon to biological functions. We also intend to contribute to streamlining the aforementioned diagnostic criteria by further stressing a few common caveats in the field.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A pulmonologist&#39;s guide to perform and analyse cross-species single lung cell transcriptomics</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/35896273/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/35896273/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Single-cell ribonucleic acid sequencing is becoming widely employed to study biological processes at a novel resolution depth. The ability to analyse transcriptomes of multiple heterogeneous cell types in parallel is especially valuable for cell-focused lung research where a variety of resident and recruited cells are essential for maintaining organ functionality. We compared the single-cell transcriptomes from publicly available and unpublished datasets of the lungs in six different species: human (&lt;em&gt;Homo sapiens&lt;/em&gt;), African green monkey (&lt;em&gt;Chlorocebus sabaeus&lt;/em&gt;), pig (&lt;em&gt;Sus domesticus&lt;/em&gt;), hamster (&lt;em&gt;Mesocricetus auratus&lt;/em&gt;), rat (&lt;em&gt;Rattus norvegicus&lt;/em&gt;) and mouse (&lt;em&gt;Mus musculus&lt;/em&gt;) by employing RNA velocity and intercellular communication based on ligand-receptor co-expression, among other techniques. Specifically, we demonstrated a workflow for interspecies data integration, applied a single unified gene nomenclature, performed cell-specific clustering and identified marker genes for each species. Overall, integrative approaches combining newly sequenced as well as publicly available datasets could help identify species-specific transcriptomic signatures in both healthy and diseased lung tissue and select appropriate models for future respiratory research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
