<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Nervous System | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/nervous-system/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/nervous-system/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Nervous System</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Nervous System</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/nervous-system/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Molecular and spatial signatures of mouse brain aging at single-cell resolution</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36580914/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36580914/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Molecular and cellular architecture of aging frontal cortex and striatum is mapped&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Aging induces spatially dependent cell-state changes in non-neuronal cells&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;White matter is a hotspot for aging-related glial and immune cell activation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Aging- and LPS-induced brain inflammation exhibit similarities and differences&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Summary&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The diversity and complex organization of cells in the brain have hindered systematic characterization of age-related changes in its cellular and molecular architecture, limiting our ability to understand the mechanisms underlying its functional decline during aging. Here, we generated a high-resolution cell atlas of brain aging within the frontal cortex and striatum using spatially resolved single-cell transcriptomics and quantified changes in gene expression and spatial organization of major cell types in these regions over the mouse lifespan. We observed substantially more pronounced changes in cell state, gene expression, and spatial organization of non-neuronal cells over neurons. Our data revealed molecular and spatial signatures of glial and immune cell activation during aging, particularly enriched in the subcortical white matter, and identified both similarities and notable differences in cell-activation patterns induced by aging and systemic inflammatory challenge. These results provide critical insights into age-related decline and inflammation in the brain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Persistent post-COVID-19 smell loss is associated with immune cell infiltration and altered gene expression in olfactory epithelium</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36542694/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36542694/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SARS-CoV-2 causes profound changes in the sense of smell, including total smell loss. Although these alterations are often transient, many patients with COVID-19 exhibit olfactory dysfunction that lasts months to years. Although animal and human autopsy studies have suggested mechanisms driving acute anosmia, it remains unclear how SARS-CoV-2 causes persistent smell loss in a subset of patients. To address this question, we analyzed olfactory epithelial samples collected from 24 biopsies, including from nine patients with objectively quantified long-term smell loss after COVID-19. This biopsy-based approach revealed a diffuse infiltrate of T cells expressing interferon-γ and a shift in myeloid cell population composition, including enrichment of CD207+ dendritic cells and depletion of anti-inflammatory M2 macrophages. Despite the absence of detectable SARS-CoV-2 RNA or protein, gene expression in the barrier supporting cells of the olfactory epithelium, termed sustentacular cells, appeared to reflect a response to ongoing inflammatory signaling, which was accompanied by a reduction in the number of olfactory sensory neurons relative to olfactory epithelial sustentacular cells. These findings indicate that T cell-mediated inflammation persists in the olfactory epithelium long after SARS-CoV-2 has been eliminated from the tissue, suggesting a mechanism for long-term post-COVID-19 smell loss.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spinal VGLUT3 lineage neurons drive visceral mechanical allodynia but not sensitized visceromotor reflexes</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36584681/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36584681/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Focal colorectal distention (fCRD) can drive both visceromotor reflexes and aversion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spinal CCK neurons drive acute visceromotor reflexes and aversion by noxious fCRD&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spinal VGLUT3 lineage neurons drive fCRD-evoked allodynia in mice with colitis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spinal VGLUT3-negative neurons sufficiently drive sensitized visceromotor reflexes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Summary&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Visceral pain is among the most prevalent and bothersome forms of chronic pain, but their transmission in the spinal cord is still poorly understood. Here, we conducted focal colorectal distention (fCRD) to drive both visceromotor responses (VMRs) and aversion. We first found that spinal CCK neurons were necessary for noxious fCRD to drive both VMRs and aversion under naive conditions. We next showed that spinal VGLUT3 neurons mediate visceral allodynia, whose ablation caused loss of aversion evoked by low-intensity fCRD in mice with gastrointestinal (GI) inflammation or spinal circuit disinhibition. Importantly, these neurons were dispensable for driving sensitized VMRs under both inflammatory and central disinhibition conditions. Anatomically, a subset of VGLUT3 neurons projected to parabrachial nuclei, whose photoactivation sufficiently generated aversion in mice with GI inflammation, without influencing VMRs. Our studies suggest the presence of different spinal substrates that transmit nociceptive versus affective dimensions of visceral sensory information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dual roles of hexokinase 2 in shaping microglial function by gating glycolytic flux and mitochondrial activity</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36536134/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36536134/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Microglia continuously survey the brain parenchyma and actively shift status following stimulation. These processes demand a unique bioenergetic programme; however, little is known about the metabolic determinants in microglia. By mining large datasets and generating transgenic tools, here we show that hexokinase 2 (HK2), the most active isozyme associated with mitochondrial membrane, is selectively expressed in microglia in the brain. Genetic ablation of HK2 reduced microglial glycolytic flux and energy production, suppressed microglial repopulation, and attenuated microglial surveillance and damage-triggered migration in male mice. HK2 elevation is prominent in immune-challenged or disease-associated microglia. In ischaemic stroke models, however, HK2 deletion promoted neuroinflammation and potentiated cerebral damages. The enhanced inflammatory responses after HK2 ablation in microglia are associated with aberrant mitochondrial function and reactive oxygen species accumulation. Our study demonstrates that HK2 gates both glycolytic flux and mitochondrial activity to shape microglial functions, changes of which contribute to metabolic abnormalities and maladaptive inflammation in brain diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Somatosensory neurons express specific sets of lincRNAs, and lincRNA CLAP promotes itch sensation in mice</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36524339/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36524339/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Somatosensory neurons are highly heterogeneous with distinct types of neural cells responding to specific stimuli. However, the distribution and roles of cell-type-specific long intergenic noncoding RNAs (lincRNAs) in somatosensory neurons remain largely unexplored. Here, by utilizing droplet-based single-cell RNA-seq (scRNA-seq) and full-length Smart-seq2, we show that lincRNAs, but not coding mRNAs, are enriched in specific types of mouse somatosensory neurons. Profiling of lincRNAs from single neurons located in dorsal root ganglia (DRG) identifies 200 lincRNAs localized in specific types or subtypes of somatosensory neurons. Among them, the conserved cell-type-specific lincRNA CLAP associates with pruritus and is abundantly expressed in somatostatin (SST)-positive neurons. CLAP knockdown reduces histamine-induced Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt; influx in cultured SST-positive neurons and in vivo reduces histamine-induced scratching in mice. In vivo knockdown of CLAP also decreases the expression of neuron-type-specific and itch-related genes in somatosensory neurons, and this partially depends on the RNA binding protein MSI2. Our data reveal a cell-type-specific landscape of lincRNAs and a function for CLAP in somatosensory neurons in sensory transmission.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Functional reconstruction of the basal ganglia neural circuit by human striatal neurons in hypoxic-ischaemic injured brain</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36516880/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36516880/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perinatal hypoxic-ischaemic encephalopathy is the leading cause of neonatal death and permanent neurological deficits, while the basal ganglia is one of the major nuclei that is selectively and greatly affected in the brains of hypoxic-ischaemic encephalopathy patients, especially in severe cases. Human embryonic stem cell-derived neurons have shown great potential in different types of brain disorders in adults. However, it remains unknown whether and how grafted human embryonic stem cell-derived neurons can repair immature brains with hypoxic-ischaemic encephalopathy. Here, by administrating genetically labelled human embryonic stem cell-derived striatal neural progenitors into the ipsilateral striatum of hypoxic-ischaemic encephalopathy-injured mice, we found that the grafted cells gradually matured into GABA spiny projection neurons morphologically and electrophysiologically, and significantly rescued the area loss of hypoxic-ischaemic encephalopathy-injured brains. Intriguingly, using immunohistochemical staining combined with enhanced ascorbate peroxidase-based immunoelectron microscopy and rabies virus-mediated trans-synaptic tracing, we show that the grafts start to extend axonal projections to the endogenous target areas (globus pallidus externa, globus pallidus internus, substantia nigra), form synapses with host striatal, globus pallidus and nigra neurons, and receive extensive and stable synaptic inputs as early as 2 months post-transplantation. Importantly, we further demonstrated functional neural circuits re-established between the grafted neurons and host cortical, striatal and substantial nigra neurons at 3-6 months post-transplantation in the hypoxic-ischaemic encephalopathy-injured brain by optogenetics combined with electrophysiological recording. Finally, the transplanted striatal spiny projection neurons but not spinal GABA neurons restored the motor defects of hypoxic-ischaemic encephalopathy, which were reversed by clozapine-N-oxide-based inhibition of graft function. These findings demonstrate anatomical and functional reconstruction of the basal ganglia neural circuit including multiple loops by striatal spiny projection neurons in hypoxic-ischaemic encephalopathy-injured immature brains, which raises the possibility of such a cell replacement therapeutic strategy for hypoxic-ischaemic encephalopathy in neonates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resveratrol-loaded macrophage exosomes alleviate multiple sclerosis through targeting microglia</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36521687/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36521687/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite exosome promise as endogenous drug delivery vehicles, the current understanding of exosome may be insufficient to develop their various applications. Here we synthesized five sialic acid analogues with different length N-acyl side chains and screened out the optimal metabolic precursor for exosome labeling via bio-orthogonal click chemistry. In proof-of-principle labeling experiments, exosomes derived from macrophages (RAW-Exo) strongly co-localized with central nervous system (CNS) microglia. Inspired by this discovery, we developed a resveratrol-loaded RAW-Exo formulation (RSV&amp;amp;Exo) for multiple sclerosis (MS) treatment. Intranasal administration of RSV&amp;amp;Exo significantly inhibited inflammatory responses in the CNS and peripheral system in a mouse model of MS and effectively improved the clinical evolution of MS in vivo. These findings suggested the feasibility and efficacy of engineered RSV&amp;amp;Exo administration for MS, providing a potential therapeutic strategy for CNS diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An HSV-1-H129 amplicon tracer system for rapid and efficient monosynaptic anterograde neural circuit tracing</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36496505/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36496505/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Monosynaptic viral tracers are essential tools for dissecting neuronal connectomes and for targeted delivery of molecular sensors and effectors. Viral toxicity and complex multi-injection protocols are major limiting application barriers. To overcome these barriers, we developed an anterograde monosynaptic H129&lt;sub&gt;Amp&lt;/sub&gt; tracer system based on HSV-1 strain H129. The H129&lt;sub&gt;Amp&lt;/sub&gt; tracer system consists of two components: an H129-dTK-T2-pac&lt;sup&gt;Flox&lt;/sup&gt; helper which assists H129&lt;sub&gt;Amp&lt;/sub&gt; tracer&amp;rsquo;s propagation and transneuronal monosynaptic transmission. The shared viral features of tracer/helper allow for simultaneous single-injection and subsequent high expression efficiency from multiple-copy of expression cassettes in H129&lt;sub&gt;Amp&lt;/sub&gt; tracer. These improvements of H129&lt;sub&gt;Amp&lt;/sub&gt; tracer system shorten experiment duration from 28-day to 5-day for fast-bright monosynaptic tracing. The lack of toxic viral genes in the H129&lt;sub&gt;Amp&lt;/sub&gt;tracer minimizes toxicity in postsynaptic neurons, thus offering the potential for functional anterograde mapping and long-term tracer delivery of genetic payloads. The H129&lt;sub&gt;Amp&lt;/sub&gt; tracer system is a powerful tracing tool for revealing neuronal connectomes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exosomal noncoding RNAs in central nervous system diseases: biological functions and potential clinical applications</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/36438184/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/36438184/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Central nervous system (CNS) disease is a general term for a series of complex and diverse diseases, including Alzheimer&amp;rsquo;s disease (AD), Parkinson&amp;rsquo;s disease (PD), multiple sclerosis (MS), CNS tumors, stroke, epilepsy, and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS). Interneuron and neuron-glia cells communicate with each other through their homeostatic microenvironment. Exosomes in the microenvironment have crucial impacts on interneuron and neuron-glia cells by transferring their contents, such as proteins, lipids, and ncRNAs, constituting a novel form of cell-to-cell interaction and communication. Exosomal noncoding RNAs (ncRNAs), including microRNAs (miRNAs), long noncoding RNAs (lncRNAs), circular RNAs (circRNAs), and PIWI-interacting RNAs (piRNAs), regulate physiological functions and maintain CNS homeostasis. Exosomes are regarded as extracellular messengers that transfer ncRNAs between neurons and body fluids due to their ability to cross the blood-brain barrier. This review aims to summarize the current understanding of exosomal ncRNAs in CNS diseases, including prospective diagnostic biomarkers, pathological regulators, therapeutic strategies and clinical applications. We also provide an all-sided discussion of the comparison with some similar CNS diseases and the main limitations and challenges for exosomal ncRNAs in clinical applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PANoptosis-like cell death in ischemia/reperfusion injury of retinal neurons</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35900430/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35900430/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We screened small molecules to identify two compounds, which we named RSL3 and RSL5, that have increased lethality in the presence of oncogenic RAS. Counter screening with biologically active compounds defined aspects of the mechanism of action for RSL3 and RSL5, such as a nonapoptotic, MEK-dependent, and iron-dependent oxidative cell death. Erastin, a previously reported compound with RAS-selective lethality, showed similar properties. RNA interference experiments targeting voltage-dependent anion channel 3 (VDAC3), a target of erastin, demonstrated that RSL5 is a scaffold that acts through VDACs to activate the observed pathway. RSL3 activated a similar death mechanism but in a VDAC-independent manner. We found that cells transformed with oncogenic RAS have increased iron content relative to their normal cell counterparts through upregulation of transferrin receptor 1 and downregulation of ferritin heavy chain 1 and ferritin light chain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Divergent Neural Activity in the VLPO During Anesthesia and Sleep</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36461756/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36461756/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therapeutics that discriminate between the genetic makeup of normal cells and tumour cells are valuable for treating and understanding cancer. Small molecules with oncogene-selective lethality may reveal novel functions of oncoproteins and enable the creation of more selective drugs. Here we describe the mechanism of action of the selective anti-tumour agent erastin, involving the RAS-RAF-MEK signalling pathway functioning in cell proliferation, differentiation and survival. Erastin exhibits greater lethality in human tumour cells harbouring mutations in the oncogenes HRAS, KRAS or BRAF. Using affinity purification and mass spectrometry, we discovered that erastin acts through mitochondrial voltage-dependent anion channels (VDACs)&amp;ndash;a novel target for anti-cancer drugs. We show that erastin treatment of cells harbouring oncogenic RAS causes the appearance of oxidative species and subsequent death through an oxidative, non-apoptotic mechanism. RNA-interference-mediated knockdown of VDAC2 or VDAC3 caused resistance to erastin, implicating these two VDAC isoforms in the mechanism of action of erastin. Moreover, using purified mitochondria expressing a single VDAC isoform, we found that erastin alters the permeability of the outer mitochondrial membrane. Finally, using a radiolabelled analogue and a filter-binding assay, we show that erastin binds directly to VDAC2. These results demonstrate that ligands to VDAC proteins can induce non-apoptotic cell death selectively in some tumour cells harbouring activating mutations in the RAS-RAF-MEK pathway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Caspase-8 as a novel mediator linking Src kinase signaling to enhanced glioblastoma malignancy </title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36460775/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36460775/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Caspase-8 is a cysteine protease that plays an essential role in apoptosis. Consistently with its canonical proapoptotic function, cancer cells may genetically or epigenetically downregulate its expression. Unexpectedly, Caspase-8 is often retained in cancer, suggesting the presence of alternative mechanisms that may be exploited by cancer cells to their own benefit. In this regard, we reported that Src tyrosine kinase, which is aberrantly activated in many tumors, promotes Caspase-8 phosphorylation on Tyrosine 380 (Y380) preventing its full activation. Here, we investigated the significance of Caspase-8 expression and of its phosphorylation on Y380 in glioblastoma, a brain tumor where both Caspase-8 expression and Src activity are often aberrantly upregulated. Transcriptomic analyses identified inflammatory response as a major target of Caspase-8, and in particular, NFκB signaling as one of the most affected pathways. More importantly, we could show that Src-dependent phosphorylation of Caspase-8 on Y380 drives the assembly of a multiprotein complex that triggers NFκB activation, thereby inducing the expression of inflammatory and pro-angiogenic factors. Remarkably, phosphorylation on Y380 sustains neoangiogenesis and resistance to radiotherapy. In summary, our work identifies a novel interplay between Src kinase and Caspase-8 that allows cancer cells to hijack Caspase-8 to sustain tumor growth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Proper wiring of newborn neurons to control bladder function after complete spinal cord injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36455486/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36455486/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Activation of endogenous neurogenesis by bioactive materials enables restoration of sensory/motor function after complete spinal cord injury (SCI) via formation of new relay neural circuits. The underlying wiring logic of newborn neurons in adult central nervous system (CNS) is unknown. Here, we report neurotrophin3-loaded chitosan biomaterial substantially recovered bladder function after SCI. Multiple neuro-circuitry tracing technologies using pseudorabies virus (PRV), rabies virus (RV), and anterograde adeno-associated virus (AAV), demonstrated that newborn neurons were integrated into the micturition neural circuits and reconnected higher brain centers and lower spinal cord centers to control voiding, and participated in the restoration of the lower urinary tract function, even in the absence of long-distance axonal regeneration. Opto- and chemo-genetic studies further supported the notion that the supraspinal control of the lower urinary tract function was partially recovered. Our data demonstrated that regenerated relay neurons could be properly integrated into disrupted long-range neural circuits to restore function of adult CNS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generation of neural organoids for spinal-cord regeneration via the direct reprogramming of human astrocytes</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36424465/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36424465/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Organoids with region-specific architecture could facilitate the repair of injuries of the central nervous system. Here we show that human astrocytes can be directly reprogrammed into early neuroectodermal cells via the overexpression of &lt;em&gt;OCT4&lt;/em&gt;, the suppression of &lt;em&gt;p53&lt;/em&gt; and the provision of the small molecules CHIR99021, SB431542, RepSox and Y27632. We also report that the activation of signalling mediated by fibroblast growth factor, sonic hedgehog and bone morphogenetic protein 4 in the reprogrammed cells induces them to form spinal-cord organoids with functional neurons specific to the dorsal and ventral domains. In mice with complete spinal-cord injury, organoids transplanted into the lesion differentiated into spinal-cord neurons, which migrated and formed synapses with host neurons. The direct reprogramming of human astrocytes into neurons may pave the way for in vivo neural organogenesis from endogenous astrocytes for the repair of injuries to the central nervous system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intestinal dysbiosis mediates cognitive impairment via the intestine and brain NLRP3 inflammasome activation in chronic sleep deprivation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36427810/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36427810/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Growing evidence suggests the involvement of the microbiota-gut-brain axis in cognitive impairment induced by sleep deprivation (SD), however how the microbiota-gut-brain axis work remains elusive. Here, we discovered that chronic SD induced intestinal dysbiosis, activated NLRP3 inflammasome in the colon and brain, destructed intestinal/blood-brain barrier, and impaired cognitive function in mice. Transplantation of &amp;ldquo;SD microbiota&amp;rdquo; could almost mimic the pathological and behavioral changes caused by chronic SD. Furthermore, all the behavioral and pathological abnormalities were practically reversed in chronic sleep-deprived NLRP3-/- mice. Regional knockdown NLRP3 expression in the gut and hippocampus, respectively. We observed that down-regulation of NLRP3 in the hippocampus inhibited neuroinflammation, and ameliorated synaptic dysfunction and cognitive impairment induced by chronic SD. More intriguingly, the down-regulation of NLRP3 in the gut protected the intestinal barrier, attenuated the levels of peripheral inflammatory factors, down-regulated the expression of NLRP3 in the brain, and improved cognitive function in chronic SD mice. Our results identified gut microbiota as a driver in chronic SD and highlighted the NLRP3 inflammasome as a key regulator within the microbiota-gut-brain axis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A blood-brain penetrant RNA-targeted small molecule triggers elimination of r(G4C2)exp in c9ALS/FTD via the nuclear RNA exosome</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36409902/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36409902/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A hexanucleotide repeat expansion in intron 1 of the &lt;em&gt;C9orf72&lt;/em&gt; gene is the most common genetic cause of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and frontotemporal dementia, or c9ALS/FTD. The RNA transcribed from the expansion, r(G&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;C&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;)&lt;sup&gt;exp&lt;/sup&gt;, causes various pathologies, including intron retention, aberrant translation that produces toxic dipeptide repeat proteins (DPRs), and sequestration of RNA-binding proteins (RBPs) in RNA foci. Here, we describe a small molecule that potently and selectively interacts with r(G&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;C&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;)&lt;sup&gt;exp&lt;/sup&gt; and mitigates disease pathologies in spinal neurons differentiated from c9ALS patient-derived induced pluripotent stem cells (iPSCs) and in two c9ALS/FTD mouse models. These studies reveal a mode of action whereby a small molecule diminishes intron retention caused by the r(G&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;C&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;)&lt;sup&gt;exp&lt;/sup&gt; and allows the liberated intron to be eliminated by the nuclear RNA exosome, a multi-subunit degradation complex. Our findings highlight the complexity of mechanisms available to RNA-binding small molecules to alleviate disease pathologies and establishes a pipeline for the design of brain penetrant small molecules targeting RNA with novel modes of action &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integrative omics indicate FMRP sequesters mRNA from translation and deadenylation in human neuronal cells</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36356584/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36356584/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How fragile X syndrome protein (FMRP) binds mRNAs and regulates mRNA metabolism remains unclear. Our previous work using human neuronal cells focused on mRNAs targeted for nonsense-mediated mRNA decay (NMD), which we showed are generally bound by FMRP and destabilized upon FMRP loss. Here, we identify &amp;gt;400 high-confidence FMRP-bound mRNAs, only ∼35% of which are NMD targets. Integrative transcriptomics together with SILAC-LC-MS/MS reveal that FMRP loss generally results in mRNA destabilization and more protein produced per FMRP target. We use our established RIP-seq technology to show that FMRP footprints are independent of protein-coding potential, target GC-rich and structured sequences, and are densest in 5&amp;rsquo; UTRs. Regardless of where within an mRNA FMRP binds, we find that FMRP protects mRNAs from deadenylation and directly binds the cytoplasmic poly(A)-binding protein. Our results reveal how FMRP sequesters polyadenylated mRNAs into stabilized and translationally repressed complexes, whose regulation is critical for neurogenesis and synaptic plasticity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The intestinal barrier in disorders of the central nervous system</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/36334596/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/36334596/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The intestinal barrier, which primarily consists of a mucus layer, an epithelial barrier, and a gut vascular barrier, has a crucial role in health and disease by facilitating nutrient absorption and preventing the entry of pathogens. The intestinal barrier is in close contact with gut microbiota on its luminal side and with enteric neurons and glial cells on its tissue side. Mounting evidence now suggests that the intestinal barrier is compromised not only in digestive disorders, but also in disorders of the central nervous system (CNS), such as Parkinson&amp;rsquo;s disease, autism spectrum disorder, depression, multiple sclerosis, and Alzheimer&amp;rsquo;s disease. After providing an overview of the structure and functions of the intestinal barrier, we review existing preclinical and clinical studies supporting the notion that intestinal barrier dysfunction is present in neurological, neurodevelopmental, and psychiatric disorders. On the basis of this evidence, we discuss the mechanisms that possibly link gut barrier dysfunction and CNS disorders and the potential impact that evaluating enteric barriers in brain disorders could have on clinical practice, in terms of novel diagnostic and therapeutic strategies, in the near future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integrated proteogenomic characterization across major histological types of pituitary neuroendocrine tumors</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36307579/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36307579/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pituitary neuroendocrine tumor (PitNET) is one of the most common intracranial tumors. Due to its extensive tumor heterogeneity and the lack of high-quality tissues for biomarker discovery, the causative molecular mechanisms are far from being fully defined. Therefore, more studies are needed to improve the current clinicopathological classification system, and advanced treatment strategies such as targeted therapy and immunotherapy are yet to be explored. Here, we performed the largest integrative genomics, transcriptomics, proteomics, and phosphoproteomics analysis reported to date for a cohort of 200 PitNET patients. Genomics data indicate that GNAS copy number gain can serve as a reliable diagnostic marker for hyperproliferation of the PIT1 lineage. Proteomics-based classification of PitNETs identified 7 clusters, among which, tumors overexpressing epithelial-mesenchymal transition (EMT) markers clustered into a more invasive subgroup. Further analysis identified potential therapeutic targets, including CDK6, TWIST1, EGFR, and VEGFR2, for different clusters. Immune subtyping to explore the potential for application of immunotherapy in PitNET identified an association between alterations in the JAK1-STAT1-PDL1 axis and immune exhaustion, and between changes in the JAK3-STAT6-FOS/JUN axis and immune infiltration. These identified molecular markers and alternations in various clusters/subtypes were further confirmed in an independent cohort of 750 PitNET patients. This proteogenomic analysis across traditional histological boundaries improves our current understanding of PitNET pathophysiology and suggests novel therapeutic targets and strategies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Identification and validation of an anoikis-associated gene signature to predict clinical character, stemness, IDH mutation, and immune filtration in glioblastoma</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36091049/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36091049/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Glioblastoma (GBM) is the most prominent and aggressive primary brain tumor in adults. Anoikis is a specific form of programmed cell death that plays a key role in tumor invasion and metastasis. The presence of anti-anoikis factors is associated with tumor aggressiveness and drug resistance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; The non-negative matrix factorization algorithm was used for effective dimension reduction for integrated datasets. Differences in the tumor microenvironment (TME), stemness indices, and clinical characteristics between the two clusters were analyzed. Difference analysis, weighted gene coexpression network analysis (WGCNA), univariate Cox regression, and least absolute shrinkage and selection operator regression were leveraged to screen prognosis-related genes and construct a risk score model. Immunohistochemistry was performed to evaluate the expression of representative genes in clinical specimens. The relationship between the risk score and the TME, stemness, clinical traits, and immunotherapy response was assessed in GBM and pancancer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; Two definite clusters were identified on the basis of anoikis-related gene expression. Patients with GBM assigned to C1 were characterized by shortened overall survival, higher suppressive immune infiltration levels, and lower stemness indices. We further constructed a risk scoring model to quantify the regulatory patterns of anoikis-related genes. The higher risk score group was characterized by a poor prognosis, the infiltration of suppressive immune cells and a differentiated phenotype, whereas the lower risk score group exhibited the opposite effects. In addition, patients in the lower risk score group exhibited a higher frequency of isocitrate dehydrogenase (IDH) mutations and a more sensitive response to immunotherapy. Drug sensitivity analysis was performed, revealing that the higher risk group may benefit more from drugs targeting the PI3K/mTOR signaling pathway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/em&gt; We revealed potential relationships between anoikis-related genes and clinical features, TME, stemness, IDH mutation, and immunotherapy and elucidated their therapeutic value.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A novel circular RNA, circIgfbp2, links neural plasticity and anxiety through targeting mitochondrial dysfunction and oxidative stress-induced synapse dysfunction after traumatic brain injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35918398/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35918398/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Traumatic brain injury (TBI) can lead to different neurological and psychiatric disorders. Circular RNAs (circRNAs) are highly expressed in the nervous system and enriched in synapses; yet, the underlying role and mechanisms of circRNAs in neurological impairment and dysfunction are still not fully understood. In this study, we investigated the expression of circRNAs and their relation with neurological dysfunction after TBI. RNA-Seq was used to detect differentially expressed circRNAs in injured brain tissue, revealing that circIgfbp2 was significantly increased. Up-regulated hsa_circ_0058195, which was highly homologous to circIgfbp2, was further confirmed in the cerebral cortex specimens and serum samples of patients after TBI. Moreover, correlation analysis showed a positive correlation between hsa_circ_0058195 levels and the Self-Rating Anxiety Scale scores in these subjects. Furthermore, knockdown of circIgfbp2 in mice relieved anxiety-like behaviors and sleep disturbances induced by TBI. Knockdown of circIgfbp2 in H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; treated HT22 cells alleviated mitochondrial dysfunction, while its overexpression reversed the process. Mechanistically, we discovered that circIgfbp2 targets miR-370-3p to regulate BACH1, and down-regulating BACH1 alleviated mitochondrial dysfunction and oxidative stress-induced synapse dysfunction. In conclusion, inhibition of circIgfbp2 alleviated mitochondrial dysfunction and oxidative stress-induced synapse dysfunction after TBI through the miR-370-3p/BACH1/HO-1 axis. Thus, circIgfbp2 might be a novel therapeutic target for anxiety and sleep disorders after TBI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dedifferentiated Schwann cell-derived TGF-β3 is essential for the neural system to promote wound healing</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35910794/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35910794/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rationale:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wound healing is among the most complicated physiological processes and requires the synchronization of various cell types with distinct roles to re-establish the condition of the original skin. Patients affected by peripheral neuropathies often experience failure to heal. Loss of Schwann cells (SCs), a crucial population of peripheral nervous system cells in skin, may contribute to chronic wounds. However, the role of SCs in wound healing are poorly understood.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Methods:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The activity of SCs was investigated by using a cell atlas of the wound healing process, which was generated by integrating single-cell RNA sequencing (scRNA-seq) libraries covering different states of mouse back skin. The results of in silico analysis were validated by in vitro cell culture and in vivo mouse model. Selective inhibitors and conditional RNAi by virus transfection were utilized to investigate the role of SCs in wound healing. Findings from mouse experiments were further verified in scRNA-seq analysis of diabetic patients.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Results:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our in silico analysis revealed the heterogeneous cellular components of skin and the dynamic interactions of neural crest derived cells (NCs) with other cell types. We found that SCs dedifferentiated at an early stage of wound repair with upregulated Wnt signaling. We also identified dedifferentiated SC (dSC) defect in diabetic wounds in both mouse and human. Wnt inhibition at the wound site repressed SC dedifferentiation, leading to defective repair. Furthermore, dSCs derived TGF-β3, which is context-dependent, promoted the migration of fibroblasts and keratinocytes. Moreover, TGF-β3 supplementation enhanced the healing of chronic wounds in diabetic mice with impaired SCs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our study thus advances the understanding of the roles of neural-derived cells in skin regeneration and suggests a potential therapeutic strategy for wound healing disorders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SHF Acts as a Novel Tumor Suppressor in Glioblastoma Multiforme by Disrupting STAT3 Dimerization</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35843865/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35843865/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sustained activation of signal transducer and activator of transcription 3 (STAT3) is a critical contributor in tumorigenesis and chemoresistance, thus making it an attractive cancer therapeutic target. Here, SH2 domain-containing adapter protein F (SHF) is identified as a tumor suppressor in glioblastoma Multiforme (GBM) and its negative regulation of STAT3 activity is characterized. Mechanically, SHF selectively binds and inhibits acetylated STAT3 dimerization without affecting STAT3 phosphorylation or acetylation. Additionally, by blocking STAT3-DNMT1 (DNA Methyltransferase 1) interaction, SHF relieves methylation of tumor suppressor genes. The SH2 domain is documented to be essential for SHF&amp;rsquo;s actions on STAT3, and almost entirely replaces the functions of SHF on STAT3 independently. Moreover, the peptide C16 a peptide derived from the STAT3-binding sites of SHF inhibits STAT3 dimerization and STAT3/DNMT1 interaction, and achieves remarkable growth inhibition in GBM cells in vitro and in vivo. These findings strongly identify targeting of the SHF/STAT3 interaction as a promising strategy for developing an optimal STAT3 inhibitor and provide early evidence of the potential clinical efficacy of STAT3 inhibitors such as C16 in GBM.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sound induces analgesia through corticothalamic circuits</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35857536/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35857536/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sound-including music and noise-can relieve pain in humans, but the underlying neural mechanisms remain unknown. We discovered that analgesic effects of sound depended on a low (5-decibel) signal-to-noise ratio (SNR) relative to ambient noise in mice. Viral tracing, microendoscopic calcium imaging, and multitetrode recordings in freely moving mice showed that low-SNR sounds inhibited glutamatergic inputs from the auditory cortex (ACx&lt;sup&gt;Glu&lt;/sup&gt;) to the thalamic posterior (PO) and ventral posterior (VP) nuclei. Optogenetic or chemogenetic inhibition of the ACx&lt;sup&gt;Glu&lt;/sup&gt;→PO and ACx&lt;sup&gt;Glu&lt;/sup&gt;→VP circuits mimicked the low-SNR sound-induced analgesia in inflamed hindpaws and forepaws, respectively. Artificial activation of these two circuits abolished the sound-induced analgesia. Our study reveals the corticothalamic circuits underlying sound-promoted analgesia by deciphering the role of the auditory system in pain processing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conservation and divergence of cortical cell organization in human and mouse revealed by MERFISH</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35771910/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35771910/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The human cerebral cortex has tremendous cellular diversity. How different cell types are organized in the human cortex and how cellular organization varies across species remain unclear. In this study, we performed spatially resolved single-cell profiling of 4000 genes using multiplexed error-robust fluorescence in situ hybridization (MERFISH), identified more than 100 transcriptionally distinct cell populations, and generated a molecularly defined and spatially resolved cell atlas of the human middle and superior temporal gyrus. We further explored cell-cell interactions arising from soma contact or proximity in a cell type-specific manner. Comparison of the human and mouse cortices showed conservation in the laminar organization of cells and differences in somatic interactions across species. Our data revealed human-specific cell-cell proximity patterns and a markedly increased enrichment for interactions between neurons and non-neuronal cells in the human cortex.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Activated Drp1 regulates p62-mediated autophagic flux and aggravates inflammation in cerebral ischemia-reperfusion via the ROS-RIP1/RIP3-exosome axis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35624495/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35624495/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Cerebral ischemia-reperfusion injury (CIRI) refers to a secondary brain injury that can occur when the blood supply to the ischemic brain tissue is restored. However, the mechanism underlying such injury remains elusive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; The 150 male C57 mice underwent middle cerebral artery occlusion (MCAO) for 1 h and reperfusion for 24 h, Among them, 50 MCAO mice were further treated with Mitochondrial division inhibitor 1 (Mdivi-1) and 50 MCAO mice were further treated with N-acetylcysteine (NAC). SH-SY5Y cells were cultured in a low-glucose culture medium for 4 h under hypoxic conditions and then transferred to normal conditions for 12 h. Then, cerebral blood flow, mitochondrial structure, mitochondrial DNA (mtDNA) copy number, intracellular and mitochondrial reactive oxygen species (ROS), autophagic flux, aggresome and exosome expression profiles, cardiac tissue structure, mitochondrial length and cristae density, mtDNA and ROS content, as well as the expression of Drp1-Ser616/Drp1, RIP1/RIP3, LC3 II/LC3 I, TNF-α, IL-1β, etc., were detected under normal or Drp1 interference conditions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; The mtDNA content, ROS levels, and Drp1-Ser616/Drp1 were elevated by 2.2, 1.7 and 2.7 times after CIRI (&lt;em&gt;P&lt;/em&gt; &amp;lt; 0.05). However, the high cytoplasmic LC3 II/I ratio and increased aggregation of p62 could be reversed by 44% and 88% by Drp1 short hairpin RNA (shRNA) (&lt;em&gt;P&lt;/em&gt; &amp;lt; 0.05). The low fluorescence intensity of autophagic flux and the increased phosphorylation of RIP3 induced by CIRI could be attenuated by ROS scavenger, NAC (&lt;em&gt;P&lt;/em&gt; &amp;lt; 0.05). RIP1/RIP3 inhibitor Necrostatin-1 (Nec-1) restored 75% to a low LC3 II/LC3 I ratio and enhanced 2 times to a high RFP-LC3 after Drp1 activation (&lt;em&gt;P&lt;/em&gt; &amp;lt; 0.05). In addition, although CIRI-induced ROS production caused no considerable accumulation of autophagosomes (&lt;em&gt;P&lt;/em&gt; &amp;gt; 0.05), it increased the packaging and extracellular secretion of exosomes containing p62 by 4 - 5 times, which could be decreased by Mdivi-1, Drp1 shRNA, and Nec-1 (&lt;em&gt;P&lt;/em&gt; &amp;lt; 0.05). Furthermore, TNF-α and IL-1β increased in CIRI-derived exosomes could increase RIP3 phosphorylation in normal or oxygen-glucose deprivation/reoxygenation (OGD/R) conditions (&lt;em&gt;P&lt;/em&gt; &amp;lt; 0.05).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; CIRI activated Drp1 and accelerated the p62-mediated formation of autophagosomes while inhibiting the transition of autophagosomes to autolysosomes via the RIP1/RIP3 pathway activation. Undegraded autophagosomes were secreted extracellularly in the form of exosomes, leading to inflammatory cascades that further damaged mitochondria, resulting in excessive ROS generation and the blockage of autophagosome degradation, triggering a vicious cycle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lighting Up Neural Circuits by Viral Tracing</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/35578093/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/35578093/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Neurons are highly interwoven to form intricate neural circuits that underlie the diverse functions of the brain. Dissecting the anatomical organization of neural circuits is key to deciphering how the brain processes information, produces thoughts, and instructs behaviors. Over the past decades, recombinant viral vectors have become the most commonly used tracing tools to define circuit architecture. In this review, we introduce the current categories of viral tools and their proper application in circuit tracing. We further discuss some advances in viral tracing strategy and prospective innovations of viral tools for future study.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PAAN/MIF nuclease inhibition prevents neurodegeneration in Parkinson&#39;s disease</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35545089/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35545089/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Parthanatos-associated apoptosis-inducing factor (AIF) nuclease (PAAN), also known as macrophage migration inhibitor factor (MIF), is a member of the PD-D/E(X)K nucleases that acts as a final executioner in parthanatos. PAAN&amp;rsquo;s role in Parkinson&amp;rsquo;s disease (PD) and whether it is amenable to chemical inhibition is not known. Here, we show that neurodegeneration induced by pathologic α-synuclein (α-syn) occurs via PAAN/MIF nuclease activity. Genetic depletion of PAAN/MIF and a mutant lacking nuclease activity prevent the loss of dopaminergic neurons and behavioral deficits in the α-syn preformed fibril (PFF) mouse model of sporadic PD. Compound screening led to the identification of PAANIB-1, a brain-penetrant PAAN/MIF nuclease inhibitor that prevents neurodegeneration induced by α-syn PFF, AAV-α-syn overexpression, or MPTP intoxication in vivo. Our findings could have broad relevance in human pathologies where parthanatos plays a role in the development of cell death inhibitors targeting the druggable PAAN/MIF nuclease.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A High-Efficiency AAV for Endothelial Cell Transduction Throughout the Central Nervous System</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35571675/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35571675/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Endothelial cells have a crucial role in nervous system function, and mounting evidence points to endothelial impairment as a major contributor to a wide range of neurological diseases. However, tools to genetically interrogate these cells in vivo remain limited. Here, we describe AAV-BI30, a capsid that specifically and efficiently transduces endothelial cells throughout the central nervous system. At relatively low systemic doses, this vector transduces the majority of arterial, capillary, and venous endothelial cells in the brain, retina, and spinal cord vasculature of adult C57BL/6 mice. Furthermore, we show that AAV-BI30 robustly transduces endothelial cells in multiple mouse strains and rats in vivo and human brain microvascular endothelial cells in vitro. Finally, we demonstrate AAV-BI30&amp;rsquo;s capacity to achieve efficient and endothelial-specific Cre-mediated gene manipulation in the central nervous system. This combination of attributes makes AAV-BI30 uniquely well-suited to address outstanding research questions in neurovascular biology and aid the development of therapeutics to remediate endothelial dysfunction in disease.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Positive feedback regulation of microglial glucose metabolism by histone H4 lysine 12 lactylation in Alzheimer&#39;s disease</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35303422/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35303422/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Histone lactylation is elevated in the brains of 5XFAD model mice and AD patients&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;H4K12la activates transcription of glycolytic genes in AD microglia&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A glycolysis/H4K12la/PKM2 positive feedback loop exacerbates microglial dysfunction&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interruption of this loop ameliorates microglial dysfunction and Aβ pathology&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The pro-inflammatory activation of microglia is a hallmark of Alzheimer&amp;rsquo;s disease (AD), and this process involves a switch from oxidative phosphorylation (OXPHOS) toward glycolysis. Here, we show how a positive feedback loop in microglia drives AD pathogenesis, and we demonstrate that inhibiting this cycle in microglia can ameliorate Aβ burden and cognitive deficits in an AD mouse model (5XFAD). After first detecting elevated histone lactylation in brain samples from both 5XFAD mice and individuals with AD, we observed that H4K12la levels are elevated in Aβ plaque-adjacent microglia. This lactate-dependent histone modification is enriched at the promoters of glycolytic genes and activates transcription, thereby increasing glycolytic activity. Ultimately, the glycolysis/H4K12la/PKM2 positive feedback loop exacerbates microglial dysfunction in AD. Pharmacologic inhibition of PKM2 attenuated microglial activation, and microglia-specific ablation of Pkm2 improved spatial learning and memory in AD mice. Thus, our study illustrates that disruption of the positive feedback loop may be a potential therapeutic approach for the treatment of AD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IFNγ and GM-CSF control complementary differentiation programs in the monocyte-to-phagocyte transition during neuroinflammation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35102344/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35102344/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During inflammation, Ly6C&lt;sup&gt;hi&lt;/sup&gt; monocytes are rapidly mobilized from the bone marrow (BM) and are recruited into inflamed tissues, where they undergo monocyte-to-phagocyte transition (MTPT). The in vivo developmental trajectories of the MTPT and the contribution of individual cytokines to this process remain unclear. Here, we used a murine model of neuroinflammation to investigate how granulocyte–macrophage colony-stimulating factor (GM-CSF) and interferon-γ (IFNγ), two type 1 cytokines, controlled MTPT. Using genetic fate mapping, gene targeting and high-dimensional single-cell multiomics analyses, we found that IFNγ was essential for the gradual acquisition of a mature inflammatory phagocyte phenotype in Ly6C&lt;sup&gt;hi&lt;/sup&gt; monocytes, while GM-CSF was required to license interleukin-1β (IL-1β) production, phagocytosis and oxidative burst. These results suggest that the proinflammatory cytokine environment guided MTPT trajectories in the inflamed central nervous system (CNS) and indicated that GM-CSF was the most prominent target for the disarming of monocyte progenies during neuroinflammation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multi-omics of human plasma reveals molecular features of dysregulated inflammation and accelerated aging in schizophrenia</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34741130/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34741130/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therapeutics that discriminate between the genetic makeup of normal cells and tumour cells are valuable for treating and understanding cancer. Small molecules with oncogene-selective lethality may reveal novel functions of oncoproteins and enable the creation of more selective drugs. Here we describe the mechanism of action of the selective anti-tumour agent erastin, involving the RAS-RAF-MEK signalling pathway functioning in cell proliferation, differentiation and survival. Erastin exhibits greater lethality in human tumour cells harbouring mutations in the oncogenes HRAS, KRAS or BRAF. Using affinity purification and mass spectrometry, we discovered that erastin acts through mitochondrial voltage-dependent anion channels (VDACs)&amp;ndash;a novel target for anti-cancer drugs. We show that erastin treatment of cells harbouring oncogenic RAS causes the appearance of oxidative species and subsequent death through an oxidative, non-apoptotic mechanism. RNA-interference-mediated knockdown of VDAC2 or VDAC3 caused resistance to erastin, implicating these two VDAC isoforms in the mechanism of action of erastin. Moreover, using purified mitochondria expressing a single VDAC isoform, we found that erastin alters the permeability of the outer mitochondrial membrane. Finally, using a radiolabelled analogue and a filter-binding assay, we show that erastin binds directly to VDAC2. These results demonstrate that ligands to VDAC proteins can induce non-apoptotic cell death selectively in some tumour cells harbouring activating mutations in the RAS-RAF-MEK pathway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Long noncoding RNA BS-DRL1 modulates the DNA damage response and genome stability by interacting with HMGB1 in neurons</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34210972/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34210972/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Long noncoding RNAs (lncRNAs) are known to regulate DNA damage response (DDR) and genome stability in proliferative cells. However, it remains unknown whether lncRNAs are involved in these vital biological processes in post-mitotic neurons. Here, we report and characterize a lncRNA, termed Brain Specific DNA-damage Related lncRNA1 (BS-DRL1), in the central nervous system. BS-DRL1 is a brain-specific lncRNA and depletion of BS-DRL1 in neurons leads to impaired DDR upon etoposide treatment in vitro. Mechanistically, BS-DRL1 interacts with HMGB1, a chromatin protein that is important for genome stability, and is essential for the assembly of HMGB1 on chromatin. BS-DRL1 mediated DDR exhibits cell-type specificity in the cortex and cerebellum in gamma-irradiated mice and BS-DRL1 knockout mice show impaired motor function and concomitant purkinje cell degeneration. Our study extends the understanding of lncRNAs in DDR and genome stability and implies a protective role of lncRNA against neurodegeneration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Genome-wide CRISPRi/a screens in human neurons link lysosomal failure to ferroptosis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34031600/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34031600/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Single-cell transcriptomics provide a systematic map of gene expression in different human cell types. The next challenge is to systematically understand cell-type-specific gene function. The integration of CRISPR-based functional genomics and stem cell technology enables the scalable interrogation of gene function in differentiated human cells. Here we present the first genome-wide CRISPR interference and CRISPR activation screens in human neurons. We uncover pathways controlling neuronal response to chronic oxidative stress, which is implicated in neurodegenerative diseases. Unexpectedly, knockdown of the lysosomal protein prosaposin strongly sensitizes neurons, but not other cell types, to oxidative stress by triggering the formation of lipofuscin, a hallmark of aging, which traps iron, generating reactive oxygen species and triggering ferroptosis. We also determine transcriptomic changes in neurons after perturbation of genes linked to neurodegenerative diseases. To enable the systematic comparison of gene function across different human cell types, we establish a data commons named &lt;a href=&#34;https://crisprbrain.org&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CRISPRbrain&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://crisprbrain.org&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CRISPRbrain&lt;/a&gt; is a data commons organizing results from genetic screens for different phenotypes in different human cell types, by different research groups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aagab acts as a novel regulator of NEDD4-1-mediated Pten nuclear translocation to promote neurological recovery following hypoxic-ischemic brain damage</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33712741/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33712741/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hypoxic-ischemic encephalopathy (HIE) is a main cause of mortality and severe neurologic impairment in the perinatal and neonatal period. However, few satisfactory therapeutic strategies are available. Here, we reported that a rapid nuclear translocation of phosphatase and tensin homolog deleted on chromosome TEN (PTEN) is an essential step in hypoxic-ischemic brain damage (HIBD)- and oxygen-glucose deprivation (OGD)-induced neuronal injures both in vivo and in vitro. In addition, we found that OGD-induced nuclear translocation of PTEN is dependent on PTEN mono-ubiquitination at the lysine 13 residue (K13) that is mediated by neural precursor cell expressed developmentally downregulated protein 4-1 (NEDD4-1). Importantly, we for the first time identified α- and γ-adaptin binding protein (Aagab) as a novel NEDD4-1 regulator to regulate the level of NEDD4-1, subsequently mediating Pten nuclear translocation. Finally, we demonstrated that genetic upregulation of Aagab or application of Tat-K13 peptide (a short interference peptide that flanks K13 residue of PTEN) not only reduced Pten nuclear translocation, but also significantly alleviated the deficits of myodynamia, motor and spatial learning and memory in HIBD model rats. These results suggest that Aagab may serve as a regulator of NEDD4-1-mediated Pten nuclear translocation to promote functional recovery following HIBD in neonatal rats, and provide a new potential therapeutic target to guide the clinical treatment for HIE.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Viral Vectors for Neural Circuit Mapping and Recent Advances in Trans-synaptic Anterograde Tracers</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/32755550/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/32755550/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Viral tracers are important tools for neuroanatomical mapping and genetic payload delivery. Genetically modified viruses allow for cell-type-specific targeting and overcome many limitations of non-viral tracers. Here, we summarize the viruses that have been developed for neural circuit mapping, and we provide a primer on currently applied anterograde and retrograde viral tracers with practical guidance on experimental uses. We also discuss and highlight key technical and conceptual considerations for developing new safer and more effective anterograde trans-synaptic viral vectors for neural circuit analysis in multiple species.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paraventricular hypothalamus mediates diurnal rhythm of metabolism</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32732906/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32732906/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Defective rhythmic metabolism is associated with high-fat high-caloric diet (HFD) feeding, ageing and obesity; however, the neural basis underlying HFD effects on diurnal metabolism remains elusive. Here we show that deletion of BMAL1, a core clock gene, in paraventricular hypothalamic (PVH) neurons reduces diurnal rhythmicity in metabolism, causes obesity and diminishes PVH neuron activation in response to fast-refeeding. Animal models mimicking deficiency in PVH neuron responsiveness, achieved through clamping PVH neuron activity at high or low levels, both show obesity and reduced diurnal rhythmicity in metabolism. Interestingly, the PVH exhibits BMAL1-controlled rhythmic expression of GABA-A receptor γ2 subunit, and dampening rhythmicity of GABAergic input to the PVH reduces diurnal rhythmicity in metabolism and causes obesity. Finally, BMAL1 deletion blunts PVH neuron responses to external stressors, an effect mimicked by HFD feeding. Thus, BMAL1-driven PVH neuron responsiveness in dynamic activity changes involving rhythmic GABAergic neurotransmission mediates diurnal rhythmicity in metabolism and is implicated in diet-induced obesity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CircGRIA1 shows an age-related increase in male macaque brain and regulates synaptic plasticity and synaptogenesis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32681011/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32681011/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Circular RNAs (circRNAs) are abundant in mammalian brain and some show age-dependent expression patterns. Here, we report that circGRIA1, a conserved circRNA isoform derived from the genomic loci of α-mino-3-hydroxy-5-methyl-4-isoxazole propionic acid (AMPA) receptor subunit Gria1, shows an age-related and male-specific increase in expression in the rhesus macaque prefrontal cortex and hippocampus. We show circGRIA1 is predominantly localized to the nucleus, and find an age-related increase in its association with the promoter region of Gria1 gene, suggesting it has a regulatory role in Gria1 transcription. In vitro and in vivo manipulation of circGRIA1 negatively regulates Gria1 mRNA and protein levels. Knockdown of circGRIA1 results in an age-related improvement of synaptogenesis, and GluR1 activity-dependent synaptic plasticity in the hippocampal neurons in males. Our findings underscore the importance of circRNA regulation and offer an insight into the biology of brain aging.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visualizing and Modulating Mitophagy for Therapeutic Studies of Neurodegeneration</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32437660/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32437660/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dysfunctional mitochondria accumulate in many human diseases. Accordingly, mitophagy, which removes these mitochondria through lysosomal degradation, is attracting broad attention. Due to uncertainties in the operational principles of conventional mitophagy probes, however, the specificity and quantitativeness of their readouts are disputable. Thorough investigation of the behaviors and fates of fluorescent proteins inside and outside lysosomes enabled us to develop an indicator for mitophagy, mito-SRAI. Through strict control of its mitochondrial targeting, we were able to monitor mitophagy in fixed biological samples more reproducibly than before. Large-scale image-based high-throughput screening led to the discovery of a hit compound that induces selective mitophagy of damaged mitochondria. In a mouse model of Parkinsons disease, we found that dopaminergic neurons selectively failed to execute mitophagy that promoted their survival within lesions. These results show that mito-SRAI is an essential tool for quantitative studies of mitochondrial quality control.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Highly Conserved Circular RNA Is Required to Keep Neural Cells in a Progenitor State in the Mammalian Brain</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32075758/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32075758/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;circSLC45A4 is the main RNA splice isoform produced from its genetic locus and one of the highest expressed circRNAs in the developing human frontal cortex. Knockdown of this highly conserved circRNA in a human neuroblastoma cell line is sufficient to induce spontaneous neuronal differentiation, measurable by increased expression of neuronal marker genes. Depletion of circSlc45a4 in the developing mouse cortex causes a significant reduction of the basal progenitor pool and increases the expression of neurogenic regulators. Furthermore, knockdown of circSlc45a4a induces a significant depletion of cells in the cortical plate. In addition, deconvolution of the bulk RNA-seq data with the help of single-cell RNA-seq data validates the depletion of basal progenitors and reveals an increase in Cajal-Retzius cells. In summary, we present a detailed study of a highly conserved circular RNA that is necessary to maintain the pool of neural progenitors &lt;em&gt;in vitro&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cell-Surface Proteomic Profiling in the Fly Brain Uncovers Wiring Regulators</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/31955847/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/31955847/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Molecular interactions at the cellular interface mediate organized assembly of single cells into tissues and, thus, govern the development and physiology of multicellular organisms. Here, we developed a cell-type-specific, spatiotemporally resolved approach to profile cell-surface proteomes in intact tissues. Quantitative profiling of cell-surface proteomes of Drosophila olfactory projection neurons (PNs) in pupae and adults revealed global downregulation of wiring molecules and upregulation of synaptic molecules in the transition from developing to mature PNs. A proteome-instructed in vivo screen identified 20 cell-surface molecules regulating neural circuit assembly, many of which belong to evolutionarily conserved protein families not previously linked to neural development. Genetic analysis further revealed that the lipoprotein receptor LRP1 cell-autonomously controls PN dendrite targeting, contributing to the formation of a precise olfactory map. These findings highlight the power of temporally resolved in situ cell-surface proteomic profiling in discovering regulators of brain wiring.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VEGF-C-driven lymphatic drainage enables immunosurveillance of brain tumours</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/31942068/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/31942068/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Erratum in:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Publisher Correction: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-021-03204-z&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;VEGF-C-driven lymphatic drainage enables immunosurveillance of brain tumours&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Immune surveillance against pathogens and tumours in the central nervous system is thought to be limited owing to the lack of lymphatic drainage. However, the characterization of the meningeal lymphatic network has shed light on previously unappreciated ways that an immune response can be elicited to antigens that are expressed in the brain1-3. Despite progress in our understanding of the development and structure of the meningeal lymphatic system, the contribution of this network in evoking a protective antigen-specific immune response in the brain remains unclear. Here, using a mouse model of glioblastoma, we show that the meningeal lymphatic vasculature can be manipulated to mount better immune responses against brain tumours. The immunity that is mediated by CD8 T cells to the glioblastoma antigen is very limited when the tumour is confined to the central nervous system, resulting in uncontrolled tumour growth. However, ectopic expression of vascular endothelial growth factor C (VEGF-C) promotes enhanced priming of CD8 T cells in the draining deep cervical lymph nodes, migration of CD8 T cells into the tumour, rapid clearance of the glioblastoma and a long-lasting antitumour memory response. Furthermore, transfection of an mRNA construct that expresses VEGF-C works synergistically with checkpoint blockade therapy to eradicate existing glioblastoma. These results reveal the capacity of VEGF-C to promote immune surveillance of tumours, and suggest a new therapeutic approach to treat brain tumours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Developmental Heterogeneity of Microglia and Brain Myeloid Cells Revealed by Deep Single-Cell RNA Sequencing</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/30606613/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/30606613/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Microglia are increasingly recognized for their major contributions during brain development and neurodegenerative disease. It is currently unknown whether these functions are carried out by subsets of microglia during different stages of development and adulthood or within specific brain regions. Here, we performed deep single-cell RNA sequencing (scRNA-seq) of microglia and related myeloid cells sorted from various regions of embryonic, early postnatal, and adult mouse brains. We found that the majority of adult microglia expressing homeostatic genes are remarkably similar in transcriptomes, regardless of brain region. By contrast, early postnatal microglia are more heterogeneous. We discovered a proliferative-region-associated microglia (PAM) subset, mainly found in developing white matter, that shares a characteristic gene signature with degenerative disease-associated microglia (DAM). Such PAM have amoeboid morphology, are metabolically active, and phagocytose newly formed oligodendrocytes. This scRNA-seq atlas will be a valuable resource for dissecting innate immune functions in health and disease.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An oncolytic herpesvirus expressing E-cadherin improves survival in mouse models of glioblastoma</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/30475349/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/30475349/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The efficacy of oncolytic herpes simplex virus (oHSV) is limited by rapid viral clearance by innate immune effector cells and poor intratumoral viral spread. We combine two approaches to overcome these barriers: inhibition of natural killer (NK) cells and enhancement of intratumoral viral spread. We engineered an oHSV to express CDH1, encoding E-cadherin, an adherent molecule and a ligand for KLRG1, an inhibitory receptor expressed on NK cells. In vitro, infection with this engineered virus, named OV-CDH1, induced high surface E-cadherin expression on infected glioblastoma (GBM) cells, which typically lack endogenous E-cadherin. Ectopically expressed E-cadherin enhanced the spread of OV-CDH1 by facilitating cell-to-cell infection and viral entry and reduced viral clearance by selectively protecting OV-CDH1-infected cells from KLRG1+ NK cell killing. In vivo, OV-CDH1 treatment substantially prolonged the survival in GBM-bearing mouse models, primarily because of improved viral spread rather than inhibition of NK cell activity. Thus, virus-induced overexpression of E-cadherin may be a generalizable strategy for improving cancer virotherapy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rhythms of life: circadian disruption and brain disorders across the lifespan</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/30459365/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/30459365/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many processes in the human body — including brain function — are regulated over the 24-hour cycle, and there are strong associations between disrupted circadian rhythms (for example, sleep–wake cycles) and disorders of the CNS. Brain disorders such as autism, depression and Parkinson disease typically develop at certain stages of life, and circadian rhythms are important during each stage of life for the regulation of processes that may influence the development of these disorders. Here, we describe circadian disruptions observed in various brain disorders throughout the human lifespan and highlight emerging evidence suggesting these disruptions affect the brain. Currently, much of the evidence linking brain disorders and circadian dysfunction is correlational, and so whether and what kind of causal relationships might exist are unclear. We therefore identify remaining questions that may direct future research towards a better understanding of the links between circadian disruption and CNS disorders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Biallelic UFM1 and UFC1 mutations expand the essential role of ufmylation in brain development</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/29868776/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/29868776/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post-translational modification of proteins through the addition of UFM1, also known as ufmylation, plays a critical developmental role as revealed by studies in animal models. The recent finding that biallelic mutations in UBA5 (the E1-like enzyme for ufmylation) cause severe early-onset encephalopathy with progressive microcephaly implicates ufmylation in human brain development. More recently, a homozygous UFM1 variant was proposed as a candidate aetiology of severe early-onset encephalopathy with progressive microcephaly. Here, we establish a locus for severe early-onset encephalopathy with progressive microcephaly based on two families, and map the phenotype to a novel homozygous UFM1 mutation. This mutation has a significantly diminished capacity to form thioester intermediates with UBA5 and with UFC1 (the E2-like enzyme for ufmylation), with resulting impaired ufmylation of cellular proteins. Remarkably, in four additional families where eight children have severe early-onset encephalopathy with progressive microcephaly, we identified two biallelic UFC1 mutations, which impair UFM1-UFC1 intermediate formation with resulting widespread reduction of cellular ufmylation, a pattern similar to that observed with UFM1 mutation. The striking resemblance between UFM1- and UFC1-related clinical phenotype and biochemical derangements strongly argues for an essential role for ufmylation in human brain development. The hypomorphic nature of UFM1 and UFC1 mutations and the conspicuous depletion of biallelic null mutations in the components of this pathway in human genome databases suggest that it is necessary for embryonic survival, which is consistent with the embryonic lethal nature of knockout models for the orthologous genes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Network of Noncoding Regulatory RNAs Acts in the Mammalian Brain</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/29887379/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/29887379/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Noncoding RNAs (ncRNAs) play increasingly appreciated gene-regulatory roles. Here, we describe a regulatory network centered on four ncRNAs-a long ncRNA, a circular RNA, and two microRNAs-using gene editing in mice to probe the molecular consequences of disrupting key components of this network. The long ncRNA Cyrano uses an extensively paired site to miR-7 to trigger destruction of this microRNA. Cyrano-directed miR-7 degradation is much more effective than previously described examples of target-directed microRNA degradation, which come primarily from studies of artificial and viral RNAs. By reducing miR-7 levels, Cyrano prevents repression of miR-7-targeted mRNAs and enables accumulation of Cdr1as, a circular RNA known to regulate neuronal activity. Without Cyrano, excess miR-7 causes cytoplasmic destruction of Cdr1as in neurons, in part through enhanced slicing of Cdr1as by a second miRNA, miR-671. Thus, several types of ncRNAs can collaborate to establish a sophisticated regulatory network.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optogenetic and chemogenetic techniques for neurogastroenterology</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/29184183/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/29184183/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Optogenetics and chemogenetics comprise a wide variety of applications in which genetically encoded actuators and indicators are used to modulate and monitor activity with high cellular specificity. Over the past 10 years, development of these genetically encoded tools has contributed tremendously to our understanding of integrated physiology. In concert with the continued refinement of probes, strategies to target transgene expression to specific cell types have also made much progress in the past 20 years. In addition, the successful implementation of optogenetic and chemogenetic techniques thrives thanks to ongoing advances in live imaging microscopy and optical technology. Although innovation of optogenetic and chemogenetic methods has been primarily driven by researchers studying the central nervous system, these techniques also hold great promise to boost research in neurogastroenterology. In this Review, we describe the different classes of tools that are currently available and give an overview of the strategies to target them to specific cell types in the gut wall. We discuss the possibilities and limitations of optogenetic and chemogenetic technology in the gut and provide an overview of their current use, with a focus on the enteric nervous system. Furthermore, we suggest some experiments that can advance our understanding of how the intrinsic and extrinsic neural networks of the gut control gastrointestinal function.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Targeting neural reflex circuits in immunity to treat kidney disease</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/28970585/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/28970585/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Key Points&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Neural circuits that control immunity and inflammation provide novel targets for the treatment of kidney disease and hypertension&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Activation of the cholinergic anti-inflammatory pathway (CAP) blocks splenic-dependent systemic inflammation and acute kidney injury (AKI); non-invasive, nonpharmacological approaches to activate the CAP include ultrasound application and vagus nerve stimulation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Neural circuits that directly regulate kidney function or carry sensory feedback from the kidney to the central nervous system could provide additional mechanisms for bidirectional neuroimmunomodulation of kidney disease&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Interactions between neural circuits and the immune system have important roles in the pathogenesis of hypertension and renal fibrosis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Further defining neuroimmunomodulatory pathways in hypertension could enable the development of selective neuronal stimulatory or inhibitory strategies for lowering blood pressure that could potentially be more effective than renal denervation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Optogenetic tools provide unprecedented opportunities to dissect the neural pathways that control immunity and inflammation and enable the identification of novel approaches to therapy for kidney diseases&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Neural pathways regulate immunity and inflammation via the inflammatory reflex and specific molecular targets can be modulated by stimulating neurons. Neuroimmunomodulation by nonpharmacological methods is emerging as a novel therapeutic strategy for inflammatory diseases, including kidney diseases and hypertension. Electrical stimulation of vagus neurons or treatment with pulsed ultrasound activates the cholinergic anti-inflammatory pathway (CAP) and protects mice from acute kidney injury (AKI). Direct innervation of the kidney, by afferent and efferent neurons, might have a role in modulating and responding to inflammation in various diseases, either locally or by providing feedback to regions of the central nervous system that are important in the inflammatory reflex pathway. Increased sympathetic drive to the kidney has a role in the pathogenesis of hypertension, and selective modulation of neuroimmune interactions in the kidney could potentially be more effective for lowering blood pressure and treating inflammatory kidney diseases than renal denervation. Use of optogenetic tools for selective stimulation of specific neurons has enabled the identification of neural circuits in the brain that modulate kidney function via activation of the CAP. In this Review we discuss evidence for a role of neural circuits in the control of renal inflammation as well as the therapeutic potential of targeting these circuits in the settings of AKI, kidney fibrosis and hypertension.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
