<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Biomaterials | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/biomaterials/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/biomaterials/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Biomaterials</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Biomaterials</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/biomaterials/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Species-agnostic polymeric formulations for inhalable messenger RNA delivery to the lung</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36443576/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36443576/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Messenger RNA has now been used to vaccinate millions of people. However, the diversity of pulmonary pathologies, including infections, genetic disorders, asthma and others, reveals the lung as an important organ to directly target for future RNA therapeutics and preventatives. Here we report the screening of 166 polymeric nanoparticle formulations for functional delivery to the lungs, obtained from a combinatorial synthesis approach combined with a low-dead-volume nose-only inhalation system for mice. We identify P76, a poly-β-amino-thio-ester polymer, that exhibits increased expression over formulations lacking the thiol component, delivery to different animal species with varying RNA cargos and low toxicity. P76 allows for dose sparing when delivering an mRNA-expressed Cas13a-mediated treatment in a SARS-CoV-2 challenge model, resulting in similar efficacy to a 20-fold higher dose of a neutralizing antibody. Overall, the combinatorial synthesis approach allowed for the discovery of promising polymeric formulations for future RNA pharmaceutical development for the lungs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A multivalent nucleoside-modified mRNA vaccine against all known influenza virus subtypes</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36423275/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36423275/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seasonal influenza vaccines offer little protection against pandemic influenza virus strains. It is difficult to create effective prepandemic vaccines because it is uncertain which influenza virus subtype will cause the next pandemic. In this work, we developed a nucleoside-modified messenger RNA (mRNA)-lipid nanoparticle vaccine encoding hemagglutinin antigens from all 20 known influenza A virus subtypes and influenza B virus lineages. This multivalent vaccine elicited high levels of cross-reactive and subtype-specific antibodies in mice and ferrets that reacted to all 20 encoded antigens. Vaccination protected mice and ferrets challenged with matched and mismatched viral strains, and this protection was at least partially dependent on antibodies. Our studies indicate that mRNA vaccines can provide protection against antigenically variable viruses by simultaneously inducing antibodies against multiple antigens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A composite hydrogel containing resveratrol-laden nanoparticles and platelet-derived extracellular vesicles promotes wound healing in diabetic mice</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36309190/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36309190/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Diabetic wounds are difficult to heal because of persistent inflammation and limited angiogenesis. Resveratrol (RES) is an anti-inflammatory and antioxidant agent. Platelet-derived extracellular vesicles (PDEVs) are rich in growth factors and cytokines, which promote proliferation and angiogenesis. However, single drug treatment has limited efficacy and delivery efficiency. Bioengineering can improve the limited effect of single drugs by combining drugs and materials to obtain complementary or cooperative bioengineered drugs. In this study, gelatin methacrylate (GelMA) and silk fibroin glycidyl methacrylate (SFMA) were used to synthesize GelMA/SFMA composite hydrogels with suitable mechanical properties, swelling ratio and biodegradability. The composite hydrogel was used as a wound dressing for sustained drug release. RES was loaded into mesoporous silica nanoparticles (MSNs) to synthesize MSN-RES to enhance the release dynamic, and MSN-RES and PDEVs were combined with the composite hydrogels to form GelMA/SFMA/MSN-RES/PDEVs hydrogels. The GelMA/SFMA/MSN-RES/PDEVs had low cytotoxicity and good biocompatibility, inhibited macrophage iNOS expression, and promoted the tube formation by human umbilical vein endothelial cells (HUVECs) in vitro. In a diabetic mouse wound model, the GelMA/SFMA/MSN-RES/PDEVs hydrogels decreased the expression of pro-inflammatory factors TNF-α and iNOS, increased the expression of anti-inflammatory factors TGF-β1 and Arg-1, promoted angiogenesis, and accelerated wound healing. Interestingly, the GelMA/SFMA/MSN-RES/PDEVs hydrogels promoted the expression of extracellular purinergic signaling pathway-related CD73 and adenosine 2A receptor (A2A-R). Therefore, the GelMA/SFMA/MSN-RES/PDEVs hydrogels could be used as wound dressings to regulate the inflammation and angiogenesis of diabetic wounds and accelerate wound healing. STATEMENT OF SIGNIFICANCE: Drugs often fail to function because of a continuous oxidative stress microenvironment and inflammation. Here, a GelMA/SFMA hydrogel, with enhanced mechanical properties and liquid absorption ability, is proposed for sustained release of drugs. In addition to carrying platelet-derived extracellular vesicles (PDEVs) with pro-angiogenic effects, the hydrogels were also loaded with nanoparticle-encapsulated resveratrol with anti-inflammatory activities, aiming to reduce inflammation and oxidative stress in the wound microenvironment, such that the wound could receive proliferative repair signals to achieve sequential treatment and heal quickly. We also experimentally predicted that the regulatory mechanism of the GelMA/SFMA/MSN-RES/PDEVs in wound healing might be related to the extracellular purinergic signaling pathway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mesenchymal Stem Cell-Derived Extracellular Vesicles with High PD-L1 Expression for Autoimmune Diseases Treatment</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34613627/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34613627/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Autoimmune diseases are the third most common disease influencing the quality of life of many patients. Here, a programmed cell death-ligand 1 + (PD-L1) mesenchymal stem cell (MSC) derived extracellular vesicles (MSC-sEVs-PD-L1) using lentivirus-mediated gene transfection technology is developed for reconfiguration of the local immune microenvironment of affected tissue in autoimmune diseases. MSC-sEVs-PD-L1 exhibits an impressive ability to regulate various activated immune cells to an immunosuppressed state in vitro. More importantly, in dextran sulfate sodium-induced ulcerative colitis (UC) and imiquimod-induced psoriasis mouse models, a significantly high accumulation of MSC-sEVs-PD-L1 is observed in the inflamed tissues compared to the PD-L1+ MSCs. Therapeutic efficiency in both UC and psoriasis mouse disease models is demonstrated using MSC-sEVs-PD-L1 to reshape the inflammatory ecosystem in the local immune context. A technology is developed using MSC-sEVs-PD-L1 as a natural delivery platform for autoimmune diseases treatment with high clinical potential.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In situ gas foaming based on magnesium particle degradation: A novel approach to fabricate injectable macroporous hydrogels</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/31918223/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/31918223/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Injectable hydrogels are attractive biomaterials for cell delivery in tissue engineering. However, the in vivo viability of transplanted cells remains limited. Typically, macroporous structures constructed in hydrogels are utilized to enhance oxygen and nutrients diffusion for cell survival and to promote integration between the material and host tissue. A new gas-foaming method to generate pores was proposed by directly adding Mg particles into cell-laden hydrogel solutions, taking advantage of the H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; gas formed during the degradation of Mg. The optimization design of the size and amount of Mg particles added into the hydrogels was investigated. Improved cell viability and proliferation were demonstrated in the group with Mg particles. Additionally, Mg&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt; ions generated during Mg degradation facilitated the osteogenic differentiation of stem cells encapsulated in hydrogels. Extensive vascularized bone regeneration in the femoral defects of rats revealed that the use of Mg particles as the foaming agent is feasible, endowing injectable hydrogels with optimized porosity and enhanced bioactivity, and providing a new strategy for future designs of porous hydrogels in tissue engineering.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
