<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Biomaterials | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/biomaterials/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/biomaterials/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Biomaterials</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Biomaterials</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/biomaterials/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cationic phosphorus dendron nanomicelles deliver microRNA mimics and microRNA inhibitors for enhanced anti-inflammatory therapy of acute lung injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36607143/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36607143/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The development of efficient nanomedicines to repress the repolarization of M1 phenotype macrophages and therefore inhibit pro-inflammatory cytokine overexpression for anti-inflammatory therapy is still a challenging task. We report here an original gene delivery nanoplatform based on pyrrolidinium-modified amphiphilic generation 1 phosphorus dendron (C12G1) nanomicelles with a rigid phosphorous dendron structure. The nanomicelles display higher gene delivery efficiency than the counterpart materials of pyrrolidinium-modified G1 phosphorus dendrimers, and meanwhile exhibit excellent cytocompatibility. The C12G1 nanomicelles can be employed to co-deliver the miRNA-146a mimic (miR-146a mimic) and miRNA-429 inhibitor (miR-429i) to inhibit the Toll-like receptor-4 signaling pathway and p38 mitogen-activated protein kinase signaling pathway, respectively, thus causing repression of M1 phenotype alveolar macrophage polarization. The developed C12G1/miR-mixture polyplexes enable efficient therapy of lipopolysaccharide-activated alveolar macrophages &lt;em&gt;in vitro&lt;/em&gt; and an acute lung injury mouse model &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt;. The generated cationic phosphorus dendron nanomicelles may hold promising potential for anti-inflammatory gene therapy of other inflammatory diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bionic artificial penile Tunica albuginea</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/matt.2022.11.032/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/matt.2022.11.032/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A method for preparing hydrogels with parallel wavy fibers was developed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ATA with a bionic double-layer structure was prepared&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ATA has bionic mechanical properties and biocompatibility and can repair TA injury&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This approach could provide a common platform for future tissue analog preparations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The mammalian tunica albuginea (TA) is characterized by a double-layer orthogonal structure composed of stacked parallel wavy collagen fibers. During an erection, these fibers undergo sequential straightening and stretching to mediate the soft-to-firm transition. Inspired by the delicate strain-adaptive structure of natural TA, we propose an artificial TA (ATA) composed of a strain-stiffening hydrogel consisting of aligned yet crimped fibers. This delicate structure is produced via the stretching of an isotropic polyvinyl alcohol gel followed by covalent cross-linking. ATA possesses several key mechanical features of natural TA, including rapid strain stiffening over small intervals of deformation, excellent fatigue resistance to sustain cyclic bursts, and high toughness to withstand pointwise acupuncture during suturing. Furthermore, ATA displays the capability to repair injuries and restore normal erectile function of the TA-damaged penile tissue in a pig model. Our study demonstrates that ATA has great promise for penile injury repair.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Progress and potential&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A mammalian tunica albuginea (TA) is characterized by a double-layer orthogonal structure composed of stacked parallel wavy collagen fibrils. A TA mimic fiber with directional crimping was synthesized in this study by stretching an isotropic polyvinyl alcohol gel followed by covalent cross-linking to permanently fix the parallel aligned curved structures. Similar to the sequential response of the crimped structure in natural TA, the curved fibers first straighten to absorb strain and then stretch to induce a soft-to-firm transition. The proposed method paves the way for building a variety of weight-bearing organizations. Through the imitation of the structure, performance matching can be achieved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Assembly of Antimicrobial Peptide-Based Micelles Breaks the Limitation of Trypsin</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36577517/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36577517/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Targeting the limitation of antimicrobial peptides (AMPs) application in vivo, self-assembled AMPs library with specific nanostructures is expected to gradually overtake monomer AMPs libraries in the future. Peptide polymers are fascinating self-assembling nanoscale structures that have great advantage in biomedical applications because of their satisfactory biocompatibility and versatile properties. Herein, we describe a strategy for inducing the self-assembly of T9W into nanostructured antimicrobial micelles with evidently improved pharmacological properties, that is, PEGylation at the C-terminal of T9W (CT9W&lt;sub&gt;1000&lt;/sub&gt;), an antibacterial biomaterial that self-assembles in aqueous media without exogenous excipients, has been developed. Compared with parental molecular, the CT9W&lt;sub&gt;1000&lt;/sub&gt; is more effective against &lt;em&gt;Pseudomonas aeruginosa&lt;/em&gt;, and its antibacterial spectrum had also been broadened. Additionally, CT9W&lt;sub&gt;1000&lt;/sub&gt; micelles had higher stability under salt ion, serum, and acid-base environments. Importantly, the self-assembled structure is highly resistant to trypsin degradation, probably allowing T9W to be applied in clinical settings in the future. Mechanistically, by acting on membranes and through supplementary bactericidal mechanisms, CT9W&lt;sub&gt;1000&lt;/sub&gt; micelles contribute to the antibacterial process. Collectively, CT9W&lt;sub&gt;1000&lt;/sub&gt; micelles exhibited good biocompatibility &lt;em&gt;in vitro&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt;, resulting in highly effective treatment in a mouse acute lung injury model induced by &lt;em&gt;P. aeruginosa&lt;/em&gt; PAO1 without drug resistance. These advances may profoundly accelerate the clinical transformation of T9W and promote the development of a combination of peptide-based antibiotics and PEGylated nanotechnology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1,2-Bis(2-aminophenoxy)ethane- N, N, N&#39;, N&#39;-tetraacetic Acid Acetoxymethyl Ester Loaded Reactive Oxygen Species Responsive Hyaluronic Acid-Bilirubin Nanoparticles for Acute Kidney Injury Therapy via Alleviating Calcium Overload Mediated Endoplasmic Reticulum Stress</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36574627/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36574627/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Calcium overload is one of the early determinants of the core cellular events that contribute to the pathogenesis of acute kidney injury (AKI), which include oxidative stress, ATP depletion, calcium overload, and inflammatory response with self-amplifying and interactive feedback loops that ultimately lead to cellular injury and renal failure. Excluding adjuvant therapy, there are currently no approved pharmacotherapies for the treatment of AKI. Using an adipic dihydride linker, we modified the hyaluronic acid polymer chain with a potent antioxidant, bilirubin, to produce an amphiphilic conjugate. Subsequently, we developed a kidney-targeted and reactive oxygen species (ROS)-responsive drug delivery system based on the flash nanocomplexation method to deliver a well-known intracellular calcium chelator, 1,2-bis(2-aminophenoxy)ethane-N,N,N&amp;rsquo;,N&amp;rsquo;-tetraacetic acid acetoxymethyl ester (BAPTA-AM, BA), with the goal of rescuing renal cell damage via rapidly scavenging of intracellularly overloaded Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt;. In the ischemia-reperfusion (I/R) induced AKI rat model, a single dose of as-prepared formulation (BA 100 μg·kg&lt;sup&gt;-1&lt;/sup&gt;) 6 h post-reperfusion significantly reduced renal function indicators by more than 60% within 12 h, significantly alleviated tissular pathological changes, ameliorated tissular oxidative damage, significantly inhibited apoptosis of renal tubular cells and the expression of renal tubular marker kidney injury molecule 1, etc., thus greatly reducing the risk of kidney failure. Mechanistically, the treatment with BA-loaded NPs significantly inhibited the activation of the ER stress cascade response (IRE1-TRAF2-JNK, ATF4-CHOP, and ATF6 axis) and regulated the downstream apoptosis-related pathway while also reducing the inflammatory response. The BA-loaded NPs hold great promise as a potential therapy for I/R injury-related diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oral Delivery of siRNA Using Fluorinated, Small-Sized Nanocapsules Toward Anti-Inflammation Treatment</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36574636/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36574636/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oral delivery of siRNA provides a promising paradigm for treating diseases that require regular injections. However, the multiple gastrointestinal and systemic barriers often lead to inefficient oral absorption and low bioavailability of siRNA. Technologies that can overcome these barriers are still lacking, which hurdles the clinical potential of orally delivered siRNA. Herein, small-sized, fluorinated nanocapsules (F-NCs) were developed to mediate efficient oral delivery of TNF-α siRNA for anti-inflammation treatment. The NCs possessed a disulfide-cross-linked shell structure, thus featuring robust stability in the gastrointestinal tract. Because of their small size (∼30 nm) and fluorocarbon-assisted repelling of mucin adsorption, the best-performing F&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;-NCs showed excellent mucus penetration and intestinal transport capabilities without impairing the intestinal tight junction, conferring the oral bioavailability of 20.4% in relative to i.v. injection. The disulfide cross-linker could be cleaved inside target cells, causing NCs dissociation and siRNA release to potentiate the TNF-α silencing efficiency. In murine models of acute and chronic inflammation, orally delivered F&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;-NCs provoked efficient TNF-α silencing and pronounced anti-inflammatory efficacies. This study therefore provides a transformative strategy for oral siRNA delivery, and would render promising utilities for anti-inflammation treatment. This article is protected by copyright. All rights reserved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dual-Responsive STAT3 Inhibitor Nanoprodrug Combined with Oncolytic Virus Elicits Synergistic Antitumor Immune Responses by Igniting Pyroptosis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36545949/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36545949/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Immune checkpoint blockade (ICB) therapy shows excellent efficacy against malignancies; however, insufficient tumor immunogenicity and immunosuppressive tumor microenvironment are considered as the two major stumbling blocks to a broad ICB response. Here, we report a combinational therapeutic strategy combining tumor microenvironment reactive oxygen species (ROS)/pH dual-responsive signal transducers and activators of transcription 3 (STAT3) inhibitor nanoprodrugs MPNPs with oncolytic herpes simplex virus 1 (HSV-1) virotherapy to synergistically ignite pyroptosis for enhancing immunotherapy. MPNPs exhibited a certain level of tumor accumulation, reduce tumor cell stemness, and enhance antitumor immune responses. Furthermore, the simultaneous application of oncolytic viruses (OVs) confers MPNPs with higher tumor penetration capacity and remarkable gasdermin E-mediated pyroptosis, thereby reshaping the tumor microenvironment and transforming &amp;ldquo;cold&amp;rdquo; tumors into &amp;ldquo;hot&amp;rdquo; ones. This &amp;ldquo;fire of immunity&amp;rdquo; strategy successfully activates robust T cell-dependent antitumor responses, potentiating ICB effects against local recurrence and pulmonary metastasis in preclinical &amp;ldquo;cold&amp;rdquo; murine triple-negative breast cancer and syngeneic oral cancer models. Collectively, this work may pave a new way and offer an unprecedented opportunity for the combination of OVs with nanomedicine for cancer immunotherapy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Macrophage Membrane-Coated Nano-Gemcitabine Promotes Lymphocyte Infiltration and Synergizes AntiPD-L1 to Restore the Tumoricidal Function</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36525314/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36525314/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The limited lymphocyte infiltration and exhaustion of tumoricidal functions in solid tumors remain a formidable obstacle to cancer immunotherapy. Herein, we designed a macrophage membrane-coated nano-gemcitabine system (MNGs) to promote lymphocyte infiltration and then synergized anti-programmed death ligand 1 (antiPD-L1) to reinvigorate the exhausted lymphocytes. MNGs exhibited effective intratumor-permeating and responsive drug-releasing capacity, produced notable elimination of versatile immunosuppressive cells, and promoted lymphocyte infiltration into cancer cell regions in tumors, but over 50% of these infiltrated lymphocytes were in the exhausted state. Compared with MNG monotherapy, the MNGs+antiPD-L1 combination produced 31.77% and 30.63% reduction of exhausted CD3&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt;CD8&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T cells and natural killer (NK) cells and 2.83- and 3.17-fold increases of interferon-γ (IFN-γ)-positive subtypes, respectively, thereby resulting in considerable therapeutic benefits in several tumor models. Thus, MNGs provide an encouraging strategy to promote lymphocyte infiltration and synergize antiPD-L1 to restore their tumoricidal function for cancer immunotherapy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Injectable MMP1-sensitive microspheres with spatiotemporally controlled exosome release promote neovascularized bone healing</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36481504/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36481504/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bone marrow mesenchymal stromal cell-derived exosomes (BMSC-Exos) can recruit stem cells for bone repair, with neovessels serving as the main migratory channel for stem cells to the injury site. However, existing exosome (Exo) delivery strategies cannot reach the angiogenesis phase following bone injury. To that end, an enzyme-sensitive Exo delivery material that responds to neovessel formation during the angiogenesis phase was designed in the present study to achieve spatiotemporally controlled Exo release. Herein, matrix metalloproteinase-1 (MMP1) was found to be highly expressed in neovascularized bone; as a result, we proposed an injectable MMP1-sensitive hydrogel microspheres (KGE) made using a microfluidic chip prepared by mixing self-assembling peptide (KLDL-MMP1), GelMA, and BMSC-Exos. The results revealed that KGE microspheres had a uniform diameter of 50-70 μm, ideal for minimally invasive injection and could release exosomes in response to MMP1 expression. In vitro experiments demonstrated that KGE had less cytotoxicity and could promote the migration and osteodifferentiation of BMSCs. Furthermore, in vivo experiments confirmed that KGE could promote bone repair during angiogenesis by recruiting CD90+ stem cells via neovessels. Collectively, our results suggest that injectable enzyme-responsive KGE microspheres could be a promising Exo-secreting material for accelerating neovascularized bone healing. STATEMENT OF SIGNIFICANCE: Exosomes can spread through blood vessels and activate stem cells to participate in bone repair, but under normal circumstances, exosomes lacking sustained-release delivery materials cannot be maintained until the angiogenesis phase. In this study, we found that MMP1 was highly expressed in neovascularized bone, then we proposed an MMP1-sensitive injectable microsphere that carries exosomes and responds temporally and spatially to neovascularization, which maximizes the ability of exosomes to recruit stem cells. Different from previous strategies that focus on promoting angiogenesis to accelerate bone healing, this is a brand new delivery strategy that is stimuli-responsive to neovessel formation. In addition, the preparation of self-assembled peptide microspheres by a microfluidic chip is also proposed for the first time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Low dimensional nanomaterials for treating acute kidney injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/36456976/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/36456976/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acute kidney injury (AKI) is one of the most common severe complications among hospitalized patients. In the absence of specific drugs to treat AKI, hemodialysis remains the primary clinical treatment for AKI patients. AKI treatment has received significant attention recently due to the excellent drug delivery capabilities of low-dimensional nanomaterials (LDNs) and their unique therapeutic effects. Diverse LDNs have been proposed to treat AKI, with promising results and the potential for future clinical application. This article aims to provide an overview of the pathogenesis of AKI and the recent advances in the treatment of AKI using different types of LDNs. In addition, it is intended to provide theoretical support for the design of LDNs and implications for AKI treatment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inhaled platelet vesicle-decoyed biomimetic nanoparticles attenuate inflammatory lung injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36523494/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36523494/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acute lung injury (ALI) is an inflammatory response which causes serious damages to alveolar epithelia and vasculature, and it still remains high lethality and mortality with no effective treatment. Based on the inflammatory homing of platelets and cell membrane cloaking nanotechnology, in this study we developed a biomimetic anti-inflammation nanoparticle delivery system for ALI treatment. PM@Cur-RV NPs were designed by combining the poly (lactic-co-glycolic acid) nanoparticles (NPs) coated with platelet membrane vesicles (PM) for the purpose of highly targeting delivery of curcumin (Cur) and resveratrol (RV) to inflammatory lungs. PM@Cur-RV NPs showed good biocompatibility and biosafety both in vitro and in vivo. Accumulation of NPs into lung tract was observed after inhaled NPs. Remarkably, the inhalation of PM@Cur-RV NPs effectively inhibited lung vascular injury evidenced by the decreased lung vascular permeability, and the reduced proinflammatory cytokine burden in an ALI mouse model. The analysis of infiltrated macrophages in the lungs showed that the Cur-RV-modulated macrophage polarized towards M2 phenotype and the decreased histone lactylation might contribute to their anti-inflammation effects. Together, this work highlights the potential of inhalation of biomimetic nanoparticle delivery of curcumin and resveratrol for the treatment of pulmonary diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Injectable double-network hydrogel for corneal repair</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/cej.2022.140698/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/cej.2022.140698/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Injuries to the cornea can cause corneal opacity or even blindness. Especially scald wounds and chemical burns to the cornea can usually lead to loss of corneal epithelium function and deep damage to the corneal stroma. Injectable hydrogel has been widely applied in corneal tissue engineering because it is easy to handle and can completely fill the defect area with minimally invasive surgical procedures. To reduce the risk and complications of penetrating keratoplasty and lamellar keratoplasty and to meet the demand for donated cornea, an injectable double-network (IDN) hydrogel based on methacrylated gelatin (Gel-MA) and oxidized hyaluronic acid (OHA) was constructed for focal corneal defect repairing. The Gel-MA/OHA IDN hydrogel had an interconnected porous microstructure and tunable mechanical properties with a modulus between 3.4 and 176.4 kPa. The hydrogel could promote cell adhesion and proliferation and afford the sustained release of hydrophilic/hydrophobic drugs. &lt;em&gt;In-vivo&lt;/em&gt; corneal repair was performed by injecting the precursors into the pre-drilled epithelial-stromal defects of New Zealand White rabbits followed by immediate &lt;em&gt;in-situ&lt;/em&gt; UV crosslinking. The results showed that the hydrogel had a strong capacity to promote corneal regeneration. Optical coherence tomography, slip lamp, fluorescein staining, scanning electron microscopy (SEM), and haematoxylin &amp;amp; eosin (H&amp;amp;E) staining were employed to illustrate the effectiveness and safety of corneal tissue regeneration. All the results showed that the optimized Gel-MA/OHA IDN hydrogel possessed excellent biocompatibility and could promote cornea repair &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt;. This study suggests that the injectable biocompatible double network hydrogel may provide a good choice for corneal repair and regeneration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Species-agnostic polymeric formulations for inhalable messenger RNA delivery to the lung</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36443576/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36443576/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Messenger RNA has now been used to vaccinate millions of people. However, the diversity of pulmonary pathologies, including infections, genetic disorders, asthma and others, reveals the lung as an important organ to directly target for future RNA therapeutics and preventatives. Here we report the screening of 166 polymeric nanoparticle formulations for functional delivery to the lungs, obtained from a combinatorial synthesis approach combined with a low-dead-volume nose-only inhalation system for mice. We identify P76, a poly-β-amino-thio-ester polymer, that exhibits increased expression over formulations lacking the thiol component, delivery to different animal species with varying RNA cargos and low toxicity. P76 allows for dose sparing when delivering an mRNA-expressed Cas13a-mediated treatment in a SARS-CoV-2 challenge model, resulting in similar efficacy to a 20-fold higher dose of a neutralizing antibody. Overall, the combinatorial synthesis approach allowed for the discovery of promising polymeric formulations for future RNA pharmaceutical development for the lungs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A multivalent nucleoside-modified mRNA vaccine against all known influenza virus subtypes</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36423275/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36423275/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seasonal influenza vaccines offer little protection against pandemic influenza virus strains. It is difficult to create effective prepandemic vaccines because it is uncertain which influenza virus subtype will cause the next pandemic. In this work, we developed a nucleoside-modified messenger RNA (mRNA)-lipid nanoparticle vaccine encoding hemagglutinin antigens from all 20 known influenza A virus subtypes and influenza B virus lineages. This multivalent vaccine elicited high levels of cross-reactive and subtype-specific antibodies in mice and ferrets that reacted to all 20 encoded antigens. Vaccination protected mice and ferrets challenged with matched and mismatched viral strains, and this protection was at least partially dependent on antibodies. Our studies indicate that mRNA vaccines can provide protection against antigenically variable viruses by simultaneously inducing antibodies against multiple antigens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advances in Extracellular Vesicle Nanotechnology for Precision Theranostics</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/36373730/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/36373730/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Extracellular vesicles (EVs) have increasingly been recognized as important cell surrogates influencing many pathophysiological processes, including cellular homeostasis, cancer progression, neurologic disease, and infectious disease. These behaviors enable EVs broad application prospects for clinical application in disease diagnosis and treatment. Many studies suggest that EVs are superior to conventional synthetic carriers in terms of drug delivery and circulating biomarkers for early disease diagnosis, opening up new frontiers for modern theranostics. Despite these clinical potential, EVs containing diverse cellular components, such as nucleic acids, proteins, and metabolites are highly heterogeneous and small size. The limitation of preparatory, engineering and analytical technologies for EVs poses technical barriers to clinical translation. This article aims at present a critical overview of emerging technologies in EVs field for biomedical applications and challenges involved in their clinic translations. The current methods for isolation and identification of EVs are discussed. Additionally, engineering strategies developed to enhance scalable production and improved cargo loading as well as tumor targeting are presented. The superior clinical potential of EVs, particularly in terms of different cell origins and their application in the next generation of diagnostic and treatment platforms, are clarified.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A composite hydrogel containing resveratrol-laden nanoparticles and platelet-derived extracellular vesicles promotes wound healing in diabetic mice</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36309190/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36309190/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Diabetic wounds are difficult to heal because of persistent inflammation and limited angiogenesis. Resveratrol (RES) is an anti-inflammatory and antioxidant agent. Platelet-derived extracellular vesicles (PDEVs) are rich in growth factors and cytokines, which promote proliferation and angiogenesis. However, single drug treatment has limited efficacy and delivery efficiency. Bioengineering can improve the limited effect of single drugs by combining drugs and materials to obtain complementary or cooperative bioengineered drugs. In this study, gelatin methacrylate (GelMA) and silk fibroin glycidyl methacrylate (SFMA) were used to synthesize GelMA/SFMA composite hydrogels with suitable mechanical properties, swelling ratio and biodegradability. The composite hydrogel was used as a wound dressing for sustained drug release. RES was loaded into mesoporous silica nanoparticles (MSNs) to synthesize MSN-RES to enhance the release dynamic, and MSN-RES and PDEVs were combined with the composite hydrogels to form GelMA/SFMA/MSN-RES/PDEVs hydrogels. The GelMA/SFMA/MSN-RES/PDEVs had low cytotoxicity and good biocompatibility, inhibited macrophage iNOS expression, and promoted the tube formation by human umbilical vein endothelial cells (HUVECs) in vitro. In a diabetic mouse wound model, the GelMA/SFMA/MSN-RES/PDEVs hydrogels decreased the expression of pro-inflammatory factors TNF-α and iNOS, increased the expression of anti-inflammatory factors TGF-β1 and Arg-1, promoted angiogenesis, and accelerated wound healing. Interestingly, the GelMA/SFMA/MSN-RES/PDEVs hydrogels promoted the expression of extracellular purinergic signaling pathway-related CD73 and adenosine 2A receptor (A2A-R). Therefore, the GelMA/SFMA/MSN-RES/PDEVs hydrogels could be used as wound dressings to regulate the inflammation and angiogenesis of diabetic wounds and accelerate wound healing. STATEMENT OF SIGNIFICANCE: Drugs often fail to function because of a continuous oxidative stress microenvironment and inflammation. Here, a GelMA/SFMA hydrogel, with enhanced mechanical properties and liquid absorption ability, is proposed for sustained release of drugs. In addition to carrying platelet-derived extracellular vesicles (PDEVs) with pro-angiogenic effects, the hydrogels were also loaded with nanoparticle-encapsulated resveratrol with anti-inflammatory activities, aiming to reduce inflammation and oxidative stress in the wound microenvironment, such that the wound could receive proliferative repair signals to achieve sequential treatment and heal quickly. We also experimentally predicted that the regulatory mechanism of the GelMA/SFMA/MSN-RES/PDEVs in wound healing might be related to the extracellular purinergic signaling pathway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pulmonary delivery of curcumin-loaded glycyrrhizic acid nanoparticles for anti-inflammatory therapy</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36263591/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36263591/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acute lung injury (ALI) is an inflammatory disease of the lungs. Curcumin (Cur) shows protective effects in ALI animal models. However, Cur is a hydrophobic drug and its administration into the lungs is inefficient due to its low bioavailability. In this study, glycyrrhizic acid (GA) micelles were produced and evaluated as a carrier of Cur for treatment of ALI. Cur-loaded GA (GA-Cur) nanoparticles were produced using an oil-in-water emulsion/solvent evaporation method. The size and surface charge of the GA-Cur nanoparticles were 159 nm and -23 mV, respectively. In lipopolysaccharide-activated RAW264.7 cells, the GA-Cur nanoparticles decreased the pro-inflammatory cytokine levels more efficiently than GA, Cur, or a simple mixture of GA and Cur (GA + Cur). This suggests that the GA-Cur nanoparticles improved the therapeutic efficiency by enhanced delivery of GA and Cur. GA-Cur inhibited the nuclear translocation of nuclear factor-κb and induced endogenous heme oxygenase-1 more efficiently than the other treatments. Furthermore, an in vitro toxicity test showed that GA-Cur had little cytotoxicity. In vivo therapeutic effects of GA-Cur were evaluated in ALI mouse models. GA-Cur was administered into the animals by intratracheal instillation. The results showed that GA-Cur reduced pro-inflammatory cytokines in a dose-dependent manner and did so more efficiently than GA, Cur, or GA + Cur. Furthermore, the hemolysis and infiltration of monocytes into the lungs were more effectively inhibited by GA-Cur than the other treatments. The data indicate that GA is an efficient carrier of Cur and an anti-inflammatory drug. Owing to their delivery efficiency and safety, GA-Cur nanoparticles will be useful for treatment of ALI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hierarchical Microparticles Delivering Oxaliplatin and NLG919 Nanoprodrugs for Local Chemo-immunotherapy</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36263713/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36263713/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chemo-immunotherapy shows promising antitumor therapeutic outcomes for many primary cancers. Research in this area has been focusing on developing an ideal formula that enables the potent efficacy of chemo-immunotherapy in combating various cancers with reduced systemic toxicity. Herein, we present novel hierarchical hydrogel microparticles (MDDP) delivering oxaliplatin and NLG919 nanoprodrugs for local chemo-immunotherapy with desired features. The oxaliplatin prodrug and NLG919 were efficiently loaded in the dual-drug polymeric nanoparticles (DDP NPs), which were further encapsulated into a MDDP by using microfluidic technology. When delivered to the tumor site, the DDP NPs will be sustainedly released from the MDDP and retained locally to reduce systemic toxicity. After being endocytosed by cancer cells, the cytotoxic oxaliplatin and NLG919 could be successfully triggered to release from DDP NPs in a chain-shattering manner, leading to the immunogenic cell death (ICD) of tumor cells and the suppression of intratumoral immunosuppressive Tregs, respectively. With the assistance of an immune modulator, the chemotherapeutics-induced ICD could trigger robust systemic antitumor immune responses, presenting superior synergistic antitumor efficacies. Thus, the hierarchical microparticles could substantially inhibit the growth of mouse subcutaneous colorectal tumors, breast tumors, and colorectal tumors with large initial sizes via synergized chemo-immunotherapy, showing great potential in the practical clinical application of oncotherapy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kidney-Targeted Nanoparticles Loaded with the Natural Antioxidant Rosmarinic Acid for Acute Kidney Injury Treatment</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36253133/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36253133/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acute kidney injury (AKI) is a common clinical disease with high morbidity and mortality, and with a lack of effective drugs for treatment. Oxidative stress is very important in the occurrence and progression of AKI, and antioxidants use is one of the promising treatments. Rosmarinic acid (RA) is a ubiquitous natural polyphenol with powerful antioxidant and anti-inflammatory activities. Due to its inherent characteristic with poor water solubility and inferior bioavailability, its clinical application is impeded. Hence, the authors design a nanoparticle for effectively delivering RA, which is a chemical complex of RA and fourth-generation poly-amidoamine-based amphiphilic polymer (G4-PAMAM). The nanoparticle is modified with l-serine due to the specific interaction between kidney injury molecule-1 (Kim-1) and serine, which eventually generates a promising AKI kidney-targeting nanoparticle (S-G-R). The S-G-R is rapidly cumulated and long-term retained in ischemia-reperfusion-induced AKI kidneys, especially in the damaged renal tubular cells. The S-G-R exhibits more excellent antioxidative and antiapoptotic effects in vitro and has a more outstanding ability to improve the renal function, repair damaged renal tissue, and decrease oxidative stress, inflammatory response and apoptosis of tubular cells in vivo. Overall, this study might develop a safe and effective targeting strategy for the therapy of AKI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nanodrugs alleviate acute kidney injury: Manipulate RONS at kidney</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/36203963/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/36203963/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;AKI is a common clinical acute syndrome with high morbidity and mortality but without effective clinical drug available.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hypoxia and accumulation of toxic substances are key pathological features of various heterogeneous AKI.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Excessive RONS is the core of the pathological mechanism of AKI.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The development of nanodrugs is expected to achieve successful treatment in AKI.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently, there are no clinical drugs available to treat acute kidney injury (AKI). Given the high prevalence and high mortality rate of AKI, the development of drugs to effectively treat AKI is a huge unmet medical need and a research hotspot. Although existing evidence fully demonstrates that reactive oxygen and nitrogen species (RONS) burst at the AKI site is a major contributor to AKI progression, the heterogeneity, complexity, and unique physiological structure of the kidney make most antioxidant and anti-inflammatory small molecule drugs ineffective because of the lack of kidney targeting and side effects. Recently, nanodrugs with intrinsic kidney targeting through the control of size, shape, and surface properties have opened exciting prospects for the treatment of AKI. Many antioxidant nanodrugs have emerged to address the limitations of current AKI treatments. In this review, we systematically summarized for the first time about the emerging nanodrugs that exploit the pathological and physiological features of the kidney to overcome the limitations of traditional small-molecule drugs to achieve high AKI efficacy. First, we analyzed the pathological structural characteristics of AKI and the main pathological mechanism of AKI: hypoxia, harmful substance accumulation-induced RONS burst at the renal site despite the multifactorial initiation and heterogeneity of AKI. Subsequently, we introduced the strategies used to improve renal targeting and reviewed advances of nanodrugs for AKI: nano-RONS-sacrificial agents, antioxidant nanozymes, and nanocarriers for antioxidants and anti-inflammatory drugs. These nanodrugs have demonstrated excellent therapeutic effects, such as greatly reducing oxidative stress damage, restoring renal function, and low side effects. Finally, we discussed the challenges and future directions for translating nanodrugs into clinical AKI treatment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Injectable adhesive self-healing biocompatible hydrogel for haemostasis, wound healing, and postoperative tissue adhesion prevention in nephron-sparing surgery</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36100176/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36100176/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Statement of significance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Extended warm ischemia time during nephron sparing surgery negatively affected postoperative renal function due to the need for hemostasis at the wound with abundant blood supply, and postoperative wound healing and additional adhesions caused by the surgical procedure deserve attention. Based on the efficient and stable adhesion properties of hydrogels and the ability to promote wound healing. Herein, a series of adhesive self-healing biocompatible hydrogels were prepared based on free-radical polymerization of acryloyl-6-aminocaproic acid (AA) and N-acryloyl 2-glycine (NAG) and the ionic coordination between Ca2+ with the abundant carboxyl groups in AA and NAG. AA/NAG/Ca hydrogel showed hemostasis property in nephron sparing surgery model, promote kidney wound healing, and could perform anti-postoperative adhesion efficacy in an abdomen-caecum adhesion model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nephron-sparing surgery is a well-established treatment in patients with T1a renal cell carcinoma; however, the complex suturing process prolongs warm ischaemia time, affects the preservation of normal renal parenchymal function, and causes avoidable postoperative tissue adhesion complications, including chronic abdominal pain, intestinal obstruction, and female infertility. Hence, the design of multifunctional biomaterials with haemostasis, postoperative wound management, and postoperative tissue adhesion prevention properties for nephron-sparing surgeries is urgently needed. In this study, a series of injectable adhesive multifunctional biocompatible hydrogels were designed based on the free-radical polymerisation of monomers acryloyl-6-aminocaproic acid (AA) and N-acryloyl 2-glycine (NAG), and the ionic coordination between Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt; and the abundant carboxyl groups in AA and NAG. AA/NAG/Ca (AA, NAG, and Ca refer to acryloyl-6-aminocaproic acid, N-acryloyl 2-glycine and calcium chloride, respectively) hydrogel exhibited good mechanical properties, swelling and adhesion properties, flexibility, in vitro blood-clotting ability, and cytocompatibility. In vivo experiments on liver injury models and rat/rabbit nephron-sparing surgery models elucidated that the AA/NAG/Ca hydrogel had haemostasis performance and wound healing properties that led to short bleeding time, reduced bleeding volume, and well-organised nephron structures. An abdomen-caecum adhesion model indicated that the AA/NAG/Ca hydrogel showed excellent anti-adhesion properties. In summary, this multifunctional hydrogel exhibited potential for improving haemostasis and wound management in nephron-sparing surgeries, showing potential for clinical application. STATEMENT OF SIGNIFICANCE: Extended warm ischemia time during nephron sparing surgery negatively affected postoperative renal function due to the need for hemostasis at the wound with abundant blood supply, and postoperative wound healing and additional adhesions caused by the surgical procedure deserve attention. Based on the efficient and stable adhesion properties of hydrogels and the ability to promote wound healing. Herein, a series of adhesive self-healing biocompatible hydrogels were prepared based on free-radical polymerization of acryloyl-6-aminocaproic acid (AA) and N-acryloyl 2-glycine (NAG) and the ionic coordination between Ca2+ with the abundant carboxyl groups in AA and NAG. AA/NAG/Ca hydrogel showed hemostasis property in nephron sparing surgery model, promote kidney wound healing, and could perform anti-postoperative adhesion efficacy in an abdomen-caecum adhesion model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tanshinone IIA loaded bioactive nanoemulsion for alleviation of lipopolysaccharide induced acute lung injury via inhibition of endothelial glycocalyx shedding</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36099790/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36099790/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;TSIIA showed evident protective effects in acute lung injury.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nanoemulsion with bioactive excipients enhanced TSIIA activity.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;TSIIA alleviates endothelial glycocalyx shedding.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Endothelial glycocalyx is an important therapeutic target for acute lung injury.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;TSIIA effect may be attributed to its antioxidant and anti-inflammatory actions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acute lung injury (ALI) and its more serious form; acute respiratory distress syndrome are major causes of COVID-19 related mortality. Finding new therapeutic targets for ALI is thus of great interest. This work aimed to prepare a biocompatible nanoformulation for effective pulmonary delivery of the herbal drug; tanshinone-IIA (TSIIA) for ALI management. A nanoemulsion (NE) formulation based on bioactive natural ingredients; rhamnolipid biosurfactant and tea-tree oil, was developed using a simple ultrasonication technique, optimized by varying oil concentration and surfactant:oil ratio. The selected TSIIA-NE formulation showed 105.7 nm diameter and a PDI ∼ 0.3. EE exceeded 98 % with biphasic sustained drug release and good stability over 3-months. In-vivo efficacy was evaluated in lipopolysaccharide (LPS)-induced ALI model. TSIIA-NE (30 µg/kg) was administered once intratracheally 2 h after LPS instillation. Evaluation was performed 7days post-treatment. Pulmonary function assessment, inflammatory, oxidative stress and glycocalyx shedding markers analysis in addition to histopathological examination of lung tissue were performed. When compared to untreated rats, in-vivo efficacy study demonstrated 1.4 and 1.9-fold increases in tidal volume and minute respiratory volume, respectively, with 32 % drop in wet/dry lung weight ratio and improved levels of arterial blood gases. Lung histopathology and biochemical analysis of different biomarkers in tissue homogenate and bronchoalveolar lavage fluid indicated that treatment may ameliorate LPS-induced ALI symptoms thorough anti-oxidative, anti-inflammatory effects and inhibition of glycocalyx degradation. TSIIA-NE efficacy was superior to free medication and blank-NE. The enhanced efficacy of TSIIA bioactive nanoemulsion significantly suggests the pharmacotherapeutic potential of bioactive TSIIA-NE as a promising nanoplatform for ALI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Copper-olsalazine metal-organic frameworks as a nanocatalyst and epigenetic modulator for efficient inhibition of colorectal cancer growth and metastasis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36087871/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36087871/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite the extensive explorations of nanoscale metal-organic frameworks (nanoMOFs) in drug delivery, the intrinsic bioactivity of nanoMOFs, such as anticancer activity, is severely underestimated owing to the overlooked integration of the hierarchical components including nanosized MOFs and molecular-level organic ligands and metal-organic complexes. Herein, we propose a de novo design of multifunctional bioactive nanoMOFs ranging from molecular to nanoscale level, and demonstrate this proof-of-concept by a copper-olsalazine (Olsa, a clinically approved drug for inflammatory bowel disease, here as a bioactive linker and DNA hypomethylating agent) nanoMOF displaying a multifaceted anticancer mechanism: (1) Cu-Olsa nanoMOF-mediated redox dyshomeostasis for enhanced catalytic tumor therapy, (2) targeting downregulation of cyclooxygenase-2 by the organic complex of Cu&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt; and Olsa, and (3) Olsa-mediated epigenetic regulation. Cu-Olsa nanoMOF displayed an enzyme-like catalytic activity to generate cancericidal species ·OH and &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; from rich H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; in tumors, improved the expression of tumor suppressors TIMP3 and AXIN2 by epigenetic modulation, and fulfilled selective inhibition of colorectal cancer cells over normal cells. The hyaluronic acid-modified nanoMOF further verified the efficient suppression of CT26 colorectal tumor growth and metastasis in murine models. Overall, these results suggest that Olsa-based MOF presents a platform of epigenetic therapy-synergized nanomedicine for efficient cancer treatment and provides a powerful strategy for the design of intrinsically bioactive nanoMOFs. STATEMENT OF SIGNIFICANCE: Metal-organic frameworks (MOFs) with intrinsic bioactivities such as anticancer and antibacterial activity are of great interest. Herein, we reported a bioactive copper-olsalazine (Cu-Olsa) nanoMOF as a nanodrug for colorectal cancer treatment. This nanoMOF per se displayed enzyme-like catalytic activity to generate cancericidal species ·OH and &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; from rich H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; in tumors for nanocatalytic tumor therapy. Upon dissociation into small molecular copper-organic complex and olsalazine in cancer cells, COX-2 inhibition and epigenetic modulation were fulfilled for selective inhibition of colorectal cancer growth and metastasis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Roles and current applications of S-nitrosoglutathione in anti-infective biomaterials</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/36105674/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/36105674/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bacterial infections can compromise the physical and biological functionalities of humans and pose a huge economical and psychological burden on infected patients. Nitric oxide (NO) is a broad-spectrum antimicrobial agent, whose mechanism of action is not affected by bacterial resistance. S-nitrosoglutathione (GSNO), an endogenous donor and carrier of NO, has gained increasing attention because of its potent antibacterial activity and efficient biocompatibility. Significant breakthroughs have been made in the application of GSNO in biomaterials. This review is based on the existing evidence that comprehensively summarizes the progress of antimicrobial GSNO applications focusing on their anti-infective performance, underlying antibacterial mechanisms, and application in anti-infective biomaterials. We provide an accurate overview of the roles and applications of GSNO in antibacterial biomaterials and shed new light on the avenues for future studies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hydrogel-metal-organic-framework hybrids mediated efficient oral delivery of siRNA for the treatment of ulcerative colitis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36064365/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36064365/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Ulcerative colitis (UC) is a major type of inflammatory bowel disease (IBD), which could induce bloody stool, diarrhea, colon atrophy and eventually lead to colorectal cancer. The conventional daily oral administration of drugs only relieve the inflammatory response of colon in the short term, Biological agents such as antibody drugs has proven its efficiency in inhibiting colitis, while the low drug bioavailability means that large doses of antibodies are required, ultimately causing systemic toxicity. Small interfering RNA (siRNA) has significant advantages over antibody drugs in terms of safety and efficacy, and it have been widely applied as potential candidates for a variety of inflammation-related diseases. However, oral delivery of siRNA fails to overcome the degradation of the gastrointestinal environment to produce a significant therapeutic effect in ulcerative colitis. Herein, we design the hybrid delivery system that the siRNA loaded MOF encapsulated in the sodium alginate particles to overcome the barriers in the oral process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; The hybrid delivery system (SA@MOF-siRNA&lt;sup&gt;TNFα&lt;/sup&gt;) was successfully constructed, and it could not only survive the low pH environment in the stomach and small intestine, but also taken up more by inflammatory macrophages, as well as released much more MOF-siRNA&lt;sup&gt;TNFα&lt;/sup&gt;. Moreover, SA@MOF-siRNA&lt;sup&gt;TNFα&lt;/sup&gt; tended to enriched and infiltrated into local colon tissues. As a result, SA@MOF-siRNA&lt;sup&gt;TNFα&lt;/sup&gt; significantly reduced the progression of colitis, of which the treated mice did not experience significant weight loss, bloody stools and diarrhea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/em&gt; We confirmed that the formulation of hydrogel-metal-organic framework hybrids could improve the protection of incorporated payload in the gastric and early small intestine, enhancing the delivery of MOF-siRNA to colon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lung-Targeted Delivery of Cepharanthine by an Erythrocyte-Anchoring Strategy for the Treatment of Acute Lung Injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36145566/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36145566/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As one of the most frequent complications of critical illness, acute lung injury (ALI) carries a high risk of clinical morbidity and mortality. Cepharanthine (CPA) has significant anti-inflammatory activity, however, due to poor water solubility, low bioavailability, and short half-life, it fails to provide effective clinical management measures. Here, we explored the flexibility of an erythrocyte-anchoring strategy using CPA-encapsulated chitosan-coating nanoparticles (CPA-CNPs) anchored onto circulating erythrocytes for the treatment of ALI. CPA-CNPs adhered to erythrocytes successfully (E-CPA-CNPs) and exhibited high erythrocyte adhesion efficiency (&amp;gt;80%). Limited toxicity and favorable biocompatibility enabled further application of E-CPA-CNPs. Next, the reticuloendothelial system evasion features were analyzed in RAW264.7 macrophages and Sprague-Dawley rats. Compared with bare CPA-CNPs, erythrocyte-anchored CNPs significantly decreased cellular uptake in immune cells and prolonged circulation time in vivo. Notably, the erythrocyte-anchoring strategy enabled CNPs to be delivered and accumulated in the lungs (up to 6-fold). In the ALI mouse model, E-CPA-CNPs attenuated the progression of ALI by inhibiting inflammatory responses. Overall, our results demonstrate the outstanding advantages of erythrocyte-anchored CPA-CNPs in improving the pharmacokinetics and bioavailability of CPA, which offers great promise for a lung-targeted drug delivery system for the effective treatment of ALI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lentinan-functionalized selenium nanoparticles induce apoptosis and cell cycle arrest in human colon carcinoma HCT-116 cells</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36082027/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36082027/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Selenium nanoparticles (SeNPs) have gained extensive attention for their excellent biological activity and low toxicity. However, SeNPs are extremely liable to aggregate into non-bioactive or gray elemental selenium, which limits their application in the biomedicine field. This study aimed to prepare stable SeNPs by using lentinan (LNT) as a template and evaluate its anti-colon cancer activity. The average particle diameter of obtained lentinan-selenium nanoparticles (LNT-SeNPs) was approximately 59 nm and presented zero-valent, amorphous, and spherical structures. The monodisperse SeNPs were stabilized by LNT through hydrogen bonding interactions. LNT-SeNPs solution remained highly stable at 4°C for at least 8 weeks. The stability of LNT-SeNPs solution sharply decreased under high temperature and strong acidic conditions. LNT-SeNPs showed no obvious cytotoxic effect on normal cells (IEC-6) but significantly inhibited the proliferation of five colon cancer cells (HCT-116, HT-29, Caco-2, SW620, and CT26). Among them, LNT-SeNPs exhibited the highest sensitivity toward HCT-116 cells with an IC50 value of 7.65 μM. Also, LNT-SeNPs displayed better cancer cell selectivity than sodium selenite and selenomethionine. Moreover, LNT-SeNPs promoted apoptosis of HCT-116 cells through activating mitochondria-mediated apoptotic pathway. Meanwhile, LNT-SeNPs induced cell cycle arrest at G0/G1 phase in HCT-116 cells via modulation of cell cycle regulatory proteins. The results of this study indicated that LNT-SeNPs possessed strong potential application in the treatment of colorectal cancer (CRC).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nanoparticles: Attractive tools to treat colorectal cancer</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/36028154/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/36028154/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Colorectal Cancer (CRC) is one of the leading causes of cancer-related deaths worldwide. Despite the notable advances achieved over the last few decades, CRC remains a hard-to-treat deadly disease in many patients. This is attributed mainly to chemo- and immuno-resistance, which frequently emerge soon after treatment with conventional therapeutics. Systemic treatments are also constrained by their many undesired and serious side effects. More recently, nanomedicine has emerged as an attractive modality that can overcome issues of therapeutic resistance, improper delivery, or suboptimal targeting of tumor cells. Many nanomaterials, having already been examined in pre-clinical and clinical studies, are now considered biocompatible and relatively safe. Indeed, around 50 nano-formulations have so far been approved as diagnostic and therapeutic agents in humans. Here, in this review, we describe a set of imperative nanoparticles (NPs) involved in diagnosing and treating CRC. In particular, we discuss the theragnostic roles of quantum dots, iron oxide NPs, Polylactide-co-glycolic acid (PLGA) NPs, dendrimer NPs, carbon nanotubes, liposomes, and gold NPs. We dissect the molecular and clinical evidence supporting the use of these NPs in CRC. We also highlight their implications in targeted drug delivery as well as their anti-tumorigenic properties and effects on the cardinal hallmarks of CRC. We conclude by highlighting the notion that nanomedicine is emerging as an attractive approach to address the unmet needs in managing several diseases, including CRC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bioengineered immunomodulatory organelle targeted nanozymes for photodynamic immunometabolic therapy</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35987351/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35987351/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Intelligent nanomedicines integrated with stimuli-responsive components enable on-demand customizable treatment options which would improve therapeutic outcome and reduce systemic toxicity. In this work, we explore the synergistic therapeutic potential of photodynamic therapy and immunometabolic modulation to achieve tumour regression and to trigger an adaptive immunity to prevent tumour recurrence. The therapeutic potential of the fabricated Bioengineered Immunomodulatory Organelle targeted Nanozymes (BIONs) was tested on 3D printed mini-brains which could effectively recapitulate the biologically relevant interactions between glioblastoma cells and macrophages. In the presence of glioblastoma organotypic brain slices, activated BIONs upregulated the cell surface expression of CD86, a costimulatory molecule and CD83, maturation marker, on monocyte derived dendritic cells, suggesting its ability to elicit a strong immune response. Furthermore, the antigen pulsed dendritic cells by chemotaxis and transendothelial migration readily relocate into the draining lymph node where they present the antigenic cargo to enable the proliferation of T lymphocytes. The stealth and tunable catalytic activity of BIONs prevent ROS mediated diseases such as acute kidney injury by providing environment dependent protection without compromising on its promising anti-cancer activity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bidirectional anisotropic palladium nanozymes reprogram macrophages to enhance collaborative chemodynamic therapy of colorectal cancer</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35981687/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35981687/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although genomewide RNA expression analysis has become a routine tool in biomedical research, extracting biological insight from such information remains a major challenge. Here, we describe a powerful analytical method called Gene Set Enrichment Analysis (GSEA) for interpreting gene expression data. The method derives its power by focusing on gene sets, that is, groups of genes that share common biological function, chromosomal location, or regulation. We demonstrate how GSEA yields insights into several cancer-related data sets, including leukemia and lung cancer. Notably, where single-gene analysis finds little similarity between two independent studies of patient survival in lung cancer, GSEA reveals many biological pathways in common. The GSEA method is embodied in a freely available software package, together with an initial database of 1,325 biologically defined gene sets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kidney targeting of formoterol containing polymeric nanoparticles improves recovery from ischemia reperfusion-induced acute kidney injury in mice</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35779607/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35779607/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The β2 adrenergic receptor agonist, formoterol, is an inducer of mitochondrial biogenesis and restorer of mitochondrial and kidney function in acute and chronic models of kidney injury. Unfortunately, systemic administration of formoterol has the potential for adverse cardiovascular effects, increased heart rate, and decreased blood pressure. To minimize these effects, we developed biodegradable and biocompatible polymeric nanoparticles containing formoterol that target the kidney, thereby decreasing the effective dose, and lessen cardiovascular effects while restoring kidney function after injury. Male C57Bl/6 mice, treated with these nanoparticles daily, had reduced ischemia-reperfusion-induced serum creatinine and kidney cortex kidney injury molecule-1 levels by 78% and 73% respectively, compared to control mice six days after injury. With nanoparticle therapy, kidney cortical mitochondrial number and proteins reduced by ischemic injury, recovered to levels of sham-operated mice. Tubular necrosis was reduced 69% with nanoparticles treatment. Nanoparticles improved kidney recovery even when the dosing frequency was reduced from daily to two days per week. Finally, compared to treatment with formoterol-free drug alone, these nanoparticles did not increase heart rate nor decrease blood pressure. Thus, targeted kidney delivery of formoterol-containing nanoparticles is an improvement in standard formoterol therapy for ischemia-reperfusion-induced acute kidney injuries by decreasing the dose, dosing frequency, and cardiac side effects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A novel inhalable quercetin-alginate nanogel as a promising therapy for acute lung injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35690763/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35690763/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Acute lung injury (ALI), a severe health-threatening disease, has a risk of causing chronic pulmonary fibrosis. Informative and powerful evidence suggests that inflammation and oxidative stress play a central role in the pathogenesis of ALI. Quercetin is well recognized for its excellent antioxidant and anti-inflammatory properties, which showed great potential for ALI treatment. However, the application of quercetin is often hindered by its low solubility and bioavailability. Therefore, to overcome these challenges, an inhalable quercetin-alginate nanogel (QU-Nanogel) was fabricated, and by this special &amp;ldquo;material-drug&amp;rdquo; structure, the solubility and bioavailability of quercetin were significantly enhanced, which could further increase the activity of quercetin and provide a promising therapy for ALI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; QU-Nanogel is a novel alginate and quercetin based &amp;ldquo;material-drug&amp;rdquo; structural inhalable nanogel, in which quercetin was stabilized by hydrogen bonding to obtain a &amp;ldquo;co-construct&amp;rdquo; water-soluble nanogel system, showing antioxidant and anti-inflammatory properties. QU-Nanogel has an even distribution in size of less than 100 nm and good biocompatibility, which shows a stronger protective and antioxidant effect in vitro. Tissue distribution results provided evidence that the QU-Nanogel by ultrasonic aerosol inhalation is a feasible approach to targeted pulmonary drug delivery. Moreover, QU-Nanogel was remarkably reversed ALI rats by relieving oxidative stress damage and acting the down-regulation effects of mRNA and protein expression of inflammation cytokines via ultrasonic aerosol inhalation administration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; In the ALI rat model, this novel nanogel showed an excellent therapeutic effect by ultrasonic aerosol inhalation administration by protecting and reducing pulmonary inflammation, thereby preventing subsequent pulmonary fibrosis. This work demonstrates that this inhalable QU-Nanogel may function as a promising drug delivery strategy in treating ALI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dressing blood-contacting devices with platelet membrane enables large-scale multifunctional biointerfacing</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/matt.2022.05.018/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/matt.2022.05.018/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Platelet membrane were first used for coating macroscale blood-contacting devices&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Platelet-membrane coating (PMC) endows material-improved biocompatibility&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Biofunctional proteins confer favorable performance on PMC-modified vascular stents&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So far, cloaking materials with platelet membranes have been widely studied, mainly focused on covering nanosized materials but rarely forwarded to dressing large-scale materials. Herein, a platelet-membrane coating (PMC) constructed on the surface of a macroscopic device is reported, driven by the spontaneous fusion of platelet-membrane vesicles (PMVs) with a negatively charged superhydrophilic surface. The coating contains not only phospholipids but also a variety of functional proteins of the platelet membrane, which is a further leap compared with surface-modification strategies of imitating cell-membrane structure with inert synthetic amphiphilic molecules. The preservation of membrane proteins by dressing PMC endows the surface of macroscopic devices with bioactivity. The implantation of vascular stents covered with PMC demonstrates the potential to address the desired biointerface properties, such as thromboprotection and anti-inflammation, and promote re-endothelialization. Overall, dressing large-scale blood-contacting materials with PMC provides a multifunctional biointerface by naturally preserved membrane proteins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intraarticularly injectable silk hydrogel microspheres with enhanced mechanical and structural stability to attenuate osteoarthritis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35660867/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35660867/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A silk fibroin (silk) hydrogel was prepared by using diglycidyl ether (BDDE), a chemical crosslinker commonly used to generate Food and Drug Administration (FDA)-approved hyaluronic acid (HA) medical products. The silk/BDDE hydrogels exhibited high elasticity (compressive modulus of 166 ± 15.0 kPa), anti-fatigue properties, and stable structure and mechanical strength in aqueous solution. Chemical crosslinking was conducted in a high concentration (9.3 M) of lithium bromide (LiBr) solution, a salt that is commonly used to dissolve degummed silk fibers during silk solubilization. The unfolded and extended structure of silk molecules with these reaction conditions, as well as the unique ionic environment provided by LiBr facilitated a high degree of crosslinking in the hydrogel. Similar hydrogels were not obtained when the silk was dissolved in other silk fiber-dissolving reagents (——, Ajisawa&amp;rsquo;s, formic acid (FA)/LiBr, FA/CaCl&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; solutions), likely because partially folded silk structures and the ionic conditions with these reagents were less favorable for the crosslinking reaction. Based on these findings, silk/BDDE hydrogel spheres were prepared using an oil/water (o/w) emulsification method and biocompatibility and biodegradation were evaluated in vivo, along with other silk gel control systems (e.g., enzyme-catalyzed di-tyrosine and pulverized silk/BDDE gel particles with irregular shapes). Histological and immunohistochemical analyses demonstrated that the silk/BDDE hydrogel spheres were biocompatible and served as a bio-lubricant to treat osteoarthritis (OA). The intra-articular injection of the gel spheres reduced pain as measured with OA rats, reduced cartilage damage and resisted the digestive environment in the articular cavity for extended time frames (&amp;gt;4 weeks), suggesting utility for pain relief and sustained drug release for future OA treatments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Biomimic Trained Immunity-MSCs Delivery Microcarriers for Acute Liver Failure Regeneration</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35411651/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35411651/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mesenchymal stem cells (MSCs) have a demonstrated value for acute liver failure (ALF) regeneration, while their delivery stratagems with long-term biological functions, low immune response, and high biocompatibility are still a challenge. Here, a lipopolysaccharide (LPS)-loaded photoresponsive cryogel porous microcarrier (CPM) for MSCs delivery and colonization is presented to promote defect liver regeneration. The CPMs are fabricated with graphene oxide, poly(N-isopropylacrylamide), and gelatin methacrylate (GelMA) via droplet microfluidic technology and a gradient-cooling procedure. Benefitting from the biocompatible GelMA component and the porous microstructure of the CPMs, MSCs can be nondestructively captured and abundantly delivered. Because the LPS can be released from the CPMs under NIR irradiation, the delivered MSCs are imparted with the feature of &amp;ldquo;trained immunity.&amp;rdquo; Thus, when the MSCs-laden CPMs are tailored into the liver matched patches by bioprinting and applied in ALF rats, they display superior anti-inflammatory and more significant liver regeneration properties than the untrained MSCs. These features make the CPMs an excellent MSCs delivery system for clinical applications in tissue repair.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Construction of a magnesium hydroxide/graphene oxide/hydroxyapatite composite coating on Mg-Ca-Zn-Ag alloy to inhibit bacterial infection and promote bone regeneration</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35415306/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35415306/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A Mg(OH)&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;/GO/HA composite coating with high bonding strength was constructed on the surface of Mg–Ca–Zn–Ag alloy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The outer HA layer with excellent osteogenic activity recovered the high corrosion resistance of inner Mg(OH)&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; layer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Mg(OH)&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;/GO/HA composite coating promoted new bone regeneration significantly under both normal and infected conditions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The improved corrosion resistance, osteogenic activity, and antibacterial ability are the key factors for promoting the large-scale clinical application of magnesium (Mg)-based implants. In the present study, a novel nanocomposite coating composed of inner magnesium hydroxide, middle graphene oxide, and outer hydroxyapatite (Mg(OH)&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;/GO/HA) is constructed on the surface of Mg-0.8Ca-5Zn-1.5Ag by a combined strategy of hydrothermal treatment, electrophoretic deposition, and electrochemical deposition. The results of material characterization and electrochemical corrosion test showed that all the three coatings have high bonding strength, hydrophilicity and corrosion resistance. In vitro studies show that Mg(OH)&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; indeed improves the antibacterial activity of the substrate. The next GO and GO/HA coating procedures both promote the osteogenic differentiation of MC3T3-E1 cells and show no harm to the antibacterial activity of Mg(OH)&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; coating, but the latter exhibits the best promoting effect. In vivo studies demonstrate that the Mg alloy with the composite coating not only ameliorates osteolysis induced by bacterial invasion but also promotes bone regeneration under both normal and infected conditions. The current study provides a promising surface modification strategy for developing multifunctional Mg-based implants with good corrosion resistance, antibacterial ability and osteogenic activity to enlarge their biomedical applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mesenchymal Stem Cell-Derived Extracellular Vesicles with High PD-L1 Expression for Autoimmune Diseases Treatment</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34613627/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34613627/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Autoimmune diseases are the third most common disease influencing the quality of life of many patients. Here, a programmed cell death-ligand 1 + (PD-L1) mesenchymal stem cell (MSC) derived extracellular vesicles (MSC-sEVs-PD-L1) using lentivirus-mediated gene transfection technology is developed for reconfiguration of the local immune microenvironment of affected tissue in autoimmune diseases. MSC-sEVs-PD-L1 exhibits an impressive ability to regulate various activated immune cells to an immunosuppressed state in vitro. More importantly, in dextran sulfate sodium-induced ulcerative colitis (UC) and imiquimod-induced psoriasis mouse models, a significantly high accumulation of MSC-sEVs-PD-L1 is observed in the inflamed tissues compared to the PD-L1+ MSCs. Therapeutic efficiency in both UC and psoriasis mouse disease models is demonstrated using MSC-sEVs-PD-L1 to reshape the inflammatory ecosystem in the local immune context. A technology is developed using MSC-sEVs-PD-L1 as a natural delivery platform for autoimmune diseases treatment with high clinical potential.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gene-engineered exosomes-thermosensitive liposomes hybrid nanovesicles by the blockade of CD47 signal for combined photothermal therapy and cancer immunotherapy</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34147721/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34147721/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CD47, overexpressed on kinds of tumor cells, activates a &amp;ldquo;don&amp;rsquo;t eat me&amp;rdquo; signal through binding to signal regulatory protein α (SIRPα), leading to immune escape from the mononuclear phagocyte system (MPS). It is also a huge challenge to deliver therapeutic drugs to the tumor sites due to the short retention time in blood, poor targeting of tumor cells and accelerated clearance by MPS. Herein, we designed a hybrid therapeutic nanovesicles, named as hGLV, by fusing gene-engineered exosomes with drug-loaded thermosensitive liposomes. We demonstrated that the CD47-overexpressed hGLV exhibited the long blood circulation and improved the macrophages-mediated the phagocytosis of tumor cells by blocking CD47 signal. Moreover, the resulted hGLV could remarkably target the homologous tumor in mice, achieving the preferential accumulation at the tumor sites. Importantly, hGLV loading the photothermal agent could achieve the excellent photothermal therapy (PTT) under laser irradiation after the intravenous injection, completely eliminating the tumors, leading to immunogenic cell death and generating substantial tumor-associated antigens, which could promote the maturation of immature dendritic cells with the help of the co-encapsulated immune adjuvant to trigger strong immune responses. Generally, the hybrid nanovesicles based on CD47 immune check point blockade can be a promising platform for the drug delivery in cancer treatment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Polyethylenimine-Modified Mesoporous Silica Nanoparticles Induce a Survival Mechanism in Vascular Endothelial Cells via Microvesicle-Mediated Autophagosome Release</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34080832/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34080832/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Surface-modified mesoporous silica nanoparticles (MSNs) have attracted more and more attention as promising materials for biomolecule delivery. However, the lack of detailed evaluation relevant to the potential cytotoxicity of these MSNs is still a major obstacle for their applications. Unlike the bare MSNs and amino- or liposome-modified MSNs, we found that polyethylenimine-modified MSNs (MSNs-PEI) had no obvious toxicity to human umbilical vein endothelial cells (HUVECs) at the concentrations up to 100 μg/mL. However, MSNs-PEI induced autophagosomes accumulation by blocking their fusion with lysosomes, an essential mechanism for the cytotoxicity of many nanoparticles (NPs). Thus, we predicted that an alternative pathway for autophagosome clearance exists in HUVECs to relieve autophagic stress induced by MSNs-PEI. We found that MSNs-PEI prevented STX17 loading onto autophagosomes instead of influencing lysosomal pH or proteolytic activity. MSNs-PEI induced the structural alternation of the cytoskeleton but did not cause endoplasmic reticulum stress. The accumulated autophagosomes were released to the extracellular space via microvesicles (MVs) when the autophagic degradation was blocked by MSNs-PEI. More importantly, blockade of either autophagosome formation or release caused the accumulation of damaged mitochondria and excessive ROS production in the MSNs-PEI-treated HUVECs, which in turn led to cell death. Thus, we propose here that the MV-mediated autophagosome release, a compensation mechanism, allows the vascular endothelial cell survival when the degradation of autophagosomes is blocked by MSNs-PEI. Accordingly, promoting the release of accumulated autophagosomes may be a protective strategy against the endothelial toxicity of NPs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Functional reconstruction of injured corpus cavernosa using 3D-printed hydrogel scaffolds seeded with HIF-1α-expressing stem cells</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32483116/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32483116/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Injury of corpus cavernosa results in erectile dysfunction, but its treatment has been very difficult. Here we construct heparin-coated 3D-printed hydrogel scaffolds seeded with hypoxia inducible factor-1α (HIF-1α)-mutated muscle-derived stem cells (MDSCs) to develop bioengineered vascularized corpora. HIF-1α-mutated MDSCs significantly secrete various angiogenic factors in MDSCs regardless of hypoxia or normoxia. The biodegradable scaffolds, along with MDSCs, are implanted into corpus cavernosa defects in a rabbit model to show good histocompatibility with no immunological rejection, support vascularized tissue ingrowth, and promote neovascularisation to repair the defects. Evaluation of morphology, intracavernosal pressure, elasticity and shrinkage of repaired cavernous tissue prove that the bioengineered corpora scaffolds repair the defects and recover penile erectile and ejaculation function successfully. The function recovery restores the reproductive capability of the injured male rabbits. Our work demonstrates that the 3D-printed hydrogels with angiogenic cells hold great promise for penile reconstruction to restore reproductive capability of males.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In situ gas foaming based on magnesium particle degradation: A novel approach to fabricate injectable macroporous hydrogels</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/31918223/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/31918223/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Injectable hydrogels are attractive biomaterials for cell delivery in tissue engineering. However, the in vivo viability of transplanted cells remains limited. Typically, macroporous structures constructed in hydrogels are utilized to enhance oxygen and nutrients diffusion for cell survival and to promote integration between the material and host tissue. A new gas-foaming method to generate pores was proposed by directly adding Mg particles into cell-laden hydrogel solutions, taking advantage of the H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; gas formed during the degradation of Mg. The optimization design of the size and amount of Mg particles added into the hydrogels was investigated. Improved cell viability and proliferation were demonstrated in the group with Mg particles. Additionally, Mg&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt; ions generated during Mg degradation facilitated the osteogenic differentiation of stem cells encapsulated in hydrogels. Extensive vascularized bone regeneration in the femoral defects of rats revealed that the use of Mg particles as the foaming agent is feasible, endowing injectable hydrogels with optimized porosity and enhanced bioactivity, and providing a new strategy for future designs of porous hydrogels in tissue engineering.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
