<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>PANoptosis | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/panoptosis/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/panoptosis/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>PANoptosis</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>PANoptosis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/panoptosis/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>SARS-CoV-2 Z-RNA activates the ZBP1-RIPK3 pathway to promote virus-induced inflammatory responses</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36650286/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36650286/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SARS-CoV-2 infection can trigger strong inflammatory responses and cause severe lung damage in COVID-19 patients with critical illness. However, the molecular mechanisms by which the infection induces excessive inflammatory responses are not fully understood. Here, we report that SARS-CoV-2 infection results in the formation of viral Z-RNA in the cytoplasm of infected cells and thereby activates the ZBP1-RIPK3 pathway. Pharmacological inhibition of RIPK3 by GSK872 or genetic deletion of MLKL reduced SARS-CoV-2-induced IL-1β release. ZBP1 or RIPK3 deficiency leads to reduced production of both inflammatory cytokines and chemokines during SARS-CoV-2 infection both in vitro and in vivo. Furthermore, deletion of ZBP1 or RIPK3 alleviated SARS-CoV-2 infection-induced immune cell infiltration and lung damage in infected mouse models. These results suggest that the ZBP1-RIPK3 pathway plays a critical role in SARS-CoV-2-induced inflammatory responses and lung damage. Our study provides novel insights into how SARS-CoV-2 infection triggers inflammatory responses and lung pathology, and implicates the therapeutic potential of targeting ZBP1-RIPK3 axis in treating COVID-19.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PANoptosis-like cell death in ischemia/reperfusion injury of retinal neurons</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35900430/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35900430/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We screened small molecules to identify two compounds, which we named RSL3 and RSL5, that have increased lethality in the presence of oncogenic RAS. Counter screening with biologically active compounds defined aspects of the mechanism of action for RSL3 and RSL5, such as a nonapoptotic, MEK-dependent, and iron-dependent oxidative cell death. Erastin, a previously reported compound with RAS-selective lethality, showed similar properties. RNA interference experiments targeting voltage-dependent anion channel 3 (VDAC3), a target of erastin, demonstrated that RSL5 is a scaffold that acts through VDACs to activate the observed pathway. RSL3 activated a similar death mechanism but in a VDAC-independent manner. We found that cells transformed with oncogenic RAS have increased iron content relative to their normal cell counterparts through upregulation of transferrin receptor 1 and downregulation of ferritin heavy chain 1 and ferritin light chain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FUNDC1 protects against doxorubicin-induced cardiomyocyte PANoptosis through stabilizing mtDNA via interaction with TUFM</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36470869/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36470869/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Doxorubicin (DOX) is an effective anthracycline chemotherapeutic anticancer drug with its life-threatening cardiotoxicity severely limiting its clinical application. Mitochondrial damage-induced cardiomyocyte death is considered an essential cue for DOX cardiotoxicity. FUN14 domain containing 1 (FUNDC1) is a mitochondrial membrane protein participating in the regulation of mitochondrial integrity in multiple diseases although its role in DOX cardiomyopathy remains elusive. Here, we examined whether PANoptosis, a novel type of programmed cell death closely associated with mitochondrial damage, was involved in DOX-induced heart injury, and FUNDC1-mediated regulation of cardiomyocyte PANoptosis, if any. FUNDC1 was downregulated in heart tissues in patients with dilated cardiomyopathy (DCM) and DOX-challenged mice. FUNDC1 deficiency aggravated DOX-induced cardiac dysfunction, mitochondrial injury, and cardiomyocyte PANoptosis. Further examination revealed that FUNDC1 countered cytoplasmic release of mitochondrial DNA (mtDNA) and activation of PANoptosome through interaction with mitochondrial Tu translation elongation factor (TUFM), a key factor in the translational expression and repair of mitochondrial DNA, via its 96-133 amino acid domain. TUFM intervention reversed FUNDC1-elicited protection against DOX-induced mtDNA cytosolic release and cardiomyocyte PANoptosis. Our findings shed light toward a beneficial role of FUNDC1 in DOX cardiotoxicity and cardiomyocyte PANoptosis, thus offering therapeutic promises in DOX-induced cardiotoxicity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ferroptosis inhibitor liproxstatin-1 alleviates metabolic dysfunction-associated fatty liver disease in mice: potential involvement of PANoptosis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36323829/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36323829/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ferroptosis is a new form of regulated cell death characterized by excessive iron accumulation and uncontrollable lipid peroxidation. The role of ferroptosis in metabolic dysfunction-associated fatty liver disease (MAFLD) is not fully elucidated. In this study we compared the therapeutic effects of ferroptosis inhibitor liproxstatin-1 (LPT1) and iron chelator deferiprone (DFP) in MAFLD mouse models. This model was established in mice by feeding a high-fat diet with 30% fructose in water (HFHF) for 16 weeks. The mice then received LPT1 (10 mg·kg&lt;sup&gt;-1&lt;/sup&gt;·d&lt;sup&gt;-1&lt;/sup&gt;, ip) or DFP (100 mg·kg&lt;sup&gt;-1&lt;/sup&gt;·d&lt;sup&gt;-1&lt;/sup&gt;, ig) for another 2 weeks. We showed that both LPT1 and DFP treatment blocked the ferroptosis markers ACSL4 and ALOX15 in MAFLD mice. Furthermore, LPT1 treatment significantly reduced the liver levels of triglycerides and cholesterol, lipid peroxidation markers 4-hydroxynonenal (4-HNE) and malondialdehyde (MDA), and ameliorated the expression of lipid synthesis/oxidation genes (Pparα, Scd1, Fasn, Hmgcr and Cpt1a), insulin resistance, mitochondrial ROS content and liver fibrosis. Importantly, LPT1 treatment potently inhibited hepatic apoptosis (Bax/Bcl-xL ratio and TUNEL+ cell number), pyroptosis (cleavages of Caspase-1 and GSDMD) and necroptosis (phosphorylation of MLKL). Moreover, LPT1 treatment markedly inhibited cleavages of PANoptosis-related caspase-8 and caspase-6 in MAFLD mouse liver. In an in vitro MAFLD model, treatment with LPT1 (100 nM) prevented cultured hepatocyte against cell death induced by pro-PANoptosis molecules (TNF-α, LPS and nigericin) upon lipid stress. On the contrary, DFP treatment only mildly attenuated hepatic inflammation but failed to alleviate lipid deposition, insulin resistance, apoptosis, pyroptosis and necroptosis in MAFLD mice. We conclude that ferroptosis inhibitor LPT1 protects against steatosis and steatohepatitis in MAFLD mice, which may involve regulation of PANoptosis, a coordinated cell death pathway that involves apoptosis, pyroptosis and necroptosis. These results suggest a potential link between ferroptosis and PANoptosis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PANoptosis: A Unique Innate Immune Inflammatory Cell Death Modality</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/36253067/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/36253067/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Innate immunity is the first response to protect against pathogens and cellular insults. Pattern recognition receptors sense pathogen- and damage-associated molecular patterns and induce an innate immune response characterized by inflammation and programmed cell death (PCD). In-depth characterization of innate immune PCD pathways has highlighted significant cross-talk. Recent advances led to the identification of a unique inflammatory PCD modality called PANoptosis, which is regulated by multifaceted PANoptosome complexes that are assembled by integrating components from other PCD pathways. The totality of biological effects observed in PANoptosis cannot be accounted for by any other PCD pathway alone. In this review, we briefly describe mechanisms of innate immune cell death, including molecular mechanisms of PANoptosis activation and regulation. We also highlight the PANoptosomes identified to date and provide an overview of the implications of PANoptosis in disease and therapeutic targeting. Improved understanding of innate immune-mediated cell death, PANoptosis, is critical to inform the next generation of treatment strategies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Caspase-1 Inhibition Reduces Occurrence of PANoptosis in Macrophages Infected by E. faecalis OG1RF</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36294525/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36294525/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To investigate the effect of caspase-1 inhibition on PANoptosis in macrophages infected with &lt;em&gt;Enterococcus faecalis&lt;/em&gt; OG1RF. RAW264.7 cells with and without pretreatment by caspase-1 inhibitor were infected with &lt;em&gt;E. faecalis&lt;/em&gt; OG1RF at multiplicities of infection (MOIs). A live cell imaging analysis system and Western blot were applied to evaluate the dynamic curve of cell death and the expression of executor proteins of PANoptosis. The mRNA expression of &lt;em&gt;IL-1β&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;IL-18&lt;/em&gt; was quantified by RT-qPCR. Morphological changes were observed under scanning electron microscopy. We found that PI-positive cells emerged earlier and peaked at a faster rate in &lt;em&gt;E. faecalis&lt;/em&gt;-infected macrophages (Ef-MPs) at higher MOIs. The expression of the N-terminal domain of the effector protein gasdermin D (GSDMD-N), cleaved caspase-3 and pMLKL were significantly upregulated at MOIs of 10:1 at 6 h and at MOI of 1:1 at 12 h postinfection. In Ef-MPs pretreated with caspase-1 inhibitor, the number of PI-positive cells was significantly reduced, and the expression of &lt;em&gt;IL-1β&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;IL-18&lt;/em&gt; genes and cleaved caspase-1/-3 and GSDMD-N proteins was significantly downregulated (&lt;em&gt;p&lt;/em&gt; &amp;lt; 0.05), while pMLKL was still markedly increased (&lt;em&gt;p&lt;/em&gt; &amp;lt; 0.05). Ef-MPs remained relatively intact with caspase-1 inhibitor. In conclusion, &lt;em&gt;E. faecalis&lt;/em&gt; induced cell death in macrophages in an MOI-dependent manner. Caspase-1 inhibitor simultaneously inhibited pyroptosis and apoptosis in Ef-MPs, but necroptosis still occurred.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Molecular mechanism of RIPK1 and caspase-8 in homeostatic type I interferon production and regulation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36198273/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36198273/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Caspase-8 regulates tonic type I IFN in homeostasis through the RIPK1-TBK1 axis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Caspase-8 inhibits the interaction between RIPK1 and TBK1 to regulate type I IFN&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When caspase-8 is absent, RIPK1 drives pathogenic IFN production and lymphadenopathy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RIPK1-mediated IFN leads to natural viral resistance when caspase-8 is absent&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Type I interferons (IFNs) are essential innate immune proteins that maintain tissue homeostasis through tonic expression and can be upregulated to drive antiviral resistance and inflammation upon stimulation. However, the mechanisms that inhibit aberrant IFN upregulation in homeostasis and the impacts of tonic IFN production on health and disease remain enigmatic. Here, we report that caspase-8 negatively regulates type I IFN production by inhibiting the RIPK1-TBK1 axis during homeostasis across multiple cell types and tissues. When caspase-8 is deleted or inhibited, RIPK1 interacts with TBK1 to drive elevated IFN production, leading to heightened resistance to norovirus infection in macrophages but also early onset lymphadenopathy in mice. Combined deletion of caspase-8 and RIPK1 reduces the type I IFN signaling and lymphadenopathy, highlighting the critical role of RIPK1 in this process. Overall, our study identifies a mechanism to constrain tonic type I IFN during homeostasis which could be targeted for infectious and inflammatory diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Single cell analysis of PANoptosome cell death complexes through an expansion microscopy method</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36169732/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36169732/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In response to infection or sterile insults, inflammatory programmed cell death is an essential component of the innate immune response to remove infected or damaged cells. PANoptosis is a unique innate immune inflammatory cell death pathway regulated by multifaceted macromolecular complexes called PANoptosomes, which integrate components from other cell death pathways. Growing evidence shows that PANoptosis can be triggered in many physiological conditions, including viral and bacterial infections, cytokine storms, and cancers. However, PANoptosomes at the single cell level have not yet been fully characterized. Initial investigations have suggested that key pyroptotic, apoptotic, and necroptotic molecules including the inflammasome adaptor protein ASC, apoptotic caspase-8 (CASP8), and necroptotic RIPK3 are conserved components of PANoptosomes. Here, we optimized an immunofluorescence procedure to probe the highly dynamic multiprotein PANoptosome complexes across various innate immune cell death-inducing conditions. We first identified and validated antibodies to stain endogenous mouse ASC, CASP8, and RIPK3, without residual staining in the respective knockout cells. We then assessed the formation of PANoptosomes across innate immune cell death-inducing conditions by monitoring the colocalization of ASC with CASP8 and/or RIPK3. Finally, we established an expansion microscopy procedure using these validated antibodies to image the organization of ASC, CASP8, and RIPK3 within the PANoptosome. This optimized protocol, which can be easily adapted to study other multiprotein complexes and other cell death triggers, provides confirmation of PANoptosome assembly in individual cells and forms the foundation for a deeper molecular understanding of the PANoptosome complex and PANoptosis to facilitate therapeutic targeting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anti-PANoptosis is involved in neuroprotective effects of melatonin in acute ocular hypertension model</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36031799/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36031799/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acute ocular hypertension (AOH) is the most important characteristic of acute glaucoma, which can lead to retinal ganglion cell (RGC) death and permanent vision loss. So far, approved effective therapy is still lacking in acute glaucoma. PANoptosis (pyroptosis, apoptosis, and necroptosis), which consists of three key modes of programmed cell death-apoptosis, necroptosis, and pyroptosis-may contribute to AOH-induced RGC death. Previous studies have demonstrated that melatonin (N-acetyl-5-methoxytryptamine) exerts a neuroprotective effect in many retinal degenerative diseases. However, whether melatonin is anti-PANoptotic and neuroprotective in the progression of acute glaucoma remains unclear. Thus, this study aimed to explore the role of melatonin in AOH retinas and its underlying mechanisms. The results showed that melatonin treatment attenuated the loss of ganglion cell complex thickness, retinal nerve fiber layer thickness, and RGC after AOH injury, and improved the amplitudes of a-wave, b-wave, and oscillatory potentials in the electroretinogram. Additionally, the number of terminal deoxynucleotidyl transferase dUTP nick-end labeling-positive cells was decreased, and the upregulation of cleaved caspase-8, cleaved caspase-3, Bax, and Bad and downregulation of Bcl-2 and p-Bad were inhibited after melatonin administration. Meanwhile, both the expression and activation of MLKL, RIP1, and RIP3, along with the number of PI-positive cells, were reduced in melatonin-treated mice, and p-RIP3 was in both RGC and microglia/macrophage after AOH injury. Furthermore, melatonin reduced the expression of NLRP3, ASC, cleaved caspase-1, gasdermin D (GSDMD), and cleaved GSDMD, and decreased the number of Iba1/interleukin-1β-positive cells. In conclusion, melatonin ameliorated retinal structure, prevented retinal dysfunction after AOH, and exerted a neuroprotective effect via inhibition of PANoptosis in AOH retinas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Innate Immune Cell Death in Neuroinflammation and Alzheimer&#39;s Disease</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/35741014/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/35741014/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alzheimer&amp;rsquo;s disease (AD) is a neurodegenerative disorder molecularly characterized by the formation of amyloid β (Aβ) plaques and type 2 microtubule-associated protein (Tau) abnormalities. Multiple studies have shown that many of the brain&amp;rsquo;s immunological cells, specifically microglia and astrocytes, are involved in AD pathogenesis. Cells of the innate immune system play an essential role in eliminating pathogens but also regulate brain homeostasis and AD. When activated, innate immune cells can cause programmed cell death through multiple pathways, including pyroptosis, apoptosis, necroptosis, and PANoptosis. The cell death often results in the release of proinflammatory cytokines that propagate the innate immune response and can eliminate Aβ plaques and aggregated Tau proteins. However, chronic neuroinflammation, which can result from cell death, has been linked to neurodegenerative diseases and can worsen AD. Therefore, the innate immune response must be tightly balanced to appropriately clear these AD-related structural abnormalities without inducing chronic neuroinflammation. In this review, we discuss neuroinflammation, innate immune responses, inflammatory cell death pathways, and cytokine secretion as they relate to AD. Therapeutic strategies targeting these innate immune cell death mechanisms will be critical to consider for future preventive or palliative treatments for AD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ZBP1-dependent inflammatory cell death, PANoptosis, and cytokine storm disrupt IFN therapeutic efficacy during coronavirus infection</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35587515/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35587515/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ZBP1 fans the flames of cytokine storm&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Type I interferons (IFNs) provide robust innate immune protection against β-coronaviruses including SARS-CoV-2 when available soon after infection. Paradoxically, therapeutic use of type I IFNs in patients with severe COVID-19 may promote increased pathology and clinical deterioration. Using a mouse model of respiratory β-coronavirus infection with mouse hepatitis virus (MHV), Karki et al. found that the detrimental effects of type I IFNs in later stages of infection were related to IFN-induced expression of ZBP1, an innate immune sensor also capable of inducing PANoptosis, an inflammatory form of cell death. Mice lacking ZBP1 were protected from IFN-induced lethality in the MHV infection model. These findings suggest that ZBP1 could be targeted therapeutically in severe COVID-19 to ward off deleterious effects of type I IFNs including cytokine storm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 (SARS-CoV-2), the virus responsible for coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19), continues to cause substantial morbidity and mortality in the ongoing global pandemic. Understanding the fundamental mechanisms that govern innate immune and inflammatory responses during SARS-CoV-2 infection is critical for developing effective therapeutic strategies. Whereas interferon (IFN)-based therapies are generally expected to be beneficial during viral infection, clinical trials in COVID-19 have shown limited efficacy and potential detrimental effects of IFN treatment during SARS-CoV-2 infection. However, the underlying mechanisms responsible for this failure remain unknown. In this study, we found that IFN induced Z-DNA-binding protein 1 (ZBP1)-mediated inflammatory cell death, PANoptosis, in human and murine macrophages and in the lungs of mice infected with β-coronaviruses, including SARS-CoV-2 and mouse hepatitis virus (MHV). In patients with COVID-19, expression of the innate immune sensor &lt;em&gt;ZBP1&lt;/em&gt; was increased in immune cells from those who succumbed to the disease compared with those who recovered, further suggesting a link between ZBP1 and pathology. In mice, IFN-β treatment after β-coronavirus infection increased lethality, and genetic deletion of &lt;em&gt;Zbp1&lt;/em&gt; or its Zα domain suppressed cell death and protected the mice from IFN-mediated lethality during β-coronavirus infection. Overall, our results identify that ZBP1 induced during coronavirus infection limits the efficacy of IFN therapy by driving inflammatory cell death and lethality. Therefore, inhibiting ZBP1 activity may improve the efficacy of IFN therapy, paving the way for the development of new and critically needed therapeutics for COVID-19 as well as other infections and inflammatory conditions where IFN-mediated cell death and pathology occur.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MiR-29a-3p Improves Acute Lung Injury by Reducing Alveolar Epithelial Cell PANoptosis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35656115/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35656115/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alveolar epithelial cell damage is an important determinant of the severity of acute lung injury/acute respiratory distress syndrome (ALI/ARDS). However, the molecular mechanisms of alveolar epithelial death during the development of ALI/ARDS remain unclear. In this study, we explore the role of miR-29a-3p in ALI/ARDS and its molecular mechanism. Plasma samples were collected from healthy controls and ARDS patients. Mice were intratracheally instilled with lipopolysaccharide (LPS) to establish acute lung injury. N6-adenosine (m6A) quantification, RNA-binding protein immunoprecipitation, cell viability assay, quantitative real-time polymerase chain reaction, and western blotting were performed. We found that miR-29a-3p was down-regulated in plasma of ARDS patients and lung tissue of ALI model mice, and miR-29a-3p agomir injection down-regulated the levels of the inflammatory factors, including tumor necrosis factor-α (TNF-α), interleukin-1β (IL-1β), and interleukin-6 (IL-6) in the lungs, reducing alveolar epithelial cell PANoptosis as evaluated by the downregulation of Z-DNA binding protein 1 (ZBP1), gasdermin D (GSDMD), caspase-3, caspase-8, and mixed lineage kinase domain-like protein (MLKL), ultimately improving lung injury in the ALI model mice. Mechanism studies demonstrated that the knockout of methyltransferase 3 (N6-adenosine-methyltransferase complex catalytic subunit) removed the m6A modification of miR-29a-3p and reduced miR-29a-3p expression. Our findings suggest that miR-29a-3p is a potential target that can be manipulated for ALI/ARDS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analysis of PANoptosis-Related LncRNA-miRNA-mRNA Network Reveals LncRNA SNHG7 Involved in Chemo-Resistance in Colon Adenocarcinoma</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35646635/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35646635/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Colon adenocarcinoma (COAD) is one of the most common malignancies, and its metastatic lesions are the leading cause of death in COAD patients. PANoptosis is a recently identified pathway for programmed cell death implicated in developing COAD. Long non-coding RNAs (lncRNAs) are key regulators of cancer occurrence and progress. Although their function has captured much attention in COAD, the relationship between COAD metastasis-associated lncRNA expression and PANoptosis remains elusive. Therefore, this study aimed to explore the potential regulatory roles of metastasis- and PANoptosis-associated lncRNAs in COAD. Nine lncRNAs associated with metastasis and PANoptosis in COAD were identified from The Cancer Genome Atlas (TCGA) and GEO databases. Their functions were analyzed by multiple bioinformatics methods, and the lncRNA-miRNA-mRNA network was constructed. Multivariate Cox analysis identified one lncRNA (SNHG7) significantly related to COAD prognosis. Subsequent analyses showed its expression correlated with tumor stage and lymph node metastasis. Moreover, drug sensitivity analysis and in vitro experiments suggest that lncRNA SNHG7 contributes to drug resistance in COAD. In summary, lncRNA SNHG7 is a potential target for diagnosing and treating COAD and plays a crucial role in regulating apoptosis, metastasis, and drug resistance in COAD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DEAD/H-Box Helicases in Immunity, Inflammation, Cell Differentiation, and Cell Death and Disease</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/35626643/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/35626643/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DEAD/H-box proteins are the largest family of RNA helicases in mammalian genomes, and they are present in all kingdoms of life. Since their discovery in the late 1980s, DEAD/H-box family proteins have been a major focus of study. They have been found to play central roles in RNA metabolism, gene expression, signal transduction, programmed cell death, and the immune response to bacterial and viral infections. Aberrant functions of DEAD/H-box proteins have been implicated in a wide range of human diseases that include cancer, neurodegeneration, and inherited genetic disorders. In this review, we provide a historical context and discuss the molecular functions of DEAD/H-box proteins, highlighting the recent discoveries linking their dysregulation to human diseases. We will also discuss the state of knowledge regarding two specific DEAD/H-box proteins that have critical roles in immune responses and programmed cell death, DDX3X and DDX58, also known as RIG-I. Given their importance in homeostasis and disease, an improved understanding of DEAD/H-box protein biology and protein-protein interactions will be critical for informing strategies to counteract the pathogenesis associated with several human diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It&#39;s All in the PAN: Crosstalk, Plasticity, Redundancies, Switches, and Interconnectedness Encompassed by PANoptosis Underlying the Totality of Cell Death-Associated Biological Effects</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/35563804/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/35563804/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The innate immune system provides the first line of defense against cellular perturbations. Innate immune activation elicits inflammatory programmed cell death in response to microbial infections or alterations in cellular homeostasis. Among the most well-characterized programmed cell death pathways are pyroptosis, apoptosis, and necroptosis. While these pathways have historically been defined as segregated and independent processes, mounting evidence shows significant crosstalk among them. These molecular interactions have been described as &amp;lsquo;crosstalk&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;plasticity&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;redundancies&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;molecular switches&amp;rsquo;, and more. Here, we discuss the key components of cell death pathways and note several examples of crosstalk. We then explain how the diverse descriptions of crosstalk throughout the literature can be interpreted through the lens of an integrated inflammatory cell death concept, PANoptosis. The totality of biological effects in PANoptosis cannot be individually accounted for by pyroptosis, apoptosis, or necroptosis alone. We also discuss PANoptosomes, which are multifaceted macromolecular complexes that regulate PANoptosis. We consider the evidence for PANoptosis, which has been mechanistically characterized during influenza A virus, herpes simplex virus 1, Francisella novicida, and Yersinia infections, as well as in response to altered cellular homeostasis, in inflammatory diseases, and in cancers. We further discuss the role of IRF1 as an upstream regulator of PANoptosis and conclude by reexamining historical studies which lend credence to the PANoptosis concept. Cell death has been shown to play a critical role in infections, inflammatory diseases, neurodegenerative diseases, cancers, and more; therefore, having a holistic understanding of cell death is important for identifying new therapeutic strategies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>STING agonist diABZI induces PANoptosis and DNA mediated acute respiratory distress syndrome (ARDS)</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35338116/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35338116/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stimulator of interferon genes (STING) contributes to immune responses against tumors and may control viral infection including SARS-CoV-2 infection. However, activation of the STING pathway by airway silica or smoke exposure leads to cell death, self-dsDNA release, and STING/type I IFN dependent acute lung inflammation/ARDS. The inflammatory response induced by a synthetic non-nucleotide-based diABZI STING agonist, in comparison to the natural cyclic dinucleotide cGAMP, is unknown. A low dose of diABZI (1 µg by endotracheal route for 3 consecutive days) triggered an acute neutrophilic inflammation, disruption of the respiratory barrier, DNA release with NET formation, PANoptosis cell death, and inflammatory cytokines with type I IFN dependent acute lung inflammation. Downstream upregulation of DNA sensors including cGAS, DDX41, IFI204, as well as NLRP3 and AIM2 inflammasomes, suggested a secondary inflammatory response to dsDNA as a danger signal. DNase I treatment, inhibition of NET formation together with an investigation in gene-deficient mice highlighted extracellular DNA and TLR9, but not cGAS, as central to diABZI-induced neutrophilic response. Therefore, activation of acute cell death with DNA release may lead to ARDS which may be modeled by diABZI. These results show that airway targeting by STING activator as a therapeutic strategy for infection may enhance lung inflammation with severe ARDS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From pyroptosis, apoptosis and necroptosis to PANoptosis: A mechanistic compendium of programmed cell death pathways</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/34504660/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/34504660/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pyroptosis, apoptosis and necroptosis are the most genetically well-defined programmed cell death (PCD) pathways, and they are intricately involved in both homeostasis and disease. Although the identification of key initiators, effectors and executioners in each of these three PCD pathways has historically delineated them as distinct, growing evidence has highlighted extensive crosstalk among them. These observations have led to the establishment of the concept of PANoptosis, defined as an inflammatory PCD pathway regulated by the PANoptosome complex with key features of pyroptosis, apoptosis and/or necroptosis that cannot be accounted for by any of these PCD pathways alone. In this review, we provide a brief overview of the research history of pyroptosis, apoptosis and necroptosis. We then examine the intricate crosstalk among these PCD pathways to discuss the current evidence for PANoptosis. We also detail the molecular evidence for the assembly of the PANoptosome complex, a molecular scaffold for contemporaneous engagement of key molecules from pyroptosis, apoptosis, and/or necroptosis. PANoptosis is now known to be critically involved in many diseases, including infection, sterile inflammation and cancer, and future discovery of novel PANoptotic components will continue to broaden our understanding of the fundamental processes of cell death and inform the development of new therapeutics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Role of inflammasomes/pyroptosis and PANoptosis during fungal infection</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/33735255/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/33735255/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No abstract available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PANoptosis in microbial infection</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/32829024/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/32829024/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The immune system has evolved multiple mechanisms to restrict microbial infections and regulate inflammatory responses. Without appropriate regulation, infection-induced inflammatory pathology can be deadly. The innate immune system recognizes the microbial molecules conserved in many pathogens and engages a rapid response by producing inflammatory mediators and activating programmed cell death pathways, including pyroptosis, apoptosis, and necroptosis. Activation of pattern recognition receptors, in combination with inflammatory cytokine-induced signaling through death domain-containing receptors, initiates a highly interconnected cell death process called PANoptosis (pyroptosis, apoptosis, necroptosis). Broadly speaking, PANoptosis is critical for restricting a wide range of pathogens (including bacteria, viruses, fungi, and parasites), which we describe in this review. We propose that re-examining the role of cell death and inflammatory cytokines through the lens of PANoptosis will advance our understanding of host-pathogen evolution and may reveal new treatment strategies for controlling a wide range of infectious diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interferon regulatory factor 1 regulates PANoptosis to prevent colorectal cancer</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32554929/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32554929/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interferon regulatory factor 1 (IRF1) regulates diverse biological functions, including modulation of cellular responses involved in tumorigenesis. Genetic mutations and altered IRF1 function are associated with several cancers. Although the function of IRF1 in the immunobiology of cancer is emerging, IRF1-specific mechanisms regulating tumorigenesis and tissue homeostasis in vivo are not clear. Here, we found that mice lacking IRF1 were hypersusceptible to colorectal tumorigenesis. IRF1 functions in both the myeloid and epithelial compartments to confer protection against AOM/DSS-induced colorectal tumorigenesis. We further found that IRF1 also prevents tumorigenesis in a spontaneous mouse model of colorectal cancer. The attenuated cell death in the colons of Irf1-/- mice was due to defective pyroptosis, apoptosis, and necroptosis (PANoptosis). IRF1 does not regulate inflammation and the inflammasome in the colon. Overall, our study identified IRF1 as an upstream regulator of PANoptosis to induce cell death during colitis-associated tumorigenesis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The PANoptosome: A Deadly Protein Complex Driving Pyroptosis, Apoptosis, and Necroptosis (PANoptosis)</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/32582562/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/32582562/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Programmed cell death is regulated by evolutionarily conserved pathways that play critical roles in development and the immune response. A newly recognized pathway for proinflammatory programmed cell death called PANoptosis is controlled by a recently identified cytoplasmic multimeric protein complex named the PANoptosome. The PANoptosome can engage, in parallel, three key modes of programmed cell death-pyroptosis, apoptosis, and necroptosis. The PANoptosome components have been implicated in a wide array of human diseases including autoinflammatory diseases, neurodegenerative diseases, cancer, microbial infections, and metabolic diseases. Here, we review putative components of the PANoptosome and present a phylogenetic analysis of their molecular domains and interaction motifs that support complex assembly. We also discuss genetic data that suggest PANoptosis is coordinated by scaffolding and catalytic functions of the complex components and propose mechanistic models for PANoptosome assembly. Overall, this review presents potential mechanisms governing PANoptosis based on evolutionary analysis of the PANoptosome components.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Identification of the PANoptosome: A Molecular Platform Triggering Pyroptosis, Apoptosis, and Necroptosis (PANoptosis)</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32547960/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32547960/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Programmed cell death plays crucial roles in organismal development and host defense. Recent studies have highlighted mechanistic overlaps and extensive, multifaceted crosstalk between pyroptosis, apoptosis, and necroptosis, three programmed cell death pathways traditionally considered autonomous. The growing body of evidence, in conjunction with the identification of molecules controlling the concomitant activation of all three pathways by pathological triggers, has led to the development of the concept of PANoptosis. During PANoptosis, inflammatory cell death occurs through the collective activation of pyroptosis, apoptosis, and necroptosis, which can circumvent pathogen-mediated inhibition of individual death pathways. Many of the molecular details of this emerging pathway are unclear. Here, we describe the activation of PANoptosis by bacterial and viral triggers and report protein interactions that reveal the formation of a PANoptosome complex. Infection of macrophages with influenza A virus, vesicular stomatitis virus, Listeria monocytogenes, or Salmonella enterica serovar Typhimurium resulted in robust cell death and the hallmarks of PANoptosis activation. Combined deletion of the PANoptotic components caspase-1 (CASP1), CASP11, receptor-interacting serine/threonine-protein kinase 3 (RIPK3), and CASP8 largely protected macrophages from cell death induced by these pathogens, while deletion of individual components provided reduced or no protection. Further, molecules from the pyroptotic, apoptotic, and necroptotic cell death pathways interacted to form a single molecular complex that we have termed the PANoptosome. Overall, our study identifies pathogens capable of activating PANoptosis and the formation of a PANoptosome complex.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Caspases in Cell Death, Inflammation, and Pyroptosis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/32017655/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/32017655/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Caspases are a family of conserved cysteine proteases that play key roles in programmed cell death and inflammation. In multicellular organisms, caspases are activated via macromolecular signaling complexes that bring inactive procaspases together and promote their proximity-induced autoactivation and proteolytic processing. Activation of caspases ultimately results in programmed execution of cell death, and the nature of this cell death is determined by the specific caspases involved. Pioneering new research has unraveled distinct roles and cross talk of caspases in the regulation of programmed cell death, inflammation, and innate immune responses. In-depth understanding of these mechanisms is essential to foster the development of precise therapeutic targets to treat autoinflammatory disorders, infectious diseases, and cancer. This review focuses on mechanisms governing caspase activation and programmed cell death with special emphasis on the recent progress in caspase cross talk and caspase-driven gasdermin D-induced pyroptosis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
