<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Matrix | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/matrix/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/matrix/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Matrix</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Matrix</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/matrix/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pancreatic cancer cells upregulate LPAR4 in response to isolation stress to promote an ECM-enriched niche and support tumour initiation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36646789/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36646789/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Defining drivers of tumour initiation can provide opportunities to control cancer progression. Here we report that lysophosphatidic acid receptor 4 (LPAR4) becomes transiently upregulated on pancreatic cancer cells exposed to environmental stress or chemotherapy where it promotes stress tolerance, drug resistance, self-renewal and tumour initiation. Pancreatic cancer cells gain LPAR4 expression in response to stress by downregulating a tumour suppressor, miR-139-5p. Even in the absence of exogenous lysophosphatidic acid, LPAR4-expressing tumour cells display an enrichment of extracellular matrix genes that are established drivers of cancer stemness. Mechanistically, upregulation of fibronectin via an LPAR4/AKT/CREB axis is indispensable for LPAR4-induced tumour initiation and stress tolerance. Moreover, ligation of this fibronectin-containing matrix via integrins α5β1 or αVβ3 can transfer stress tolerance to LPAR4-negative cells. Therefore, stress- or drug-induced LPAR4 enhances cell-autonomous production of a fibronectin-rich extracellular matrix, allowing cells to survive ‘isolation stress’ and compensate for the absence of stromal-derived factors by creating their own tumour-initiating niche.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Increased expression and accumulation of GDF15 in IPF extracellular matrix contribute to fibrosis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35993367/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35993367/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis (IPF) is a chronic disease of unmet medical need. It is characterized by formation of scar tissue leading to a progressive and irreversible decline in lung function. IPF is associated with repeated injury, which may alter the composition of the extracellular matrix (ECM). Here, we demonstrate that IPF patient-derived pulmonary ECM drives profibrotic response in normal human lung fibroblasts (NHLF) in a 3D spheroid assay. Next, we reveal distinct alterations in composition of the diseased ECM, identifying potentially novel associations with IPF. Growth differentiation factor 15 (GDF15) was identified among the most significantly upregulated proteins in the IPF lung-derived ECM. In vivo, GDF15 neutralization in a bleomycin-induced lung fibrosis model led to significantly less fibrosis. In vitro, recombinant GDF15 (rGDF15) stimulated α smooth muscle actin (αSMA) expression in NHLF, and this was mediated by the activin receptor-like kinase 5 (ALK5) receptor. Furthermore, in the presence of rGDF15, the migration of NHLF in collagen gel was reduced. In addition, we observed a cell type-dependent effect of GDF15 on the expression of cell senescence markers. Our data suggest that GDF15 mediates lung fibrosis through fibroblast activation and differentiation, implicating a potential direct role of this matrix-associated cytokine in promoting aberrant cell responses in disease.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Complementary Nck1/2 Signaling in Podocytes Controls α Actinin-4-Mediated Actin Organization, Adhesion, and Basement Membrane Composition</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35906089/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35906089/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Maintenance of the kidney filtration barrier requires coordinated interactions between podocytes and the underlying glomerular basement membrane (GBM). GBM ligands bind podocyte integrins, which triggers actin-based signaling events critical for adhesion. Nck1/2 adaptors have emerged as essential regulators of podocyte cytoskeletal dynamics. However, the precise signaling mechanisms mediated by Nck1/2 adaptors in podocytes remain to be fully elucidated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; We generated podocytes deficient in Nck1 and Nck2 and used transcriptomic approaches to profile expression differences. Proteomic techniques identified specific binding partners for Nck1 and Nck2 in podocytes. We used cultured podocytes and mice deficient in Nck1 and/or Nck2, along with podocyte injury models, to comprehensively verify our findings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; Compound loss of Nck1/2 altered expression of genes involved in actin binding, cell adhesion, and extracellular matrix composition. Accordingly, Nck1/2-deficient podocytes showed defects in actin organization and cell adhesion &lt;em&gt;in vitro&lt;/em&gt;, with podocyte detachment and altered GBM morphology present &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt;. We identified distinct interactomes for Nck1 and Nck2 and uncovered a mechanism by which Nck1 and Nck2 cooperate to regulate actin bundling at focal adhesions via α actinin-4. Furthermore, loss of Nck1 or Nck2 resulted in increased matrix deposition &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt;, with more prominent defects in Nck2-deficient mice, consistent with enhanced susceptibility to podocyte injury.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/em&gt; These findings reveal distinct, yet complementary, roles for Nck proteins in regulating podocyte adhesion, controlling GBM composition, and sustaining filtration barrier integrity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cartilaginous Extracellular Matrix Enriched with Human Gingival Mesenchymal Stem Cells Derived &#39;Matrix Bound Extracellular Vesicles&#39; Enabled Functional Reconstruction of Tracheal Defect</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34841733/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34841733/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stem cells derived extracellular vesicles (EVs) conceive cues essential for tissue repair. Mammalian cartilaginous extracellular matrix (cECM) may not be optimally inductive for tracheal regeneration because of the granulomatous, instead of regenerative, responses in injured adult mammalian tracheas. Given the high regenerative capacity of gingiva, it is hypothesized human gingival mesenchymal stem cells derived EVs (gEVs) can induce mammalian tracheal epithelia regeneration. Coculturing chondrocytes with GMSCs produce abundant &amp;ldquo;matrix bound gEVs (gMVs)&amp;rdquo; in forming cartilaginous ECM, which are further preserved in acellular cECM (cACM) following mild, short-period decellularization. The results show that gMVs-cACM could be well anchored on polyglycerol sebacate microporous patch thus enforce the surgical suturability and mechanical strength. In rabbit tracheal defect, the gMVs-cACM patch induces rapid regeneration of vascularized ciliated columnar epithelium, which supports long-term survival of animals. gMVs-cACM treated groups exhibit proliferation of tracheal progenitors-basal epithelial cells, as well as, activation of JAK2/STAT1 pathway in reparative cells. This study departs from conventional focuses on tissue derived ECM and introduces a new approach for tracheal tissue regeneration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Highway to heal: Influence of altered extracellular matrix on infiltrating immune cells during acute and chronic lung diseases</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/36408219/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/36408219/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Environmental insults including respiratory infections, in combination with genetic predisposition, may lead to lung diseases such as chronic obstructive pulmonary disease, lung fibrosis, asthma, and acute respiratory distress syndrome. Common characteristics of these diseases are infiltration and activation of inflammatory cells and abnormal extracellular matrix (ECM) turnover, leading to tissue damage and impairments in lung function. The ECM provides three-dimensional (3D) architectural support to the lung and crucial biochemical and biophysical cues to the cells, directing cellular processes. As immune cells travel to reach any site of injury, they encounter the composition and various mechanical features of the ECM. Emerging evidence demonstrates the crucial role played by the local environment in recruiting immune cells and their function in lung diseases. Moreover, recent developments in the field have elucidated considerable differences in responses of immune cells in two-dimensional versus 3D modeling systems. Examining the effect of individual parameters of the ECM to study their effect independently and collectively in a 3D microenvironment will help in better understanding disease pathobiology. In this article, we discuss the importance of investigating cellular migration and recent advances in this field. Moreover, we summarize changes in the ECM in lung diseases and the potential impacts on infiltrating immune cell migration in these diseases. There has been compelling progress in this field that encourages further developments, such as advanced in vitro 3D modeling using native ECM-based models, patient-derived materials, and bioprinting. We conclude with an overview of these state-of-the-art methodologies, followed by a discussion on developing novel and innovative models and the practical challenges envisaged in implementing and utilizing these systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The matrix in cancer</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/33589810/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/33589810/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The extracellular matrix is a fundamental, core component of all tissues and organs, and is essential for the existence of multicellular organisms. From the earliest stages of organism development until death, it regulates and fine-tunes every cellular process in the body. In cancer, the extracellular matrix is altered at the biochemical, biomechanical, architectural and topographical levels, and recent years have seen an exponential increase in the study and recognition of the importance of the matrix in solid tumours. Coupled with the advancement of new technologies to study various elements of the matrix and cell-matrix interactions, we are also beginning to see the deployment of matrix-centric, stromal targeting cancer therapies. This Review touches on many of the facets of matrix biology in solid cancers, including breast, pancreatic and lung cancer, with the aim of highlighting some of the emerging interactions of the matrix and influences that the matrix has on tumour onset, progression and metastatic dissemination, before summarizing the ongoing work in the field aimed at developing therapies to co-target the matrix in cancer and cancer metastasis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
