<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Oncolytic Virus | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/oncolytic-virus/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/oncolytic-virus/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Oncolytic Virus</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Oncolytic Virus</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/oncolytic-virus/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dual-Responsive STAT3 Inhibitor Nanoprodrug Combined with Oncolytic Virus Elicits Synergistic Antitumor Immune Responses by Igniting Pyroptosis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36545949/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36545949/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Immune checkpoint blockade (ICB) therapy shows excellent efficacy against malignancies; however, insufficient tumor immunogenicity and immunosuppressive tumor microenvironment are considered as the two major stumbling blocks to a broad ICB response. Here, we report a combinational therapeutic strategy combining tumor microenvironment reactive oxygen species (ROS)/pH dual-responsive signal transducers and activators of transcription 3 (STAT3) inhibitor nanoprodrugs MPNPs with oncolytic herpes simplex virus 1 (HSV-1) virotherapy to synergistically ignite pyroptosis for enhancing immunotherapy. MPNPs exhibited a certain level of tumor accumulation, reduce tumor cell stemness, and enhance antitumor immune responses. Furthermore, the simultaneous application of oncolytic viruses (OVs) confers MPNPs with higher tumor penetration capacity and remarkable gasdermin E-mediated pyroptosis, thereby reshaping the tumor microenvironment and transforming &amp;ldquo;cold&amp;rdquo; tumors into &amp;ldquo;hot&amp;rdquo; ones. This &amp;ldquo;fire of immunity&amp;rdquo; strategy successfully activates robust T cell-dependent antitumor responses, potentiating ICB effects against local recurrence and pulmonary metastasis in preclinical &amp;ldquo;cold&amp;rdquo; murine triple-negative breast cancer and syngeneic oral cancer models. Collectively, this work may pave a new way and offer an unprecedented opportunity for the combination of OVs with nanomedicine for cancer immunotherapy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The emerging field of oncolytic virus-based cancer immunotherapy</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/36402738/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/36402738/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Natural or genetically modified oncolytic viruses (OVs) are promising antitumor agents for specifically targeting tumor cells without harming normal cells.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;OV-based oncolysis and OV-induced antiviral immune responses play an important role in remodeling the tumor microenvironment (TME) from immunologically &amp;lsquo;cold&amp;rsquo; to &amp;lsquo;hot&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As single agents or combined with other strategies, OVs can enhance cancer immunotherapy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;OV persistence, replication, spread, systemic delivery, lack of therapeutic biomarkers, and moderate efficacy as single agents are among the main challenges in the field. If these problems can be solved, OV will most likely substantially enhance clinical outcomes for cancer patients.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oncolytic viruses (OVs) provide novel and promising therapeutic options for patients with cancers resistant to traditional therapies. Natural or genetically modified OVs are multifaceted tumor killers. They directly lyse tumor cells while sparing normal cells, and indirectly potentiate antitumor immunity by releasing antigens and activating inflammatory responses in the tumor microenvironment. However, some limitations, such as limited penetration of OVs into tumors, short persistence, and the host antiviral immune response, are impeding the broad translation of oncolytic virotherapy into the clinic. If these challenges can be overcome, combination therapies, such as OVs plus immune checkpoint blockade (ICB), chimeric antigen receptor (CAR) T cells, or CAR natural killer (NK) cells, may provide powerful therapeutic platforms in the clinic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neoadjuvant Intravenous Oncolytic Vaccinia Virus Therapy Promotes Anticancer Immunity in Patients</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35439304/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35439304/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Improving the chances of curing patients with cancer who have had surgery to remove metastatic sites of disease is a priority area for cancer research. &lt;em&gt;Pexa-Vec&lt;/em&gt; (Pexastimogene Devacirepvec; JX-594, TG6006) is a principally immunotherapeutic oncolytic virus that has reached late-phase clinical trials. We report the results of a single-center, nonrandomized biological end point study (trial registration: EudraCT number 2012-000704-15), which builds on the success of the presurgical intravenous delivery of oncolytic viruses to tumors. Nine patients with either colorectal cancer liver metastases or metastatic melanoma were treated with a single intravenous infusion of &lt;em&gt;Pexa-Vec&lt;/em&gt; ahead of planned surgical resection of the metastases. Grade 3 and 4 &lt;em&gt;Pexa-Vec&lt;/em&gt;-associated side effects were lymphopaenia and neutropaenia. &lt;em&gt;Pexa-Vec&lt;/em&gt; was peripherally carried in plasma and was not associated with peripheral blood mononuclear cells. Upon surgical resection, &lt;em&gt;Pexa-Vec&lt;/em&gt; was found in the majority of analyzed tumors. &lt;em&gt;Pexa-Vec&lt;/em&gt; therapy associated with IFNα secretion, chemokine induction, and resulted in transient innate and long-lived adaptive anticancer immunity. In the 2 patients with significant and complete tumor necrosis, a reduction in the peripheral T-cell receptor diversity was observed at the time of surgery. These results support the development of presurgical oncolytic vaccinia virus-based therapies to stimulate anticancer immunity and increase the chances to cure patients with cancer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An oncolytic herpesvirus expressing E-cadherin improves survival in mouse models of glioblastoma</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/30475349/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/30475349/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The efficacy of oncolytic herpes simplex virus (oHSV) is limited by rapid viral clearance by innate immune effector cells and poor intratumoral viral spread. We combine two approaches to overcome these barriers: inhibition of natural killer (NK) cells and enhancement of intratumoral viral spread. We engineered an oHSV to express CDH1, encoding E-cadherin, an adherent molecule and a ligand for KLRG1, an inhibitory receptor expressed on NK cells. In vitro, infection with this engineered virus, named OV-CDH1, induced high surface E-cadherin expression on infected glioblastoma (GBM) cells, which typically lack endogenous E-cadherin. Ectopically expressed E-cadherin enhanced the spread of OV-CDH1 by facilitating cell-to-cell infection and viral entry and reduced viral clearance by selectively protecting OV-CDH1-infected cells from KLRG1+ NK cell killing. In vivo, OV-CDH1 treatment substantially prolonged the survival in GBM-bearing mouse models, primarily because of improved viral spread rather than inhibition of NK cell activity. Thus, virus-induced overexpression of E-cadherin may be a generalizable strategy for improving cancer virotherapy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
