<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Wnt | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/wnt/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/wnt/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Wnt</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Wnt</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/wnt/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wnt/β-catenin signaling mediates both heart and kidney injury in type 2 cardiorenal syndrome</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/30770217/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/30770217/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Erratum in:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Corrigendum to Zhao Y, Wang C, Hong X, et al. &lt;a href=&#34;https://linkinghub.elsevier.com/retrieve/pii/S0085253822006226&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Wnt/β-catenin signaling mediates both heart and kidney injury in type 2 cardiorenal syndrome&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Kidney Int. 2019;95:815-829.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In type 2 cardiorenal syndrome, chronic heart failure is thought to cause or promote chronic kidney disease; however, the underlying mechanisms remain poorly understood. We investigated the role of Wnt signaling in heart and kidney injury in a mouse model of cardiac hypertrophy and heart failure induced by transverse aortic constriction (TAC). At 8 weeks after TAC, cardiac hypertrophy, inflammation, and fibrosis were prominent, and echocardiography confirmed impaired cardiac function. The cardiac lesions were accompanied by upregulation of multiple Wnt ligands and activation of β-catenin, as well as activation of the renin-angiotensin system (RAS). Wnt3a induced multiple components of the RAS in primary cardiomyocytes and cardiac fibroblasts in vitro. TAC also caused proteinuria and kidney fibrosis, accompanied by klotho depletion and β-catenin activation in the kidney. Pharmacologic blockade of β-catenin with a small molecule inhibitor or the RAS with losartan ameliorated cardiac injury, restored heart function, and mitigated the renal lesions. Serum from TAC mice was sufficient to activate β-catenin and trigger tubular cell injury in vitro, indicating a role for circulating factors. Multiple inflammatory cytokines were upregulated in the circulation of TAC mice, and tumor necrosis factor-α was able to inhibit klotho, induce β-catenin activation, and cause tubular cell injury in vitro. These studies identify Wnt/β-catenin signaling as a common pathogenic mediator of heart and kidney injury in type 2 cardiorenal syndrome after TAC. Targeting this pathway could be a promising therapeutic strategy to protect both organs in cardiorenal syndrome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
