<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Wnt | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/wnt/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/wnt/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Wnt</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Wnt</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/wnt/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oxidative stress-triggered Wnt signaling perturbation characterizes the tipping point of lung adeno-to-squamous transdifferentiation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36627278/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36627278/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Lkb1&lt;/em&gt; deficiency confers the Kras-mutant lung cancer with strong plasticity and the potential for adeno-to-squamous transdifferentiation (AST). However, it remains largely unknown how &lt;em&gt;Lkb1&lt;/em&gt; deficiency dynamically regulates AST. Using the classical AST mouse model (&lt;em&gt;Kras&lt;sup&gt;LSL-G12D/+&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt;;&lt;em&gt;Lkb1&lt;sup&gt;flox/flox&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, KL), we here comprehensively analyze the temporal transcriptomic dynamics of lung tumors at different stages by dynamic network biomarker (DNB) and identify the tipping point at which the Wnt signaling is abruptly suppressed by the excessive accumulation of reactive oxygen species (ROS) through its downstream effector FOXO3A. Bidirectional genetic perturbation of the Wnt pathway using two different &lt;em&gt;Ctnnb1&lt;/em&gt; conditional knockout mouse strains confirms its essential role in the negative regulation of AST. Importantly, pharmacological activation of the Wnt pathway before but not after the tipping point inhibits squamous transdifferentiation, highlighting the irreversibility of AST after crossing the tipping point. Through comparative transcriptomic analyses of mouse and human tumors, we find that the lineage-specific transcription factors (TFs) of adenocarcinoma and squamous cell carcinoma form a &amp;ldquo;Yin-Yang&amp;rdquo; counteracting network. Interestingly, inactivation of the Wnt pathway preferentially suppresses the adenomatous lineage TF network and thus disrupts the &amp;ldquo;Yin-Yang&amp;rdquo; homeostasis to lean towards the squamous lineage, whereas ectopic expression of NKX2-1, an adenomatous lineage TF, significantly dampens such phenotypic transition accelerated by the Wnt pathway inactivation. The negative correlation between the Wnt pathway and AST is further observed in a large cohort of human lung adenosquamous carcinoma. Collectively, our study identifies the tipping point of AST and highlights an essential role of the ROS-Wnt axis in dynamically orchestrating the homeostasis between adeno- and squamous-specific TF networks at the AST tipping point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hypercapnia alters stromal-derived Wnt production limiting β-catenin signaling and proliferation in alveolar type 2 cells</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36626234/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36626234/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Persistent symptoms and radiographic abnormalities suggestive of failed lung repair are among the most common symptoms in patients with COVID-19 after hospital discharge. In mechanically ventilated patients with ARDS secondary to SARS-CoV-2 pneumonia, low tidal volumes to reduce ventilator-induced lung injury necessarily elevate blood CO2 levels, often leading to hypercapnia. The role of hypercapnia on lung repair after injury is not completely understood. Here, using a mouse model of hypercapnia exposure, cell lineage-tracing, spatial transcriptomics and 3D-cultures, we show that hypercapnia limits β-catenin signaling in AT2 cells, leading to their reduced proliferative capacity. Hypercapnia alters expression of major Wnts in PDGFRα+-fibroblasts from those maintaining AT2 progenitor activity towards those that antagonize β-catenin signaling thereby limiting progenitor function. Constitutive activation of β-catenin signaling in AT2 cells or treatment of organoid cultures with recombinant WNT3A protein bypasses the inhibitory effects of hypercapnia. Inhibition of AT2 proliferation in hypercapnic patients may contribute to impaired lung repair after injury, preventing sealing of the epithelial barrier, increasing lung flooding, ventilator dependency and mortality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A DLG1-ARHGAP31-CDC42 axis is essential for the intestinal stem cell response to fluctuating niche Wnt signaling</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36640764/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36640764/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Polarity of the mammalian intestinal epithelium is independent of &lt;em&gt;Dlg1&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Loss of &lt;em&gt;Dlg1&lt;/em&gt; in ISCs results in cell death under high Wnt conditions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ISCs lacking &lt;em&gt;Dlg1&lt;/em&gt; have impaired cell division and migration&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Canonical WNT ligands activate non-canonical Wnt signaling via DLG1-ARHGAP31-CDC42&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A central factor in the maintenance of tissue integrity is the response of stem cells to variations in the levels of niche signals. In the gut, intestinal stem cells (ISCs) depend on Wnt ligands for self-renewal and proliferation. Transient increases in Wnt signaling promote regeneration after injury or in inflammatory bowel diseases, whereas constitutive activation of this pathway leads to colorectal cancer. Here, we report that Discs large 1 (&lt;em&gt;Dlg1&lt;/em&gt;), although dispensable for polarity and cellular turnover during intestinal homeostasis, is required for ISC survival in the context of increased Wnt signaling. RNA sequencing (RNA-seq) and genetic mouse models demonstrated that DLG1 regulates the cellular response to increased canonical Wnt ligands. This occurs via the transcriptional regulation of &lt;em&gt;Arhgap31&lt;/em&gt;, a GTPase-activating protein that deactivates CDC42, an effector of the non-canonical Wnt pathway. These findings reveal a DLG1-ARHGAP31-CDC42 axis that is essential for the ISC response to increased niche Wnt signaling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TRIM27 maintains gut homeostasis by promoting intestinal stem cell self-renewal</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36596873/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36596873/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dysregulation of gut homeostasis is associated with irritable bowel syndrome (IBS), a chronic functional gastrointestinal disorder affecting approximately 11.2% of the global population. The poorly understood pathogenesis of IBS has impeded its treatment. Here, we report that the E3 ubiquitin ligase tripartite motif-containing 27 (TRIM27) is weakly expressed in IBS but highly expressed in inflammatory bowel disease (IBD), a frequent chronic organic gastrointestinal disorder. Accordingly, knockout of &lt;em&gt;Trim27&lt;/em&gt; in mice causes spontaneously occurring IBS-like symptoms, including increased visceral hyperalgesia and abnormal stool features, as observed in IBS patients. Mechanistically, TRIM27 stabilizes β-catenin and thus activates Wnt/β-catenin signaling to promote intestinal stem cell (ISC) self-renewal. Consistent with these findings, &lt;em&gt;Trim27&lt;/em&gt; deficiency disrupts organoid formation, which is rescued by reintroducing TRIM27 or β-catenin. Furthermore, Wnt/β-catenin signaling activator treatment ameliorates IBS symptoms by promoting ISC self-renewal. Taken together, these data indicate that TRIM27 is critical for maintaining gut homeostasis, suggesting that targeting the TRIM27/Wnt/β-catenin axis could be a potential treatment strategy for IBS. Our study also indicates that TRIM27 might serve as a potential biomarker for differentiating IBS from IBD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gut microbiota-stem cell niche crosstalk: A new territory for maintaining intestinal homeostasis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/imt2.54/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/imt2.54/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Intestinal stem cells (ISCs) are protected by their niche and are regulated by Wnt, bone morphogenetic protein, and Notch.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ISCs and their relationship with intestinal microbiota provide a feasible pathway to alleviate intestinal diseases.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Diverse bacteria-related postbiotics regulate ISCs and maintain their homeostasis.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Intestinal epithelium undergoes rapid cellular turnover, relying on the local niche, to support intestinal stem cells (ISCs) function and self-renewal. Research into the association between ISCs and disease continues to expand at a rapid rate. However, the detailed interaction of ISCs and gut microbes remains to be elucidated. Thus, this review witnessed major advances in the crosstalk between ISCs and gut microbes, delivering key insights into (1) construction of ISC niche and molecular mechanism of how to jointly govern epithelial homeostasis and protect against intestinal diseases with the participation of Wnt, bone morphogenetic protein, and Notch; (2) differentiation fate of ISCs affect the gut microbiota. Meanwhile, the presence of intestinal microbes also regulates ISC function; (3) microbiota regulation on ISCs by Wnt and Notch signals through pattern recognition receptors; (4) how do specific microbiota-related postbiotics influence ISCs to maintain intestinal epithelial regeneration and homeostasis that provide insights into a promising alternative therapeutic method for intestinal diseases. Considering the detailed interaction is still unclear, it is necessary to further explore the regulatory role of gut microbiota on ISCs to utilize microbes to alleviate gut disorders. Furthermore, these major advances collectively drive us ever closer to breakthroughs in regenerative medicine and cancer treatment by microbial transplantation in the clinic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wnt5a/β-catenin axis is involved in the downregulation of AT2 lineage by PAI-1</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36098461/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36098461/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Failure to regenerate injured alveoli functionally and promptly causes a high incidence of fatality in coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19). How elevated plasminogen activator inhibitor-1 (PAI-1) regulates the lineage of alveolar type 2 (AT2) cells for re-alveolarization has not been studied. This study aimed to examine the role of PAI-1-Wnt5a-β catenin cascades in AT2 fate. Dramatic reduction in AT2 yield was observed in &lt;em&gt;Serpine1&lt;sup&gt;Tg&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; mice. Elevated PAI-1 level suppressed organoid number, development efficiency, and total surface area in vitro. Anti-PAI-1 neutralizing antibody restored organoid number, proliferation and differentiation of AT2 cells, and β-catenin level in organoids. Both Wnt family member 5A (Wnt5a) and Wnt5a-derived N-butyloxycarbonyl hexapeptide (Box5) altered the lineage of AT2 cells. This study demonstrates that elevated PAI-1 regulates AT2 proliferation and differentiation via the Wnt5a/β catenin cascades. PAI-1 could serve as autocrine signaling for lung injury repair.
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hypoxia-induced lncRNA STEAP3-AS1 activates Wnt/β-catenin signaling to promote colorectal cancer progression by preventing m6A-mediated degradation of STEAP3 mRNA</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35986274/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35986274/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Hypoxia, a typical hallmark of solid tumors, exhibits an essential role in the progression of colorectal cancer (CRC), in which the dysregulation of long non-coding RNAs (lncRNAs) is frequently observed. However, the underlying mechanisms are not clearly defined.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; The TCGA database was analyzed to identify differential lncRNA expression involved in hypoxia-induced CRC progression. qRT-PCR was conducted to validate the upregulation of lncRNA &lt;em&gt;STEAP3-AS1&lt;/em&gt; in CRC cell lines and tumor-bearing mouse and zebrafish models under hypoxia. ChIP-qRT-PCR was used to detect the transcriptional activation of STEAP3-AS1 mediated by HIF-1α. RNA-seq, fluorescent in situ hybridization, RNA pulldown, RNA immunoprecipitation, co-immunoprecipitation, immunofluorescence and immunoblot experiments were used to ascertain the involved mechanisms. Functional assays were performed in both in vitro and in vivo models to investigate the regulatory role of &lt;em&gt;STEAP3-AS1&lt;/em&gt;/STEAP3/Wnt/β-catenin axis in CRC proliferation and metastasis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; Here, we identified a hypoxia-induced antisense lncRNA &lt;em&gt;STEAP3-AS1&lt;/em&gt; that was highly expressed in clinical CRC tissues and positively correlated with poor prognosis of CRC patients. Upregulation of lncRNA &lt;em&gt;STEAP3-AS1&lt;/em&gt;, which was induced by HIF-1α-mediated transcriptional activation, facilitated the proliferation and metastasis of CRC cells both in vitro and in vivo. Mechanistically, &lt;em&gt;STEAP3-AS1&lt;/em&gt; interacted competitively with the YTH domain-containing family protein 2 (YTHDF2), a N&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;-methyladenosine (m&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;A) reader, leading to the disassociation of YTHDF2 with &lt;em&gt;STEAP3&lt;/em&gt; mRNA. This effect protected &lt;em&gt;STEAP3&lt;/em&gt; mRNA from m6A-mediated degradation, enabling the high expression of STEAP3 protein and subsequent production of cellular ferrous iron (Fe&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt;). Increased Fe&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt; levels elevated Ser 9 phosphorylation of glycogen synthase kinase 3 beta (GSK3β) and inhibited its kinase activity, thus releasing β-catenin for nuclear translocation and subsequent activation of Wnt signaling to support CRC progression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; Taken together, our study highlights the mechanisms of lncRNA &lt;em&gt;STEAP3-AS1&lt;/em&gt; in facilitating CRC progression involving the &lt;em&gt;STEAP3-AS1&lt;/em&gt;/STEAP3/Wnt/β-catenin axis, which may provide novel diagnostic biomarkers or therapeutic targets to benefit CRC treatment. Hypoxia-induced HIF-1α transcriptionally upregulates the expression of lncRNA STEAP3-AS1, which interacts competitively with YTHDF2, thus upregulating mRNA stability of STEAP3 and consequent STEAP3 protein expression. The enhanced STEAP3 expression results in production of cellular ferrous iron (Fe&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt;), which induces the Ser 9 phosphorylation and inactivation of GSK3β, releasing β-catenin for nuclear translocation and contributing to subsequent activation of Wnt signaling to promote CRC progression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Metabolic balance in colorectal cancer is maintained by optimal Wnt signaling levels</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35904277/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35904277/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wnt pathways are important for the modulation of tissue homeostasis, and their deregulation is linked to cancer development. Canonical Wnt signaling is hyperactivated in many human colorectal cancers due to genetic alterations of the negative Wnt regulator APC. However, the expression levels of Wnt-dependent targets vary between tumors, and the mechanisms of carcinogenesis concomitant with this Wnt signaling dosage have not been understood. In this study, we integrate whole-genome CRISPR/Cas9 screens with large-scale multi-omic data to delineate functional subtypes of cancer. We engineer APC loss-of-function mutations and thereby hyperactivate Wnt signaling in cells with low endogenous Wnt activity and find that the resulting engineered cells have an unfavorable metabolic equilibrium compared with cells which naturally acquired Wnt hyperactivation. We show that the dosage level of oncogenic Wnt hyperactivation impacts the metabolic equilibrium and the mitochondrial phenotype of a given cell type in a context-dependent manner. These findings illustrate the impact of context-dependent genetic interactions on cellular phenotypes of a central cancer driver mutation and expand our understanding of quantitative modulation of oncogenic signaling in tumorigenesis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LINC01194 recruits NUMA1 to promote ubiquitination of RYR2 to enhance malignant progression in triple-negative breast cancer</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35750275/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35750275/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;LINC01194 was highly expressed in TNBC.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;LINC01194 recruited NUMA1 to stabilize UBE2C mRNA, thereby promoting RYR2 ubiquitination and degradation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;LINC01194/NUMA1/UBE2C/RYR2/Wnt/β-catenin signaling pathway might provide an effective therapeutic strategy for TNBC.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Long intergenic nonprotein coding RNA 1194 (LINC01194) has been reported as an oncogene in several cancer types, but its expression and potential role in triple-negative breast cancer (TNBC) are still unclear. We found that LINC01194 was significantly highly expressed in TNBC based on The Cancer Genome Atlas (TCGA) database. Data from in vitro experiments and in vivo assays demonstrated that LINC01194 promoted TNBC progression. Through bioinformatics prediction, mass spectrometry, and mechanical experiments, we found that LINC01194 could recruit nuclear mitotic apparatus protein 1 (NUMA1) to bind to the untranslated region (3&amp;rsquo;UTR) of ubiquitin-conjugating enzyme E2 C (UBE2C) 3&amp;rsquo; and stabilize UBE2C mRNA. Moreover, we found that UBE2C acted as an ubiquitin ligase to promote the ubiquitination and degradation of ryanodine receptor type 2 (RYR2) that inhibited the progression of TNBC by inhibiting the Wnt/β-catenin signaling pathway. In summary, LINC01194 activate the Wnt/β-catenin signaling pathway and accelerates the malignant progression of TNBC by recruiting NUMA1 to stabilize UBE2C mRNA and thus promotes RYR2 ubiquitination and degradation. These findings might provide a more effective therapeutic strategy for TNBC patients.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Follistatin-like 1 (FSTL1) interacts with Wnt ligands and Frizzled receptors to enhance Wnt/β-catenin signaling in obstructed kidneys in vivo</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35525270/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35525270/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Follistatin (FS)-like 1 (FSTL1) is a member of the FS-SPARC (secreted protein, acidic and rich in cysteine) family of secreted and extracellular matrix proteins. The functions of FSTL1 have been studied in heart and lung injury as well as in wound healing; however, the role of FSTL1 in the kidney is largely unknown. Here, we show using single-cell RNA-Seq that Fstl1 was enriched in stromal cells in obstructed mouse kidneys. In addition, immunofluorescence demonstrated that FSTL1 expression was induced in fibroblasts during kidney fibrogenesis in mice and human patients. We demonstrate that FSTL1 overexpression increased renal fibrosis and activated the Wnt/β-catenin signaling pathway, known to promote kidney fibrosis, but not the transforming growth factor β (TGF-β), Notch, Hedgehog, or Yes-associated protein (YAP) signaling pathways in obstructed mouse kidneys, whereas inhibition of FSTL1 lowered Wnt/β-catenin signaling. Importantly, we show that FSTL1 interacted with Wnt ligands and the Frizzled (FZD) receptors but not the coreceptor lipoprotein receptor-related protein 6 (LRP6). Specifically, we found FSTL1 interacted with Wnt3a through its extracellular calcium-binding (EC) domain and von Willebrand factor type C-like (VWC) domain, and with FZD4 through its EC domain. Furthermore, we show that FSTL1 increased the association of Wnt3a with FZD4 and promoted Wnt/β-catenin signaling and fibrogenesis. The EC domain interacting with both Wnt3a and FZD4 also enhanced Wnt3a signaling. Therefore, we conclude that FSTL1 is a novel extracellular enhancer of the Wnt/β-catenin pathway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A novel β-catenin/BCL9 complex inhibitor blocks oncogenic Wnt signaling and disrupts cholesterol homeostasis in colorectal cancer</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35486727/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35486727/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dysregulated Wnt/β-catenin signaling is implicated in the pathogenesis of many human cancers, including colorectal cancer (CRC), making it an attractive clinical target. With the aim of inhibiting oncogenic Wnt activity, we developed a high-throughput screening AlphaScreen assay to identify selective small-molecule inhibitors of the interaction between β-catenin and its coactivator BCL9. We identified a compound that consistently bound to β-catenin and specifically inhibited in vivo native β-catenin/BCL9 complex formation in CRC cell lines. This compound inhibited Wnt activity, down-regulated expression of the Wnt/β-catenin signature in gene expression studies, disrupted cholesterol homeostasis, and significantly reduced the proliferation of CRC cell lines and tumor growth in a xenograft mouse model of CRC. This study has therefore identified a specific small-molecule inhibitor of oncogenic Wnt signaling, which may have value as a probe for functional studies and has important implications for the development of novel therapies in patients with CRC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Loss of CLDN5 in podocytes deregulates WIF1 to activate WNT signaling and contributes to kidney disease</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35332151/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35332151/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although mature podocytes lack tight junctions, tight junction integral membrane protein claudin-5 (CLDN5) is predominantly expressed on plasma membranes of podocytes under normal conditions. Using podocyte-specific Cldn5 knockout mice, we identify CLDN5 as a crucial regulator of podocyte function and reveal that Cldn5 deletion exacerbates podocyte injury and proteinuria in a diabetic nephropathy mouse model. Mechanistically, CLDN5 deletion reduces ZO1 expression and induces nuclear translocation of ZONAB, followed by transcriptional downregulation of WNT inhibitory factor-1 (WIF1) expression, which leads to activation of WNT signaling pathway. Podocyte-derived WIF1 also plays paracrine roles in tubular epithelial cells, as evidenced by the finding that animals with podocyte-specific deletion of Cldn5 or Wif1 have worse kidney fibrosis after unilateral ureteral obstruction than littermate controls. Systemic delivery of WIF1 suppresses the progression of diabetic nephropathy and ureteral obstruction-induced renal fibrosis. These findings establish a function for podocyte CLDN5 in restricting WNT signaling in kidney.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wnt/β-catenin signaling mediates both heart and kidney injury in type 2 cardiorenal syndrome</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/30770217/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/30770217/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Erratum in:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Corrigendum to Zhao Y, Wang C, Hong X, et al. &lt;a href=&#34;https://linkinghub.elsevier.com/retrieve/pii/S0085253822006226&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Wnt/β-catenin signaling mediates both heart and kidney injury in type 2 cardiorenal syndrome&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Kidney Int. 2019;95:815-829.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In type 2 cardiorenal syndrome, chronic heart failure is thought to cause or promote chronic kidney disease; however, the underlying mechanisms remain poorly understood. We investigated the role of Wnt signaling in heart and kidney injury in a mouse model of cardiac hypertrophy and heart failure induced by transverse aortic constriction (TAC). At 8 weeks after TAC, cardiac hypertrophy, inflammation, and fibrosis were prominent, and echocardiography confirmed impaired cardiac function. The cardiac lesions were accompanied by upregulation of multiple Wnt ligands and activation of β-catenin, as well as activation of the renin-angiotensin system (RAS). Wnt3a induced multiple components of the RAS in primary cardiomyocytes and cardiac fibroblasts in vitro. TAC also caused proteinuria and kidney fibrosis, accompanied by klotho depletion and β-catenin activation in the kidney. Pharmacologic blockade of β-catenin with a small molecule inhibitor or the RAS with losartan ameliorated cardiac injury, restored heart function, and mitigated the renal lesions. Serum from TAC mice was sufficient to activate β-catenin and trigger tubular cell injury in vitro, indicating a role for circulating factors. Multiple inflammatory cytokines were upregulated in the circulation of TAC mice, and tumor necrosis factor-α was able to inhibit klotho, induce β-catenin activation, and cause tubular cell injury in vitro. These studies identify Wnt/β-catenin signaling as a common pathogenic mediator of heart and kidney injury in type 2 cardiorenal syndrome after TAC. Targeting this pathway could be a promising therapeutic strategy to protect both organs in cardiorenal syndrome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wnt/β-Catenin Signaling, Disease, and Emerging Therapeutic Modalities</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/28575679/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/28575679/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The WNT signal transduction cascade is a main regulator of development throughout the animal kingdom. Wnts are also key drivers of most types of tissue stem cells in adult mammals. Unsurprisingly, mutated Wnt pathway components are causative to multiple growth-related pathologies and to cancer. Here, we describe the core Wnt/β-catenin signaling pathway, how it controls stem cells, and contributes to disease. Finally, we discuss strategies for Wnt-based therapies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
