<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Immune Evasion | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/immune-evasion/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/immune-evasion/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Immune Evasion</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Immune Evasion</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/immune-evasion/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>PRDM1/BLIMP1 induces cancer immune evasion by modulating the USP22-SPI1-PD-L1 axis in hepatocellular carcinoma cells</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36509766/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36509766/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Programmed death receptor-1 (PD-1) blockade have achieved some efficacy but only in a fraction of patients with hepatocellular carcinoma (HCC). Programmed cell death 1 ligand 1 (PD-L1) binds to its receptor PD1 on T cells to dampen antigen-tumor immune responses. However, the mechanisms underlying PD-L1 regulation are not fully elucidated. Herein, we identify that tumoral &lt;em&gt;Prdm1&lt;/em&gt; overexpression inhibits cell growth in immune-deficient mouse models. Further, tumoral &lt;em&gt;Prdm1&lt;/em&gt; overexpression upregulates PD-L1 levels, dampening anti-tumor immunity in vivo, and neutralizes the anti-tumor efficacy of &lt;em&gt;Prdm1&lt;/em&gt; overexpression in immune-competent mouse models. Mechanistically, &lt;em&gt;PRDM1&lt;/em&gt; enhances &lt;em&gt;USP22&lt;/em&gt; transcription, thus reducing &lt;em&gt;SPI1&lt;/em&gt; protein degradation through deubiquitination, which enhances &lt;em&gt;PD-L1&lt;/em&gt; transcription. Functionally, PD-1 mAb treatment reinforces the efficacy of &lt;em&gt;Prdm1&lt;/em&gt;-overexpressing HCC immune-competent mouse models. Collectively, we demonstrate that the PRDM1-USP22-SPI1 axis regulates PD-L1 levels, resulting in infiltrated CD8&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T cell exhaustion. Furthermore, &lt;em&gt;PRDM1&lt;/em&gt; overexpression combined with PD-(L)1 mAb treatment provides a therapeutic strategy for HCC treatment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aberrant hyperexpression of the RNA binding protein FMRP in tumors mediates immune evasion</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36395212/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36395212/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many human cancers manifest the capability to circumvent attack by the adaptive immune system. In this work, we identified a component of immune evasion that involves frequent up-regulation of fragile X mental retardation protein (FMRP) in solid tumors. FMRP represses immune attack, as revealed by cancer cells engineered to lack its expression. FMRP-deficient tumors were infiltrated by activated T cells that impaired tumor growth and enhanced survival in mice. Mechanistically, FMRP&amp;rsquo;s immunosuppression was multifactorial, involving repression of the chemoattractant C-C motif chemokine ligand 7 (CCL7) concomitant with up-regulation of three immunomodulators-interleukin-33 (IL-33), tumor-secreted protein S (PROS1), and extracellular vesicles. Gene signatures associate FMRP&amp;rsquo;s cancer network with poor prognosis and response to therapy in cancer patients. Collectively, FMRP is implicated as a regulator that orchestrates a multifaceted barrier to antitumor immune responses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In vivo CRISPR screens reveal the landscape of immune evasion pathways across cancer</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36151395/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36151395/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The immune system can eliminate tumors, but checkpoints enable immune escape. Here, we identify immune evasion mechanisms using genome-scale in vivo CRISPR screens across cancer models treated with immune checkpoint blockade (ICB). We identify immune evasion genes and important immune inhibitory checkpoints conserved across cancers, including the non-classical major histocompatibility complex class I (MHC class I) molecule Qa-1&lt;sup&gt;b&lt;/sup&gt;/HLA-E. Surprisingly, loss of tumor interferon-γ (IFNγ) signaling sensitizes many models to immunity. The immune inhibitory effects of tumor IFN sensing are mediated through two mechanisms. First, tumor upregulation of classical MHC class I inhibits natural killer cells. Second, IFN-induced expression of Qa-1&lt;sup&gt;b&lt;/sup&gt; inhibits CD8&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T cells via the NKG2A/CD94 receptor, which is induced by ICB. Finally, we show that strong IFN signatures are associated with poor response to ICB in individuals with renal cell carcinoma or melanoma. This study reveals that IFN-mediated upregulation of classical and non-classical MHC class I inhibitory checkpoints can facilitate immune escape.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enterobacterial LPS-inducible LINC00152 is regulated by histone lactylation and promotes cancer cells invasion and migration</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35959377/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35959377/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gut microbes participate in pathogenesis by interacting with the host genome through epigenetic mechanisms, such as long non-coding RNAs. However, the mechanisms by which the microbiota induce expression alteration of long non-coding RNAs remains unclear. Here, we quantified the transcriptome alteration of human colon cell lines after being infected by a common enteric pathogen &lt;em&gt;Salmonella typhimurium SL1344&lt;/em&gt;. We observed a widespread lncRNAs expression alteration. Among them, the elevated expression of LINC00152 was verified and proved to be induced by enteric bacteria-derived lipopolysaccharide (LPS). The inducible LINC00152 were found to inhibit Salmonella invasion and inflammation response. LINC00152 was overexpressed in tumors of the clinical CRC samples compared with adjacent normal tissues. Accordingly, we also demonstrated that overexpression of LINC00152 promoted the migration and invasion of colorectal cancer cells. Consistently, we observed an increased abundance of gram-negative bacteria and LPS in tumors tissue. Taken together, the above data implicated that enriched gram-negative bacteria in tumor tissue might promote tumor growth through modulating the expression of LINC00152. Furthermore, we demonstrated that LPS upregulated the expression of LINC00152 by introducing histone lactylation on its promoter and decreasing the binding efficiency of the repressor, YY1, to it. Our results provide new insights into how enterobacteria affect host epigenetics in human disease.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The autophagy-related degradation of MDA5 by Tembusu virus nonstructural 2B disrupts IFNβ production</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35713934/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35713934/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Duck Tembusu virus (TMUV) is a serious avian pathogen causing a decline in egg production, but the mechanism of the virus that breaks through the innate immune system is poorly understood. Here, we show that TMUV inhibits poly(I:C)-induced interferon (IFN) production. Because poly(I:C) transfection can specifically activate the MDA5 pathway in duck primary cells, we found that infection with TMUV can specifically target MDA5 and lead to its degradation. MDA5 downregulation could be blocked by the autophagy inhibitor 3-methyladenine (3-MA) but not a proteasome inhibitor, strongly implicating MDA5 degradation as an autophagy-related degradation pathway. Pretreatment with 3-MA enhanced the expression of MDA5 and inhibited TMUV replication. To screen TMUV proteins that degraded MDA5, the TMUV replicon and MDA5-Flag were cotransfected into cells, and the western blot analysis showed that nonstructural 2B (NS2B) can degrade MDA5 in a dose-dependent manner. Dual-luciferase assays indicate that NS2B alone inhibits MDA5- or poly(I:C)-mediated IFN production. NS2B binds MDA5 in the presence of 3-MA. The deletion of the amino acids of NS2B from residues 51 to 92 (hydrophilic area) restored the expression of MDA5 and relieved the MDA5-mediated IFNβ production inhibition by NS2B, indicating that the hydrophilic area of NS2B is important for its interaction with host innate immunity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TRIB3 reduces CD8&#43; T cell infiltration and induces immune evasion by repressing the STAT1-CXCL10 axis in colorectal cancer</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34985967/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34985967/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;High CD8&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T cell infiltration in colorectal cancer (CRC) should suggest a favorable prognosis and a satisfactory response to immunotherapy; however, the vast majority of patients with CRC do not benefit from immunotherapy due to poor T cell infiltration. Therefore, a better understanding of the mechanisms for T cell exclusion from CRC tumors is needed. Tribbles homolog 3 (TRIB3) has been implicated as an oncoprotein, but its role in regulating antitumor immune responses has not been defined. Here, we demonstrated that TRIB3 inhibits CD8&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T cell infiltration in various CRC mouse models. We showed that TRIB3 was acetylated by acetyltransferase P300, which inhibited ubiquitination and subsequent proteasomal degradation of TRIB3. Ectopically expressed TRIB3 inhibited signal transducer and activator of transcription 1 (STAT1) activation and STAT1-mediated CXCL10 transcription by enhancing the epidermal growth factor receptor signaling pathway, causing a reduction in tumor-infiltrating T cells. Genetic ablation of Trib3 or pharmacological acceleration of TRIB3 degradation with a P300 inhibitor increased T cell recruitment and sensitized CRCs to immune checkpoint blockade therapy. These findings identified TRIB3 as a negative modulator of CD8&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T cell infiltration in CRCs, highlighting a potential therapeutic target for treating immunologically “cold” CRCs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Whole-genome profiling of nasopharyngeal carcinoma reveals viral-host co-operation in inflammatory NF-κB activation and immune escape</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34234122/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34234122/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Erratum in:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Author Correction: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-022-32156-9&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Whole-genome profiling of nasopharyngeal carcinoma reveals viral-host co-operation in inflammatory NF-κB activation and immune escape&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interplay between EBV infection and acquired genetic alterations during nasopharyngeal carcinoma (NPC) development remains vague. Here we report a comprehensive genomic analysis of 70 NPCs, combining whole-genome sequencing (WGS) of microdissected tumor cells with EBV oncogene expression to reveal multiple aspects of cellular-viral co-operation in tumorigenesis. Genomic aberrations along with EBV-encoded LMP1 expression underpin constitutive NF-κB activation in 90% of NPCs. A similar spectrum of somatic aberrations and viral gene expression undermine innate immunity in 79% of cases and adaptive immunity in 47% of cases; mechanisms by which NPC may evade immune surveillance despite its pro-inflammatory phenotype. Additionally, genomic changes impairing TGFBR2 promote oncogenesis and stabilize EBV infection in tumor cells. Fine-mapping of CDKN2A/CDKN2B deletion breakpoints reveals homozygous MTAP deletions in 32-34% of NPCs that confer marked sensitivity to MAT2A inhibition. Our work concludes that NPC is a homogeneously NF-κB-driven and immune-protected, yet potentially druggable, cancer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The ORF8 protein of SARS-CoV-2 mediates immune evasion through down-regulating MHC-Ι</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34021074/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34021074/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;COVID-19, caused by severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 (SARS-CoV-2), has become a global pandemic and has claimed over 2 million lives worldwide. Although the genetic sequences of SARS-CoV and SARS-CoV-2 have high homology, the clinical and pathological characteristics of COVID-19 differ significantly from those of SARS. How and whether SARS-CoV-2 evades (cellular) immune surveillance requires further elucidation. In this study, we show that SARS-CoV-2 infection leads to major histocompability complex class Ι (MHC-Ι) down-regulation both in vitro and in vivo. The viral protein encoded by open reading frame 8 (ORF8) of SARS-CoV-2, which shares the least homology with SARS-CoV among all viral proteins, directly interacts with MHC-Ι molecules and mediates their down-regulation. In ORF8-expressing cells, MHC-Ι molecules are selectively targeted for lysosomal degradation via autophagy. Thus, SARS-CoV-2-infected cells are much less sensitive to lysis by cytotoxic T lymphocytes. Because ORF8 protein impairs the antigen presentation system, inhibition of ORF8 could be a strategy to improve immune surveillance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Viral tegument proteins restrict cGAS-DNA phase separation to mediate immune evasion</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34015248/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34015248/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DNA-induced liquid-liquid phase separation of cyclic GMP-AMP synthase (cGAS) triggers a potent response to detect pathogen infection and promote innate immune signaling. Whether and how pathogens manipulate cGAS-DNA condensation to mediate immune evasion is unknown. We report the identification of a structurally related viral tegument protein family, represented by ORF52 and VP22 from gamma- and alpha-herpesvirinae, respectively, that employs a conserved mechanism to restrict cGAS-DNA phase separation. ORF52/VP22 proteins accumulate into, and effectively disrupt, the pre-formed cGAS-DNA condensation both in vitro and in cells. The inhibition process is dependent on DNA-induced liquid-liquid phase separation of the viral protein rather than a direct interaction with cGAS. Moreover, highly abundant ORF52 proteins carried within viral particles are able to target cGAS-DNA phase separation in early infection stage. Our results define ORF52/VP22-type tegument proteins as a family of inhibitors targeting cGAS-DNA phase separation and demonstrate a mechanism for how viruses overcome innate immunity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Activation and evasion of type I interferon responses by SARS-CoV-2</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32733001/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32733001/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The pandemic of COVID-19 has posed an unprecedented threat to global public health. However, the interplay between the viral pathogen of COVID-19, SARS-CoV-2, and host innate immunity is poorly understood. Here we show that SARS-CoV-2 induces overt but delayed type-I interferon (IFN) responses. By screening 23 viral proteins, we find that SARS-CoV-2 NSP1, NSP3, NSP12, NSP13, NSP14, ORF3, ORF6 and M protein inhibit Sendai virus-induced IFN-β promoter activation, whereas NSP2 and S protein exert opposite effects. Further analyses suggest that ORF6 inhibits both type I IFN production and downstream signaling, and that the C-terminus region of ORF6 is critical for its antagonistic effect. Finally, we find that IFN-β treatment effectively blocks SARS-CoV-2 replication. In summary, our study shows that SARS-CoV-2 perturbs host innate immune response via both its structural and nonstructural proteins, and thus provides insights into the pathogenesis of SARS-CoV-2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Autophagy promotes immune evasion of pancreatic cancer by degrading MHC-I</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32376951/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32376951/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Immune evasion is a major obstacle for cancer treatment. Common mechanisms of evasion include impaired antigen presentation caused by mutations or loss of heterozygosity of the major histocompatibility complex class I (MHC-I), which has been implicated in resistance to immune checkpoint blockade (ICB) therapy. However, in pancreatic ductal adenocarcinoma (PDAC), which is resistant to most therapies including ICB, mutations that cause loss of MHC-I are rarely found despite the frequent downregulation of MHC-I expression. Here we show that, in PDAC, MHC-I molecules are selectively targeted for lysosomal degradation by an autophagy-dependent mechanism that involves the autophagy cargo receptor NBR1. PDAC cells display reduced expression of MHC-I at the cell surface and instead demonstrate predominant localization within autophagosomes and lysosomes. Notably, inhibition of autophagy restores surface levels of MHC-I and leads to improved antigen presentation, enhanced anti-tumour T cell responses and reduced tumour growth in syngeneic host mice. Accordingly, the anti-tumour effects of autophagy inhibition are reversed by depleting CD8&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T cells or reducing surface expression of MHC-I. Inhibition of autophagy, either genetically or pharmacologically with chloroquine, synergizes with dual ICB therapy (anti-PD1 and anti-CTLA4 antibodies), and leads to an enhanced anti-tumour immune response. Our findings demonstrate a role for enhanced autophagy or lysosome function in immune evasion by selective targeting of MHC-I molecules for degradation, and provide a rationale for the combination of autophagy inhibition and dual ICB therapy as a therapeutic strategy against PDAC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
