<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>NETosis | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/netosis/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/netosis/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>NETosis</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>NETosis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/netosis/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neutrophil, neutrophil extracellular traps and endothelial cell dysfunction in sepsis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/36629024/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/36629024/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sepsis is a persistent systemic inflammatory condition involving multiple organ failures resulting from a dysregulated immune response to infection, and one of the hallmarks of sepsis is endothelial dysfunction. During its progression, neutrophils are the first line of innate immune defence against infection. Aside from traditional mechanisms, such as phagocytosis or the release of inflammatory cytokines, reactive oxygen species and other antibacterial substances, activated neutrophils also release web-like structures composed of tangled decondensed DNA, histone, myeloperoxidase and other granules called neutrophil extracellular traps (NETs), which can efficiently ensnare bacteria in the circulation. In contrast, excessive neutrophil activation and NET release may induce endothelial cells to shift toward a pro-inflammatory and pro-coagulant phenotype. Furthermore, neutrophils and NETs can degrade glycocalyx on the endothelial cell surface and increase endothelium permeability. Consequently, the endothelial barrier collapses, contributing to impaired microcirculatory blood flow, tissue hypoperfusion and life-threatening organ failure in the late phase of sepsis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neutrophil Extracellular Traps Delay Diabetic Wound Healing by Inducing Endothelial-to-Mesenchymal Transition via the Hippo pathway</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36594092/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36594092/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Diabetic foot ulcers (DFUs) are among the most frequent complications of diabetes with significant morbidity and mortality. Diabetes can trigger neutrophils to undergo histone citrullination by protein arginine deiminase 4 (encoded by Padi4 in mice) and release neutrophil extracellular traps (NETs). The specific mechanism of NETs-mediated wound healing impairment in diabetes remains unknown. In this study, we show neutrophils are more susceptible to NETosis in diabetic wound environments. Via in vitro experiments and in vivo models of wound healing using wide-type and Padi4 -/- mice, we demonstrate NETs can induce the activation of PAK2 via the membrane receptor TLR-9. Then PAK2 phosphorylates the intracellular protein Merlin/NF2 to inhibit the Hippo-YAP pathway. YAP binds to transcription factor SMAD2 and translocates from the cytoplasm into the nucleus to promote endothelial-to-mesenchymal transition (EndMT), which ultimately impedes angiogenesis and delays wound healing. Suppression of the Merlin/YAP/SMAD2 pathway can attenuate NET-induced EndMT. Inhibition of NETosis accelerates wound healing by reducing EndMT and promoting angiogenesis. Cumulatively, these data suggest NETosis delays diabetic wound healing by inducing EndMT via the Hippo-YAP pathway. Increased understanding of the molecular mechanism that regulates NETosis and EndMT will be of considerable value for providing cellular targets amenable to therapeutic intervention for DFUs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SIRT6-regulated macrophage efferocytosis epigenetically controls inflammation resolution of diabetic periodontitis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36593966/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36593966/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rationale:&lt;/em&gt; Diabetes exacerbates the prevalence and severity of periodontitis, leading to severe periodontal destruction and ultimately tooth loss. Delayed resolution of inflammation is a major contributor to diabetic periodontitis (DP) pathogenesis, but the underlying mechanisms of this imbalanced immune homeostasis remain unclear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; We collected periodontium from periodontitis with or without diabetes to confirm the dysfunctional neutrophils and macrophages in aggravated inflammatory damage and impaired inflammation resolution. Our in vitro experiments confirmed that SIRT6 inhibited macrophage efferocytosis by restraining miR-216a-5p-216b-5p-217 cluster maturation through &amp;lsquo;&amp;rsquo;non-canonical&amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo; microprocessor complex (RNA pulldown, RIP, immunostaining, CHIP, Luciferase assays, and FISH). Moreover, we constructed m6SKO mice that underwent LIP-induced periodontitis to explore the in vitro and in vivo effect of SIRT6 on macrophage efferocytosis. Finally, antagomiR-217, a miRNA antagonism, was delivered into the periodontium to treat LIP-induced diabetic periodontitis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; We discovered that insufficient SIRT6 as a histone deacetylase in macrophages led to unresolved inflammation and aggravated periodontitis in both human and mouse DP with accumulated apoptotic neutrophil (AN) and higher generation of neutrophil extracellular traps. Mechanistically, we validated that macrophage underwent high glucose stimulation resulting in disturbance of the SIRT6-miR-216/217 axis that triggered impeded efferocytosis of AN through targeting the DEL-1/CD36 axis directly. Furthermore, we demonstrated the inhibitory role of SIRT6 for MIR217HG transcription and identified a non-canonical action of microprocessor that SIRT6 epigenetically hindered the splicing of the primary miR-216/217 via the complex of hnRNPA2B1, DGCR8, and Drosha. Notably, by constructing myeloid-specific deletion of SIRT6 mice and locally delivering antagomir-217 in DP models, we strengthened the in vivo effect of this axis in regulating macrophage efferocytosis and inflammation resolution in DP.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; Our findings delineated the emerging role of SIRT6 in mediating metabolic dysfunction-associated inflammation, and therapeutically targeting this regulatory axis might be a promising strategy for treating diabetes-associated inflammatory diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Histone Citrullination Mediates a Protective Role in Endothelium and Modulates Inflammation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36552833/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36552833/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NETosis is a key host immune process against a pathogenic infection during innate immune activation, consisting of a neutrophil &amp;ldquo;explosion&amp;rdquo; and, consequently, NET formation, containing mainly DNA, histones, and other nuclear proteins. During sepsis, an exacerbated immune host response to an infection occurs, activating the innate immunity and NETosis events, which requires histone H3 citrullination. Our group compared the circulating histone levels with those citrullinated H3 levels in plasma samples of septic patients. In addition, we demonstrated that citrullinated histones were less cytotoxic for endothelial cells than histones without this post-translational modification. Citrullinated histones did not affect cell viability and did not activate oxidative stress. Nevertheless, citrullinated histones induced an inflammatory response, as well as regulatory endothelial mechanisms. Furthermore, septic patients showed elevated levels of circulating citrullinated histone H3, indicating that the histone citrullination is produced during the first stages of sepsis, probably due to the NETosis process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neutrophil Extracellular Traps Induce Glomerular Endothelial Cell Dysfunction and Pyroptosis in Diabetic Kidney Disease</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36095260/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36095260/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Diabetic kidney disease (DKD) is the leading cause of end-stage renal disease. Neutrophil extracellular traps (NETs) are a network structure composed of loose chromatin and embedded with multiple proteins. Here, we observed increased NETs deposition in the glomeruli of DKD patients and diabetic mice (streptozotocin-induced or db/db mice). After NETs were degraded with DNase I, diabetic mice exhibited attenuated glomerulopathy and glomerular endothelial cells (GECs) injury. We also observed alleviated glomerulopathy and GECs injury in peptidylarginine deiminase 4-knockout mice with streptozotocin-induced diabetes. In vitro, NETs-induced GECs pyroptosis was characterized by pore formation in the cell membrane, dysregulation of multiple genes involved in cell membrane function, and increased expression of pyroptosis-related proteins. Strengthening the GECs surface charge by oleylamine significantly inhibited NETs-induced GECs pyroptosis. These findings suggest that the GECs charge-related pyroptosis is involved in DKD progression, which is promoted by NETs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An anticomplement homogeneous polysaccharide from Hedyotis diffusa attenuates lipopolysaccharide-induced acute lung injury and inhibits neutrophil extracellular trap formation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36116199/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36116199/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Owing to the involvement of the overactivated complement system in acute lung injury (ALI) development, anticomplement components may attenuate ALI. Hedyotis diffusa is a traditional Chinese medicine for treating lung heat and its crude polysaccharides (HDP) exhibit significant anticomplement activity in vitro.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Purpose:&lt;/em&gt; To obtain an anticomplement homogeneous polysaccharide from HDP and verify its therapeutic effect and mechanism on ALI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; Diethylaminoethyl-52 (DEAE-52) cellulose and gel permeation columns were used to isolate a homogeneous polysaccharide HD-PS-3, which was then characterized using nuclear magnetic resonance (NMR) and methylation analysis. In vitro, the anticomplement activities of HD-PS-3 through classical and alternative pathways were determined using a hemolytic test. The therapeutic effects of HDP and HD-PS-3 on ALI were evaluated in lipopolysaccharide (LPS) intratracheal instilled mice. Hematoxylin and eosin (H&amp;amp;E) staining, enzyme-linked immunosorbent assay (ELISA), and immunohistochemical staining were used to assess histological changes, measure cytokine levels, and evaluate the degree of complement component 3c (C3c) deposition and neutrophil infiltration, respectively. ELISA, western blotting, and immunofluorescence were used to analyze neutrophil extracellular trap (NET) formation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; From HDP, 1.5 g of the homogeneous polysaccharide HD-PS-3 was obtained. HD-PS-3 was an acidic heteropolysaccharide with an acetyl group, which was composed of →4,6)-α-Glcp-(1→, →3,4)-α-Glcp-(1→, →4)-α-Glcp-(1→, →4,6)-α-Galp-(1→, →5)-α-Araf-(1→, α-Rhap-(1→, α-Araf-(1→, α-GlcpA-(1→, →4)-β-Manp-(1→, β-Manp-(1→ and →3)-β-Manp-(1→. The in vitro results suggest that HD-PS-3 exhibited anticomplement activity with CH50 and AP50 values of 115 ± 12 μg/ml and 307 ± 11 μg/ml, respectively. After confirming the efficacy of HDP (200 mg/kg) in attenuating lung injury, the effect of HD-PS-3 on ALI was also investigated. HD-PS-3 (75 and 150 mg/kg) attenuated LPS-induced ALI as well, evidenced by lung pathology, lung injury scores, protein concentration, leukocyte counts, tumor necrosis factor-α (TNF-α), and interleukin-6 (IL-6) contents in bronchoalveolar lavage fluid (BALF). Mechanistically, HD-PS-3 inhibited complement activation, manifested in reduced pulmonary C3c deposition in lung tissue and complement component 3a (C3a) content in BALF. Neutrophil recruitment was also reduced by HD-PS-3, with significantly reduced pulmonary neutrophil infiltration and lower levels of C-X-C motif chemokine ligand 1 (CXCL1) and myeloperoxidase (MPO) in BALF. In addition, HD-PS-3 reduced the levels of MPO-DNA complex in BALF, decreased citrullinated histone H3 (Cit H3) expression and NET formation (colocalization of MPO, Cit H3, and DNA) in lung tissue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/em&gt; An anticomplement homogeneous polysaccharide HD-PS-3 was isolated from H. diffusa. HD-PS-3 exhibited a therapeutic effect against ALI, and the mechanism might be related to its inhibitory effects on complement activation, neutrophil recruitment, and NET formation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NETosis and thrombosis in vaccine-induced immune thrombotic thrombocytopenia</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36064843/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36064843/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vaccine-induced immune thrombotic thrombocytopenia (VITT) is a rare yet serious adverse effect of the adenoviral vector vaccines ChAdOx1 nCoV-19 (AstraZeneca) and Ad26.COV2.S (Janssen) against COVID-19. The mechanisms involved in clot formation and thrombocytopenia in VITT are yet to be fully determined. Here we show neutrophils undergoing NETosis and confirm expression markers of NETs in VITT patients. VITT antibodies directly stimulate neutrophils to release NETs and induce thrombus formation containing abundant platelets, neutrophils, fibrin, extracellular DNA and citrullinated histone H3 in a flow microfluidics system and in vivo. Inhibition of NETosis prevents VITT-induced thrombosis in mice but not thrombocytopenia. In contrast, in vivo blockage of FcγRIIa abrogates both thrombosis and thrombocytopenia suggesting these are distinct processes. Our findings indicate that anti-PF4 antibodies activate blood cells via FcγRIIa and are responsible for thrombosis and thrombocytopenia in VITT. Future development of NETosis and FcγRIIa inhibitors are needed to treat VITT and similar immune thrombotic thrombocytopenia conditions more effectively, leading to better patient outcomes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CLEC5A is critical in Pseudomonas aeruginosa-induced NET formation and acute lung injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36048544/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36048544/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Pseudomonas aeruginosa&lt;/em&gt; is one of the most common nosocomial infections worldwide, and it frequently causes ventilator-associated acute pneumonia in immunocompromised patients. Abundant neutrophil extracellular traps (NETs) contribute to acute lung injury, thereby aggravating ventilator-induced lung damage. While pattern recognition receptors (PRRs) TLR4 and TLR5 are required for host defense against &lt;em&gt;P. aeruginosa&lt;/em&gt; invasion, the PRR responsible for &lt;em&gt;P. aeruginosa&lt;/em&gt;-induced NET formation, proinflammatory cytokine release, and acute lung injury remains unclear. We found that myeloid C-type lectin domain family 5 member A (CLEC5A) interacts with LPS of &lt;em&gt;P. aeruginosa&lt;/em&gt; and is responsible for &lt;em&gt;P. aeruginosa&lt;/em&gt;-induced NET formation and lung inflammation. &lt;em&gt;P. aeruginosa&lt;/em&gt; activates CLEC5A to induce caspase-1-dependent NET formation, but it neither causes gasdermin D (GSDMD) cleavage nor contributes to &lt;em&gt;P. aeruginosa&lt;/em&gt;-induced neutrophil death. Blockade of CLEC5A attenuates &lt;em&gt;P. aeruginosa&lt;/em&gt;-induced NETosis and lung injury, and simultaneous administration of anti-CLEC5A mAb with ciprofloxacin increases survival rate and decreases collagen deposition in the lungs of mice challenged with a lethal dose of &lt;em&gt;P. aeruginosa&lt;/em&gt;. Thus, CLEC5A is a promising therapeutic target to reduce ventilator-associated lung injury and fibrosis in &lt;em&gt;P. aeruginosa&lt;/em&gt;-induced pneumonia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neutrophil extracellular traps-triggered impaired autophagic flux via METTL3 underlies sepsis-associated acute lung injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36030287/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36030287/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Neutrophil extracellular traps (NETs) assist pathogen clearance, while excessive NETs formation is associated with exacerbated inflammatory responses and tissue injury in acute lung injury (ALI)/acute respiratory distress syndrome (ARDS). Autophagy is generally considered to be a protective process, but autophagy dysfunction is harmful. Whether and how NETs affect autophagic flux during sepsis-induced ALI are currently unknown. Here, we confirmed that the level of NETs was increased in ARDS patients and mice models, which led to impairment of autophagic flux and deterioration of the disease. Mechanistically, NETs activated METTL3 mediated m&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;A methylation of Sirt1 mRNA in alveolar epithelial cells, resulting in abnormal autophagy. These findings provide new insights into how NETs contribute to the development of sepsis-associated ALI/ARDS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CuO-NPs-triggered heterophil extracellular traps exacerbate liver injury in chicks by promoting oxidative stress and inflammatory responses</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35962800/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35962800/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the widespread use of copper oxide nanoparticles (CuO-NPs), their potential toxicity to the environment and biological health has attracted close attention. Heterophil extracellular traps (HETs) are an innate immune mechanism of chicken heterophils against adverse stimuli, but excessive HETs cause damage. Here, we explored the effect and mechanism of CuO-NPs on HETs formation in vitro and further evaluated the potential role of HETs in chicken liver and kidney injury. Heterophils were exposed to 5, 10, and 20 µg/mL of CuO-NPs for 2 h. The results showed that CuO-NPs induced typical HETs formation, which was dependent on NADPH oxidase, P38 and extracellular regulated protein kinases (ERK&lt;sub&gt;1/2&lt;/sub&gt;) pathways, and glycolysis. In in vivo experiments, fluorescence microplate and morphological analysis showed that CuO-NPs elevated the level of HETs in chicken serum and caused liver and kidney damage. Meanwhile, CuO-NPs caused hepatic oxidative stress (MDA, SOD, CAT, and GSH-PX imbalance), and also induced an increase in mRNA expression of their inflammatory and apoptosis-related factors (IL-1β, IL-6, TNF-α, COX-2, iNOS, NLRP3, and Caspase-1, 3, 11). However, these results were significantly altered by DNase I (HETs degradation reagent). In conclusion, the present study demonstrates for the first time that CuO-NPs induce the formation of HETs and that HETs exacerbate pathological damage in chicken liver and kidney by promoting oxidative stress and inflammation, providing insights into immunotoxicity and potential prevention and treatment targets caused by CuO-NPs overexposure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Noninvasive imaging of the lung NETosis by anti-Ly6G iron oxide nanoparticles</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35991979/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35991979/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is challenging to visualize noninvasively the formation of neutrophil extracellular traps, known as NETosis, and therefore difficult to monitor disease progression. A desirable molecular imaging probe is the iron oxide nanoparticle (NP) that could induce reactive oxygen species. Here, we used C57BL/6 mice with pristane-induced lupus, which mimics systemic lupus erythematosus. Administration of anti-Ly6G antibody-conjugated NP allowed detection of NETosis with fluorescent molecular imaging, as evidenced by flow cytometric analysis of citrullinated histone H3 expression in lung neutrophils. This finding was consistent with NP-induced blood NETosis in a spontaneous lupus model of B6.MRL-&lt;em&gt;lpr&lt;/em&gt; mice. &lt;em&gt;A chronic&lt;/em&gt; assessment was performed in which the lupus mice were protected from enhanced oxidative burst by anti-Ly6G NP. This NP can migrate from the peritoneal cavity to the lungs, as visualized by magnetic particle imaging. Overall, our study provides evidence for a highly sensitive assessment of NETosis in lupus through magnetic particle imaging.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Platelets in the NETworks interweaving inflammation and thrombosis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/35979369/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/35979369/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Platelets are well characterized for their indispensable role in primary hemostasis to control hemorrhage. Research over the past years has provided a substantial body of evidence demonstrating that platelets also participate in host innate immunity. The surface expression of pattern recognition receptors, such as TLR2 and TLR4, provides platelets with the ability to sense bacterial products in their environment. Platelet α-granules contain microbicidal proteins, chemokines and growth factors, which upon release may directly engage pathogens and/or contribute to inflammatory signaling. Additionally, platelet interactions with neutrophils enhance neutrophil activation and are often crucial to induce a sufficient immune response. In particular, platelets can activate neutrophils to form neutrophil extracellular traps (NETs). This specific neutrophil effector function is characterized by neutrophils expelling chromatin fibres decorated with histones and antimicrobial proteins into the extracellular space where they serve to trap and kill pathogens. Until now, the mechanisms and signaling pathways between platelets and neutrophils inducing NET formation are still not fully characterized. NETs were also detected in thrombotic lesions in several disease backgrounds, pointing towards a role as an interface between neutrophils, platelets and thrombosis, also known as immunothrombosis. The negatively charged DNA within NETs provides a procoagulant surface, and in particular NET-derived proteins may directly activate platelets. In light of the current COVID-19 pandemic, the topic of immunothrombosis has become more relevant than ever, as a majority of COVID-19 patients display thrombi in the lung capillaries and other vascular beds. Furthermore, NETs can be found in the lung and other tissues and are associated with an increased mortality. Here, virus infiltration may lead to a cytokine storm that potently activates neutrophils and leads to massive neutrophil infiltration into the lung and NET formation. The resulting NETs presumably activate platelets and coagulation factors, further contributing to the subsequent emergence of microthrombi in pulmonary capillaries. In this review, we will discuss the interplay between platelets and NETs and the potential of this alliance to influence the course of inflammatory diseases. A better understanding of the underlying molecular mechanisms and the identification of treatment targets is of utmost importance to increase patients&amp;rsquo; survival and improve the clinical outcome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The role of neutrophil extracellular traps in acute lung injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/35967320/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/35967320/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acute lung injury (ALI) is a heterogeneous inflammatory condition associated with high morbidity and mortality. Neutrophils play a key role in the development of different forms of ALI, and the release of neutrophil extracellular traps (NETs) is emerging as a common pathogenic mechanism. NETs are essential in controlling pathogens, and their defective release or increased degradation leads to a higher risk of infection. However, NETs also contain several pro-inflammatory and cytotoxic molecules than can exacerbate thromboinflammation and lung tissue injury. To reduce NET-mediated lung damage and inflammation, DNase is frequently used in preclinical models of ALI due to its capability of digesting NET DNA scaffold. Moreover, recent advances in neutrophil biology led to the development of selective NET inhibitors, which also appear to reduce ALI in experimental models. Here we provide an overview of the role of NETs in different forms of ALI discussing existing gaps in our knowledge and novel therapeutic approaches to modulate their impact on lung injury.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Targeting ETosis by miR-155 inhibition mitigates mixed granulocytic asthmatic lung inflammation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35958610/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35958610/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Asthma is phenotypically heterogeneous with several distinctive pathological mechanistic pathways. Previous studies indicate that neutrophilic asthma has a poor response to standard asthma treatments comprising inhaled corticosteroids. Therefore, it is important to identify critical factors that contribute to increased numbers of neutrophils in asthma patients whose symptoms are poorly controlled by conventional therapy. Leukocytes release chromatin fibers, referred to as extracellular traps (ETs) consisting of double-stranded (ds) DNA, histones, and granule contents. Excessive components of ETs contribute to the pathophysiology of asthma; however, it is unclear how ETs drive asthma phenotypes and whether they could be a potential therapeutic target. We employed a mouse model of severe asthma that recapitulates the intricate immune responses of neutrophilic and eosinophilic airway inflammation identified in patients with severe asthma. We used both a pharmacologic approach using miR-155 inhibitor-laden exosomes and genetic approaches using miR-155 knockout mice. Our data show that ETs are present in the bronchoalveolar lavage fluid of patients with mild asthma subjected to experimental subsegmental bronchoprovocation to an allergen and a severe asthma mouse model, which resembles the complex immune responses identified in severe human asthma. Furthermore, we show that miR-155 contributes to the extracellular release of dsDNA, which exacerbates allergic lung inflammation, and the inhibition of miR-155 results in therapeutic benefit in severe asthma mice. Our findings show that targeting dsDNA release represents an attractive therapeutic target for mitigating neutrophilic asthma phenotype, which is clinically refractory to standard care.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Salvianolic Acid A Protects against Lipopolysaccharide-Induced Acute Lung Injury by Inhibiting Neutrophil NETosis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35910849/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35910849/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Salvianolic acid A (SAA) is one of bioactive polyphenol extracted from a Salvia miltiorrhiza (Danshen), which was widely used to treat cardiovascular disease in traditional Chinese medicine. SAA has been reported to be protective in cardiovascular disease and ischemia injury, with anti-inflammatory and antioxidative effect, but its role in acute lung injury (ALI) is still unknown. In this study, we sought to investigate the therapeutic effects of SAA in a murine model of lipopolysaccharide- (LPS-) induced ALI. The optimal dose of SAA was determined by comparing the attenuation of lung injury score after administration of SAA at three different doses (low, 5 mg/kg; medium, 10 mg/kg; and, high 15 mg/kg). Dexamethasone (DEX) was used as a positive control for SAA. Here, we showed that the therapeutic effect of SAA (10 mg/kg) against LPS-induced pathologic injury in the lungs was comparable to DEX. SAA and DEX attenuated the increased W/D ratio and the protein level, counts of total cells and neutrophils, and cytokine levels in the BALF of ALI mice similarly. The oxidative stress was also relieved by SAA and DEX according to the superoxide dismutase and malondialdehyde. NET level in the lungs was elevated in the injured lung while SAA and DEX reduced it significantly. LPS induced phosphorylation of Src, Raf, MEK, and ERK in the lungs, which was inhibited by SAA and DEX. NET level and phosphorylation level of Src/Raf/MEK/ERK pathway in the neutrophils from acute respiratory distress syndrome (ARDS) patients were also inhibited by SAA and DEX in vitro, but the YEEI peptide reversed the protective effect of SAA completely. The inhibition of NET release by SAA was also reversed by YEEI peptide in LPS-challenged neutrophils from healthy volunteers. Our data demonstrated that SAA ameliorated ALI via attenuating inflammation, oxidative stress, and neutrophil NETosis. The mechanism of such protective effect might involve the inhibition of Src activation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Benzyl butyl phthalate (BBP) induces lung injury and fibrosis through neutrophil extracellular traps</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35835272/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35835272/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Benzyl butyl phthalate (BBP) is an extensively used plasticizer that has aroused widespread concern about its potential toxicity. Previous evidences demonstrate that BBP exposure is associated with asthma and impaired lung function. Accumulating data indicates that neutrophil extracellular traps (NETs), a particular manner of neutrophil death, play a vital role in the pathogenesis of respiratory diseases. However, the immunotoxicity effects of BBP in lung injury are unclear. Here, we aimed to investigate the potential impacts of BBP-induced NETs on lung injury and fibrosis. Mice treated with BBP exhibited significant lung injury, with alveolar hemorrhage, lung edema and increased neutrophil infiltration. Meanwhile, BBP promoted extensive neutrophil infiltration in bronchoalveolar lavage fluid and NETs deposition in lung tissues. Moreover, BBP clearly triggered NETs formation in vitro, which was confirmed by net-like structures decorated with myeloperoxidase and citrullinated histone H3. Furthermore, BBP fueled glucose uptake and ROS burst of neutrophils playing essential roles during NETs formation. Additionally, we proved that NETs could promote fibrogenesis in murine lung epithelial cells and observed lung fibrosis remarkably after BBP-induced injury. Taken together, our findings indicated that exposure to BBP could increase the risk for lung injury and fibrosis by disturbing innate immunity via NETs formation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lysophosphatidylcholine Alleviates Acute Lung Injury by Regulating Neutrophil Motility and Neutrophil Extracellular Trap Formation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35859904/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35859904/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sepsis is predominantly initiated by bacterial infection and can cause systemic inflammation, which frequently leads to rapid death of the patient. However, this acute systemic inflammatory response requires further investigation from the perspectives of clinical judgment criteria and early treatment strategies for the relief of symptoms. Lysophosphatidylcholine (LPC) 18:0 may relieve septic symptoms, but the relevant mechanism is not clearly understood. Therefore, we aimed to assess the effectiveness of LPC as a therapeutic treatment for acute inflammation in the lung induced by lipopolysaccharide in mice. Systemic inflammation of mice was induced by lipopolysaccharide (LPS) inoculation to investigate the role of LPC in the migration and the immune response of neutrophils during acute lung injury. By employing two-photon intravital imaging of the LPS-stimulated LysM-GFP mice and other &lt;em&gt;in vitro&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt; assays, we examined whether LPC alleviates the inflammatory effect of sepsis. We also tested the effect of LPC to human neutrophils from healthy control and sepsis patients. Our data showed that LPC treatment reduced the infiltration of innate immune cells into the lung. Specifically, LPC altered neutrophil migratory patterns and enhanced phagocytic efficacy in the damaged lung. Moreover, LPC treatment reduced the release of neutrophil extracellular trap (NET), which can damage tissue in the inflamed organ and exacerbate disease. It also reduced human neutrophil migration under inflammatory environment. Our results suggest that LPC can alleviate sepsis-induced lung inflammation by regulating the function of neutrophils. These findings provide evidence for the beneficial application of LPC treatment as a potential therapeutic strategy for sepsis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Fatal Circle of NETs and NET-Associated DAMPs Contributing to Organ Dysfunction</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/35741047/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/35741047/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The innate immune system is the first line of defense against invading pathogens or sterile injuries. Pattern recognition receptors (PRR) sense molecules released from inflamed or damaged cells, or foreign molecules resulting from invading pathogens. PRRs can in turn induce inflammatory responses, comprising the generation of cytokines or chemokines, which further induce immune cell recruitment. Neutrophils represent an essential factor in the early immune response and fulfill numerous tasks to fight infection or heal injuries. The release of neutrophil extracellular traps (NETs) is part of it and was originally attributed to the capture and elimination of pathogens. In the last decade studies revealed a detrimental role of NETs during several diseases, often correlated with an exaggerated immune response. Overwhelming inflammation in single organs can induce remote organ damage, thereby further perpetuating release of inflammatory molecules. Here, we review recent findings regarding damage-associated molecular patterns (DAMPs) which are able to induce NET formation, as well as NET components known to act as DAMPs, generating a putative fatal circle of inflammation contributing to organ damage and sequentially occurring remote organ injury.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Down-regulated miR-146a expression with increased neutrophil extracellular traps and apoptosis formation in autoimmune-mediated diffuse alveolar hemorrhage</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36028828/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36028828/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Increasing evidences have suggested an important role of microRNAs (miRNAs) in regulating cell death processes including NETosis and apoptosis. Dysregulated expression of miRNAs and increased formation of neutrophil extracellular traps (NETs) and apoptosis participate in autoimmune-mediated diffuse alveolar hemorrhage (DAH), mostly associated with pulmonary capillaritis in systemic lupus erythematosus (SLE) patients. In particular, besides the inhibition of apoptosis, miR-146a can control innate and acquired immune responses, and regulate the toll-like receptor pathway through targeting TRAF6 to reduce the expression of pro-inflammatory cytokines/chemokines like IL-8, a NETosis inducer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; Expression of miR-146a, TRAF6 and NETs were examined in peripheral blood neutrophils (PBNs) and lung tissues from SLE-associated DAH patients, and in neutrophils and pristane-induced DAH lung tissues from C57BL/6 mice. To assess NETs formation, we examined NETosis-related DNAs morphology and crucial mediators including protein arginine deiminase 4 and citrullinated Histone 3. Expression of miR-146a and its endogenous RNA SNHG16 were studied in HL-60 promyelocytic cells and MLE-12 alveolar cells during NETosis and apoptosis processes, respectively. MiR-146a-overexpressed and CRISPR-Cas13d-mediated SNHG16-silenced HL-60 cells were investigated for NETosis. MiR-146a-overexpressed MLE-12 cells were analyzed for apoptosis. Pristane-injected mice received intra-pulmonary miR-146a delivery to evaluate therapeutic efficacy in DAH.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; In DAH patients, there were down-regulated miR-146a levels with increased TRAF6 expression and PMA/LPS-induced NETosis in PBNs, and down-regulated miR-146a levels with increased TRAF6, high-mobility group box 1 (HMGB1), IL-8, NETs and apoptosis expression in lung tissues. HMGB1-stimulated mouse neutrophils had down-regulated miR-146a levels with increased TRAF6, IL-8 and NETs expression. PMA-stimulated HL-60 cells had down-regulated miR-146a levels with enhanced NETosis. MiR-146a-overexpressed or SNHG16-silenced HL-60 cells showed reduced NETosis. Apoptotic MLE-12 cells had down-regulated miR-146a expression and increased HMGB1 release, while miR-146a-overexpressed MLE-12 cells showed reduced apoptosis and HMGB1 production. There were down-regulated miR-146a levels with increased TRAF6, HMGB1, IL-8, NETs and apoptosis expression in mouse DAH lung tissues. Intra-pulmonary miR-146a delivery could suppress DAH by reducing TRAF6, IL-8, NETs and apoptosis expression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; Our results demonstrate firstly down-regulated pulmonary miR-146a levels with increased TRAF6 and IL-8 expression and NETs and apoptosis formation in autoimmune-mediated DAH, and implicate a therapeutic potential of intra-pulmonary miR-146a delivery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oxidized Phospholipids Promote NETosis and Arterial Thrombosis in LNK(SH2B3) Deficiency</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34846914/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34846914/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; LNK/SH2B3 inhibits Janus kinase/signal transducer and activator of transcription (JAK/STAT) signaling by hematopoietic cytokine receptors. Genome-wide association studies have shown association of a common single nucleotide polymorphism in &lt;em&gt;LNK&lt;/em&gt; (R262W, T allele) with neutrophilia, thrombocytosis, and coronary artery disease. We have shown that &lt;em&gt;LNK(TT)&lt;/em&gt; reduces LNK function and that LNK-deficient mice display prominent platelet-neutrophil aggregates, accelerated atherosclerosis, and thrombosis. Platelet-neutrophil interactions can promote neutrophil extracellular trap (NET) formation. The goals of this study were to assess the role of NETs in atherosclerosis and thrombosis in mice with hematopoietic &lt;em&gt;Lnk&lt;/em&gt; deficiency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; We bred mice with combined deficiency of &lt;em&gt;Lnk&lt;/em&gt; and the NETosis-essential enzyme PAD4 (peptidyl arginine deiminase 4) and transplanted their bone marrow into &lt;em&gt;Ldlr&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; mice. We evaluated the role of LNK in atherothrombosis in humans and mice bearing a gain of function variant in JAK2 (JAK2&lt;sup&gt;V617F&lt;/sup&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; Lnk-deficient mice displayed accelerated carotid artery thrombosis with prominent NETosis that was completely reversed by PAD4 deficiency. Thrombin-activated &lt;em&gt;Lnk&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; platelets promoted increased NETosis when incubated with &lt;em&gt;Lnk&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; neutrophils compared with wild-type platelets or wild-type neutrophils. This involved increased surface exposure and release of oxidized phospholipids (OxPL) from &lt;em&gt;Lnk&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; platelets, as well as increased priming and response of &lt;em&gt;Lnk&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; neutrophils to OxPL. To counteract the effects of OxPL, we introduced a transgene expressing the single-chain variable fragment of E06 (E06-scFv). E06-scFv reversed accelerated NETosis, atherosclerosis, and thrombosis in Lnk-/- mice. We also showed increased NETosis when human induced pluripotent stem cell-derived &lt;em&gt;LNK(TT)&lt;/em&gt; neutrophils were incubated with &lt;em&gt;LNK(TT)&lt;/em&gt; platelet/megakaryocytes, but not in isogenic &lt;em&gt;LNK(CC)&lt;/em&gt; controls, confirming human relevance. Using data from the UK Biobank, we found that individuals with the JAK2&lt;sup&gt;VF&lt;/sup&gt; mutation only showed increased risk of coronary artery disease when also carrying the LNK R262W allele. Mice with hematopoietic &lt;em&gt;Lnk&lt;sup&gt;+/-&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Jak2&lt;sup&gt;VF&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; clonal hematopoiesis showed accelerated arterial thrombosis but not atherosclerosis compared with &lt;em&gt;Jak2&lt;sup&gt;VF&lt;/sup&gt;Lnk&lt;sup&gt;+/+&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; controls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; Hematopoietic &lt;em&gt;Lnk&lt;/em&gt; deficiency promotes NETosis and arterial thrombosis in an OxPL-dependent fashion. LNK(R262W) reduces LNK function in human platelets and neutrophils, promoting NETosis, and increases coronary artery disease risk in humans carrying &lt;em&gt;Jak2&lt;sup&gt;VF&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; mutations. Therapies targeting OxPL may be beneficial for coronary artery disease in genetically defined human populations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Complement and tissue factor-enriched neutrophil extracellular traps are key drivers in COVID-19 immunothrombosis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32759504/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32759504/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Emerging data indicate that complement and neutrophils contribute to the maladaptive immune response that fuels hyperinflammation and thrombotic microangiopathy, thereby increasing coronavirus 2019 (COVID-19) mortality. Here, we investigated how complement interacts with the platelet/neutrophil extracellular traps (NETs)/thrombin axis, using COVID-19 specimens, cell-based inhibition studies, and NET/human aortic endothelial cell (HAEC) cocultures. Increased plasma levels of NETs, tissue factor (TF) activity, and sC5b-9 were detected in patients. Neutrophils of patients yielded high TF expression and released NETs carrying active TF. Treatment of control neutrophils with COVID-19 platelet-rich plasma generated TF-bearing NETs that induced thrombotic activity of HAECs. Thrombin or NETosis inhibition or C5aR1 blockade attenuated platelet-mediated NET-driven thrombogenicity. COVID-19 serum induced complement activation in vitro, consistent with high complement activity in clinical samples. Complement C3 inhibition with compstatin Cp40 disrupted TF expression in neutrophils. In conclusion, we provide a mechanistic basis for a pivotal role of complement and NETs in COVID-19 immunothrombosis. This study supports strategies against severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 that exploit complement or NETosis inhibition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
