<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>NETosis | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/netosis/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/netosis/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>NETosis</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>NETosis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/netosis/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Homeostatic, Non-Canonical Role of Macrophage Elastase in Vascular Integrity</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36691905/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36691905/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Matrix metalloproteinase (MMP)-12 is highly expressed in abdominal aortic aneurysms and its elastolytic function has been implicated in the pathogenesis. This concept is challenged, however, by conflicting data. Here, we sought to revisit the role of MMP-12 in abdominal aortic aneurysm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;Apoe&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Mmp12&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt;/&lt;em&gt;Apoe&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; mice were infused with Ang II (angiotensin). Expression of neutrophil extracellular traps (NETs) markers and complement component 3 (C3) levels were evaluated by immunostaining in aortas of surviving animals. Plasma complement components were analyzed by immunoassay. The effects of a complement inhibitor, IgG-FH1-5 (factor H-immunoglobulin G), and macrophage-specific MMP-12 deficiency on adverse aortic remodeling and death from rupture in Ang II-infused mice were determined.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; Unexpectedly, death from aortic rupture was significantly higher in &lt;em&gt;Mmp12&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt;/&lt;em&gt;Apoe&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; mice. This associated with more neutrophils, citrullinated histone H3 and neutrophil elastase, markers of NETs, and C3 levels in &lt;em&gt;Mmp12&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; aortas. These findings were recapitulated in additional models of abdominal aortic aneurysm. MMP-12 deficiency also led to more pronounced elastic laminae degradation and reduced collagen integrity. Higher plasma C5a in &lt;em&gt;Mmp12&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; mice pointed to complement overactivation. Treatment with IgG-FH1-5 decreased aortic wall NETosis and reduced adverse aortic remodeling and death from rupture in Ang II-infused &lt;em&gt;Mmp12&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; mice. Finally, macrophage-specific MMP-12 deficiency recapitulated the effects of global MMP-12 deficiency on complement deposition and NETosis, as well as adverse aortic remodeling and death from rupture in Ang II-infused mice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; An MMP-12 deficiency/complement activation/NETosis pathway compromises aortic integrity, which predisposes to adverse vascular remodeling and abdominal aortic aneurysm rupture. Considering these new findings, the role of macrophage MMP-12 in vascular homeostasis demands re-evaluation of MMP-12 function in diverse settings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chloroquine reduces neutrophil extracellular trap (NET) formation through inhibition of peptidyl arginine deiminase 4 (PAD4)</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36655514/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36655514/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Neutrophil extracellular traps (NETs) occur when chromatin is decondensed and extruded from the cell, generating a web-like structure. NETs have been implicated in the pathogenesis of several sterile disease states and thus a potential therapeutic target. Various pathways have been shown to induce NETs, including autophagy, with several key enzymes being activated like peptidyl arginine deiminase 4 (PAD4), an enzyme responsible for citrullination of histones, allowing for DNA unwinding and subsequent release from the cell. Pre-clinical studies have already demonstrated that chloroquine (CQ) and hydroxychloroquine (HCQ) are able to reduce NETs and slow disease progression. The exact mechanism as to how these drugs reduce NETs has yet to be elucidated. CQ and HCQ decrease NET formation from various NET activators, independent of their autophagy inhibitory function. CQ and HCQ were found to inhibit PAD4 exclusively, in a dose dependent manner, confirmed with reduced CitH3+ NETs after CQ or HCQ treatment. Circulating CitH3 levels were reduced in pancreatic cancer patients after HCQ treatment. In silico screening of PAD4 protein structure identified a likely binding site interaction at Arg639 for CQ and Trp347, Ser468 and Glu580 for HCQ. SPR analysis confirmed binding of HCQ and CQ with PAD4 with KD values of 54.1 µM (CQ) and 88.1 µM (HCQ). This data provides evidence of direct PAD4 inhibition as a mechanism for CQ/HCQ inhibition of NETs. We propose that these drugs likely reduce NET formation through multiple mechanisms; the previously established TLR9 and autophagy inhibitory mechanism and the novel PAD4 inhibitory mechanism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neutrophil, neutrophil extracellular traps and endothelial cell dysfunction in sepsis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/36629024/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/36629024/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sepsis is a persistent systemic inflammatory condition involving multiple organ failures resulting from a dysregulated immune response to infection, and one of the hallmarks of sepsis is endothelial dysfunction. During its progression, neutrophils are the first line of innate immune defence against infection. Aside from traditional mechanisms, such as phagocytosis or the release of inflammatory cytokines, reactive oxygen species and other antibacterial substances, activated neutrophils also release web-like structures composed of tangled decondensed DNA, histone, myeloperoxidase and other granules called neutrophil extracellular traps (NETs), which can efficiently ensnare bacteria in the circulation. In contrast, excessive neutrophil activation and NET release may induce endothelial cells to shift toward a pro-inflammatory and pro-coagulant phenotype. Furthermore, neutrophils and NETs can degrade glycocalyx on the endothelial cell surface and increase endothelium permeability. Consequently, the endothelial barrier collapses, contributing to impaired microcirculatory blood flow, tissue hypoperfusion and life-threatening organ failure in the late phase of sepsis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alpha-1 antitrypsin limits neutrophil extracellular trap disruption of airway epithelial barrier function</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36703990/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36703990/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Neutrophil extracellular traps contribute to lung injury in cystic fibrosis and asthma, but the mechanisms are poorly understood. We sought to understand the impact of human NETs on barrier function in primary human bronchial epithelial and a human airway epithelial cell line. We demonstrate that NETs disrupt airway epithelial barrier function by decreasing transepithelial electrical resistance and increasing paracellular flux, partially by NET-induced airway cell apoptosis. NETs selectively impact the expression of tight junction genes claudins 4, 8 and 11. Bronchial epithelia exposed to NETs demonstrate visible gaps in E-cadherin staining, a decrease in full-length E-cadherin protein and the appearance of cleaved E-cadherin peptides. Pretreatment of NETs with alpha-1 antitrypsin (A1AT) inhibits NET serine protease activity, limits E-cadherin cleavage, decreases bronchial cell apoptosis and preserves epithelial integrity. In conclusion, NETs disrupt human airway epithelial barrier function through bronchial cell death and degradation of E-cadherin, which are limited by exogenous A1AT.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neutrophil Extracellular Traps Promote Metastases of Colorectal Cancers through Activation of ERK Signaling by Releasing Neutrophil Elastase</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36674635/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36674635/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Neutrophil extracellular traps (NETs) play important roles in host immunity, as there is increasing evidence of their contribution to the progression of several types of cancers even though their role in colorectal cancers (CRCs) remains unclear. To investigate the clinical relevance of NETs in CRCs, we examined the expression of citrullinated histone H3 using immunohistochemistry and preoperative serum myeloperoxidase-DNA complexes in CRC patients using an enzyme-linked immunosorbent assay. High expression of intratumoral or systemic NETs was found to correlate with poor relapse-free survival (RFS), for which it is an independent prognostic factor. In vitro investigations of CRC cells (HCT116, HT29) revealed that NETs did not affect their proliferation but did promote the migration of CRC cells mediated by neutrophil elastase (NE) released during NETosis to increase extracellular signal-regulated kinase (ERK) activity. In vivo experiments using nude mice (KSN/slc) revealed that NE inhibition suppressed liver metastases in CRC cells, although it did not affect the growth of subcutaneously implanted tumors. Taken together, these results suggest that NET formation correlates with poor prognoses of patients with CRC and that the inhibition of NE could be a potential therapy for CRC metastases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neutrophil Extracellular Traps Delay Diabetic Wound Healing by Inducing Endothelial-to-Mesenchymal Transition via the Hippo pathway</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36594092/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36594092/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Diabetic foot ulcers (DFUs) are among the most frequent complications of diabetes with significant morbidity and mortality. Diabetes can trigger neutrophils to undergo histone citrullination by protein arginine deiminase 4 (encoded by Padi4 in mice) and release neutrophil extracellular traps (NETs). The specific mechanism of NETs-mediated wound healing impairment in diabetes remains unknown. In this study, we show neutrophils are more susceptible to NETosis in diabetic wound environments. Via in vitro experiments and in vivo models of wound healing using wide-type and Padi4 -/- mice, we demonstrate NETs can induce the activation of PAK2 via the membrane receptor TLR-9. Then PAK2 phosphorylates the intracellular protein Merlin/NF2 to inhibit the Hippo-YAP pathway. YAP binds to transcription factor SMAD2 and translocates from the cytoplasm into the nucleus to promote endothelial-to-mesenchymal transition (EndMT), which ultimately impedes angiogenesis and delays wound healing. Suppression of the Merlin/YAP/SMAD2 pathway can attenuate NET-induced EndMT. Inhibition of NETosis accelerates wound healing by reducing EndMT and promoting angiogenesis. Cumulatively, these data suggest NETosis delays diabetic wound healing by inducing EndMT via the Hippo-YAP pathway. Increased understanding of the molecular mechanism that regulates NETosis and EndMT will be of considerable value for providing cellular targets amenable to therapeutic intervention for DFUs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SIRT6-regulated macrophage efferocytosis epigenetically controls inflammation resolution of diabetic periodontitis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36593966/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36593966/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rationale:&lt;/em&gt; Diabetes exacerbates the prevalence and severity of periodontitis, leading to severe periodontal destruction and ultimately tooth loss. Delayed resolution of inflammation is a major contributor to diabetic periodontitis (DP) pathogenesis, but the underlying mechanisms of this imbalanced immune homeostasis remain unclear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; We collected periodontium from periodontitis with or without diabetes to confirm the dysfunctional neutrophils and macrophages in aggravated inflammatory damage and impaired inflammation resolution. Our in vitro experiments confirmed that SIRT6 inhibited macrophage efferocytosis by restraining miR-216a-5p-216b-5p-217 cluster maturation through &amp;lsquo;&amp;rsquo;non-canonical&amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo; microprocessor complex (RNA pulldown, RIP, immunostaining, CHIP, Luciferase assays, and FISH). Moreover, we constructed m6SKO mice that underwent LIP-induced periodontitis to explore the in vitro and in vivo effect of SIRT6 on macrophage efferocytosis. Finally, antagomiR-217, a miRNA antagonism, was delivered into the periodontium to treat LIP-induced diabetic periodontitis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; We discovered that insufficient SIRT6 as a histone deacetylase in macrophages led to unresolved inflammation and aggravated periodontitis in both human and mouse DP with accumulated apoptotic neutrophil (AN) and higher generation of neutrophil extracellular traps. Mechanistically, we validated that macrophage underwent high glucose stimulation resulting in disturbance of the SIRT6-miR-216/217 axis that triggered impeded efferocytosis of AN through targeting the DEL-1/CD36 axis directly. Furthermore, we demonstrated the inhibitory role of SIRT6 for MIR217HG transcription and identified a non-canonical action of microprocessor that SIRT6 epigenetically hindered the splicing of the primary miR-216/217 via the complex of hnRNPA2B1, DGCR8, and Drosha. Notably, by constructing myeloid-specific deletion of SIRT6 mice and locally delivering antagomir-217 in DP models, we strengthened the in vivo effect of this axis in regulating macrophage efferocytosis and inflammation resolution in DP.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; Our findings delineated the emerging role of SIRT6 in mediating metabolic dysfunction-associated inflammation, and therapeutically targeting this regulatory axis might be a promising strategy for treating diabetes-associated inflammatory diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Histone Citrullination Mediates a Protective Role in Endothelium and Modulates Inflammation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36552833/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36552833/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NETosis is a key host immune process against a pathogenic infection during innate immune activation, consisting of a neutrophil &amp;ldquo;explosion&amp;rdquo; and, consequently, NET formation, containing mainly DNA, histones, and other nuclear proteins. During sepsis, an exacerbated immune host response to an infection occurs, activating the innate immunity and NETosis events, which requires histone H3 citrullination. Our group compared the circulating histone levels with those citrullinated H3 levels in plasma samples of septic patients. In addition, we demonstrated that citrullinated histones were less cytotoxic for endothelial cells than histones without this post-translational modification. Citrullinated histones did not affect cell viability and did not activate oxidative stress. Nevertheless, citrullinated histones induced an inflammatory response, as well as regulatory endothelial mechanisms. Furthermore, septic patients showed elevated levels of circulating citrullinated histone H3, indicating that the histone citrullination is produced during the first stages of sepsis, probably due to the NETosis process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neutrophil Extracellular Traps Induce Glomerular Endothelial Cell Dysfunction and Pyroptosis in Diabetic Kidney Disease</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36095260/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36095260/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Diabetic kidney disease (DKD) is the leading cause of end-stage renal disease. Neutrophil extracellular traps (NETs) are a network structure composed of loose chromatin and embedded with multiple proteins. Here, we observed increased NETs deposition in the glomeruli of DKD patients and diabetic mice (streptozotocin-induced or db/db mice). After NETs were degraded with DNase I, diabetic mice exhibited attenuated glomerulopathy and glomerular endothelial cells (GECs) injury. We also observed alleviated glomerulopathy and GECs injury in peptidylarginine deiminase 4-knockout mice with streptozotocin-induced diabetes. In vitro, NETs-induced GECs pyroptosis was characterized by pore formation in the cell membrane, dysregulation of multiple genes involved in cell membrane function, and increased expression of pyroptosis-related proteins. Strengthening the GECs surface charge by oleylamine significantly inhibited NETs-induced GECs pyroptosis. These findings suggest that the GECs charge-related pyroptosis is involved in DKD progression, which is promoted by NETs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Proteomic Analysis of NETosis in Trauma: Emergence of SerpinB1 as a Key Player</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36730076/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36730076/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Release of neutrophil extracellular traps (NETosis) may mediate post-injury organ dysfunction, but mechanisms remain unclear. The intracellular serine protease inhibitor (serpin) B1 is vital to neutrophil function and has been shown to restrict NETosis in inflammatory settings. In this study, we utilized discovery proteomics to identify the proteomic signature of trauma-induced NETosis. We hypothesized that serpinB1 would be a major component of this NET protein profile and associated with adverse outcomes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; This was a post hoc analysis of data collected as part of the COMBAT randomized clinical trial. Blood was collected from injured patients at a single Level I Trauma Center. Proteomic analyses were performed through targeted liquid chromatography coupled with mass spectrometry. Abundances of serpinB1 and known NETosis markers were analyzed with patient and injury characteristics, clinical data, and outcomes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; SerpinB1 levels on ED arrival were significantly correlated with proteomic markers of NETosis, including core histones, transketolase, and S100A8/A9 proteins. More severely injured patients had elevated serpinB1 and NETosis markers on ED arrival. Levels of serpinB1 and top NETosis markers were significantly elevated on ED arrival in non-survivors and patients with fewer ventilator- and ICU-free days. In proteome-wide ROC analysis, serpinB1 was consistently among the top proteins associated with adverse outcomes. Among NETosis markers, levels of serpinB1 early in the patient&amp;rsquo;s course exhibited the greatest separation between patients with fewer and greater ventilator- and ICU-free days. Gene Ontology analysis of top predictors of adverse outcomes further supports NETosis as a potential mediator of post-injury organ dysfunction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; We have identified a proteomic signature of trauma-induced NETosis, and NETosis is an early process following severe injury that may mediate organ dysfunction. In addition, serpinB1 is a major component of this NET protein profile that may serve as an early marker of excessive NETosis after injury.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Evidence:&lt;/em&gt; Level III, Prognostic/Epidemiological.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An anticomplement homogeneous polysaccharide from Hedyotis diffusa attenuates lipopolysaccharide-induced acute lung injury and inhibits neutrophil extracellular trap formation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36116199/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36116199/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Owing to the involvement of the overactivated complement system in acute lung injury (ALI) development, anticomplement components may attenuate ALI. Hedyotis diffusa is a traditional Chinese medicine for treating lung heat and its crude polysaccharides (HDP) exhibit significant anticomplement activity in vitro.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Purpose:&lt;/em&gt; To obtain an anticomplement homogeneous polysaccharide from HDP and verify its therapeutic effect and mechanism on ALI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; Diethylaminoethyl-52 (DEAE-52) cellulose and gel permeation columns were used to isolate a homogeneous polysaccharide HD-PS-3, which was then characterized using nuclear magnetic resonance (NMR) and methylation analysis. In vitro, the anticomplement activities of HD-PS-3 through classical and alternative pathways were determined using a hemolytic test. The therapeutic effects of HDP and HD-PS-3 on ALI were evaluated in lipopolysaccharide (LPS) intratracheal instilled mice. Hematoxylin and eosin (H&amp;amp;E) staining, enzyme-linked immunosorbent assay (ELISA), and immunohistochemical staining were used to assess histological changes, measure cytokine levels, and evaluate the degree of complement component 3c (C3c) deposition and neutrophil infiltration, respectively. ELISA, western blotting, and immunofluorescence were used to analyze neutrophil extracellular trap (NET) formation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; From HDP, 1.5 g of the homogeneous polysaccharide HD-PS-3 was obtained. HD-PS-3 was an acidic heteropolysaccharide with an acetyl group, which was composed of →4,6)-α-Glcp-(1→, →3,4)-α-Glcp-(1→, →4)-α-Glcp-(1→, →4,6)-α-Galp-(1→, →5)-α-Araf-(1→, α-Rhap-(1→, α-Araf-(1→, α-GlcpA-(1→, →4)-β-Manp-(1→, β-Manp-(1→ and →3)-β-Manp-(1→. The in vitro results suggest that HD-PS-3 exhibited anticomplement activity with CH50 and AP50 values of 115 ± 12 μg/ml and 307 ± 11 μg/ml, respectively. After confirming the efficacy of HDP (200 mg/kg) in attenuating lung injury, the effect of HD-PS-3 on ALI was also investigated. HD-PS-3 (75 and 150 mg/kg) attenuated LPS-induced ALI as well, evidenced by lung pathology, lung injury scores, protein concentration, leukocyte counts, tumor necrosis factor-α (TNF-α), and interleukin-6 (IL-6) contents in bronchoalveolar lavage fluid (BALF). Mechanistically, HD-PS-3 inhibited complement activation, manifested in reduced pulmonary C3c deposition in lung tissue and complement component 3a (C3a) content in BALF. Neutrophil recruitment was also reduced by HD-PS-3, with significantly reduced pulmonary neutrophil infiltration and lower levels of C-X-C motif chemokine ligand 1 (CXCL1) and myeloperoxidase (MPO) in BALF. In addition, HD-PS-3 reduced the levels of MPO-DNA complex in BALF, decreased citrullinated histone H3 (Cit H3) expression and NET formation (colocalization of MPO, Cit H3, and DNA) in lung tissue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/em&gt; An anticomplement homogeneous polysaccharide HD-PS-3 was isolated from H. diffusa. HD-PS-3 exhibited a therapeutic effect against ALI, and the mechanism might be related to its inhibitory effects on complement activation, neutrophil recruitment, and NET formation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NETosis and thrombosis in vaccine-induced immune thrombotic thrombocytopenia</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36064843/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36064843/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vaccine-induced immune thrombotic thrombocytopenia (VITT) is a rare yet serious adverse effect of the adenoviral vector vaccines ChAdOx1 nCoV-19 (AstraZeneca) and Ad26.COV2.S (Janssen) against COVID-19. The mechanisms involved in clot formation and thrombocytopenia in VITT are yet to be fully determined. Here we show neutrophils undergoing NETosis and confirm expression markers of NETs in VITT patients. VITT antibodies directly stimulate neutrophils to release NETs and induce thrombus formation containing abundant platelets, neutrophils, fibrin, extracellular DNA and citrullinated histone H3 in a flow microfluidics system and in vivo. Inhibition of NETosis prevents VITT-induced thrombosis in mice but not thrombocytopenia. In contrast, in vivo blockage of FcγRIIa abrogates both thrombosis and thrombocytopenia suggesting these are distinct processes. Our findings indicate that anti-PF4 antibodies activate blood cells via FcγRIIa and are responsible for thrombosis and thrombocytopenia in VITT. Future development of NETosis and FcγRIIa inhibitors are needed to treat VITT and similar immune thrombotic thrombocytopenia conditions more effectively, leading to better patient outcomes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CLEC5A is critical in Pseudomonas aeruginosa-induced NET formation and acute lung injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36048544/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36048544/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Pseudomonas aeruginosa&lt;/em&gt; is one of the most common nosocomial infections worldwide, and it frequently causes ventilator-associated acute pneumonia in immunocompromised patients. Abundant neutrophil extracellular traps (NETs) contribute to acute lung injury, thereby aggravating ventilator-induced lung damage. While pattern recognition receptors (PRRs) TLR4 and TLR5 are required for host defense against &lt;em&gt;P. aeruginosa&lt;/em&gt; invasion, the PRR responsible for &lt;em&gt;P. aeruginosa&lt;/em&gt;-induced NET formation, proinflammatory cytokine release, and acute lung injury remains unclear. We found that myeloid C-type lectin domain family 5 member A (CLEC5A) interacts with LPS of &lt;em&gt;P. aeruginosa&lt;/em&gt; and is responsible for &lt;em&gt;P. aeruginosa&lt;/em&gt;-induced NET formation and lung inflammation. &lt;em&gt;P. aeruginosa&lt;/em&gt; activates CLEC5A to induce caspase-1-dependent NET formation, but it neither causes gasdermin D (GSDMD) cleavage nor contributes to &lt;em&gt;P. aeruginosa&lt;/em&gt;-induced neutrophil death. Blockade of CLEC5A attenuates &lt;em&gt;P. aeruginosa&lt;/em&gt;-induced NETosis and lung injury, and simultaneous administration of anti-CLEC5A mAb with ciprofloxacin increases survival rate and decreases collagen deposition in the lungs of mice challenged with a lethal dose of &lt;em&gt;P. aeruginosa&lt;/em&gt;. Thus, CLEC5A is a promising therapeutic target to reduce ventilator-associated lung injury and fibrosis in &lt;em&gt;P. aeruginosa&lt;/em&gt;-induced pneumonia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neutrophil extracellular traps-triggered impaired autophagic flux via METTL3 underlies sepsis-associated acute lung injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36030287/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36030287/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Neutrophil extracellular traps (NETs) assist pathogen clearance, while excessive NETs formation is associated with exacerbated inflammatory responses and tissue injury in acute lung injury (ALI)/acute respiratory distress syndrome (ARDS). Autophagy is generally considered to be a protective process, but autophagy dysfunction is harmful. Whether and how NETs affect autophagic flux during sepsis-induced ALI are currently unknown. Here, we confirmed that the level of NETs was increased in ARDS patients and mice models, which led to impairment of autophagic flux and deterioration of the disease. Mechanistically, NETs activated METTL3 mediated m&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;A methylation of Sirt1 mRNA in alveolar epithelial cells, resulting in abnormal autophagy. These findings provide new insights into how NETs contribute to the development of sepsis-associated ALI/ARDS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CuO-NPs-triggered heterophil extracellular traps exacerbate liver injury in chicks by promoting oxidative stress and inflammatory responses</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35962800/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35962800/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the widespread use of copper oxide nanoparticles (CuO-NPs), their potential toxicity to the environment and biological health has attracted close attention. Heterophil extracellular traps (HETs) are an innate immune mechanism of chicken heterophils against adverse stimuli, but excessive HETs cause damage. Here, we explored the effect and mechanism of CuO-NPs on HETs formation in vitro and further evaluated the potential role of HETs in chicken liver and kidney injury. Heterophils were exposed to 5, 10, and 20 µg/mL of CuO-NPs for 2 h. The results showed that CuO-NPs induced typical HETs formation, which was dependent on NADPH oxidase, P38 and extracellular regulated protein kinases (ERK&lt;sub&gt;1/2&lt;/sub&gt;) pathways, and glycolysis. In in vivo experiments, fluorescence microplate and morphological analysis showed that CuO-NPs elevated the level of HETs in chicken serum and caused liver and kidney damage. Meanwhile, CuO-NPs caused hepatic oxidative stress (MDA, SOD, CAT, and GSH-PX imbalance), and also induced an increase in mRNA expression of their inflammatory and apoptosis-related factors (IL-1β, IL-6, TNF-α, COX-2, iNOS, NLRP3, and Caspase-1, 3, 11). However, these results were significantly altered by DNase I (HETs degradation reagent). In conclusion, the present study demonstrates for the first time that CuO-NPs induce the formation of HETs and that HETs exacerbate pathological damage in chicken liver and kidney by promoting oxidative stress and inflammation, providing insights into immunotoxicity and potential prevention and treatment targets caused by CuO-NPs overexposure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Noninvasive imaging of the lung NETosis by anti-Ly6G iron oxide nanoparticles</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35991979/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35991979/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is challenging to visualize noninvasively the formation of neutrophil extracellular traps, known as NETosis, and therefore difficult to monitor disease progression. A desirable molecular imaging probe is the iron oxide nanoparticle (NP) that could induce reactive oxygen species. Here, we used C57BL/6 mice with pristane-induced lupus, which mimics systemic lupus erythematosus. Administration of anti-Ly6G antibody-conjugated NP allowed detection of NETosis with fluorescent molecular imaging, as evidenced by flow cytometric analysis of citrullinated histone H3 expression in lung neutrophils. This finding was consistent with NP-induced blood NETosis in a spontaneous lupus model of B6.MRL-&lt;em&gt;lpr&lt;/em&gt; mice. &lt;em&gt;A chronic&lt;/em&gt; assessment was performed in which the lupus mice were protected from enhanced oxidative burst by anti-Ly6G NP. This NP can migrate from the peritoneal cavity to the lungs, as visualized by magnetic particle imaging. Overall, our study provides evidence for a highly sensitive assessment of NETosis in lupus through magnetic particle imaging.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Platelets in the NETworks interweaving inflammation and thrombosis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/35979369/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/35979369/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Platelets are well characterized for their indispensable role in primary hemostasis to control hemorrhage. Research over the past years has provided a substantial body of evidence demonstrating that platelets also participate in host innate immunity. The surface expression of pattern recognition receptors, such as TLR2 and TLR4, provides platelets with the ability to sense bacterial products in their environment. Platelet α-granules contain microbicidal proteins, chemokines and growth factors, which upon release may directly engage pathogens and/or contribute to inflammatory signaling. Additionally, platelet interactions with neutrophils enhance neutrophil activation and are often crucial to induce a sufficient immune response. In particular, platelets can activate neutrophils to form neutrophil extracellular traps (NETs). This specific neutrophil effector function is characterized by neutrophils expelling chromatin fibres decorated with histones and antimicrobial proteins into the extracellular space where they serve to trap and kill pathogens. Until now, the mechanisms and signaling pathways between platelets and neutrophils inducing NET formation are still not fully characterized. NETs were also detected in thrombotic lesions in several disease backgrounds, pointing towards a role as an interface between neutrophils, platelets and thrombosis, also known as immunothrombosis. The negatively charged DNA within NETs provides a procoagulant surface, and in particular NET-derived proteins may directly activate platelets. In light of the current COVID-19 pandemic, the topic of immunothrombosis has become more relevant than ever, as a majority of COVID-19 patients display thrombi in the lung capillaries and other vascular beds. Furthermore, NETs can be found in the lung and other tissues and are associated with an increased mortality. Here, virus infiltration may lead to a cytokine storm that potently activates neutrophils and leads to massive neutrophil infiltration into the lung and NET formation. The resulting NETs presumably activate platelets and coagulation factors, further contributing to the subsequent emergence of microthrombi in pulmonary capillaries. In this review, we will discuss the interplay between platelets and NETs and the potential of this alliance to influence the course of inflammatory diseases. A better understanding of the underlying molecular mechanisms and the identification of treatment targets is of utmost importance to increase patients&amp;rsquo; survival and improve the clinical outcome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The role of neutrophil extracellular traps in acute lung injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/35967320/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/35967320/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acute lung injury (ALI) is a heterogeneous inflammatory condition associated with high morbidity and mortality. Neutrophils play a key role in the development of different forms of ALI, and the release of neutrophil extracellular traps (NETs) is emerging as a common pathogenic mechanism. NETs are essential in controlling pathogens, and their defective release or increased degradation leads to a higher risk of infection. However, NETs also contain several pro-inflammatory and cytotoxic molecules than can exacerbate thromboinflammation and lung tissue injury. To reduce NET-mediated lung damage and inflammation, DNase is frequently used in preclinical models of ALI due to its capability of digesting NET DNA scaffold. Moreover, recent advances in neutrophil biology led to the development of selective NET inhibitors, which also appear to reduce ALI in experimental models. Here we provide an overview of the role of NETs in different forms of ALI discussing existing gaps in our knowledge and novel therapeutic approaches to modulate their impact on lung injury.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Targeting ETosis by miR-155 inhibition mitigates mixed granulocytic asthmatic lung inflammation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35958610/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35958610/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Asthma is phenotypically heterogeneous with several distinctive pathological mechanistic pathways. Previous studies indicate that neutrophilic asthma has a poor response to standard asthma treatments comprising inhaled corticosteroids. Therefore, it is important to identify critical factors that contribute to increased numbers of neutrophils in asthma patients whose symptoms are poorly controlled by conventional therapy. Leukocytes release chromatin fibers, referred to as extracellular traps (ETs) consisting of double-stranded (ds) DNA, histones, and granule contents. Excessive components of ETs contribute to the pathophysiology of asthma; however, it is unclear how ETs drive asthma phenotypes and whether they could be a potential therapeutic target. We employed a mouse model of severe asthma that recapitulates the intricate immune responses of neutrophilic and eosinophilic airway inflammation identified in patients with severe asthma. We used both a pharmacologic approach using miR-155 inhibitor-laden exosomes and genetic approaches using miR-155 knockout mice. Our data show that ETs are present in the bronchoalveolar lavage fluid of patients with mild asthma subjected to experimental subsegmental bronchoprovocation to an allergen and a severe asthma mouse model, which resembles the complex immune responses identified in severe human asthma. Furthermore, we show that miR-155 contributes to the extracellular release of dsDNA, which exacerbates allergic lung inflammation, and the inhibition of miR-155 results in therapeutic benefit in severe asthma mice. Our findings show that targeting dsDNA release represents an attractive therapeutic target for mitigating neutrophilic asthma phenotype, which is clinically refractory to standard care.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Salvianolic Acid A Protects against Lipopolysaccharide-Induced Acute Lung Injury by Inhibiting Neutrophil NETosis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35910849/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35910849/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Salvianolic acid A (SAA) is one of bioactive polyphenol extracted from a Salvia miltiorrhiza (Danshen), which was widely used to treat cardiovascular disease in traditional Chinese medicine. SAA has been reported to be protective in cardiovascular disease and ischemia injury, with anti-inflammatory and antioxidative effect, but its role in acute lung injury (ALI) is still unknown. In this study, we sought to investigate the therapeutic effects of SAA in a murine model of lipopolysaccharide- (LPS-) induced ALI. The optimal dose of SAA was determined by comparing the attenuation of lung injury score after administration of SAA at three different doses (low, 5 mg/kg; medium, 10 mg/kg; and, high 15 mg/kg). Dexamethasone (DEX) was used as a positive control for SAA. Here, we showed that the therapeutic effect of SAA (10 mg/kg) against LPS-induced pathologic injury in the lungs was comparable to DEX. SAA and DEX attenuated the increased W/D ratio and the protein level, counts of total cells and neutrophils, and cytokine levels in the BALF of ALI mice similarly. The oxidative stress was also relieved by SAA and DEX according to the superoxide dismutase and malondialdehyde. NET level in the lungs was elevated in the injured lung while SAA and DEX reduced it significantly. LPS induced phosphorylation of Src, Raf, MEK, and ERK in the lungs, which was inhibited by SAA and DEX. NET level and phosphorylation level of Src/Raf/MEK/ERK pathway in the neutrophils from acute respiratory distress syndrome (ARDS) patients were also inhibited by SAA and DEX in vitro, but the YEEI peptide reversed the protective effect of SAA completely. The inhibition of NET release by SAA was also reversed by YEEI peptide in LPS-challenged neutrophils from healthy volunteers. Our data demonstrated that SAA ameliorated ALI via attenuating inflammation, oxidative stress, and neutrophil NETosis. The mechanism of such protective effect might involve the inhibition of Src activation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Benzyl butyl phthalate (BBP) induces lung injury and fibrosis through neutrophil extracellular traps</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35835272/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35835272/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Benzyl butyl phthalate (BBP) is an extensively used plasticizer that has aroused widespread concern about its potential toxicity. Previous evidences demonstrate that BBP exposure is associated with asthma and impaired lung function. Accumulating data indicates that neutrophil extracellular traps (NETs), a particular manner of neutrophil death, play a vital role in the pathogenesis of respiratory diseases. However, the immunotoxicity effects of BBP in lung injury are unclear. Here, we aimed to investigate the potential impacts of BBP-induced NETs on lung injury and fibrosis. Mice treated with BBP exhibited significant lung injury, with alveolar hemorrhage, lung edema and increased neutrophil infiltration. Meanwhile, BBP promoted extensive neutrophil infiltration in bronchoalveolar lavage fluid and NETs deposition in lung tissues. Moreover, BBP clearly triggered NETs formation in vitro, which was confirmed by net-like structures decorated with myeloperoxidase and citrullinated histone H3. Furthermore, BBP fueled glucose uptake and ROS burst of neutrophils playing essential roles during NETs formation. Additionally, we proved that NETs could promote fibrogenesis in murine lung epithelial cells and observed lung fibrosis remarkably after BBP-induced injury. Taken together, our findings indicated that exposure to BBP could increase the risk for lung injury and fibrosis by disturbing innate immunity via NETs formation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lysophosphatidylcholine Alleviates Acute Lung Injury by Regulating Neutrophil Motility and Neutrophil Extracellular Trap Formation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35859904/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35859904/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sepsis is predominantly initiated by bacterial infection and can cause systemic inflammation, which frequently leads to rapid death of the patient. However, this acute systemic inflammatory response requires further investigation from the perspectives of clinical judgment criteria and early treatment strategies for the relief of symptoms. Lysophosphatidylcholine (LPC) 18:0 may relieve septic symptoms, but the relevant mechanism is not clearly understood. Therefore, we aimed to assess the effectiveness of LPC as a therapeutic treatment for acute inflammation in the lung induced by lipopolysaccharide in mice. Systemic inflammation of mice was induced by lipopolysaccharide (LPS) inoculation to investigate the role of LPC in the migration and the immune response of neutrophils during acute lung injury. By employing two-photon intravital imaging of the LPS-stimulated LysM-GFP mice and other &lt;em&gt;in vitro&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt; assays, we examined whether LPC alleviates the inflammatory effect of sepsis. We also tested the effect of LPC to human neutrophils from healthy control and sepsis patients. Our data showed that LPC treatment reduced the infiltration of innate immune cells into the lung. Specifically, LPC altered neutrophil migratory patterns and enhanced phagocytic efficacy in the damaged lung. Moreover, LPC treatment reduced the release of neutrophil extracellular trap (NET), which can damage tissue in the inflamed organ and exacerbate disease. It also reduced human neutrophil migration under inflammatory environment. Our results suggest that LPC can alleviate sepsis-induced lung inflammation by regulating the function of neutrophils. These findings provide evidence for the beneficial application of LPC treatment as a potential therapeutic strategy for sepsis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Fatal Circle of NETs and NET-Associated DAMPs Contributing to Organ Dysfunction</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/35741047/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/35741047/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The innate immune system is the first line of defense against invading pathogens or sterile injuries. Pattern recognition receptors (PRR) sense molecules released from inflamed or damaged cells, or foreign molecules resulting from invading pathogens. PRRs can in turn induce inflammatory responses, comprising the generation of cytokines or chemokines, which further induce immune cell recruitment. Neutrophils represent an essential factor in the early immune response and fulfill numerous tasks to fight infection or heal injuries. The release of neutrophil extracellular traps (NETs) is part of it and was originally attributed to the capture and elimination of pathogens. In the last decade studies revealed a detrimental role of NETs during several diseases, often correlated with an exaggerated immune response. Overwhelming inflammation in single organs can induce remote organ damage, thereby further perpetuating release of inflammatory molecules. Here, we review recent findings regarding damage-associated molecular patterns (DAMPs) which are able to induce NET formation, as well as NET components known to act as DAMPs, generating a putative fatal circle of inflammation contributing to organ damage and sequentially occurring remote organ injury.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Down-regulated miR-146a expression with increased neutrophil extracellular traps and apoptosis formation in autoimmune-mediated diffuse alveolar hemorrhage</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36028828/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36028828/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Increasing evidences have suggested an important role of microRNAs (miRNAs) in regulating cell death processes including NETosis and apoptosis. Dysregulated expression of miRNAs and increased formation of neutrophil extracellular traps (NETs) and apoptosis participate in autoimmune-mediated diffuse alveolar hemorrhage (DAH), mostly associated with pulmonary capillaritis in systemic lupus erythematosus (SLE) patients. In particular, besides the inhibition of apoptosis, miR-146a can control innate and acquired immune responses, and regulate the toll-like receptor pathway through targeting TRAF6 to reduce the expression of pro-inflammatory cytokines/chemokines like IL-8, a NETosis inducer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; Expression of miR-146a, TRAF6 and NETs were examined in peripheral blood neutrophils (PBNs) and lung tissues from SLE-associated DAH patients, and in neutrophils and pristane-induced DAH lung tissues from C57BL/6 mice. To assess NETs formation, we examined NETosis-related DNAs morphology and crucial mediators including protein arginine deiminase 4 and citrullinated Histone 3. Expression of miR-146a and its endogenous RNA SNHG16 were studied in HL-60 promyelocytic cells and MLE-12 alveolar cells during NETosis and apoptosis processes, respectively. MiR-146a-overexpressed and CRISPR-Cas13d-mediated SNHG16-silenced HL-60 cells were investigated for NETosis. MiR-146a-overexpressed MLE-12 cells were analyzed for apoptosis. Pristane-injected mice received intra-pulmonary miR-146a delivery to evaluate therapeutic efficacy in DAH.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; In DAH patients, there were down-regulated miR-146a levels with increased TRAF6 expression and PMA/LPS-induced NETosis in PBNs, and down-regulated miR-146a levels with increased TRAF6, high-mobility group box 1 (HMGB1), IL-8, NETs and apoptosis expression in lung tissues. HMGB1-stimulated mouse neutrophils had down-regulated miR-146a levels with increased TRAF6, IL-8 and NETs expression. PMA-stimulated HL-60 cells had down-regulated miR-146a levels with enhanced NETosis. MiR-146a-overexpressed or SNHG16-silenced HL-60 cells showed reduced NETosis. Apoptotic MLE-12 cells had down-regulated miR-146a expression and increased HMGB1 release, while miR-146a-overexpressed MLE-12 cells showed reduced apoptosis and HMGB1 production. There were down-regulated miR-146a levels with increased TRAF6, HMGB1, IL-8, NETs and apoptosis expression in mouse DAH lung tissues. Intra-pulmonary miR-146a delivery could suppress DAH by reducing TRAF6, IL-8, NETs and apoptosis expression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; Our results demonstrate firstly down-regulated pulmonary miR-146a levels with increased TRAF6 and IL-8 expression and NETs and apoptosis formation in autoimmune-mediated DAH, and implicate a therapeutic potential of intra-pulmonary miR-146a delivery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In Vivo Imaging of Circadian NET Formation During Lung Injury by Four-Dimensional Intravital Microscopy</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35610434/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35610434/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Neutrophil extracellular traps (NETs) are toxic extracellular structures deployed by neutrophils in response to pathogens and sterile danger signals. NETs are circadian in nature as mouse and human neutrophils preferentially deploy them at night or early morning. Traditionally, NETs have been quantified using a plethora of methods including immunofluorescence and ELISA-based assays; however few options are available to visualize them in vivo. Here we describe a method to directly visualize and quantify NET formation and release in the microvasculature of the lung using intravital imaging in a model of acute lung injury. The method allows four-dimensional capture and quantification of NET formation dynamics over time and should be a useful resource for those interested in visualizing neutrophil responses &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Antagonistic Effect of Selenium on Fumonisin B1 Promotes Neutrophil Extracellular Traps Formation in Chicken Neutrophils</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35535747/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35535747/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Neutrophils are an important component of the innate immune system, and one of their defense mechanisms, neutrophil extracellular traps (NETs), is a hot topic of the current research. This study explored the effects of fumonisin B1 (FB1) on chicken neutrophil production of NETs and its possible molecular mechanism of action. Scanning electron microscopy and fluorescence microscopy were used to observe morphological changes in neutrophils, and a fluorescence microplate reader was used to detect reactive oxygen species (ROS) and extracellular DNA release from neutrophils. Quantitative PCR (qPCR) and western blot were used to determine the expression levels of selenoproteins. The results indicate that FB1 inhibited the zymosan-induced formation of NETs in chicken neutrophils by preventing ROS burst and histone H3 (H3) and neutrophil elastase (NE) release. Moreover, the mRNA expression levels of glutathione peroxidase (GPX), thioredoxin reductase (TXNRD), and deiodinase (DIO) were downregulated in the FB1 group. The protein expression levels of GPX1, GPX2, GPX3, DIO3, and TXNRD1 were consistent with the changes in their gene expressions, suggesting an abnormal selenoprotein expression in response to the toxic effects of FB1. Conversely, selenium (Se) supplementation reduced the toxic effects of FB1 and restored the NETs formation, indicating that Se can be used as a potential drug to prevent and control FB1 toxicity in livestock farming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neutrophil extracellular traps mediate m6A modification and regulates sepsis-associated acute lung injury by activating ferroptosis in alveolar epithelial cells</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35637949/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35637949/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Neutrophil extracellular traps (NETs) production is a major strategy employed by polymorphonuclear neutrophils (PMNs) to fight against microbes. NETs have been implicated in the pathogenesis of various lung injuries, although few studies have explored NETs in sepsis-associated acute lung injury (SI-ALI). Here, we demonstrate a major contribution of NETs to the pathology of sepsis-associated ALI by inducing ferroptosis of alveolar epithelial cells. Using both &lt;em&gt;in vitro&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt; studies, our findings show enhanced NETs accumulation in sepsis-associated ALI patients and mice, as well as the closely related upregulation of ferroptosis, the induction of which depends on METTL3-induced m&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;A modification of GPX4. Using a CLP-induced sepsis-associated ALI mouse model established with &lt;em&gt;METTL3&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; versus WT mice, in addition to METTL3 knockout and overexpression in vitro, we elucidated and confirmed the critical role of ferroptosis in NETs-induced ALI. These findings support a role for NETs-induced METTL3 modification and the subsequent induction of ferroptosis in the pathogenesis of sepsis-associated ALI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chicken heterophils extracellular traps act as early effectors against cyclopiazonic acid dependent upon NADPH oxidase, ROS and glycolysis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35508807/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35508807/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cyclopiazonic acid (CPA) is a secondary metabolite produced by Aspergillus and Penicillium, which is present in contaminated crops and food, causing severe toxicity to humans and animals. Heterophil extracellular traps (HETs) are a novel host innate immune mechanism of chicken heterophils against pathogen infection. However, whether CPA can cause immunotoxicity of heterophils on HETs release remains unclear. Here, we attempt to detect the effects of CPA on HETs release, and further investigate the molecular mechanisms underlying these processes. We exposed heterophils to 2.5, 5, 10 μM CPA for 90 min. The results showed that CPA induced the release of HETs in heterophils, consisting of DNA-modified citrullinated histone 3 and elastase. The quantitative analysis of HETs content was positively correlated with CPA concentration. CPA also promoted reactive oxygen species production and phosphorylation of ERK1/2 and p38. In addition, CPA-triggered HETs formation was reduced by NADPH oxidase, ERK1/2, and p38 signaling pathway and glycolysis inhibitors, indicating that CPA-induced HETs were related to the production of ROS dependent on NADPH oxidase, ERK1/2, and p38 signaling pathways, as well as glycolysis. Our study describes the underlying mechanism of CPA-induced HETs release, which may provide a further understanding of the immunotoxicology of CPA poisoning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cineole alleviates the BPA-inhibited NETs formation by regulating the p38 pathway-mediated programmed cell death</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35483150/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35483150/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;BPA inhibited the release of NETs by inducing necroptosis and apoptosis.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CIN can alleviate the oxidative stress and programmed cell death induced by BPA.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CIN via p38 pathway alleviates BPA-induced neutrophil injury.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enriched the research on toxicology of BPA and detoxification mechanism of CIN.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bisphenol A (BPA) is an endocrine disruptor, that can cause immune dysfunction. Cineole (CIN) has that effect of regulating immune function and resist oxidation. Neutrophil extracellular traps (NETs) are one of the ways to resist pathogen invasion. In order to explore the effects of BPA and CIN on the release of chicken NETs and the antagonistic effect of CIN, take chicken peripheral blood neutrophils as object of study, grouping as NC, CIN, BPA + CIN and BPA. SEM, flow cytometry, RT-PCR, Western-blot and other methods were used to detect related indicators. The results showed that BPA inhibited the activities of GPX, SOD and CAT, increased the contents of MDA and NO, increased the activity of iNOS. BPA exposure inhibited the expression of myeloperoxidase (MPO), neutrophil elastase (NE) and histone, and inhibited the release of NETs. BPA activated downstream apoptosis and necroptosis through the p38 mitogen-activated protein kinase (p38-MAPK) pathway, which increased the expression of cytochrome C (CytC), bcl-2 associated K protein gene (bak), cysteinyl aspartate specific proteinase 3 (caspase-3), cysteinyl aspartate specific proteinase 9 (caspase-9), receptor-interacting protein kinase 1 (RIPK1), receptor-interacting protein kinase 1 (RIPK3) and mixed lineage kinase domain-like protein (MLKL), decreased the expression of B-cell lymphoma-2 (bcl-2). However, the co-exposure of CIN and BPA partially recovered the release of NETs, alleviated BPA-induced oxidative stress, and inhibited the activation of p38-MAPK pathway, necroptosis, and mitochondrial apoptosis pathway. These results indicated that CIN modulated p38 pathway alleviated BPA-induced neutrophil necroptosis and apoptosis, and increased NETs formation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neutrophil phenotypes in bronchial airways differentiate single from dual responding allergic asthmatics</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35437872/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35437872/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Introduction:&lt;/em&gt; Allergic asthmatics with both an early (EAR) and a late allergic reaction (LAR) following allergen exposure are termed &amp;lsquo;dual responders&amp;rsquo; (DR), while &amp;lsquo;single responders&amp;rsquo; (SR) only have an EAR. Mechanisms that differentiate DR from SR are largely unknown, particularly regarding the role and phenotypes of neutrophils. Therefore, we aimed to study neutrophils in DR and SR asthmatics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; Thirty-four allergic asthmatics underwent an inhaled allergen challenge, samples were collected before and up to 24 h post-challenge. Cell differentials were counted from bronchial lavage, alveolar lavage and blood; and tissue neutrophils were quantified in immune-stained bronchial biopsies. Lavage neutrophil nuclei lobe segmentation was used to classify active (1-4 lobes) from suppressive neutrophils (≥5 lobes). Levels of transmigration markers: soluble (s)CD62L and interleukin-1Ra, and activity markers: neutrophil elastase (NE), DNA-histone complex and dsDNA were measured in lavage fluid and plasma.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; Compared with SR at baseline, DR had more neutrophils in their bronchial airways at baseline, both in the lavage (p = .0031) and biopsies (p = .026) and elevated bronchial neutrophils correlated with less antitransmigratory IL-1Ra levels (r = -0.64). DR airways had less suppressive neutrophils and more 3-lobed (active) neutrophils (p = .029) that correlated with more bronchial lavage histone (p = .020) and more plasma NE (p = .0016). Post-challenge, DR released neutrophil extracellular trap factors in the blood earlier and had less pro-transmigratory sCD62L during the late phase (p = .0076) than in SR.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/em&gt; DR have a more active airway neutrophil phenotype at baseline and a distinct neutrophil response to allergen challenge that may contribute to the development of an LAR. Therefore, neutrophil activity should be considered during targeted diagnosis and bio-therapeutic development for DR.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Key Messages&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dual responding allergic asthmatics have more baseline airway neutrophils with an active morphology than single responders.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Increased airway neutrophils in dual responders were associated with less antimigration signalling rather than more chemoattraction.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Post-challenge, dual responders release an active neutrophil response in the blood earlier than in single responders.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Role of Cellular Metabolism in the Formation of Neutrophil Extracellular Traps in Airway Diseases</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/35493475/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/35493475/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Neutrophil extracellular traps (NETs) are a recently described mechanism of neutrophils that play an important role in health and disease. NETs are an innate defense mechanism that participate in clearance of pathogens, but they may also cause collateral damage in unrelated host tissues. Neutrophil dysregulation and NETosis occur in multiple lung diseases, such as pathogen-induced acute lung injury, pneumonia, chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD), severe asthma, cystic fibrosis, and recently, the novel coronavirus SARS-CoV-2. More recently, research into immunometabolism has surged due to the possibility of reprogramming metabolism in order to modulate immune functions. The present review analyzes the different metabolic pathways associated with NETs formation, and how these impact on pathologies of the airways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beyond Hemostasis: Platelet Innate Immune Interactions and Thromboinflammation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/35409226/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/35409226/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is accumulating evidence that platelets play roles beyond their traditional functions in thrombosis and hemostasis, e.g., in inflammatory processes, infection and cancer, and that they interact, stimulate and regulate cells of the innate immune system such as neutrophils, monocytes and macrophages. In this review, we will focus on platelet activation in hemostatic and inflammatory processes, as well as platelet interactions with neutrophils and monocytes/macrophages. We take a closer look at the contributions of major platelet receptors GPIb, α&lt;sub&gt;IIb&lt;/sub&gt;β&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;, TLT-1, CLEC-2 and Toll-like receptors (TLRs) as well as secretions from platelet granules on platelet-neutrophil aggregate and neutrophil extracellular trap (NET) formation in atherosclerosis, transfusion-related acute lung injury (TRALI) and COVID-19. Further, we will address platelet-monocyte and macrophage interactions during cancer metastasis, infection, sepsis and platelet clearance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Glycyrrhizin alleviates sepsis-induced acute respiratory distress syndrome via suppressing of HMGB1/TLR9 pathways and neutrophils extracellular traps formation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35354111/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35354111/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GL attenuated inflammatory lung injury.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GL reduced the NETs formation in lung tissues.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GL inhibited the HMGB1 / TLR9 pathway.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GL improved lung function in mice with sepsis-induced ARDS.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Neutrophil extracellular traps (NETs) are involved in the development of sepsis-induced acute respiratory distress syndrome (ARDS). Glycyrrhizin (GL), the main active ingredient of the traditional Chinese medicine Glycyrrhiza glabra, has anti-inflammatory, anti-viral, and immunomodulatory effects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Objective:&lt;/em&gt; The study aims to explore the efficacy and potential mechanism of GL on sepsis-induced ARDS in mice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Materials and methods:&lt;/em&gt; Mice were randomly divided into 3 groups: Control, CLP, and GL + CLP. Mice sepsis ARDS model was induced by cecal ligation and puncture (CLP) followed by intraperitoneal GL treatment. Then, the 7-day survival rate of mice was recorded. The lung function of mice was determined by whole-body plethysmography. Lung pathology and scores were observed by hematoxylin-eosin staining. The wet/dry ratio (W/D) of the lung was measured by weighing method. The protein concentration in bronchoalveolar lavage fluid (BALF) was measured by the BCA method. NETs formation in lung tissue was detected by immunofluorescence. Furthermore, HMGB1、TLR9、MyD88 and IL6 expression in lung tissue were detected by western blot and by quantitative real-time PCR, respectively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; The results showed that GL improved the survival rate, attenuated lung tissue injury and reduced the expression of inflammatory factors in mice with CLP-induced sepsis. Meanwhile, we confirmed that GL could inhibit TLR9 / MyD88 activation from reducing NETs formation by decreasing HMGB1 expression. The formation of NETs is regulated by HMGB1/TLR9/MyD88. In addition, GL improved lung function in mice with sepsis-induced ARDS. Lung function suggested that GL increased alveolar ventilation, alleviated ventilator fatigue and reduced airway resistance in mice with ARDS induced by sepsis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; GL ameliorated sepsis-induced ARDS and reduced the NETs formation in lung tissues, which may be associated with the inhibition of the HMGB1/TLR9 pathway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neutrophil-vascular interactions drive myeloperoxidase accumulation in the brain in Alzheimer&#39;s disease</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35331340/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35331340/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Introduction:&lt;/em&gt; Neutrophil accumulation is a well-established feature of Alzheimer&amp;rsquo;s disease (AD) and has been linked to cognitive impairment by modulating disease-relevant neuroinflammatory and vascular pathways. Neutrophils express high levels of the oxidant-generating enzyme myeloperoxidase (MPO), however there has been controversy regarding the cellular source and localisation of MPO in the AD brain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Materials and methods:&lt;/em&gt; We used immunostaining and immunoassays to quantify the accumulation of neutrophils in human AD tissue microarrays and in the brains of APP/PS1 mice. We also used multiplexed immunolabelling to define the presence of NETs in AD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; There was an increase in neutrophils in AD brains as well as in the murine APP/PS1 model of AD. Indeed, MPO expression was almost exclusively confined to S100A8-positive neutrophils in both human AD and murine APP/PS1 brains. The vascular localisation of neutrophils in both human AD and mouse models of AD was striking and driven by enhanced neutrophil adhesion to small vessels. We also observed rare infiltrating neutrophils and deposits of MPO around plaques. Citrullinated histone H3, a marker of neutrophil extracellular traps (NETs), was also detected in human AD cases at these sites, indicating the presence of extracellular MPO in the vasculature. Finally, there was a reduction in the endothelial glycocalyx in AD that may be responsible for non-productive neutrophil adhesion to the vasculature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/em&gt; Our report indicates that vascular changes may drive neutrophil adhesion and NETosis, and that neutrophil-derived MPO may lead to vascular oxidative stress and be a relevant therapeutic target in AD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stimulator of Interferon Genes (STING) Promotes Staphylococcus aureus-Induced Extracellular Traps Formation via the ROS-ERK Signaling Pathway</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35399524/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35399524/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stimulator of interferon genes (STING) is a cytosolic DNA sensor or directly recognizes bacterial cyclic dinucleotides, which is required for the detection of microbial infection. Extracellular traps (ETs) are known to be part of the antimicrobial defense system. However, the implication of STING in ETs formation during microbial infection remains unknown. Here, we showed that STING contributed to &lt;em&gt;Staphylococcus aureus&lt;/em&gt; (&lt;em&gt;S. aureus&lt;/em&gt;)-induced ETs formation through the ROS-ERK signaling. STING deficiency exhibited decreased cell-free DNA (cfDNA) level, reduced expression of citrullinated histone H3 (CitH3), and diminished DNA colocalization with CitH3 and myeloperoxidase (MPO). Interestingly, NADPH oxidase-derived reactive oxygen species (ROS) promoted ETs formation, accompanied by increased activation of extracellular signal-regulated kinase 1 and 2 (ERK1/2) in &lt;em&gt;S. aureus&lt;/em&gt;-stimulated bone marrow-derived macrophages (BMDMs). Corresponding to less ROS production, decreased ERK1/2 activation was shown in STING-/- BMDMs after &lt;em&gt;S. aureus&lt;/em&gt; infection. Importantly, inhibiting the ROS-ERK signal reduced the ETs formation and the differences disappeared between WT and STING&lt;sup&gt;-/&lt;/sup&gt;- BMDMs after &lt;em&gt;S. aureus&lt;/em&gt; infection. Moreover, STING&lt;sup&gt;-/&lt;/sup&gt; BMDMs exhibited significantly increased levels of extracellular bacteria compared to WT BMDMs regardless of phagocytosis. In addition, such differences disappeared after DNase I treatment. DNase I treatment also facilitated pathogen colonization without affecting the inflammatory cells infiltration and pro-inflammatory factors secretion following pulmonary &lt;em&gt;S. aureus&lt;/em&gt; infection. Furthermore, STING&lt;sup&gt;-/&lt;/sup&gt; mice presented decreased levels of cfDNA and CitH3, along with increased bacterial colonization compared to WT mice. Altogether, these findings highlighted that STING promoted ETs formation via the ROS-ERK signal for host defense against &lt;em&gt;S. aureus&lt;/em&gt; infection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Actin-related protein 2/3 complex regulates neutrophil extracellular trap expulsion and lung damage in abdominal sepsis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35272488/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35272488/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Neutrophil extracellular trap (NET) formation is a key feature in sepsis. The aim of the present study was to examine the role of the actin cytoskeleton in regulating the expulsion of NETs. Actin-related protein 2/3 (Arp 2/3) complex is an important regulator of F-actin polymerization. Coincubation with CK666, a specific Arp 2/3 inhibitor, decreased 12-phorbol 13-myristate acetate-induced NET formation in vitro. CK666 not only abolished F-actin polymerization but also caused intracellular retention of NETs. Inhibition of Arp 2/3 reduced NET formation on circulating neutrophils and in the bronchoalveolar space in mice undergoing cecal ligation and puncture (CLP). Notably, treatment with CK666 attenuated CLP-induced neutrophil recruitment, edema formation, and tissue damage in the lungs. Moreover, Arp 2/3 inhibition decreased levels of C-X-C motif chemokine ligand 1 (CXCL-1) and interleukin-6 in the lung and plasma of septic animals. Taken together, this study shows that expulsion of NETs is regulated by the actin cytoskeleton and that inhibition of Arp 2/3-dependent F-actin polymerization not only decreases NET formation but also protects against pathological inflammation and tissue damage in septic lung injury. Thus, we suggest that targeting NET release is a novel and useful way to ameliorate lung damage in abdominal sepsis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Histones released by NETosis enhance the infectivity of SARS-CoV-2 by bridging the spike protein subunit 2 and sialic acid on host cells</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35273357/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35273357/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Neutrophil extracellular traps (NETs) can capture and kill viruses, such as influenza viruses, human immunodeficiency virus (HIV), and respiratory syncytial virus (RSV), thus contributing to host defense. Contrary to our expectation, we show here that the histones released by NETosis enhance the infectivity of SARS-CoV-2, as found by using live SARS-CoV-2 and two pseudovirus systems as well as a mouse model. The histone H3 or H4 selectively binds to subunit 2 of the spike (S) protein, as shown by a biochemical binding assay, surface plasmon resonance and binding energy calculation as well as the construction of a mutant S protein by replacing four acidic amino acids. Sialic acid on the host cell surface is the key molecule to which histones bridge subunit 2 of the S protein. Moreover, histones enhance cell-cell fusion. Finally, treatment with an inhibitor of NETosis, histone H3 or H4, or sialic acid notably affected the levels of sgRNA copies and the number of apoptotic cells in a mouse model. These findings suggest that SARS-CoV-2 could hijack histones from neutrophil NETosis to promote its host cell attachment and entry process and may be important in exploring pathogenesis and possible strategies to develop new effective therapies for COVID-19.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tissue accumulation of neutrophil extracellular traps mediates muscle hyperalgesia in a mouse model</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35264677/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35264677/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Accumulation of uric acid (UA) during muscular trauma is a factor involved in the development of muscle hyperalgesia. Neutrophil extracellular traps (NETs), DNA-based reticular structures to capture UA, play a central role in the pain onset of gout attacks; however, the involvement of NETs via the elevation of local UA level in muscle hyperalgesia due to injuries from muscle overuse remains unknown. The triceps surae muscles (TSMs) in the unilateral hindlimb of mice were electrically stimulated to induce excessive muscle contraction. Mechanical withdrawal thresholds, tissue UA levels, neutrophil recruitment, and protein amount of citrullinated histone 3 (citH3), a major marker of NETs, were investigated. Furthermore, whether neutrophil depletion, extracellular DNA cleavage, and administration of the urate-lowering agent febuxostat improved muscle hyperalgesia caused by NET formation was examined. CitH3 expression upon neutrophil recruitment was significantly increased in the stimulated TSMs with increased tissue UA levels, whereas febuxostat administration improved muscle hyperalgesia with decreased citH3 and tissue UA levels, as observed in neutrophil depletion and extracellular DNA digestion. The underlying mechanism of muscle hyperalgesia associated with locally recruited neutrophils forming NETs due to increased tissue UA levels potentially plays a significant role in creating a vicious circle of muscle pain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Phorbol 12-myristate 13-acetate stimulation under hypoxia induces nuclear swelling with DNA outflow but not extracellular trap formation of neutrophils</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35259405/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35259405/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Neutrophils stand sentinel over infection and possess diverse antimicrobial weapons, including neutrophil extracellular traps (NETs). NETs are composed of web-like extracellular DNA decorated with antimicrobial substances and can trap and eliminate invading microorganisms. Although phorbol 12-myristate 13-acetate (PMA) is a potent NET inducer, previous studies have demonstrated that not all neutrophils exhibit NET formation even if stimulated by PMA at high concentrations. This study first showed that some neutrophils stimulated by PMA displayed a swollen nucleus but not NET formation and that hypoxic environments suppressed the NET release. Next, characterization of PMA-stimulated neutrophils with a swollen nucleus was accomplished by differentiating between suicidal-type NETosis and apoptosis. Furthermore, the significance of the phenomenon was examined using formalin-fixed, paraffin-embedded human lung disease tissues with and without pneumonia. As a result, histone H3 citrullination, DNA outflow, propidium iodide labeling, resistance to DNase I, and suspended actin rearrangement were characteristics of PMA-stimulated neutrophils with a swollen nucleus distinct from neutrophils that underwent either suicidal-type NETosis or apoptosis. Neutrophils stimulated by PMA under hypoxic conditions secreted matrix metalloproteinase-9 cytotoxic to human lung-derived fibroblasts. Further, deposition of neutrophil-derived citrullinated histone H3+ chromatin substances in pulmonary lesions was greater in patients with pneumonia than in patients without pneumonia and positively correlated with hypoxia-inducible factor-1α expression. The collective findings suggested that neutrophils activated under hypoxic conditions could be putative modulators of hypoxia-related disease manifestations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neutrophil extracellular traps in chronic lung disease: implications for pathogenesis and therapy</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/35197267/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/35197267/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Neutrophilic inflammation has a key role in the pathophysiology of multiple chronic lung diseases. The formation of neutrophil extracellular traps (NETs) has emerged as a key mechanism of disease in neutrophilic lung diseases including asthma, COPD, cystic fibrosis and, most recently, bronchiectasis. NETs are large, web-like structures composed of DNA and anti-microbial proteins that are able to bind pathogens, prevent microbial dissemination and degrade bacterial virulence factors. The release of excess concentrations of proteases, antimicrobial proteins, DNA and histones, however, also leads to tissue damage, impaired mucociliary clearance, impaired bacterial killing and increased inflammation. A number of studies have linked airway NET formation with greater disease severity, increased exacerbations and overall worse disease outcomes across the spectrum of airway diseases. Treating neutrophilic inflammation has been challenging in chronic lung disease because of the delicate balance between reducing inflammation and increasing the risk of infections through immunosuppression. Novel approaches to suppressing NET formation or the associated inflammation are in development and represent an important therapeutic target. This review will discuss the relationship between NETs and the pathophysiology of cystic fibrosis, asthma, COPD and bronchiectasis, and explore the current and future development of NET-targeting therapies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Insights into peptidylarginine deiminase expression and citrullination pathways</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/35197210/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/35197210/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Peptidylarginine deiminases (PADs) are calcium-dependent enzymes that mediate citrullination, an irreversible post-translational modification (PTM). PAD enzymes have received increasing attention in (patho-)physiology since multi-omics analysis accelerated their expression profiling. Here, we provide a comprehensive overview of PAD expression at the RNA and protein levels, and a list of annotated substrates per PAD isozyme. We discuss novel roles of citrullination in cellular growth, epigenetic regulation, tissue remodeling, inflammation, and cancer in mouse models and humans. Additionally, we cluster similar effects of protein deimination to offer a different perspective and improve our understanding of citrullination in health and disease. Citrullination should no longer be considered as a rare PTM, but as an important regulatory mechanism in physiology and pathology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Molecular Prerequisites for Neutrophil Extracellular Trap Formation and Evasion Mechanisms of Staphylococcus aureus</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/35237275/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/35237275/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NETosis is a multi-facetted cellular process that promotes the formation of neutrophil extracellular traps (NETs). NETs as web-like structures consist of DNA fibers armed with granular proteins, histones, and microbicidal peptides, thereby exhibiting pathogen-immobilizing and antimicrobial attributes that maximize innate immune defenses against invading microbes. However, clinically relevant pathogens often tolerate entrapment and even take advantage of the remnants of NETs to cause persistent infections in mammalian hosts. Here, we briefly summarize how &lt;em&gt;Staphylococcus aureus&lt;/em&gt;, a high-priority pathogen and causative agent of fatal diseases in humans as well as animals, catalyzes and concurrently exploits NETs during pathogenesis and recurrent infections. Specifically, we focus on toxigenic and immunomodulatory effector molecules produced by staphylococci that prime NET formation, and further highlight the molecular and underlying principles of suicidal NETosis compared to vital NET-formation by viable neutrophils in response to these stimuli. We also discuss the inflammatory potential of NET-controlled microenvironments, as excessive expulsion of NETs from activated neutrophils provokes local tissue injury and may therefore amplify staphylococcal disease severity in hospitalized or chronically ill patients. Combined with an overview of adaptation and counteracting strategies evolved by S. aureus to impede NET-mediated killing, these insights may stimulate biomedical research activities to uncover novel aspects of NET biology at the host-microbe interface.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Disulfiram inhibits neutrophil extracellular trap formation and protects rodents from acute lung injury and SARS-CoV-2 infection</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/35133984/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/35133984/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Severe acute lung injury has few treatment options and a high mortality rate. Upon injury, neutrophils infiltrate the lungs and form neutrophil extracellular traps (NETs), damaging the lungs and driving an exacerbated immune response. Unfortunately, no drug preventing NET formation has completed clinical development. Here, we report that disulfiram - an FDA-approved drug for alcohol use disorder - dramatically reduced NETs, increased survival, improved blood oxygenation, and reduced lung edema in a transfusion-related acute lung injury (TRALI) mouse model. We then tested whether disulfiram could confer protection in the context of SARS-CoV-2 infection, as NETs are elevated in patients with severe COVID-19. In SARS-CoV-2-infected golden hamsters, disulfiram reduced NETs and perivascular fibrosis in the lungs, and it downregulated innate immune and complement/coagulation pathways, suggesting that it could be beneficial for patients with COVID-19. In conclusion, an existing FDA-approved drug can block NET formation and improve disease course in 2 rodent models of lung injury for which treatment options are limited.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Localized Degradation of Neutrophil Extracellular Traps by Photoregulated Enzyme Delivery for Cancer Immunotherapy and Metastasis Suppression</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35080858/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35080858/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Extrusion of neutrophil extracellular traps (NETs), a fundamental host innate immune defense against pathogens, has recently been linked to cancer resistance to immunotherapy and distant metastasis. These findings highlight interesting areas of cancer-elicited inflammation and potential therapeutic strategies. Disrupting existing NETs with DNase I has been proved to enhance the therapeutic efficacy of tumor immunotherapy and attenuate metastatic spread. However, systemic biodistribution of DNase I raises safety issues, potentially impairing host defense against infection. Hence, tumor-specific delivery and metastatic niche-targeted effects are attractive options for localized degradation of NETs. We have engineered a nanoplatform with a plasmonic gold blackbody (AuPB) core with broad-spectrum photo activity and a mesoporous polydopamine (mPDA) shell for efficient loading and photoregulated release of DNase I. The on-demand released DNase I triggered by the second near-infrared (NIR-II) light irradiation breaks the &amp;ldquo;NET-mediated physical barrier&amp;rdquo;, thereby increasing the contact of immune cytotoxic cells with tumor cells in living mice and sensitizing immune checkpoint therapy of primary colorectal cancer (CRC). Moreover, the deposition and light-controlled cargo release from systemically delivered AuPB@mPDA carriers in liver, the most frequent site of CRC metastasis, abolished NET-mediated capture of circulating tumor cells and hence metastatic seeding. Our findings indicate that the localized, light-regulated release of DNase I by photoactive carriers in the NIR-II window represent a translational route for immune-mediated tumor regression and metastasis inhibition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neutrophil Extracellular Traps (NETs) and Covid-19: A new frontiers for therapeutic modality</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/35032828/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/35032828/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In severe SARS-CoV-2 infection, there are solid inflammatory reactions due to neutrophil recruitments and formation of NETs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sustained formations of NETs during respiratory viral infections are associated with collateral tissue injury.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Anti-NETs of natural or synthetic sources may mitigate SARS-CoV-2 infection-induced complications.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;NETs can inactivate a wide range of enveloped and non-enveloped viruses.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;NETs can trigger innate immunity through activation release of interferon from dendritic cells and adaptive immunity.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coronavirus disease 2019 (Covid-19) is a worldwide infectious disease caused by severe acute respiratory coronavirus 2 (SARS-CoV-2). In severe SARS-CoV-2 infection, there is severe inflammatory reactions due to neutrophil recruitments and infiltration in the different organs with the formation of neutrophil extracellular traps (NETs), which involved various complications of SARS-CoV-2 infection. Therefore, the objective of the present review was to explore the potential role of NETs in the pathogenesis of SARS-CoV-2 infection and to identify the targeting drugs against NETs in Covid-19 patients. Different enzyme types are involved in the formation of NETs, such as neutrophil elastase (NE), which degrades nuclear protein and release histones, peptidyl arginine deiminase type 4 (PADA4), which releases chromosomal DNA and gasdermin D, which creates pores in the NTs cell membrane that facilitating expulsion of NT contents. Despite of the beneficial effects of NETs in controlling of invading pathogens, sustained formations of NETs during respiratory viral infections are associated with collateral tissue injury. Excessive development of NETs in SARS-CoV-2 infection is linked with the development of acute lung injury (ALI) and acute respiratory distress syndrome (ARDS) due to creation of the NETs-IL-1β loop. Also, aberrant NTs activation alone or through NETs formation may augment SARS-CoV-2-induced cytokine storm (CS) and macrophage activation syndrome (MAS) in patients with severe Covid-19. Furthermore, NETs formation in SARS-CoV-2 infection is associated with immuno-thrombosis and the development of ALI/ARDS. Therefore, anti-NETs therapy of natural or synthetic sources may mitigate SARS-CoV-2 infection-induced exaggerated immune response, hyperinflammation, immuno-thrombosis, and other complications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Free fatty acids-induced neutrophil extracellular traps lead to dendritic cells activation and T cell differentiation in acute lung injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34959222/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34959222/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This study aimed to investigate whether free fatty acids (FFAs) could induce the release of neutrophil extracellular traps (NETs), as well as the mechanism of FFAs-induced NETs in acute lung injury (ALI). FFAs were used to induce NETs production. The reactive oxygen species (ROS) production was detected after FFA and NADPH oxidase inhibitor treatments. The association between FFAs-induced NETs and the activation of p38, ERK, and JNK pathways was investigated. The effect of FFAs-induced NETs on the dendritic cells (DCs) activation and T cell differentiation was investigated. FFAs could induce neutrophils to produce NETs. FFAs significantly promoted ROS production and increased the expression of ERK, p38 and JNK, and treatment of the inhibitors of NAPDH oxidase (DPI), p38 (SB202190), ERK1/2 (U0126) and JNK (SP600125) inhibited FAAs-induced NETs production. FFAs induced NETs could promote DCs activation and consequently led to the differentiation of primary CD4+ T cells into Th1 and Th17 cells and the release of IL-1β, IL-12 and TNF-α. FFAs are capable of inducing NETs via NOX, ERK, p38 and JNK pathways. FFA-induced NETs further lead to DCs activation and T cell differentiation, which can well explain the mechanism of ALI caused by FFAs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oxidized Phospholipids Promote NETosis and Arterial Thrombosis in LNK(SH2B3) Deficiency</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34846914/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34846914/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; LNK/SH2B3 inhibits Janus kinase/signal transducer and activator of transcription (JAK/STAT) signaling by hematopoietic cytokine receptors. Genome-wide association studies have shown association of a common single nucleotide polymorphism in &lt;em&gt;LNK&lt;/em&gt; (R262W, T allele) with neutrophilia, thrombocytosis, and coronary artery disease. We have shown that &lt;em&gt;LNK(TT)&lt;/em&gt; reduces LNK function and that LNK-deficient mice display prominent platelet-neutrophil aggregates, accelerated atherosclerosis, and thrombosis. Platelet-neutrophil interactions can promote neutrophil extracellular trap (NET) formation. The goals of this study were to assess the role of NETs in atherosclerosis and thrombosis in mice with hematopoietic &lt;em&gt;Lnk&lt;/em&gt; deficiency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; We bred mice with combined deficiency of &lt;em&gt;Lnk&lt;/em&gt; and the NETosis-essential enzyme PAD4 (peptidyl arginine deiminase 4) and transplanted their bone marrow into &lt;em&gt;Ldlr&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; mice. We evaluated the role of LNK in atherothrombosis in humans and mice bearing a gain of function variant in JAK2 (JAK2&lt;sup&gt;V617F&lt;/sup&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; Lnk-deficient mice displayed accelerated carotid artery thrombosis with prominent NETosis that was completely reversed by PAD4 deficiency. Thrombin-activated &lt;em&gt;Lnk&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; platelets promoted increased NETosis when incubated with &lt;em&gt;Lnk&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; neutrophils compared with wild-type platelets or wild-type neutrophils. This involved increased surface exposure and release of oxidized phospholipids (OxPL) from &lt;em&gt;Lnk&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; platelets, as well as increased priming and response of &lt;em&gt;Lnk&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; neutrophils to OxPL. To counteract the effects of OxPL, we introduced a transgene expressing the single-chain variable fragment of E06 (E06-scFv). E06-scFv reversed accelerated NETosis, atherosclerosis, and thrombosis in Lnk-/- mice. We also showed increased NETosis when human induced pluripotent stem cell-derived &lt;em&gt;LNK(TT)&lt;/em&gt; neutrophils were incubated with &lt;em&gt;LNK(TT)&lt;/em&gt; platelet/megakaryocytes, but not in isogenic &lt;em&gt;LNK(CC)&lt;/em&gt; controls, confirming human relevance. Using data from the UK Biobank, we found that individuals with the JAK2&lt;sup&gt;VF&lt;/sup&gt; mutation only showed increased risk of coronary artery disease when also carrying the LNK R262W allele. Mice with hematopoietic &lt;em&gt;Lnk&lt;sup&gt;+/-&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Jak2&lt;sup&gt;VF&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; clonal hematopoiesis showed accelerated arterial thrombosis but not atherosclerosis compared with &lt;em&gt;Jak2&lt;sup&gt;VF&lt;/sup&gt;Lnk&lt;sup&gt;+/+&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; controls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; Hematopoietic &lt;em&gt;Lnk&lt;/em&gt; deficiency promotes NETosis and arterial thrombosis in an OxPL-dependent fashion. LNK(R262W) reduces LNK function in human platelets and neutrophils, promoting NETosis, and increases coronary artery disease risk in humans carrying &lt;em&gt;Jak2&lt;sup&gt;VF&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; mutations. Therapies targeting OxPL may be beneficial for coronary artery disease in genetically defined human populations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Complement and tissue factor-enriched neutrophil extracellular traps are key drivers in COVID-19 immunothrombosis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32759504/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32759504/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Emerging data indicate that complement and neutrophils contribute to the maladaptive immune response that fuels hyperinflammation and thrombotic microangiopathy, thereby increasing coronavirus 2019 (COVID-19) mortality. Here, we investigated how complement interacts with the platelet/neutrophil extracellular traps (NETs)/thrombin axis, using COVID-19 specimens, cell-based inhibition studies, and NET/human aortic endothelial cell (HAEC) cocultures. Increased plasma levels of NETs, tissue factor (TF) activity, and sC5b-9 were detected in patients. Neutrophils of patients yielded high TF expression and released NETs carrying active TF. Treatment of control neutrophils with COVID-19 platelet-rich plasma generated TF-bearing NETs that induced thrombotic activity of HAECs. Thrombin or NETosis inhibition or C5aR1 blockade attenuated platelet-mediated NET-driven thrombogenicity. COVID-19 serum induced complement activation in vitro, consistent with high complement activity in clinical samples. Complement C3 inhibition with compstatin Cp40 disrupted TF expression in neutrophils. In conclusion, we provide a mechanistic basis for a pivotal role of complement and NETs in COVID-19 immunothrombosis. This study supports strategies against severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 that exploit complement or NETosis inhibition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
