<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cell Cycle | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/cell-cycle/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/cell-cycle/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Cell Cycle</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Cell Cycle</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/cell-cycle/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>SARS-CoV-2 N Protein Induces Acute Kidney Injury via Smad3-Dependent G1 Cell Cycle Arrest Mechanism</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34813685/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34813685/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Significance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We show that the selective overactivation of autophagy can cause cell death with unique morphological features distinct from apoptosis or necrosis. This unique type of autophagic cell death, termed “autosis,” occurs not only &lt;em&gt;in vitro&lt;/em&gt; but also in vivo in cerebral hypoxia–ischemia. Moreover, autosis is inhibited both &lt;em&gt;in vitro&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt; by cardiac glycosides, which are Na&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt;,K&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt;-ATPase antagonists used in clinical medicine. Our findings contribute to the basic understanding of cell-death mechanisms and suggest strategies for protecting cells against stresses such as hypoxia–ischemia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;COVID-19 is infected by severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 (SARS-CoV-2) and can cause severe multiple organ injury and death. Kidney is one of major target organs of COVID-19 and acute kidney injury (AKI) is common in critically ill COVID-19 patients. However, mechanisms through which COVID-19 causes AKI remain largely unknown and treatment remains unspecific and ineffective. Here, the authors report that normal kidney-specifically overexpressing SARS-CoV-2 N develops AKI, which worsens in mice under ischemic condition. Mechanistically, it is uncovered that SARS-CoV-2 N-induced AKI is Smad3-dependent as SARS-CoV-2 N protein can interact with Smad3 and enhance TGF-β/Smad3 signaling to cause tubular epithelial cell death and AKI via the G1 cell cycle arrest mechanism. This is further confirmed in Smad3 knockout mice and cells in which deletion of Smad3 protects against SARS-CoV-2 N protein-induced cell death and AKI in vivo and in vitro. Most significantly, it is also found that targeting Smad3 with a Smad3 pharmacological inhibitor is able to inhibit SARS-CoV-2 N-induced AKI. In conclusion, the authors identify that SARS-CoV-2 N protein is a key mediator for AKI and induces AKI via the Smad3-dependent G1 cell cycle arrest mechanism. Targeting Smad3 may represent as a novel therapy for COVID-19-asscoaited AKI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
