<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Spleen | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/spleen/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/spleen/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Spleen</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Spleen</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/spleen/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Distinct Role of TNFR1 and TNFR2 in Protective Immunity Against Orientia tsutsugamushi Infection in Mice</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35479068/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35479068/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Infection with &lt;em&gt;Orientia tsutsugamushi&lt;/em&gt;, an obligate intracellular bacterium, can cause mild or severe scrub typhus. Some patients develop acute lung injury, multi-organ failure, and fatal infection; however, little is known regarding key immune mediators that mediate infection control or disease pathogenesis. Using murine models of scrub typhus, we demonstrated in this study the requirement of TNF-TNFR signaling in protective immunity against this infection. Mice lacking both TNF receptors (TNFR1 and TNFR2) were highly susceptible to &lt;em&gt;O. tsutsugamushi&lt;/em&gt; infection, displaying significantly increased tissue bacterial burdens and succumbing to infection by day 9, while most wild-type mice survived through day 20. This increased susceptibility correlated with poor activation of cellular immunity in inflamed tissues. Flow cytometry of lung- and spleen-derived cells revealed profound deficiencies in total numbers and activation status of NK cells, neutrophils, and macrophages, as well as CD4 and CD8 T cells. To define the role of individual receptors in &lt;em&gt;O. tsutsugamushi&lt;/em&gt; infection, we used mice lacking either TNFR1 or TNFR2. While deficiency in either receptor alone was sufficient to increase host susceptibility to the infection, TNFR1 and TNFR2 played a distinct role in cellular responses. TNF signaling through TNFR1 promoted inflammatory responses and effector T cell expansion, while TNFR2 signaling was associated with anti-inflammatory action and tissue homeostasis. Moreover, TNFRs played an intrinsic role in CD8&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T cell activation, revealing an indispensable role of TNF in protective immunity against &lt;em&gt;O. tsutsugamushi&lt;/em&gt; infection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
