<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Autophagy | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/autophagy/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/autophagy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Autophagy</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Autophagy</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/autophagy/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>microRNA-33 deficiency in macrophages enhances autophagy, improves mitochondrial homeostasis, and protects against lung fibrosis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36626225/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36626225/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis (IPF) is a progressive and ultimately fatal disease. Recent findings have shown a marked metabolic reprogramming associated with changes in mitochondrial homeostasis and autophagy during pulmonary fibrosis. The microRNA-33 (miR-33) family of microRNAs (miRNAs) encoded within the introns of SREBP (sterol regulatory element binding protein) genes are master regulators of sterol and fatty acid (FA) metabolism. miR-33 controls macrophage immuno-metabolic response and enhances mitochondrial biogenesis, FA oxidation, and cholesterol efflux. Here, we show that miR-33 levels are increased in Broncho Alveolar Lavage (BAL) cells isolated from IPF patients compared to healthy controls. We demonstrate that specific genetic ablation of miR-33 in macrophages protects against bleomycin-induced pulmonary fibrosis. The absence of miR-33 in macrophages improves mitochondrial homeostasis and increases autophagy while decreasing inflammatory response after bleomycin injury. Notably, pharmacological inhibition of miR-33 in macrophages via administration of anti-miR-33 Peptide Nucleic Acids (PNA-33) attenuates fibrosis in different &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;ex vivo&lt;/em&gt; mice and human models of pulmonary fibrosis. Together, these studies elucidate a major role of miR-33 in macrophages in the regulation of pulmonary fibrosis and uncover a novel therapeutic approach to treat this disease.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WWOX activates autophagy to alleviate lipopolysaccharide-induced acute lung injury by regulating mTOR</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36621327/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36621327/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acute lung injury (ALI) is characterized by acute systemic inflammatory responses that may lead to severe acute respiratory distress syndrome (ARDS). The clinical course of ALI/ARDS is variable; however, it has been reported that lipopolysaccharides (LPS) play a role in its development. The fragile chromosomal site gene WWOX is highly sensitive to genotoxic stress induced by environmental exposure and is an important candidate gene for exposure-related lung disease research. However, the expression of WWOX and its role in LPS-induced ALI still remain unidentified. This study investigated the expression of WWOX in mouse lung and epithelial cells and explored the role of WWOX in LPS-induced ALI model in vitro and in vivo. In addition, we explored one of the possible mechanisms by which WWOX alleviates ALI from the perspective of autophagy. Here, we observed that LPS stimulation reduced the expression of WWOX and the autophagy marker microtubule-associated protein 1 light chain 3β-II (MAP1LC3B/LC3B) in mouse lung epithelial and human epithelial (H292) cells. Overexpression of WWOX led to the activation of autophagy and inhibited inflammatory responses in LPS-induced ALI cells and mouse model. More importantly, we found that WWOX interacts with mechanistic target of rapamycin [serine/threonine kinase] (mTOR) and regulates mTOR and ULK-1 signaling-mediated autophagy. Thus, reduced WWOX levels were associated with LPS-induced ALI. WWOX can activate autophagy in lung epithelial cells and protect against LPS-induced ALI, which is partly related to the mTOR-ULK1 signaling pathway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Palmitoylation prevents sustained inflammation by limiting NLRP3 inflammasome activation through chaperone-mediated autophagy</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36586411/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36586411/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Palmitoylation of NLRP3 at C844 is critical for preventing inflammasome activation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;zDHHC12 directly palmitoylates NLRP3&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;zDHHC12 enhances NLRP3 degradation through CMA pathway&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Defective NLRP3 palmitoylation is associated with inflammatory diseases&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Summary&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a key component of the inflammasome, NLRP3 is a critical intracellular danger sensor emerging as an important clinical target in inflammatory diseases. However, little is known about the mechanisms that determine the kinetics of NLRP3 inflammasome stability and activity to ensure effective and controllable inflammatory responses. Here, we show that S-palmitoylation acts as a brake to turn NLRP3 inflammasome off. zDHHC12 is identified as the S-acyltransferase for NLRP3 palmitoylation, which promotes its degradation through the chaperone-mediated autophagy pathway. Zdhhc12 deficiency in mice enhances inflammatory symptoms and lethality following alum-induced peritonitis and LPS-induced endotoxic shock. Notably, several disease-associated mutations in NLRP3 are associated with defective palmitoylation, resulting in overt NLRP3 inflammasome activation. Thus, our findings identify zDHHC12 as a repressor of NLRP3 inflammasome activation and uncover a previously unknown regulatory mechanism by which the inflammasome pathway is tightly controlled by the dynamic palmitoylation of NLRP3.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exosomal LOC85009 inhibits docetaxel resistance in lung adenocarcinoma through regulating ATG5-induced autophagy</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36641841/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36641841/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Aims:&lt;/em&gt; This study aims at investigating the role of a neighbor long non-coding RNA (lncRNA) of HDAC4 (LOC85009) in docetaxel (DTX) resistance of lung adenocarcinoma (LUAD).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; RT-qPCR was used to analyze LOC85009 expression in DTX-resistant LUAD cells. &lt;em&gt;In vitro&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt; experiments were applied to detect the influence of LOC85009 on LUAD cell growth and xenograft tumor growth. DNA pull down assay, RNA pull down assay, ChIP assay, CoIP assay and RIP assay were performed to identify the direct interactions between factors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; LOC85009 was lowly-expressed in DTX-resistant LUAD cells. Functionally, LOC85009 overexpression inhibited DTX resistance and cell proliferation but triggered cell apoptosis. Moreover, we identified that LOC85009 was transferred from LUAD cells to DTX-resistant LUAD cells via exosomes. Exosomal LOC85009 inhibited DTX resistance, proliferation and autophagy while induced apoptosis in DTX-resistant cells. Additionally, we found that LOC85009 sequestered ubiquitin-specific proteinase 5 (USP5) to destabilize upstream transcription factor 1 (USF1) protein, thereby inactivating ATG5 transcription.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; Exosomal LOC85009 inhibits DTX resistance through regulation of ATG5-induced autophagy via USP5/USF1 axis, suggesting that LOC85009 might be a potential target to reverse DTX resistance in the treatment of LUAD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Methyltransferase-like 3 suppresses phenotypic switching of vascular smooth muscle cells by activating autophagosome formation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36564367/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36564367/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prevention of neointima formation is the key to improving long-term outcomes after stenting or coronary artery bypass grafting. RNA N&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;-methyladenosine (m&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;A) methylation has been reported to be involved in the development of various cardiovascular diseases, but whether it has a regulatory effect on neointima formation is unknown. Herein, we revealed that methyltransferase-like 3 (METTL3), the major methyltransferase of m&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;A methylation, was downregulated during vascular smooth muscle cell (VSMC) proliferation and neointima formation. Knockdown of METTL3 facilitated, while overexpression of METTL3 suppressed the proliferation of human aortic smooth muscle cells (HASMCs) by arresting HASMCs at G2/M checkpoint and the phosphorylation of CDC2 (p-CDC2) was inactivated by METTL3. On the other hand, the migration and synthetic phenotype of HASMCs were enhanced by METTL3 knockdown, but inhibited by METTL3 overexpression. The protein levels of matrix metalloproteinase 2 (MMP2), MMP7 and MMP9 were reduced, while the expression level of tissue inhibitor of metalloproteinase 3 was increased in HASMCs with METTL3 overexpression. Moreover, METTL3 promoted the autophagosome formation by upregulating the expression of ATG5 (autophagy-related 5) and ATG7. Knockdown of either ATG5 or ATG7 largely reversed the regulatory effects of METTL3 overexpression on phenotypic switching of HASMCs, as evidenced by increased proliferation and migration, and predisposed to synthetic phenotype. These results indicate that METTL3 inhibits the phenotypic switching of VSMCs by positively regulating ATG5-mediated and ATG7-mediated autophagosome formation. Thus, enhancing the level of RNA m&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;A or the formation of autophagosomes is the promising strategy to delay neointima formation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The UFM1 system regulates ER-phagy through the ufmylation of CYB5R3</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36543799/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36543799/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Protein modification by ubiquitin-like proteins (UBLs) amplifies limited genome information and regulates diverse cellular processes, including translation, autophagy and antiviral pathways. Ubiquitin-fold modifier 1 (UFM1) is a UBL covalently conjugated with intracellular proteins through ufmylation, a reaction analogous to ubiquitylation. Ufmylation is involved in processes such as endoplasmic reticulum (ER)-associated protein degradation, ribosome-associated protein quality control at the ER and ER-phagy. However, it remains unclear how ufmylation regulates such distinct ER-related functions. Here we identify a UFM1 substrate, NADH-cytochrome b5 reductase 3 (CYB5R3), that localizes on the ER membrane. Ufmylation of CYB5R3 depends on the E3 components UFL1 and UFBP1 on the ER, and converts CYB5R3 into its inactive form. Ufmylated CYB5R3 is recognized by UFBP1 through the UFM1-interacting motif, which plays an important role in the further uyfmylation of CYB5R3. Ufmylated CYB5R3 is degraded in lysosomes, which depends on the autophagy-related protein Atg7- and the autophagy-adaptor protein CDK5RAP3. Mutations of CYB5R3 and genes involved in the UFM1 system cause hereditary developmental disorders, and ufmylation-defective Cyb5r3 knock-in mice exhibit microcephaly. Our results indicate that CYB5R3 ufmylation induces ER-phagy, which is indispensable for brain development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Degradation of HDAC10 by autophagy promotes IRF3-mediated antiviral innate immune responses</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36538592/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36538592/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Histone deacetylases (HDACs) play important roles in immunity and inflammation. Through functional screening, we identified HDAC10 as an inhibitor of the type I interferon (IFN) response mediated by interferon regulatory factor 3 (IRF3). HDAC10 abundance was decreased in mouse macrophages in response to innate immune stimuli and was reduced in peripheral blood mononuclear cells (PBMCs) from patients with systemic lupus erythematosus (SLE) compared with that in PBMCs from healthy donors. Deficiency in HDAC10 in mouse embryonic fibroblasts and in mice promoted the expression of genes encoding type I IFNs and of IFN-stimulated genes (ISGs), leading to enhanced antiviral responses in vitro and in vivo. HDAC10 bound in a deacetylase-independent manner to IRF3 in uninfected cells to inhibit the phosphorylation of IRF3 at Ser&lt;sup&gt;396&lt;/sup&gt; by TANK-binding kinase 1 (TBK1). Upon viral infection, HDAC10 was targeted for autophagy-mediated degradation through its interaction with LC3-II. Consequently, IRF3 phosphorylation was increased, which resulted in enhanced type I IFN production and antiviral responses. Our findings identify a potential target for improving host defense responses against pathogen infection and for treating autoimmune disease.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PI3K/AKT-mediated autophagy inhibition facilitates mast cell activation to enhance severe inflammatory lung injury in influenza A virus- and secondary Staphylococcus aureus-infected mice</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36549394/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36549394/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Influenza A virus infection causes considerable morbidity and mortality each year globally, and secondary bacterial infection further exacerbates the severity and fatality of the initial viral infection. Mast cells have substantial roles in protecting the respiratory tract mucosa, while their role in viral and bacterial co-infection remains unclear. The present study revealed that secondary Staphylococcus aureus infection significantly aggravated the activation of mast cells during the initial H1N1 infection both in vivo and in vitro, which was closely related to the increased inflammatory lung injury and mortality. Meanwhile, the secondary S. aureus infection suppressed autophagy and promoted inflammatory mediators released by mast cells through activating the PI3K/Akt signaling pathway. Blocking PI3K/Akt pathway by LY294002, an inhibitor of Akt phosphorylation, could rescue autophagy and inhibit the release of inflammatory mediators. Furthermore, based on the influenza A viral and secondary bacterial infected mice model, we showed that the combination of LY294002 and antiviral drug oseltamivir could effectively reduce the inflammatory damage and pro-inflammatory cytokines releasing in lungs, recovering body weight loss and improving the survival rate from the co-infections. In conclusion, secondary bacterial infection can inhibit autophagy and stimulate mast cell activation through the PI3K/Akt pathway, which might explain why secondary bacterial infection would cause severe and fatal consequences following an initial influenza A viral infection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ORP8 acts as a lipophagy receptor to mediate lipid droplet turnover</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/pwac063/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/pwac063/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lipophagy, the selective engulfment of lipid droplets (LDs) by autophagosomes for lysosomal degradation, is critical to lipid and energy homeostasis. Here we show that the lipid transfer protein ORP8 is located on LDs and mediates the encapsulation of LDs by autophagosomal membranes. This function of ORP8 is independent of its lipid transporter activity and is achieved through direct interaction with phagophore-anchored LC3/GABARAPs. Upon lipophagy induction, ORP8 has increased localization on LDs and is phosphorylated by AMPK, thereby enhancing its affinity for LC3/GABARAPs. Deletion of ORP8 or interruption of ORP8-LC3/GABARAP interaction results in accumulation of LDs and increased intracellular triglyceride. Overexpression of ORP8 alleviates LD and triglyceride deposition in the liver of ob/ob mice, and Osbpl8&lt;sup&gt;−/−&lt;/sup&gt; mice exhibit liver lipid clearance defects. Our results suggest that ORP8 is a lipophagy receptor that plays a key role in cellular lipid metabolism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SESAME-catalyzed H3T11 phosphorylation inhibits Dot1-catalyzed H3K79me3 to regulate autophagy and telomere silencing</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36473858/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36473858/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The glycolytic enzyme, pyruvate kinase Pyk1 maintains telomere heterochromatin by phosphorylating histone H3T11 (H3pT11), which promotes SIR (silent information regulator) complex binding at telomeres and prevents autophagy-mediated Sir2 degradation. However, the exact mechanism of action for H3pT11 is poorly understood. Here, we report that H3pT11 directly inhibits Dot1-catalyzed H3K79 tri-methylation (H3K79me3) and uncover how this histone crosstalk regulates autophagy and telomere silencing. Mechanistically, Pyk1-catalyzed H3pT11 directly reduces the binding of Dot1 to chromatin and inhibits Dot1-catalyzed H3K79me3, which leads to transcriptional repression of autophagy genes and reduced autophagy. Despite the antagonism between H3pT11 and H3K79me3, they work together to promote the binding of SIR complex at telomeres to maintain telomere silencing. Furthermore, we identify Reb1 as a telomere-associated factor that recruits Pyk1-containing SESAME (Serine-responsive SAM-containing Metabolic Enzyme) complex to telomere regions to phosphorylate H3T11 and prevent the invasion of H3K79me3 from euchromatin into heterochromatin to maintain telomere silencing. Together, these results uncover a histone crosstalk and provide insights into dynamic regulation of silent heterochromatin and autophagy in response to cell metabolism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Protection of adipose-derived mesenchymal stromal cells during acute lung injury requires autophagy maintained by mTOR</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36470863/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36470863/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Previous studies suggest that mesenchymal stem cells may represent a promising cellular therapy for acute lung injury (ALI); however, the underlying relevant molecular mechanisms remain unclear. Adipose-derived mesenchymal stem cells (ADSCs) were isolated and characterized by alizarin red staining, oil red staining, and flow cytometry. Lung injury and inflammatory cell infiltration were determined using the Evans blue method, wet/dry weight ratio, and H&amp;amp;E staining. An ELISA was used to detect the concentrations of IFN-γ, IL-2, and TNF-α. Autophagy was detected with an mRFP-GFP-LC3 dual-fluorescence autophagy indicator system, Western blotting, and electron microscopy. We first demonstrated that ADSCs did alleviate the inflammatory responses and tissue damage in lipopolysaccharide (LPS)-induced ALI. Next, we further demonstrated in vivo that autophagy plays a key role in the maintenance of ADSC therapeutic efficacy. In vitro experiments demonstrated that ADSCs co-cultured with alveolar epithelial cells depend on autophagy for significant anti-inflammatory functions. Moreover, the mammalian target of rapamycin (mTOR) is a key regulator of autophagy. Taken together, our findings demonstrate that the effect of ADSC on ALI, especially on alveolar epithelial cells, is dependent on mTOR-mediated autophagy maintenance. The significance of our study for ALI therapy is discussed with respect to a more complete understanding of the therapeutic strategy paradigm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MiR-199a-3p-regulated alveolar macrophage-derived secretory autophagosomes exacerbate lipopolysaccharide-induced acute respiratory distress syndrome</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36523634/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36523634/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Purpose:&lt;/em&gt; Acute respiratory distress syndrome (ARDS) is a prevalent illness in intensive care units. Extracellular vesicles and particles released from activated alveolar macrophages (AMs) assist in ARDS lung injury and the inflammatory process through mechanisms that are unclear. This study investigated the role of AM-derived secretory autophagosomes (SAPs) in lung injury and microRNA (MiR)-199a-3p-regulated inflammation associated with ARDS in vitro and in a murine model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; The ARDS model in mouse was established by intratracheal LPS lipopolysaccharide (LPS) injection. The agomirs or antagomirs of MiR-199a-3p were injected into the caudal vein to figure out whether MiR-199a-3p could influence ARDS inflammation and lung injury, whereas the mimics or inhibitors of MiR-199a-3p, siRNA of Rab8a, or PAK4 inhibitor were transfected or applied to RAW264.7 cells to evaluate the mechanism of SAP release. Culture supernatants of RAW264.7 cells treated with LPS or bronchoalveolar lavage fluid from mice were collected for the isolation of SAPs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; We found that MiR-199a-3p was over-expressed in the lungs of ARDS mice. The MiR-199a-3p antagomir alleviated, whereas the MiR-199a-3p agomir exacerbated LPS-induced inflammation in mice by promoting AM-derived SAP secretion. In addition, MiR-199a-3p over-expression exacerbated LPS-induced ARDS via activating Rab8a, and Rab8a silencing significantly suppressed the promoting influence of the MiR-199a-3p mimic on SAP secretion. Furthermore, MiR-199a-3p mimic activated Rab8a by directly inhibiting PAK4 expression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/em&gt; The novel finding of this study is that MiR-199a-3p participated in the regulation of SAP secretion and the inflammatory process via targeting of PAK4/Rab8a, and is a potential therapeutic candidate for ARDS treatment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ATG9A and ATG2A form a heteromeric complex essential for autophagosome formation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36347259/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36347259/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ATG9A and ATG2A form a heterotetrameric complex&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;HDX and CXL-MS reveal intricate interaction interface between ATG9A and ATG2A&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Disrupting the ATG9A-ATG2A complex disrupts autophagic flux&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lipid transfer tunnel of ATG2A binds proximal to the perpendicular branch of ATG9A&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ATG9A and ATG2A are essential core members of the autophagy machinery. ATG9A is a lipid scramblase that allows equilibration of lipids across a membrane bilayer, whereas ATG2A facilitates lipid flow between tethered membranes. Although both have been functionally linked during the formation of autophagosomes, the molecular details and consequences of their interaction remain unclear. By combining data from peptide arrays, crosslinking, and hydrogen-deuterium exchange mass spectrometry together with cryoelectron microscopy, we propose a molecular model of the ATG9A-2A complex. Using this integrative structure modeling approach, we identify several interfaces mediating ATG9A-2A interaction that would allow a direct transfer of lipids from ATG2A into the lipid-binding perpendicular branch of ATG9A. Mutational analyses combined with functional activity assays demonstrate their importance for autophagy, thereby shedding light on this protein complex at the heart of autophagy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PTP4A2 promotes lysophagy by dephosphorylation of VCP/p97 at Tyr805</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36300783/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36300783/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overexpression of PTP4A phosphatases are associated with advanced cancers, but their biological functions are far from fully understood due to limited knowledge about their physiological substrates. VCP is implicated in lysophagy via collaboration with specific cofactors in the ELDR complex. However, how the ELDR complex assembly is regulated has not been determined. Moreover, the functional significance of the penultimate and conserved Tyr805 phosphorylation in VCP has not been established. Here, we use an unbiased substrate trapping and mass spectrometry approach and identify VCP/p97 as a &lt;em&gt;bona fide&lt;/em&gt; substrate of PTP4A2. Biochemical studies show that PTP4A2 dephosphorylates VCP at Tyr805, enabling the association of VCP with its C-terminal cofactors UBXN6/UBXD1 and PLAA, which are components of the ELDR complex responsible for lysophagy, the autophagic clearance of damaged lysosomes. Functionally, PTP4A2 is required for cellular homeostasis by promoting lysophagy through facilitating ELDR-mediated K48-linked ubiquitin conjugate removal and autophagosome formation on the damaged lysosomes. Deletion of &lt;em&gt;Ptp4a2 in vivo&lt;/em&gt; compromises the recovery of glycerol-injection induced acute kidney injury due to impaired lysophagy and sustained lysosomal damage. Taken together, our data establish PTP4A2 as a critical regulator of VCP and uncover an important role for PTP4A2 in maintaining lysosomal homeostasis through dephosphorylation of VCP at Tyr805. Our study suggests that PTP4A2 targeting could be a potential therapeutic approach to treat cancers and other degenerative diseases by modulating lysosomal homeostasis and macroautophagy/autophagy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Activation of Pancreatic Acinar FXR Protects against Pancreatitis via Osgin1-Mediated Restoration of Efficient Autophagy</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36405253/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36405253/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pancreatitis is the leading cause of hospitalization in gastroenterology, and no medications are available for treating this disease in current clinical practice. FXR plays an anti-inflammatory role in diverse inflammatory diseases, while its function in pancreatitis remains unknown. In this study, we initially observed a marked increase of nuclear FXR in pancreatic tissues of human patients with pancreatitis. Deleting the FXR in pancreatic acinar cells (FXR&lt;sup&gt;acinarΔ/Δ &lt;/sup&gt;) led to more severe pancreatitis in mouse models of caerulein-induced acute and chronic pancreatitis, while the FXR agonist GW4064 significantly attenuated pancreatitis in caerulein or arginine-induced acute pancreatitis and caerulein-induced chronic pancreatitis. FXR deletion impaired the viability and stress responses of pancreatic exocrine organoids (PEOs) in vitro. Utilizing RNA-seq and ChIP-seq of PEOs, we identified &lt;em&gt;Osgin1&lt;/em&gt; as a direct target of FXR in the exocrine pancreas, which was also increasingly expressed in human pancreatitis tissues compared to normal pancreatic tissues. Pancreatic knockdown of &lt;em&gt;Osgin1&lt;/em&gt; by AAV-pan abolished the therapeutic effects of FXR activation on pancreatitis, whereas pancreatic overexpression of &lt;em&gt;Osgin1&lt;/em&gt; effectively alleviated caerulein-induced pancreatitis. Mechanistically, we found that the FXR-OSGIN1 axis stimulated autophagic flux in the pancreatic tissues and cell lines, which was considered as the intrinsic mechanisms through which FXR-OSGIN1 protecting against pancreatitis. Our results highlight the protective role of the FXR-OSGIN1 axis in pancreatitis and provided a new target for the treatment of this disease.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Novel Protein Encoded by Exosomal CircATG4B Induces Oxaliplatin Resistance in Colorectal Cancer by Promoting Autophagy</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36285810/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36285810/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oxaliplatin is commonly used in chemotherapeutic regimens for colorectal cancer (CRC) after surgical resection. However, acquired chemoresistance seriously affects the curative effect in CRC patients, and the mechanism is still unclear. Here, a circular RNA, circATG4B is identified, which plays an important role in oxaliplatin resistance in CRC. circATG4B expression is found to be increased in exosomes secreted by oxaliplatin-resistant CRC cells. In addition, the results suggest that circATG4B induces oxaliplatin resistance by promoting autophagy. Further in vivo and in vitro studies indicate that the effect of circATG4B is attributed to its potential to encode a novel protein, circATG4B-222aa. Next, circATG4B-222aa is found to function as a decoy to competitively interact with TMED10 and prevent TMED10 from binding to ATG4B, which leads to increased autophagy followed by induction of chemoresistance. Therefore, this study reveals that exosomal circATG4B participates in the decreased chemosensitivity of CRC cells, providing a new rationale for a potential therapeutic target for oxaliplatin resistance in CRC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intercellular transfer of activated STING triggered by RAB22A-mediated non-canonical autophagy promotes antitumor immunity</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36280710/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36280710/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;STING, an endoplasmic reticulum (ER) transmembrane protein, mediates innate immune activation upon cGAMP stimulation and is degraded through autophagy. Here, we report that activated STING could be transferred between cells to promote antitumor immunity, a process triggered by RAB22A-mediated non-canonical autophagy. Mechanistically, RAB22A engages PI4K2A to generate PI4P that recruits the Atg12-Atg5-Atg16L1 complex, inducing the formation of ER-derived RAB22A-mediated non-canonical autophagosome, in which STING activated by agonists or chemoradiotherapy is packaged. This RAB22A-induced autophagosome fuses with RAB22A-positive early endosome, generating a new organelle that we name Rafeesome (RAB22A-mediated non-canonical autophagosome fused with early endosome). Meanwhile, RAB22A inactivates RAB7 to suppress the fusion of Rafeesome with lysosome, thereby enabling the secretion of the inner vesicle of the autophagosome bearing activated STING as a new type of extracellular vesicle that we define as R-EV (RAB22A-induced extracellular vesicle). Activated STING-containing R-EVs induce IFNβ release from recipient cells to the tumor microenvironment, promoting antitumor immunity. Consistently, RAB22A enhances the antitumor effect of the STING agonist diABZI in mice, and a high RAB22A level predicts good survival in nasopharyngeal cancer patients treated with chemoradiotherapy. Our findings reveal that Rafeesome regulates the intercellular transfer of activated STING to trigger and spread antitumor immunity, and that the inner vesicle of non-canonical autophagosome originated from ER is secreted as R-EV, providing a new perspective for understanding the intercellular communication of organelle membrane proteins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2,3,5,4&#39;-tetrahydroxystilbene-2-O-β-D-glucoside ameliorates bleomycin-induced pulmonary fibrosis via regulating pro-fibrotic signaling pathways</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36267283/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36267283/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2,3,5,4&amp;rsquo;-Tetrahydroxystilbene-2-O-β-D-Glucoside (THSG) is the main active ingredient extracted from &lt;em&gt;Polygonum multiflorum&lt;/em&gt; Thunb. (PMT), which has been reported to possess extensive pharmacological properties. Nevertheless, the exact role of THSG in pulmonary fibrosis has not been demonstrated yet. The main purpose of this study was to investigate the protective effect of THSG against bleomycin (BLM)-induced lung fibrosis in a murine model, and explore the underlying mechanisms of THSG in transforming growth factor-beta 1 (TGF-β1)-induced fibrogenesis using MRC-5 human lung fibroblast cells. We found that THSG significantly attenuated lung injury by reducing fibrosis and extracellular matrix deposition. THSG treatment significantly downregulated the expression levels of TGF-β1, fibronectin, α-SMA, CTGF, and TGFBR2, however, upregulated the expression levels of antioxidants (SOD-1 and catalase) and LC3B in the lungs of BLM-treated mice. THSG treatment decreased the expression levels of fibronectin, α-SMA, and CTGF in TGF-β1-stimulated MRC-5 cells. Conversely, THSG increased the expression levels of SOD-1 and catalase. Furthermore, treatment of THSG profoundly reduced the TGF-β1-induced generation of reactive oxygen species (ROS). In addition, THSG restored TGF-β1-induced impaired autophagy, accompany by increasing the protein levels of LC3B-II and Beclin 1. Mechanism study indicated that THSG significantly reduced TGF-β1-induced increase of TGFBR2 expression and phosphorylation of Smad2/3, Akt, mTOR, and ERK1/2 in MRC-5 cells. These findings suggest that THSG may be considered as an anti-fibrotic drug for the treatment of pulmonary fibrosis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Calcium transients on the ER surface trigger liquid-liquid phase separation of FIP200 to specify autophagosome initiation sites</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36198318/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36198318/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The mechanism that initiates autophagosome formation on the ER in multicellular organisms is elusive. Here, we showed that autophagy stimuli trigger Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt; transients on the outer surface of the ER membrane, whose amplitude, frequency, and duration are controlled by the metazoan-specific ER transmembrane autophagy protein EPG-4/EI24. Persistent Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt; transients/oscillations on the cytosolic ER surface in EI24-depleted cells cause accumulation of FIP200 autophagosome initiation complexes on the ER. This defect is suppressed by attenuating ER Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt; transients. Multi-modal SIM analysis revealed that Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt; transients on the ER trigger the formation of dynamic and fusion-prone liquid-like FIP200 puncta. Starvation-induced Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt; transients on lysosomes also induce FIP200 puncta that further move to the ER. Multiple FIP200 puncta on the ER, whose association depends on the ER proteins VAPA/B and ATL2/3, assemble into autophagosome formation sites. Thus, Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt; transients are crucial for triggering phase separation of FIP200 to specify autophagosome initiation sites in metazoans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NLRC5 restricts dengue virus infection by promoting the autophagic degradation of viral NS3 through E3 ligase CUL2 (cullin 2)</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36126167/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36126167/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NLRC5 has been reported to be involved in antiviral immunity; however, the underlying mechanism remains poorly understood. Here, we investigated the functional role of NLRC5 in the infection of a flavivirus, dengue virus (DENV). We found that the expression of NLRC5 was strongly induced by virus infection and IFNB or IFNG stimulation in different cell lines. Overexpression of NLRC5 remarkably suppressed DENV infection, whereas knockout of NLRC5 led to a significant increase in DENV infection. Mechanistic study revealed that NLRC5 interacted with the viral nonstructural protein 3 (NS3) protease domain and mediated degradation of NS3 through a ubiquitin-dependent selective macroautophagy/autophagy pathway. We demonstrated that NLRC5 recruited the E3 ubiquitin ligase CUL2 (cullin 2) to catalyze K48-linked poly-ubiquitination of the NS3 protease domain, which subsequently served as a recognition signal for cargo receptor TOLLIP-mediated selective autophagic degradation. Together, we have demonstrated that NLRC5 exerted an antiviral effect by mediating the degradation of a multifunctional protein of DENV, providing a novel antiviral signal axis of NLRC5-CUL2-NS3-TOLLIP. This study expands our understanding of the regulatory network of NLRC5 in the host defense against virus infection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A protein encoded by circular ZNF609 RNA induces acute kidney injury by activating the AKT/mTOR autophagy pathway</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36110046/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36110046/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Erratum in:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cell.com/molecular-therapy-family/molecular-therapy/fulltext/S1525-0016%2822%2900610-4&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;A protein encoded by circular ZNF609 RNA induces acute kidney injury by activating the AKT/mTOR-autophagy pathway&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Autophagy plays a crucial role in the development and progression of ischemic acute kidney injury (AKI). However, the function and mechanism of circular RNAs (circRNAs) in the regulation of autophagy in ischemic AKI remain unexplored. Herein, we find that circ-ZNF609, originating from the ZNF609 locus, is highly expressed in the kidney after ischemia/reperfusion injury, and urinary circ-ZNF609 is a moderate predictor for AKI in heart disease patients. Overexpression of circ-ZNF609 can activate AKT3/mTOR signaling and induce autophagy flux impairment and cell apoptosis while inhibiting proliferation in HK-2 cells, which is blocked by silencing circ-ZNF609. Mechanistically, circ-ZNF609 encodes a functional protein consisting of 250 amino acids (aa), termed ZNF609-250aa, the overexpression of which can activate AKT3/mTOR signaling and induce autophagy flux impairment and cell apoptosis in HK-2 cells in vitro and in AKI kidneys in vivo. The blockade of AKT and mTOR signaling with pharmacological inhibitors is capable of reversing ZNF609-250aa-induced autophagy flux impairment and cell apoptosis in HK-2 cells. The present study demonstrates that highly expressed circ-ZNF609-encoded ZNF609-250aa induces cell apoptosis and AKI by impairing the autophagy flux via an AKT/mTOR-dependent mechanism. These findings imply that targeting circ-ZNF609 may be a novel therapy for ischemic AKI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The emerging mechanisms and functions of microautophagy</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/36097284/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/36097284/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;lsquo;Autophagy&amp;rsquo; refers to an evolutionarily conserved process through which cellular contents, such as damaged organelles and protein aggregates, are delivered to lysosomes for degradation. Different forms of autophagy have been described on the basis of the nature of the cargoes and the means used to deliver them to lysosomes. At present, the prevailing categories of autophagy in mammalian cells are macroautophagy, microautophagy and chaperone-mediated autophagy. The molecular mechanisms and biological functions of macroautophagy and chaperone-mediated autophagy have been extensively studied, but microautophagy has received much less attention. In recent years, there has been a growth in research on microautophagy, first in yeast and then in mammalian cells. Here we review this form of autophagy, focusing on selective forms of microautophagy. We also discuss the upstream regulatory mechanisms, the crosstalk between macroautophagy and microautophagy, and the functional implications of microautophagy in diseases such as cancer and neurodegenerative disorders in humans. Future research into microautophagy will provide opportunities to develop novel interventional strategies for autophagy- and lysosome-related diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>USP13 Deficiency Impairs Autophagy and Facilitates Age-related Lung Fibrosis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36150040/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36150040/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis (IPF) is an age-related disease. Failure of the proteostasis network with age, including insufficient autophagy, contributes to the pathology of IPF. Mechanisms underlying autophagy disruption in IPF are unclear and may involve regulation of USP (ubiquitin-specific protease) by post-translational modifications. To expand our previous observation of low USP13 expression in IPF, this study evaluated the role of USP13 in age-related lung fibrosis. Here, we demonstrated that &lt;em&gt;Usp13&lt;/em&gt;-deficient aged mice exhibited impaired autophagic activity and increased vulnerability to bleomycin-induced fibrosis. Mechanistically, USP13 interacted with and deubiquitinated Beclin 1, and Beclin 1 overexpression abolished the effects of USP13 disruption. In addition, Beclin 1 inhibition resulted in insufficient autophagy and more severe lung fibrosis after bleomycin injury, consistent with the phenotype of aged &lt;em&gt;Usp13&lt;/em&gt;-deficient mice. Collectively, we show a protective role of USP13 in age-related pulmonary fibrosis. Aging-mediated USP13 loss impairs autophagic activity and facilitates lung fibrosis through Beclin 1 deubiquitination. Our findings support the notion that age-dependent dysregulation of autophagic regulators enhances vulnerability to lung fibrosis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FOXO3 mutation predicting gefitinib-induced hepatotoxicity in NSCLC patients through regulation of autophagy</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36176901/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36176901/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hepatotoxicity is a common side effect for patients treated with gefitinib, but the related pathogenesis is unclear and lacks effective predictor and management strategies. A multi-omics approach integrating pharmacometabolomics, pharmacokinetics and pharmacogenomics was employed in non-small cell lung cancer patients to identify the effective predictor for gefitinib-induced hepatotoxicity and explore optional therapy substitution. Here, we found that patients with rs4946935 AA, located in Forkhead Box O3 (&lt;em&gt;FOXO3&lt;/em&gt;) which is a well-known autophagic regulator, had a higher risk of hepatotoxicity than those with the GA or GG variant (OR = 18.020, 95%CI = 2.473 to 459.1784, P = 0.018) in a gefitinib-concentration dependent pattern. Furthermore, functional experiments identified that rs4946935_A impaired the expression of &lt;em&gt;FOXO3&lt;/em&gt; by inhibiting the promotor activity, increasing the threshold of autophagy initiation and inhibiting the autophagic activity which contributed to gefitinib-induced liver injury. In contrast, erlotinib-induced liver injury was independent on the variant and expression levels of &lt;em&gt;FOXO3&lt;/em&gt;. This study reveals that &lt;em&gt;FOXO3&lt;/em&gt; mutation, leading to autophagic imbalance, plays important role in gefitinib-induced hepatotoxicity, especially for patients with high concentration of gefitinib. In conclusion, &lt;em&gt;FOXO3&lt;/em&gt; mutation is an effective predictor and erlotinib might be an appropriately and well-tolerated treatment option for patients carrying rs4946935 AA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Influenza A virus use of BinCARD1 to facilitate the binding of viral NP to importin α7 is counteracted by TBK1-p62 axis-mediated autophagy</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36056146/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36056146/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a major component of the viral ribonucleoprotein (vRNP) complex in influenza A virus (IAV), nucleoprotein (NP) interacts with isoforms of importin α family members, leading to the import of itself and vRNP complex into the nucleus, a process pivotal in the replication cycle of IAV. In this study, we found that BinCARD1, an isoform of Bcl10-interacting protein with CARD (BinCARD), was leveraged by IAV for efficient viral replication. BinCARD1 promoted the nuclear import of the vRNP complex and newly synthesized NP and thus enhanced vRNP complex activity. Moreover, we found that BinCARD1 interacted with NP to promote NP binding to importin α7, an adaptor in the host nuclear import pathway. However, we also found that BinCARD1 promoted RIG-I-mediated innate immune signaling by mediating Lys63-linked polyubiquitination of TRAF3, and that TBK1 appeared to degrade BinCARD1. We showed that BinCARD1 was polyubiquitinated at residue K103 through a Lys63 linkage, which was recognized by the TBK1-p62 axis for autophagic degradation. Overall, our data demonstrate that IAV leverages BinCARD1 as an important host factor that promotes viral replication, and two mechanisms in the host defense system are triggered-innate immune signaling and autophagic degradation-to mitigate the promoting effect of BinCARD1 on the life cycle of IAV.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transcriptome analysis identifies IL24 as an autophagy modulator in PM2.5 caused lung dysfunction</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36049333/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36049333/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Transcriptome analysis revealed the relationship between PM&lt;sup&gt;2.5&lt;/sup&gt; exposure and autophagy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PM&lt;sup&gt;2.5&lt;/sup&gt; exposure led to lung pathological changes in mouse model via autophagy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IL24 was identified as a potential target associated with PM&lt;sup&gt;2.5&lt;/sup&gt;-induced autophagy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;L24 was regulated by inhibition of mTOR.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Evidence suggests that exposure to PM&lt;sup&gt;2.5&lt;/sup&gt; increased hospitalization and mortality rates of respiratory diseases. However, the potential biomarkers and targets associated with PM&lt;sup&gt;2.5&lt;/sup&gt;-induced lung dysfunction are not fully discovered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; Gene Ontology (GO), Kyoto Encyclopedia of Genes and Genomes (KEGG) and HALLMARK enrichment analysis of the RNA-seq data (Beas-2B cells treated with PM&lt;sup&gt;2.5&lt;/sup&gt;) were applied. Gene set enrichment analysis (GSEA) was performed to identify the biological processes correlated with autophagy. Three gene expression profile datasets (GSE158954, GSE155616 and GSE182199) were downloaded from the Gene Expression Omnibus (GEO) database to identify the potential targets. PM&lt;sup&gt;2.5&lt;/sup&gt;-exposed mice were constructed. Real-time qPCR, siRNA transfection, western blot, immunofluorescence, and pathological staining were applied for validation both in vitro and in vivo studies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; GO, KEGG and HALLMARK enrichment based on RNA-seq data showed that the differentially expressed genes (DEGs) were associated with autophagy like lysosome and macroautophagy. GSEA analysis revealed that PM&lt;sup&gt;2.5&lt;/sup&gt; was positively correlated with autophagy-related biological processes compared with control group. Venn diagrams identified IL24 was upregulated in our data as well as in these three datasets (GSE158954, GSE155616 and GSE182199) after PM&lt;sup&gt;2.5&lt;/sup&gt; exposure. Consistent with the analysis, activation of autophagy by PM&lt;sup&gt;2.5&lt;/sup&gt; was validated in vivo and in vitro. In PM&lt;sup&gt;2.5&lt;/sup&gt;-exposed mice, lung pathological changes were observed, including airway inflammation and mucus secretion. The mRNA and protein levels of the key gene, IL24, were significantly increased. Moreover, Bafilomycin A1, the inhibitor of autophagy, inhibited the autophagy and ameliorated lung injury induced by PM&lt;sup&gt;2.5&lt;/sup&gt;. Furthermore, downregulation of IL24 decreased autophagy activity. Meanwhile, IL24 was regulated by mTOR signaling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; In summary, we discovered a potential relationship between IL24 and autophagy during PM&lt;sup&gt;2.5&lt;/sup&gt; exposure. IL24 might be a novel potential biomarker or therapeutic target in PM&lt;sup&gt;2.5&lt;/sup&gt; caused lung dysfunction through regulation of autophagy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neutrophil extracellular traps-triggered impaired autophagic flux via METTL3 underlies sepsis-associated acute lung injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36030287/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36030287/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Neutrophil extracellular traps (NETs) assist pathogen clearance, while excessive NETs formation is associated with exacerbated inflammatory responses and tissue injury in acute lung injury (ALI)/acute respiratory distress syndrome (ARDS). Autophagy is generally considered to be a protective process, but autophagy dysfunction is harmful. Whether and how NETs affect autophagic flux during sepsis-induced ALI are currently unknown. Here, we confirmed that the level of NETs was increased in ARDS patients and mice models, which led to impairment of autophagic flux and deterioration of the disease. Mechanistically, NETs activated METTL3 mediated m&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;A methylation of Sirt1 mRNA in alveolar epithelial cells, resulting in abnormal autophagy. These findings provide new insights into how NETs contribute to the development of sepsis-associated ALI/ARDS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pyrogallol enhances therapeutic effect of human umbilical cord mesenchymal stem cells against LPS-mediated inflammation and lung injury via activation of Nrf2/HO-1 signaling</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36028178/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36028178/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main challenges in clinical applications of mesenchymal stem cells (MSCs) are attributed to their heterogeneity. It is believed that preconditioning of MSCs with active compounds may enhance the expression of potentially therapeutic molecules and thus achieve stable and effective therapeutic outcomes. In the present study, we investigated the mechanism by which pyrogallol increased the therapeutic efficacy of human umbilical cord mesenchymal stem cells (hUCMSCs) against LPS-induced acute lung injury (ALI). hUCMSCs with pyrogallol treatment increased expression of HO-1 at both mRNA and protein levels, accompanied by Kelch-Like ECH-Associated Protein 1 (Keap1) degradation, and upregulation of the Nrf2 protein levels as well as nuclear translocation of Nrf2. Moreover, the modulation of Keap1 and Nrf2 as well as HO-1 upregulation by pyrogallol was reversed by pretreatment with N-acetylcysteine (NAC) and a P38 kinase inhibitor (SB203580). Whereas, NAC pretreatment abrogated pyrogallol-mediated activation of P38 kinase, indicating that pyrogallol-derived ROS led to P38 kinase activation, thus promoting Nrf2/HO-1 signaling. Additionally, we found that the induction of p62 by the pyrogallol-mediated ROS/P38/Nrf2 axis interacted with Keap1 and resulted in autophagic degradation of Keap1, which created a positive feedback loop to further release of Nrf2. Furthermore, the increased expression of HO-1 in pyrogallol-pretreated hUCMSCs led to enhanced inhibitory effects on LPS-mediated TLR4/P-P65 signaling in BEAS-2B cells, resulting in increasing suppression of LPS-indued expression of a series of pro-inflammatory mediators. Compared to untreated hUCMSCs, Sprague-Dawley (SD) rats with pyrogallol-primed hUCMSCs transplantation showed enhanced improvements in LPS-mediated lung pathological alterations, the increased lung index (lung/body ratio), apoptosis of epithelial cells, the activation of TLR4/NF-κB signaling as well as the release of pro-inflammatory mediators. Together, these results suggested that hUCMSCs with pyrogallol pretreatment enhanced the therapeutic efficacy of hUCMSCs, which may provide a promising therapeutic strategy to maximize the therapeutic efficacy of hUCMSC-based therapy for treating LPS-associated ALI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Progress in preclinical studies of macrophage autophagy in the regulation of ALI/ARDS</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/36059534/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/36059534/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acute lung injury (ALI)/acute respiratory distress syndrome (ARDS) is a critical clinical syndrome with high morbidity and mortality that poses a major challenge in critical care medicine. The development of ALI/ARDS involves excessive inflammatory response, and macrophage autophagy plays an important role in regulating the inflammatory response in ALI/ARDS. In this paper, we review the effects of autophagy in regulating macrophage function, discuss the roles of macrophage autophagy in ALI/ARDS, and highlight drugs and other interventions that can modulate macrophage autophagy in ALI/ARDS to improve the understanding of the mechanism of macrophage autophagy in ALI/ARDS and provide new ideas and further research directions for the treatment of ALI/ARDS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>miR-141 exacerbates lung ischemia-reperfusion injury by targeting EGFR/β-catenin axis-mediated autophagy</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35972910/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35972910/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some microRNAs (miRNAs) play important roles in lung ischemia-reperfusion injury (LIRI) injury. Here, this study aimed to examine whether miR-141 was related to lung ischemia-reperfusion injury (IRI) via regulating autophagy and the epidermal growth factor receptor (EGFR), and to explore the underlying signal transduction pathways. To this end, we constructed the LIRI cell model and mouse models, separately. According to RT-qPCR and Western blotting (WB) analysis results, miR-141 up-regulation together with β-catenin and EGFR down-regulation within mouse pulmonary microvascular endothelial cells (PMVECs) or lung tissues was related to lung IRI. Besides, we conducted dual-luciferase reporter assay, which suggested the binding of EGFR to miR-141. In addition, we carried out TUNEL staining, HE staining, and flow cytometric analysis to assess the apoptosis of PMVECs and the injury to mouse lung tissues. Furthermore, we performed light-chain immunofluorescence assay to examine autophagosomes within PMVECs. According to our results, miR-141 suppressed β-catenin level through reducing EGFR level. Besides, the miR-141/EGFR/β-catenin axis enhanced autophagy to aggravate LIRI. To sum up, miR-141 suppresses EGFR expression to inhibit β-catenin level, which subsequently aggravates autophagy and complicates LIRI. The above results offer the candidate therapeutic target for the treatment of lung IRI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PD-L1 maintains neutrophil extracellular traps release by inhibiting neutrophil autophagy in endotoxin-induced lung injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36016930/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36016930/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Programmed death ligand 1 (PD-L1) is not only an important molecule in mediating tumor immune escape, but also regulates inflammation development. Here we showed that PD-L1 was upregulated on neutrophils in lipopolysaccharide (LPS)-induced acute respiratory distress syndrome (ARDS). Neutrophil specific knockout of PD-L1 reduced lung injury in ARDS model induced by intratracheal LPS injection. The level of NET release was reduced and autophagy is elevated by PD-L1 knockout in ARDS neutrophils both &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;in vitro&lt;/em&gt;. Inhibition of autophagy could reverse the inhibitory effect of PD-L1 knockout on NET release. PD-L1 interacted with p85 subunit of PI3K at the endoplasmic reticulum (ER) in neutrophils from ARDS patients, activating the PI3K/Akt/mTOR pathway. An extrinsic neutralizing antibody against PD-L1 showed a protective effect against ARDS. Together, PD-L1 maintains the release of NETs by regulating autophagy through the PI3K/Akt/mTOR pathway in ARDS. Anti-PD-L1 therapy may be a promising measure in treating ARDS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>YAP1 alleviates sepsis-induced acute lung injury via inhibiting ferritinophagy-mediated ferroptosis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35979359/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35979359/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ferroptosis is a phospholipid peroxidation-mediated and iron-dependent cell death form, involved in sepsis-induced organ injury and other lung diseases. Yes-associated protein 1 (YAP1), a key regulator of the Hippo signaling pathway, could target multiple ferroptosis regulators. Herein, this study aimed to explore the involvement of ferroptosis in the etiopathogenesis of sepsis-induced acute lung injury (ALI) and demonstrate that YAP1 could disrupt ferritinophagy and moderate sepsis-induced ALI. Cecal ligation and puncture (CLP) models were constructed in wild-type (WT) and pulmonary epithelium-conditional knockout (YAP1f/f) mice to induce ALI, while MLE-12 cells with or without YAP1 overexpression were stimulated by lipopolysaccharide (LPS) in vitro. In-vivo modes showed that YAP1 knockout aggravated CLP-induced ALI and also accelerated pulmonary ferroptosis, as presented by the downregulated expression of GPX4, FTH1, and SLC7A11, along with the upregulated expression of SFXN1 and NCOA4. Transcriptome research identified these key genes and ferroptosis pathways involved in sepsis-induced ALI. In-vitro modes consistently verified that YAP1 deficiency boosted the ferrous iron accumulation and mitochondrial dysfunction in response to LPS. Furthermore, the co-IP assay revealed that YAP1 overexpression could prevent the degradation of ferritin to a mass of Fe2+ (ferritinophagy) via disrupting the NCOA4-FTH1 interaction, which blocked the transport of cytoplasmic Fe2+ into the mitochondria via the mitochondrial membrane protein (SFXN1), further reducing the generation of mitochondrial ROS. Therefore, these findings revealed that YAP1 could inhibit ferroptosis in a ferritinophagy-mediated manner, thus alleviating sepsis-induced ALI, which may provide a new approach to the therapeutic orientation for sepsis-induced ALI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Class IIa histone deacetylase inhibition ameliorates acute kidney injury by suppressing renal tubular cell apoptosis and enhancing autophagy and proliferation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35935816/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35935816/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Expression and function of histone deacetylases (HDACs) vary with cell types and pathological conditions. Our recent studies showed that pharmacological targeting class IIa HDACs attenuated renal fibrosis, but the effect of class IIa HDAC inhibition on acute kidney injury (AKI) remains unknown. In this study, we found that four class IIa HDACs (4, 5, 7, 9) were highly expressed in the kidney of folic acid (FA) and ischemia/reperfusion (I/R)-induced AKI in mice. Administration of TMP269, a potent and selective class IIa HDAC inhibitor, improved renal function and reduced tubular cell injury and apoptosis, with concomitant suppression of HDAC4 and elevation of acetyl-histone H3. Mechanistical studies showed that TMP269 treatment inhibited FA and I/R-induced caspase-3 cleavage, Bax expression and p53 phosphorylation. Conversely, TMP269 administration preserved expression of E-cadherin, BMP7, Klotho and Bcl-2 in injured kidneys. Moreover, TMP269 was effective in promoting cellular autophagy as indicated by increased expression of Atg7, beclin-1, and LC3II, and promoted renal tubular cell proliferation as shown by increased number of proliferating cell nuclear antigen-positive cells and expression of cyclin E. Finally, blocking class IIa HDACs inhibited FA-and I/R-induced phosphorylation of extracellular signal-regulated kinases 1 and 2, and p38, two signaling pathways associated with the pathogenesis of AKI. Collectively, these results suggest that pharmacological inhibition of class IIa HDACs protects against AKI through ameliorating apoptosis, enhancing autophagy and promoting proliferation of renal tubular cells by targeting multiple signaling pathways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MgIG exerts therapeutic effects on crizotinib-induced hepatotoxicity by limiting ROS-mediated autophagy and pyroptosis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35855570/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35855570/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Crizotinib (CRIZO) has been widely employed to treat non-small-cell lung cancer. However, hepatic inflammatory injury is the major toxicity of CRIZO, which limits its clinical application, and the underlying mechanism of CRIZO-induced hepatotoxicity has not been fully explored. Herein, we used cell counting kit-8 assay and flow cytometry to detect CRIZO-induced cytotoxicity on human hepatocytes (HL-7702). CRIZO significantly reduced the survival rate of hepatocytes in a dose-dependent manner. Furthermore, the reactive oxygen species (ROS) assay kit showed that CRIZO treatment strongly increased the level of ROS. In addition, CRIZO treatment caused the appearance of balloon-like bubbles and autophagosomes in HL-7702 cells. Subsequently, Western blotting, quantitative real-time PCR and ELISA assays revealed that ROS-mediated pyroptosis and autophagy contributed to CRIZO-induced hepatic injury. Based on the role of ROS in CRIZO-induced hepatotoxicity, magnesium isoglycyrrhizinate (MgIG) was used as an intervention drug. MgIG activated the Nrf2/HO-1 signalling pathway and reduced ROS level. Additionally, MgIG suppressed hepatic inflammation by inhibiting NF-κB activity, thereby reducing CRIZO-induced hepatotoxicity. In conclusion, CRIZO promoted autophagy activation and pyroptosis via the accumulation of ROS in HL-7702 cells. MgIG exerts therapeutic effects on CRIZO-induced hepatotoxicity by decreasing the level of ROS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Autophagy promotes GSDME-mediated pyroptosis via intrinsic and extrinsic apoptotic pathways in cobalt chloride-induced hypoxia reoxygenation-acute kidney injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35863214/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35863214/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cobalt ions induced more serious damage in the reoxygenation stage in HRI.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CoCl&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; induced GSDME-mediated pyroptosis in the HRI-AKI model.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CoCl&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;-activated GSDME was cleaved via the intrinsic and extrinsic apoptotic pathways in HRI-AKI.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CoCl&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;-elevated autophagy promoted the induction of apoptosis and GSDME-mediated pyroptosis in HRI-AKI.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cobalt is a transition element that abundantly exists in the environment. Besides direct hypoxia stress, cobalt ions indirectly induce hypoxia-reoxygenation injury (HRI), the main cause of acute kidney injury (AKI), a life-threatening clinical syndrome characterized by the necrosis of the proximal tubular epithelial cells (PTECs) and inflammation. Pyroptosis, a type of inflammatory programmed cell death, might play an essential role in HRI-AKI. However, whether pyroptosis is involved in cobalt chloride (CoCl&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;)-induced HRI-AKI remains unknown. Autophagy is a cellular biological process maintaining cell homeostasis that is involved in cell damage in AKI, yet the underlying regulatory mechanism of autophagy on pyroptosis has not been fully understood. In this study, the in vitro and in vivo models of CoCl&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;-induced HRI-AKI were established with HK-2 cell line and C57BL/6J mouse. Pyroptosis-related markers were detected with western blotting and immunofluorescence assays, and results showed that gasdermin E (GSDME)-mediated pyroptosis was involved in the cell damage in HRI-AKI. Specific chemical inhibitors of caspase 3, caspase 8, and caspase 9 significantly inhibited GSDME-mediated pyroptosis, verifying that GSDME-mediated pyroptosis was induced via the activation of caspase 3/8/9. The western blotting and immunofluorescence assays were adopted to detect the accumulation of the autophagosomes, and results suggested that HRI increased the autophagic level. The effects of autophagy on apoptosis and pyroptosis were evaluated using lentivirus transfection assays to knock down autophagy-specific genes atg5 and fip200, and results demonstrated that autophagy induced GSDME-mediated pyroptosis via apoptotic pathways in HRI-AKI. Our results revealed the involvement of GSDME-mediated pyroptosis in CoCl&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;-induced HRI-AKI and promoted the understanding of the regulatory mechanism of GSDME cleavage. Our study might provide a potential therapeutic target for HRI-AKI, and will be helpful for the risk evaluation of cobalt exposure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A nanoparticle probe for the imaging of autophagic flux in live mice via magnetic resonance and near-infrared fluorescence</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35817962/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35817962/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Autophagy-the lysosomal degradation of cytoplasmic components via their sequestration into double-membraned autophagosomes-has not been detected non-invasively. Here we show that the flux of autophagosomes can be measured via magnetic resonance imaging or serial near-infrared fluorescence imaging of intravenously injected iron oxide nanoparticles decorated with cathepsin-cleavable arginine-rich peptides functionalized with the near-infrared fluorochrome Cy5.5 (the peptides facilitate the uptake of the nanoparticles by early autophagosomes, and are then cleaved by cathepsins in lysosomes). In the heart tissue of live mice, the nanoparticles enabled quantitative measurements of changes in autophagic flux, upregulated genetically, by ischaemia-reperfusion injury or via starvation, or inhibited via the administration of a chemotherapeutic or the antibiotic bafilomycin. In mice receiving doxorubicin, pre-starvation improved cardiac function and overall survival, suggesting that bursts of increased autophagic flux may have cardioprotective effects during chemotherapy. Autophagy-detecting nanoparticle probes may facilitate the further understanding of the roles of autophagy in disease.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The encephalomyocarditis virus Leader promotes the release of virions inside extracellular vesicles via the induction of secretory autophagy</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35750662/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35750662/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Naked viruses can escape host cells before the induction of lysis via release in extracellular vesicles (EVs). These nanosized EVs cloak the secreted virus particles in a host-derived membrane, which alters virus-host interactions that affect infection efficiency and antiviral immunity. Currently, little is known about the viral and host factors regulating this form of virus release. Here, we assessed the role of the encephalomyocarditis virus (EMCV) Leader protein, a &amp;lsquo;viral security protein&amp;rsquo; that subverts the host antiviral response. EV release upon infection with wildtype virus or a Leader-deficient mutant was characterized at the single particle level using high-resolution flow cytometry. Inactivation of the Leader abolished EV induction during infection and strongly reduced EV-enclosed virus release. We demonstrate that the Leader promotes the release of virions within EVs by stimulating a secretory arm of autophagy. This newly discovered role of the EMCV Leader adds to the variety of mechanisms via which this protein affects virus-host interactions. Moreover, these data provide first evidence for a crucial role of a non-structural viral protein in the non-lytic release of picornaviruses via packaging in EVs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CircCEMIP promotes anoikis-resistance by enhancing protective autophagy in prostate cancer cells</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35655258/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35655258/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Circular RNAs (circRNAs) are essential participants in the development and progression of various malignant tumors. Previous studies have shown that cell migration-inducing protein (CEMIP) accelerates prostate cancer (PCa) anoikis resistance (AR) by activating autophagy. This study focused on the effect of circCEMIP on PCa metastasis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; This study gradually revealed the role of circ_0004585 in PCa anoikis resistance via quantitative real-time PCR (qRT-PCR) analysis, western blotting, pull-down assays, and dual fluorescence reporter assays.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; Functionally, circ_0004585 promoted PCa cells invasion and metastasis both in vitro and in vivo. Mechanistically, circ_0004585 directly interacted with miR-1248 to upregulate target gene expression. Furthermore, target prediction and dual-luciferase reporter assays identified transmembrane 9 superfamily member 4 (TM9SF4) as a potential miR-1248 target. Pathway analysis revealed that TM9SF4 activated autophagy to promote PCa cells anoikis resistance via mTOR phosphorylation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; These results demonstrated that circ_0004585 played an oncogenic role during PCa invasion and metastasis by targeting the miR-1248/TM9SF4 axis while providing new insight into therapeutic strategy development for metastatic PCa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Activated Drp1 regulates p62-mediated autophagic flux and aggravates inflammation in cerebral ischemia-reperfusion via the ROS-RIP1/RIP3-exosome axis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35624495/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35624495/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Cerebral ischemia-reperfusion injury (CIRI) refers to a secondary brain injury that can occur when the blood supply to the ischemic brain tissue is restored. However, the mechanism underlying such injury remains elusive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; The 150 male C57 mice underwent middle cerebral artery occlusion (MCAO) for 1 h and reperfusion for 24 h, Among them, 50 MCAO mice were further treated with Mitochondrial division inhibitor 1 (Mdivi-1) and 50 MCAO mice were further treated with N-acetylcysteine (NAC). SH-SY5Y cells were cultured in a low-glucose culture medium for 4 h under hypoxic conditions and then transferred to normal conditions for 12 h. Then, cerebral blood flow, mitochondrial structure, mitochondrial DNA (mtDNA) copy number, intracellular and mitochondrial reactive oxygen species (ROS), autophagic flux, aggresome and exosome expression profiles, cardiac tissue structure, mitochondrial length and cristae density, mtDNA and ROS content, as well as the expression of Drp1-Ser616/Drp1, RIP1/RIP3, LC3 II/LC3 I, TNF-α, IL-1β, etc., were detected under normal or Drp1 interference conditions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; The mtDNA content, ROS levels, and Drp1-Ser616/Drp1 were elevated by 2.2, 1.7 and 2.7 times after CIRI (&lt;em&gt;P&lt;/em&gt; &amp;lt; 0.05). However, the high cytoplasmic LC3 II/I ratio and increased aggregation of p62 could be reversed by 44% and 88% by Drp1 short hairpin RNA (shRNA) (&lt;em&gt;P&lt;/em&gt; &amp;lt; 0.05). The low fluorescence intensity of autophagic flux and the increased phosphorylation of RIP3 induced by CIRI could be attenuated by ROS scavenger, NAC (&lt;em&gt;P&lt;/em&gt; &amp;lt; 0.05). RIP1/RIP3 inhibitor Necrostatin-1 (Nec-1) restored 75% to a low LC3 II/LC3 I ratio and enhanced 2 times to a high RFP-LC3 after Drp1 activation (&lt;em&gt;P&lt;/em&gt; &amp;lt; 0.05). In addition, although CIRI-induced ROS production caused no considerable accumulation of autophagosomes (&lt;em&gt;P&lt;/em&gt; &amp;gt; 0.05), it increased the packaging and extracellular secretion of exosomes containing p62 by 4 - 5 times, which could be decreased by Mdivi-1, Drp1 shRNA, and Nec-1 (&lt;em&gt;P&lt;/em&gt; &amp;lt; 0.05). Furthermore, TNF-α and IL-1β increased in CIRI-derived exosomes could increase RIP3 phosphorylation in normal or oxygen-glucose deprivation/reoxygenation (OGD/R) conditions (&lt;em&gt;P&lt;/em&gt; &amp;lt; 0.05).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; CIRI activated Drp1 and accelerated the p62-mediated formation of autophagosomes while inhibiting the transition of autophagosomes to autolysosomes via the RIP1/RIP3 pathway activation. Undegraded autophagosomes were secreted extracellularly in the form of exosomes, leading to inflammatory cascades that further damaged mitochondria, resulting in excessive ROS generation and the blockage of autophagosome degradation, triggering a vicious cycle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dynamic O-GlcNAcylation coordinates ferritinophagy and mitophagy to activate ferroptosis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35504898/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35504898/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ferroptosis is a regulated iron-dependent cell death characterized by the accumulation of lipid peroxidation. A myriad of facets linking amino acid, lipid, redox, and iron metabolisms were found to drive or to suppress the execution of ferroptosis. However, how the cells decipher the diverse pro-ferroptotic stress to activate ferroptosis remains elusive. Here, we report that protein O-GlcNAcylation, the primary nutrient sensor of glucose flux, orchestrates both ferritinophagy and mitophagy for ferroptosis. Following the treatment of ferroptosis stimuli such as RSL3, a commonly used ferroptosis inducer, there exists a biphasic change of protein O-GlcNAcylation to modulate ferroptosis. Pharmacological or genetic inhibition of O-GlcNAcylation promoted ferritinophagy, resulting in the accumulation of labile iron towards mitochondria. Inhibition of O-GlcNAcylation resulted in mitochondria fragmentation and enhanced mitophagy, providing an additional source of labile iron and rendering the cell more sensitive to ferroptosis. Mechanistically, we found that de-O-GlcNAcylation of the ferritin heavy chain at S179 promoted its interaction with NCOA4, the ferritinophagy receptor, thereby accumulating labile iron for ferroptosis. Our findings reveal a previously uncharacterized link of dynamic O-GlcNAcylation with iron metabolism and decision-making for ferroptosis, thus offering potential therapeutic intervention for fighting disease.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CCT2 is an aggrephagy receptor for clearance of solid protein aggregates</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35366418/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35366418/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Protein aggregation is a hallmark of multiple human pathologies. Autophagy selectively degrades protein aggregates via aggrephagy. How selectivity is achieved has been elusive. Here, we identify the chaperonin subunit CCT2 as an autophagy receptor regulating the clearance of aggregation-prone proteins in the cell and the mouse brain. CCT2 associates with aggregation-prone proteins independent of cargo ubiquitination and interacts with autophagosome marker ATG8s through a non-classical VLIR motif. In addition, CCT2 regulates aggrephagy independently of the ubiquitin-binding receptors (P62, NBR1, and TAX1BP1) or chaperone-mediated autophagy. Unlike P62, NBR1, and TAX1BP1, which facilitate the clearance of protein condensates with liquidity, CCT2 specifically promotes the autophagic degradation of protein aggregates with little liquidity (solid aggregates). Furthermore, aggregation-prone protein accumulation induces the functional switch of CCT2 from a chaperone subunit to an autophagy receptor by promoting CCT2 monomer formation, which exposes the VLIR to ATG8s interaction and, therefore, enables the autophagic function.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Valosin Containing Protein (VCP): A Multistep Regulator of Autophagy</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/35216053/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/35216053/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Valosin containing protein (VCP) has emerged as a central protein in the regulation of the protein quality control (PQC) system. VCP mutations are causative of multisystem proteinopathies, which include neurodegenerative diseases (NDs), and share various signs of altered proteostasis, mainly associated with autophagy malfunctioning. Autophagy is a complex multistep degradative system essential for the maintenance of cell viability, especially in post-mitotic cells as neurons and differentiated skeletal muscle cells. Interestingly, many studies concerning NDs have focused on autophagy impairment as a pathological mechanism or autophagy activity boosting to rescue the pathological phenotype. The role of VCP in autophagy has been widely debated, but recent findings have defined new mechanisms associated with VCP activity in the regulation of autophagy, showing that VCP is involved in different steps of this pathway. Here we will discuss the multiple activity of VCP in the autophagic pathway underlying its leading role either in physiological or pathological conditions. A better understanding of VCP complexes and mechanisms in regulating autophagy could define the altered mechanisms by which VCP directly or indirectly causes or modulates different human diseases and revealing possible new therapeutic approaches for NDs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crosstalk between autophagy inhibitors and endosome-related secretory pathways: a challenge for autophagy-based treatment of solid cancers</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/34706732/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/34706732/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Autophagy is best known for its role in organelle and protein turnover, cell quality control, and metabolism. The autophagic machinery has, however, also adapted to enable protein trafficking and unconventional secretory pathways so that organelles (such as autophagosomes and multivesicular bodies) delivering cargo to lysosomes for degradation can change their mission from fusion with lysosomes to fusion with the plasma membrane, followed by secretion of the cargo from the cell. Some factors with key signalling functions do not enter the conventional secretory pathway but can be secreted in an autophagy-mediated manner.Positive clinical results of some autophagy inhibitors are encouraging. Nevertheless, it is becoming clear that autophagy inhibition, even within the same cancer type, can affect cancer progression differently. Even next-generation inhibitors of autophagy can have significant non-specific effects, such as impacts on endosome-related secretory pathways and secretion of extracellular vesicles (EVs). Many studies suggest that cancer cells release higher amounts of EVs compared to non-malignant cells, which makes the effect of autophagy inhibitors on EVs secretion highly important and attractive for anticancer therapy. In this review article, we discuss how different inhibitors of autophagy may influence the secretion of EVs and summarize the non-specific effects of autophagy inhibitors with a focus on endosome-related secretory pathways. Modulation of autophagy significantly impacts not only the quantity of EVs but also their content, which can have a deep impact on the resulting pro-tumourigenic or anticancer effect of autophagy inhibitors used in the antineoplastic treatment of solid cancers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Machinery, regulation and pathophysiological implications of autophagosome maturation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/34302147/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/34302147/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Autophagy is a versatile degradation system for maintaining cellular homeostasis whereby cytosolic materials are sequestered in a double-membrane autophagosome and subsequently delivered to lysosomes, where they are broken down. In multicellular organisms, newly formed autophagosomes undergo a process called &amp;lsquo;maturation&amp;rsquo;, in which they fuse with vesicles originating from endolysosomal compartments, including early/late endosomes and lysosomes, to form amphisomes, which eventually become degradative autolysosomes. This fusion process requires the concerted actions of multiple regulators of membrane dynamics, including SNAREs, tethering proteins and RAB GTPases, and also transport of autophagosomes and late endosomes/lysosomes towards each other. Multiple mechanisms modulate autophagosome maturation, including post-translational modification of key components, spatial distribution of phosphoinositide lipid species on membranes, RAB protein dynamics, and biogenesis and function of lysosomes. Nutrient status and various stresses integrate into the autophagosome maturation machinery to coordinate the progression of autophagic flux. Impaired autophagosome maturation is linked to the pathogenesis of various human diseases, including neurodegenerative disorders, cancer and myopathies. Furthermore, invading pathogens exploit various strategies to block autophagosome maturation, thus evading destruction and even subverting autophagic vacuoles (autophagosomes, amphisomes and autolysosomes) for survival, growth and/or release. Here, we discuss the recent progress in our understanding of the machinery and regulation of autophagosome maturation, the relevance of these mechanisms to human pathophysiology and how they are harnessed by pathogens for their benefit. We also provide perspectives on targeting autophagosome maturation therapeutically.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IL-6 regulates autophagy and chemotherapy resistance by promoting BECN1 phosphorylation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34131122/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34131122/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Extracellular cytokines are enriched in the tumor microenvironment and regulate various important properties of cancers, including autophagy. However, the precise molecular mechanisms underlying the link between autophagy and extracellular cytokines remain to be elucidated. In the present study, we demonstrate that IL-6 activates autophagy through the IL-6/JAK2/BECN1 pathway and promotes chemotherapy resistance in colorectal cancer (CRC). Mechanistically, IL-6 triggers the interaction between JAK2 and BECN1, where JAK2 phosphorylates BECN1 at Y333. We demonstrate that BECN1 Y333 phosphorylation is crucial for BECN1 activation and IL-6-induced autophagy by regulating PI3KC3 complex formation. Furthermore, we investigate BECN1 Y333 phosphorylation as a predictive marker for poor CRC prognosis and chemotherapy resistance. Combination treatment with autophagy inhibitors or pharmacological agents targeting the IL-6/JAK2/BECN1 signaling pathway may represent a potential strategy for CRC cancer therapy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Polyethylenimine-Modified Mesoporous Silica Nanoparticles Induce a Survival Mechanism in Vascular Endothelial Cells via Microvesicle-Mediated Autophagosome Release</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34080832/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34080832/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Surface-modified mesoporous silica nanoparticles (MSNs) have attracted more and more attention as promising materials for biomolecule delivery. However, the lack of detailed evaluation relevant to the potential cytotoxicity of these MSNs is still a major obstacle for their applications. Unlike the bare MSNs and amino- or liposome-modified MSNs, we found that polyethylenimine-modified MSNs (MSNs-PEI) had no obvious toxicity to human umbilical vein endothelial cells (HUVECs) at the concentrations up to 100 μg/mL. However, MSNs-PEI induced autophagosomes accumulation by blocking their fusion with lysosomes, an essential mechanism for the cytotoxicity of many nanoparticles (NPs). Thus, we predicted that an alternative pathway for autophagosome clearance exists in HUVECs to relieve autophagic stress induced by MSNs-PEI. We found that MSNs-PEI prevented STX17 loading onto autophagosomes instead of influencing lysosomal pH or proteolytic activity. MSNs-PEI induced the structural alternation of the cytoskeleton but did not cause endoplasmic reticulum stress. The accumulated autophagosomes were released to the extracellular space via microvesicles (MVs) when the autophagic degradation was blocked by MSNs-PEI. More importantly, blockade of either autophagosome formation or release caused the accumulation of damaged mitochondria and excessive ROS production in the MSNs-PEI-treated HUVECs, which in turn led to cell death. Thus, we propose here that the MV-mediated autophagosome release, a compensation mechanism, allows the vascular endothelial cell survival when the degradation of autophagosomes is blocked by MSNs-PEI. Accordingly, promoting the release of accumulated autophagosomes may be a protective strategy against the endothelial toxicity of NPs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Atlastin 2/3 regulate ER targeting of the ULK1 complex to initiate autophagy</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33988678/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33988678/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dynamic targeting of the ULK1 complex to the ER is crucial for initiating autophagosome formation and for subsequent formation of ER-isolation membrane (IM; autophagosomal precursor) contact during IM expansion. Little is known about how the ULK1 complex, which comprises FIP200, ULK1, ATG13, and ATG101 and does not exist as a constitutively coassembled complex, is recruited and stabilized on the ER. Here, we demonstrate that the ER-localized transmembrane proteins Atlastin 2 and 3 (ATL2/3) contribute to recruitment and stabilization of ULK1 and ATG101 at the FIP200-ATG13-specified autophagosome formation sites on the ER. In ATL2/3 KO cells, formation of FIP200 and ATG13 puncta is unaffected, while targeting of ULK1 and ATG101 is severely impaired. Consequently, IM initiation is compromised and slowed. ATL2/3 directly interact with ULK1 and ATG13 and facilitate the ATG13-mediated recruitment/stabilization of ULK1 and ATG101. ATL2/3 also participate in forming ER-IM tethering complexes. Our study provides insights into the dynamic assembly of the ULK1 complex on the ER for autophagosome formation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DDRGK1, a crucial player of ufmylation system, is indispensable for autophagic degradation by regulating lysosomal function</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33879777/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33879777/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DDRGK domain-containing protein 1 (DDRGK1) is an important component of the newly discovered ufmylation system and its absence has been reported to induce extensive endoplasmic reticulum (ER) stress. Recently, emerging evidence indicates that the ufmylation system is correlated with autophagy, although the exact mechanism remains largely unknown. To explore the regulation mechanism of DDRGK1 on autophagy, in this study, we established an immortalized mouse embryonic fibroblast (MEF) cell lines harvested from the DDRGK1F/F:ROSA26-CreERT2 mice, in which DDRGK1 depletion can be induced by 4-hydroxytamoxifen (4-OHT) treatment. Here, we show that DDRGK1 deficiency in MEFs has a dual effect on autophagy, which leads to a significant accumulation of autophagosomes. On one hand, it promotes autophagy induction by impairing mTOR signaling; on the other hand, it blocks autophagy degradation by inhibiting autophagosome-lysosome fusion. This dual effect of DDRGK1 depletion on autophagy ultimately aggravates apoptosis in MEFs. Further studies reveal that DDRGK1 loss is correlated with suppressed lysosomal function, including impaired Cathepsin D (CTSD) expression, aberrant lysosomal pH, and v-ATPase accumulation, which might be a potential trigger for impairment in autophagy process. Hence, this study confirms a crucial role of DDRGK1 as an autophagy regulator by controlling lysosomal function. It may provide a theoretical basis for the treatment strategies of various physiological diseases caused by DDRGK1 deficiency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adaptive immunity at the crossroads of autophagy and metabolism</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/33785844/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/33785844/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The function of lymphocytes is dependent on their plasticity, particularly their adaptation to energy availability and environmental stress, and their protein synthesis machinery. Lymphocytes are constantly under metabolic stress, and macroautophagy/autophagy is the primary metabolic pathway that helps cells overcome stressors. The intrinsic role of autophagy in regulating the metabolism of adaptive immune cells has recently gained increasing attention. In this review, we summarize and discuss the versatile roles of autophagy in regulating cellular metabolism and the implications of autophagy for immune cell function and fate, especially for T and B lymphocytes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SRSF1 inhibits autophagy through regulating Bcl-x splicing and interacting with PIK3C3 in lung cancer</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33664238/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33664238/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alternative splicing is a critical process to generate protein diversity. However, whether and how alternative splicing regulates autophagy remains largely elusive. Here we systematically identify the splicing factor SRSF1 as an autophagy suppressor. Specifically, SRSF1 inhibits autophagosome formation by reducing the accumulation of LC3-II and numbers of autophagosomes in different cell lines. Mechanistically, SRSF1 promotes the splicing of the long isoform of Bcl-x that interacts with Beclin1, thereby dissociating the Beclin1-PIK3C3 complex. In addition, SRSF1 also directly interacts with PIK3C3 to disrupt the interaction between Beclin1 and PIK3C3. Consequently, the decrease of SRSF1 stabilizes the Beclin1 and PIK3C3 complex and activates autophagy. Interestingly, SRSF1 can be degraded by starvation- and oxidative stresses-induced autophagy through interacting with LC3-II, whereas reduced SRSF1 further promotes autophagy. This positive feedback is critical to inhibiting Gefitinib-resistant cancer cell progression both in vitro and in vivo. Consistently, the expression level of SRSF1 is inversely correlated to LC3 level in clinical cancer samples. Our study not only provides mechanistic insights of alternative splicing in autophagy regulation but also discovers a new regulatory role of SRSF1 in tumorigenesis, thereby offering a novel avenue for potential cancer therapeutics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Identification and Validation of Autophagy-Related Genes in Chronic Obstructive Pulmonary Disease</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33469280/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33469280/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Purpose:&lt;/em&gt; Autophagy plays essential roles in the development of COPD. We aim to identify and validate the potential autophagy-related genes of COPD through bioinformatics analysis and experiment validation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; The mRNA expression profile dataset GSE38974 was obtained from GEO database. The potential differentially expressed autophagy-related genes of COPD were screened by R software. Then, protein–protein interactions (PPI), correlation analysis, gene-ontology (GO) enrichment analysis and Kyoto Encyclopedia of Genes and Genomes (KEGG) pathway enrichment analysis were applied for the differentially expressed autophagy-related genes. Finally, RNA expression of top five differentially expressed autophagy-related genes was validated in blood samples from COPD patients and healthy controls by qRT-PCR.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; A total of 40 differentially expressed autophagy-related genes (14 up-regulated genes and 26 down-regulated genes) were identified between 23 COPD patients and 9 healthy controls. The PPI results demonstrated that these autophagy-related genes interacted with each other. The GO and KEGG enrichment analysis of differentially expressed autophagy-related genes indicated several enriched terms related to autophagy and mitophagy. The results of qRT-PCR showed that the expression levels of &lt;em&gt;HIF1A&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;CDKN1A&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;BAG3&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;ERBB2&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;ATG16L1&lt;/em&gt; in COPD patients and healthy controls were consistent with the bioinformatics analysis results from mRNA microarray.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/em&gt; We identified 40 potential autophagy-related genes of COPD through bioinformatics analysis. &lt;em&gt;HIF1A&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;CDKN1A&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;BAG3&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;ERBB2&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;ATG16L1&lt;/em&gt; may affect the development of COPD by regulating autophagy. These results may expand our understanding of COPD and might be useful in the treatment of COPD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>USP19 suppresses inflammation and promotes M2-like macrophage polarization by manipulating NLRP3 function via autophagy</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33097834/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33097834/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Macrophage polarization to proinflammatory M1-like or anti-inflammatory M2-like cells is critical to mount a host defense or repair tissue. The exact molecular mechanisms controlling this process are still elusive. Here, we report that ubiquitin-specific protease 19 (USP19) acts as an anti-inflammatory switch that inhibits inflammatory responses and promotes M2-like macrophage polarization. USP19 inhibited NLRP3 inflammasome activation by increasing autophagy flux and decreasing the generation of mitochondrial reactive oxygen species. In addition, USP19 inhibited the proteasomal degradation of inflammasome-independent NLRP3 by cleaving its polyubiquitin chains. USP19-stabilized NLRP3 promoted M2-like macrophage polarization by direct association with interferon regulatory factor 4, thereby preventing its p62-mediated selective autophagic degradation. Consistent with these observations, compared to wild-type mice, Usp19-/- mice had decreased M2-like macrophage polarization and increased interleukin-1β secretion, in response to alum and chitin injections. Thus, we have uncovered an unexpected mechanism by which USP19 switches the proinflammatory function of NLRP3 into an anti-inflammatory function, and suggest that USP19 is a potential therapeutic target for inflammatory interventions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TSPAN1 promotes autophagy flux and mediates cooperation between WNT-CTNNB1 signaling and autophagy via the MIR454-FAM83A-TSPAN1 axis in pancreatic cancer</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32972302/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32972302/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pancreatic cancer is one of the most aggressive tumors associated with a poor clinical prognosis, weakly effective therapeutic options. Therefore, there is a strong impetus to discover new therapeutic targets in pancreatic cancer. In the present study, we first demonstrated that TSPAN1 is upregulated in pancreatic cancer and that TSPAN1 depletion decreases pancreatic cancer cell proliferation in vitro and in vivo. TSPAN1 expression was correlated with poor overall survival of pancreatic cancer patients. Moreover, we demonstrated that TSPAN1 is a novel positive regulator of macroautophagy/autophagy characterized by decreased LC3-II and SQSTM1/p62 expressions, inhibited puncta formation of GFP-LC3 and autophagic vacuoles. We also demonstrated that tspan1 mutation impaired autophagy in the zebrafish model. Furthermore, we showed that TSPAN1 promoted autophagy maturation via direct binding to LC3 by two conserved LIR motifs. Mutations in the LIR motifs of TSPAN1 resulted in a loss of the ability to induce autophagy and promote pancreatic cancer proliferation. Second, we discovered two conservative TCF/LEF binding elements present in the promoter region of the TSPAN1 gene, which was further verified through luciferase activity and ChIP assays. Furthermore, TSPAN1 was upregulated by FAM83A through the canonical WNT-CTNNB1 signaling pathway. We further demonstrated that both TSPAN1 and FAM83A are both direct targets of MIR454 (microRNA 454). Additionally, we revealed the role of MIR454-FAM83A-TSPAN1 in the proliferation of pancreatic cancer cells in vitro and in vivo. Our findings suggest that components of the MIR454-FAM83A-TSPAN1 axis may be valuable prognosis markers or therapeutic targets for pancreatic cancer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Decoding three distinct states of the Syntaxin17 SNARE motif in mediating autophagosome-lysosome fusion</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32817423/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32817423/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Syntaxin17, a key autophagosomal N-ethylmaleimide-sensitive factor attachment protein receptor (SNARE) protein, can associate with ATG8 family proteins SNAP29 and VAMP8 to facilitate the membrane fusion process between the double-membraned autophagosome and single-membraned lysosome in mammalian macroautophagy. However, the inherent properties of Syntaxin17 and the mechanistic basis underlying the interactions of Syntaxin17 with its binding proteins remain largely unknown. Here, using biochemical, NMR, and structural approaches, we systemically characterized Syntaxin17 as well as its interactions with ATG8 family proteins, SNAP29 and VAMP8. We discovered that Syntaxin17 alone adopts an autoinhibited conformation mediated by a direct interaction between its Habc domain and the Qa-SNARE motif. In addition, we revealed that the Qa-SNARE region of Syntaxin17 contains one LC3-interacting region (LIR) motif, which preferentially binds to GABARAP subfamily members. Importantly, the GABARAP binding of Syntaxin17 can release its autoinhibited state. The determined crystal structure of the Syntaxin17 LIR-GABARAP complex not only provides mechanistic insights into the interaction between Syntaxin17 and GABARAP but also reveals an unconventional LIR motif with a C-terminally extended 310 helix for selectively binding to ATG8 family proteins. Finally, we also elucidated structural arrangements of the autophagic Syntaxin17-SNAP29-VAMP8 SNARE core complex, and uncovered its conserved biochemical and structural characteristics common to all other SNAREs. In all, our findings reveal three distinct states of Syntaxin17, and provide mechanistic insights into the Syntaxin17-mediated autophagosome-lysosome fusion process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Autophagy regulates fatty acid availability for oxidative phosphorylation through mitochondria-endoplasmic reticulum contact sites</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32792483/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32792483/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Autophagy has been associated with oncogenesis with one of its emerging key functions being its contribution to the metabolism of tumors. Therefore, deciphering the mechanisms of how autophagy supports tumor cell metabolism is essential. Here, we demonstrate that the inhibition of autophagy induces an accumulation of lipid droplets (LD) due to a decrease in fatty acid β-oxidation, that leads to a reduction of oxidative phosphorylation (OxPHOS) in acute myeloid leukemia (AML), but not in normal cells. Thus, the autophagic process participates in lipid catabolism that supports OxPHOS in AML cells. Interestingly, the inhibition of OxPHOS leads to LD accumulation with the concomitant inhibition of autophagy. Mechanistically, we show that the disruption of mitochondria-endoplasmic reticulum (ER) contact sites (MERCs) phenocopies OxPHOS inhibition. Altogether, our data establish that mitochondria, through the regulation of MERCs, controls autophagy that, in turn finely tunes lipid degradation to fuel OxPHOS supporting proliferation and growth in leukemia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A novel selective autophagy receptor, CCDC50, delivers K63 polyubiquitination-activated RIG-I/MDA5 for degradation during viral infection</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32612200/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32612200/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Autophagy is a conserved process that delivers cytosolic substances to the lysosome for degradation, but its direct role in the regulation of antiviral innate immunity remains poorly understood. Here, through high-throughput screening, we discovered that CCDC50 functions as a previously unknown autophagy receptor that negatively regulates the type I interferon (IFN) signaling pathway initiated by RIG-I-like receptors (RLRs), the sensors for RNA viruses. The expression of CCDC50 is enhanced by viral infection, and CCDC50 specifically recognizes K63-polyubiquitinated RLRs, thus delivering the activated RIG-I/MDA5 for autophagic degradation. The association of CCDC50 with phagophore membrane protein LC3 is confirmed by crystal structure analysis. In contrast to other known autophagic cargo receptors that associate with either the LIR-docking site (LDS) or the UIM-docking site (UDS) of LC3, CCDC50 can bind to both LDS and UDS, representing a new type of cargo receptor. In mouse models with RNA virus infection, CCDC50 deficiency reduces the autophagic degradation of RIG-I/MDA5 and promotes type I IFN responses, resulting in enhanced viral resistance and improved survival rates. These results reveal a new link between autophagy and antiviral innate immune responses and provide additional insights into the regulatory mechanisms of RLR-mediated antiviral signaling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Decreased Hepatocyte Autophagy Leads to Synergistic IL-1β and TNF Mouse Liver Injury and Inflammation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32108953/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32108953/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background and aims:&lt;/em&gt; The proinflammatory cytokine IL-1β has been implicated in the pathophysiology of nonalcoholic and alcoholic steatohepatitis. How IL-1β promotes liver injury in these diseases is unclear, as no IL-1β receptor-linked death pathway has been identified. Autophagy functions in hepatocyte resistance to injury and death, and findings of decreased hepatic autophagy in many liver diseases suggest a role for impaired autophagy in disease pathogenesis. Recent findings that autophagy blocks mouse liver injury from lipopolysaccharide led to an examination of autophagy&amp;rsquo;s function in hepatotoxicity from proinflammatory cytokines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Approach and results:&lt;/em&gt; AML12 cells with decreased autophagy from a lentiviral autophagy-related 5 (Atg5) knockdown were resistant to toxicity from TNF, but sensitized to death from IL-1β, which was markedly amplified by TNF co-treatment. IL-1β/TNF death was necrosis by trypan blue and propidium iodide positivity, absence of mitochondrial death pathway and caspase activation, and failure of a caspase inhibitor or necrostatin-1s to prevent death. IL-1β/TNF depleted autophagy-deficient cells of ATP, and ATP depletion and cell death were prevented by supplementation with the energy substrate pyruvate or oleate. Pharmacological inhibitors and genetic knockdown studies demonstrated that IL-1β/TNF-induced necrosis resulted from lysosomal permeabilization and release of cathepsins B and L in autophagy-deficient cells. Mice with a tamoxifen-inducible, hepatocyte-specific Atg5 knockout were similarly sensitized to cathepsin-dependent hepatocellular injury and death from IL-1β/TNF in combination, but neither IL-1β nor TNF alone. Knockout mice had increased hepatic inflammation, and IL-1β/TNF-treated, autophagy-deficient AML12 cells secreted exosomes with proinflammatory damage-associated molecular patterns.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; The findings delineate mechanisms by which decreased hepatocyte autophagy promotes IL-1β/TNF-induced necrosis from impaired energy homeostasis and lysosomal permeabilization and inflammation through the secretion of exosomal damage-associated molecular patterns.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Autophagy promotes immune evasion of pancreatic cancer by degrading MHC-I</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32376951/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32376951/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Immune evasion is a major obstacle for cancer treatment. Common mechanisms of evasion include impaired antigen presentation caused by mutations or loss of heterozygosity of the major histocompatibility complex class I (MHC-I), which has been implicated in resistance to immune checkpoint blockade (ICB) therapy. However, in pancreatic ductal adenocarcinoma (PDAC), which is resistant to most therapies including ICB, mutations that cause loss of MHC-I are rarely found despite the frequent downregulation of MHC-I expression. Here we show that, in PDAC, MHC-I molecules are selectively targeted for lysosomal degradation by an autophagy-dependent mechanism that involves the autophagy cargo receptor NBR1. PDAC cells display reduced expression of MHC-I at the cell surface and instead demonstrate predominant localization within autophagosomes and lysosomes. Notably, inhibition of autophagy restores surface levels of MHC-I and leads to improved antigen presentation, enhanced anti-tumour T cell responses and reduced tumour growth in syngeneic host mice. Accordingly, the anti-tumour effects of autophagy inhibition are reversed by depleting CD8&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T cells or reducing surface expression of MHC-I. Inhibition of autophagy, either genetically or pharmacologically with chloroquine, synergizes with dual ICB therapy (anti-PD1 and anti-CTLA4 antibodies), and leads to an enhanced anti-tumour immune response. Our findings demonstrate a role for enhanced autophagy or lysosome function in immune evasion by selective targeting of MHC-I molecules for degradation, and provide a rationale for the combination of autophagy inhibition and dual ICB therapy as a therapeutic strategy against PDAC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mitochondrial DNA stress triggers autophagy-dependent ferroptotic death</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32186434/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32186434/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pancreatic cancer tends to be highly resistant to current therapy and remains one of the great challenges in biomedicine with very low 5-year survival rates. Here, we report that zalcitabine, an antiviral drug for human immunodeficiency virus infection, can suppress the growth of primary and immortalized human pancreatic cancer cells through the induction of ferroptosis, an iron-dependent form of regulated cell death. Mechanically, this effect relies on zalcitabine-induced mitochondrial DNA stress, which activates the STING1/TMEM173-mediated DNA sensing pathway, leading to macroautophagy/autophagy-dependent ferroptotic cell death via lipid peroxidation, but not a type I interferon response. Consequently, the genetic and pharmacological inactivation of the autophagy-dependent ferroptosis pathway diminishes the anticancer effects of zalcitabine in cell culture and animal models. Together, these findings not only provide a new approach for pancreatic cancer therapy but also increase our understanding of the interplay between autophagy and DNA damage response in shaping cell death.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Genome-wide ER-phagy Screen Highlights Key Roles of Mitochondrial Metabolism and ER-Resident UFMylation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32160526/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32160526/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Selective autophagy of organelles is critical for cellular differentiation, homeostasis, and organismal health. Autophagy of the ER (ER-phagy) is implicated in human neuropathy but is poorly understood beyond a few autophagosomal receptors and remodelers. By using an ER-phagy reporter and genome-wide CRISPRi screening, we identified 200 high-confidence human ER-phagy factors. Two pathways were unexpectedly required for ER-phagy. First, reduced mitochondrial metabolism represses ER-phagy, which is opposite of general autophagy and is independent of AMPK. Second, ER-localized UFMylation is required for ER-phagy to repress the unfolded protein response via IRE1α. The UFL1 ligase is brought to the ER surface by DDRGK1 to UFMylate RPN1 and RPL26 and preferentially targets ER sheets for degradation, analogous to PINK1-Parkin regulation during mitophagy. Our data provide insight into the cellular logic of ER-phagy, reveal parallels between organelle autophagies, and provide an entry point to the relatively unexplored process of degrading the ER network.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Local Fatty Acid Channeling into Phospholipid Synthesis Drives Phagophore Expansion during Autophagy</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/31883797/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/31883797/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Autophagy is a conserved catabolic homeostasis process central for cellular and organismal health. During autophagy, small single-membrane phagophores rapidly expand into large double-membrane autophagosomes to encapsulate diverse cargoes for degradation. It is thought that autophagic membranes are mainly derived from preformed organelle membranes. Instead, here we delineate a pathway that expands the phagophore membrane by localized phospholipid synthesis. Specifically, we find that the conserved acyl-CoA synthetase Faa1 accumulates on nucleated phagophores and locally activates fatty acids (FAs) required for phagophore elongation and autophagy. Strikingly, using isotopic FA tracing, we directly show that Faa1 channels activated FAs into the synthesis of phospholipids and promotes their assembly into autophagic membranes. Indeed, the first committed steps of de novo phospholipid synthesis at the ER, which forms stable contacts with nascent autophagosomes, are essential for autophagy. Together, our work illuminates how cells spatially tune synthesis and flux of phospholipids for autophagosome biogenesis during autophagy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LATS1 but not LATS2 represses autophagy by a kinase-independent scaffold function</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/31848340/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/31848340/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Autophagy perturbation represents an emerging therapeutic strategy in cancer. Although LATS1 and LATS2 kinases, core components of the mammalian Hippo pathway, have been shown to exert tumor suppressive activities, here we report a pro-survival role of LATS1 but not LATS2 in hepatocellular carcinoma (HCC) cells. Specifically, LATS1 restricts lethal autophagy in HCC cells induced by sorafenib, the standard of care for advanced HCC patients. Notably, autophagy regulation by LATS1 is independent of its kinase activity. Instead, LATS1 stabilizes the autophagy core-machinery component Beclin-1 by promoting K27-linked ubiquitination at lysine residues K32 and K263 on Beclin-1. Consequently, ubiquitination of Beclin-1 negatively regulates autophagy by promoting inactive dimer formation of Beclin-1. Our study highlights a functional diversity between LATS1 and LATS2, and uncovers a scaffolding role of LATS1 in mediating a cross-talk between the Hippo signaling pathway and autophagy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The ER-Localized Transmembrane Protein TMEM39A/SUSR2 Regulates Autophagy by Controlling the Trafficking of the PtdIns(4)P Phosphatase SAC1</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/31806350/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/31806350/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TMEM39A, encoding an ER-localized transmembrane protein, is a susceptibility locus for multiple autoimmune diseases. The molecular function of TMEM39A remains completely unknown. Here we demonstrated that TMEM39A, also called SUSR2, modulates autophagy activity by regulating the spatial distribution and levels of PtdIns(4)P. Depletion of SUSR2 elevates late endosomal/lysosomal PtdIns(4)P levels, facilitating recruitment of the HOPS complex to promote assembly of the SNARE complex for autophagosome maturation. SUSR2 knockdown also increases the degradative capability of lysosomes. Mechanistically, SUSR2 interacts with the ER-localized PtdIns(4)P phosphatase SAC1 and also the COPII SEC23/SEC24 subunits to promote the ER-to-Golgi transport of SAC1. Retention of SAC1 on the ER in SUSR2 knockdown cells increases the level of PtdIns(3)P produced by the VPS34 complex, promoting autophagosome formation. Our study reveals that TMEM39A/SUSR2 acts as an adaptor protein for efficient export of SAC1 from the ER and provides insights into the pathogenesis of diseases associated with TMEM39A mutations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>STYK1 promotes autophagy through enhancing the assembly of autophagy-specific class III phosphatidylinositol 3-kinase complex I</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/31696776/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/31696776/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Macroautophagy/autophagy plays key roles in development, oncogenesis, and cardiovascular and metabolic diseases. Autophagy-specific class III phosphatidylinositol 3-kinase complex I (PtdIns3K-C1) is essential for autophagosome formation. However, the regulation of this complex formation requires further investigation. Here, we discovered that STYK1 (serine/threonine/tyrosine kinase 1), a member of the receptor tyrosine kinases (RTKs) family, is a new upstream regulator of autophagy. We discovered that STYK1 facilitated autophagosome formation in human cells and zebrafish, which was characterized by elevated LC3-II and lowered SQSTM1/p62 levels and increased puncta formation by several marker proteins, such as ATG14, WIPI1, and ZFYVE1. Moreover, we observed that STYK1 directly binds to the PtdIns3K-C1 complex as a homodimer. The binding with this complex was promoted by Tyr191 phosphorylation, by means of which the kinase activity of STYK1 was elevated. We also demonstrated that STYK1 elevated the serine phosphorylation of BECN1, thereby decreasing the interaction between BECN1 and BCL2. Furthermore, we found that STYK1 preferentially facilitated the assembly of the PtdIns3K-C1 complex and was required for PtdIns3K-C1 complex kinase activity. Taken together, our findings provide new insights into autophagy induction and reveal evidence of novel crosstalk between the components of RTK signaling and autophagy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A high-throughput screen identifies the long non-coding RNA DRAIC as a regulator of autophagy</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/30872794/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/30872794/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Autophagy is a conserved degradation process that occurs in all eukaryotic cells and its dysfunction has been associated with various diseases including cancer. While a number of large-scale attempts have recently identified new molecular players in autophagy regulation, including proteins and microRNAs, little is known regarding the function of long non-coding RNAs (lncRNAs) in the regulation of this process. To identify new long non-coding RNAs with functional implications in autophagy, we performed a high-throughput RNAi screen targeting more than 600 lncRNA transcripts and monitored their effects on autophagy in MCF-7 cells. We identified 63 lncRNAs that affected GFP-LC3B puncta numbers significantly. We validated the strongest hit, the lncRNA DRAIC previously shown to impact cell proliferation, and revealed a novel role for this lncRNA in the regulation of autophagic flux. Interestingly, we find DRAIC&amp;rsquo;s pro-proliferative effects to be autophagy-independent. This study serves as a valuable resource for researchers from both the lncRNA and autophagy fields as it advances the current understanding of autophagy regulation by non-coding RNAs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The role of STAT3 in autophagy</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/25951043/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/25951043/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Autophagy is an evolutionarily conserved process in eukaryotes that eliminates harmful components and maintains cellular homeostasis in response to a series of extracellular insults. However, these insults may trigger the downstream signaling of another prominent stress responsive pathway, the STAT3 signaling pathway, which has been implicated in multiple aspects of the autophagic process. Recent reports further indicate that different subcellular localization patterns of STAT3 affect autophagy in various ways. For example, nuclear STAT3 fine-tunes autophagy via the transcriptional regulation of several autophagy-related genes such as BCL2 family members, BECN1, PIK3C3, CTSB, CTSL, PIK3R1, HIF1A, BNIP3, and microRNAs with targets of autophagy modulators. Cytoplasmic STAT3 constitutively inhibits autophagy by sequestering EIF2AK2 as well as by interacting with other autophagy-related signaling molecules such as FOXO1 and FOXO3. Additionally, the mitochondrial translocation of STAT3 suppresses autophagy induced by oxidative stress and may effectively preserve mitochondria from being degraded by mitophagy. Understanding the role of STAT3 signaling in the regulation of autophagy may provide insight into the classic autophagy model and also into cancer therapy, especially for the emerging targeted therapy, because a series of targeted agents execute antitumor activities via blocking STAT3 signaling, which inevitably affects the autophagy pathway. Here, we review several of the representative studies and the current understanding in this particular field.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Molecular pathways: autophagy in cancer--a matter of timing and context</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/25165101/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/25165101/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Autophagy is an intracellular self-digestion mechanism, by which cellular components are sorted into double-membrane autophagosomes and delivered to lysosomes for degradation. Cells use autophagy to dispose of wastes and eliminate hazards, while recycling nutrients and tuning metabolism in the process. Through these functions, autophagy promotes cell fitness, genome integrity, tissue homeostasis, and cell survival and growth under stress. Both autophagy upregulation and downregulation have been found in human cancers, suggesting a complex role in tumor development. Accumulating results from autophagy-deficient mice and mouse models of human cancers have demonstrated that autophagy generally suppresses tumor initiation, but promotes tumor progression, in a manner that is dependent on timing and context and modified by specific tumorigenic events. Given the role of autophagy in facilitating tumor growth, autophagy inhibition has gained wide attention as a potential anticancer therapy. Here, we summarize relevant genetic, preclinical, and clinical studies and discuss the multifaceted role of autophagy in cancer, as well as the prospects of autophagy inhibition for cancer therapy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tegument protein UL21 of alpha-herpesvirus inhibits the innate immunity by triggering CGAS degradation through TOLLIP-mediated selective autophagy</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36343628/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jun 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36343628/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alpha-herpesvirus causes lifelong infections and serious diseases in a wide range of hosts and has developed multiple strategies to counteract the host defense. Here, we demonstrate that the tegument protein UL21 (unique long region 21) in pseudorabies virus (PRV) dampens type I interferon signaling by triggering the degradation of CGAS (cyclic GMP-AMP synthase) through the macroautophagy/autophagy-lysosome pathway. Mechanistically, the UL21 protein scaffolds the E3 ligase UBE3C (ubiquitin protein ligase E3C) to catalyze the K27-linked ubiquitination of CGAS at Lys384, which is recognized by the cargo receptor TOLLIP (toll interacting protein) and degraded in the lysosome. Additionally, we show that the N terminus of UL21 in PRV is dominant in destabilizing CGAS-mediated innate immunity. Moreover, viral tegument protein UL21 in herpes simplex virus type 1 (HSV-1) also displays the conserved inhibitory mechanisms. Furthermore, by using PRV, we demonstrate the roles of UL21 in degrading CGAS to promote viral infection in vivo. Altogether, these findings describe a distinct pathway where alpha-herpesvirus exploits TOLLIP-mediated selective autophagy to evade host antiviral immunity, highlighting a new interface of interplay between the host and DNA virus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
