<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Acetylation | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/acetylation/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/acetylation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Acetylation</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Acetylation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/acetylation/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nuclear SPHK2/S1P induces oxidative stress and NLRP3 inflammasome activation via promoting p53 acetylation in lipopolysaccharide-induced acute lung injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36653338/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36653338/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although genomewide RNA expression analysis has become a routine tool in biomedical research, extracting biological insight from such information remains a major challenge. Here, we describe a powerful analytical method called Gene Set Enrichment Analysis (GSEA) for interpreting gene expression data. The method derives its power by focusing on gene sets, that is, groups of genes that share common biological function, chromosomal location, or regulation. We demonstrate how GSEA yields insights into several cancer-related data sets, including leukemia and lung cancer. Notably, where single-gene analysis finds little similarity between two independent studies of patient survival in lung cancer, GSEA reveals many biological pathways in common. The GSEA method is embodied in a freely available software package, together with an initial database of 1,325 biologically defined gene sets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nuclear localization of mitochondrial TCA cycle enzymes modulates pluripotency via histone acetylation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36460681/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36460681/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pluripotent stem cells hold great promise in regenerative medicine and developmental biology studies. Mitochondrial metabolites, including tricarboxylic acid (TCA) cycle intermediates, have been reported to play critical roles in pluripotency. Here we show that TCA cycle enzymes including Pdha1, Pcb, Aco2, Cs, Idh3a, Ogdh, Sdha and Mdh2 are translocated to the nucleus during somatic cell reprogramming, primed-to-naive transition and totipotency acquisition. The nuclear-localized TCA cycle enzymes Pdha1, Pcb, Aco2, Cs, Idh3a promote somatic cell reprogramming and primed-to-naive transition. In addition, nuclear-localized TCA cycle enzymes, particularly nuclear-targeted Pdha1, facilitate the 2-cell program in pluripotent stem cells. Mechanistically, nuclear Pdha1 increases the acetyl-CoA and metabolite pool in the nucleus, leading to chromatin remodeling at pluripotency genes by enhancing histone H3 acetylation. Our results reveal an important role of mitochondrial TCA cycle enzymes in the epigenetic regulation of pluripotency that constitutes a mitochondria-to-nucleus retrograde signaling mode in different states of pluripotent acquisition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dietary ketone body-escalated histone acetylation in megakaryocytes alleviates chemotherapy-induced thrombocytopenia</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36449600/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36449600/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chemotherapy-induced thrombocytopenia (CIT) is a severe complication in patients with cancer that can lead to impaired therapeutic outcome and survival. Clinically, therapeutic options for CIT are limited by severe adverse effects and high economic burdens. Here, we demonstrate that ketogenic diets alleviate CIT in both animals and humans without causing thrombocytosis. Mechanistically, ketogenic diet-induced circulating β-hydroxybutyrate (β-OHB) increased histone H3 acetylation in bone marrow megakaryocytes. Gain- and loss-of-function experiments revealed a distinct role of 3-β-hydroxybutyrate dehydrogenase (BDH)-mediated ketone body metabolism in promoting histone acetylation, which promoted the transcription of platelet biogenesis genes and induced thrombocytopoiesis. Genetic depletion of the megakaryocyte-specific ketone body transporter monocarboxylate transporter 1 (MCT1) or pharmacological targeting of MCT1 blocked β-OHB-induced thrombocytopoiesis in mice. A ketogenesis-promoting diet alleviated CIT in mouse models. Moreover, a ketogenic diet modestly increased platelet counts without causing thrombocytosis in healthy volunteers, and a ketogenic lifestyle inversely correlated with CIT in patients with cancer. Together, we provide mechanistic insights into a ketone body-MCT1-BDH-histone acetylation-platelet biogenesis axis in megakaryocytes and propose a nontoxic, low-cost dietary intervention for combating CIT.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Control of immediate early gene expression by CPEB4-repressor complex-mediated mRNA degradation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36096941/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36096941/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Cytoplasmic polyadenylation element-binding protein 4 (CPEB4) is known to associate with cytoplasmic polyadenylation elements (CPEs) located in the 3&amp;rsquo; untranslated region (UTR) of specific mRNAs and assemble an activator complex promoting the translation of target mRNAs through cytoplasmic polyadenylation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; Here, we find that CPEB4 is part of an alternative repressor complex that mediates mRNA degradation by associating with the evolutionarily conserved CCR4-NOT deadenylase complex. We identify human CPEB4 as an RNA-binding protein (RBP) with enhanced association to poly(A) RNA upon inhibition of class I histone deacetylases (HDACs), a condition known to cause widespread degradation of poly(A)-containing mRNA. Photoactivatable ribonucleoside-enhanced crosslinking and immunoprecipitation (PAR-CLIP) analysis using endogenously tagged CPEB4 in HeLa cells reveals that CPEB4 preferentially binds to the 3&amp;rsquo;UTR of immediate early gene mRNAs, at G-containing variants of the canonical U- and A-rich CPE located in close proximity to poly(A) sites. By transcriptome-wide mRNA decay measurements, we find that the strength of CPEB4 binding correlates with short mRNA half-lives and that loss of CPEB4 expression leads to the stabilization of immediate early gene mRNAs. Akin to CPEB4, we demonstrate that CPEB1 and CPEB2 also confer mRNA instability by recruitment of the CCR4-NOT complex.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; While CPEB4 was previously known for its ability to stimulate cytoplasmic polyadenylation, our findings establish an additional function for CPEB4 as the RNA adaptor of a repressor complex that enhances the degradation of short-lived immediate early gene mRNAs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NAT10 regulates neutrophil pyroptosis in sepsis via acetylating ULK1 RNA and activating STING pathway</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36068299/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36068299/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Erratum in:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author Correction: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nature.com/articles/s42003-022-04045-w&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;NAT10 regulates neutrophil pyroptosis in sepsis via acetylating ULK1 RNA and activating STING pathway&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Emerging evidence suggests that pyroptosis is involved in sepsis. However, the role of neutrophil pyroptosis in sepsis and the mechanisms remains elusive. We find that N-acetyltransferase 10 (NAT10), an acetyltransferase responsible for the N4-acetylation of Cytidine (ac4C) in mRNA, is significantly downregulated in neutrophils from septic mice. Neutrophil-specific over-expression of NAT10 improves the survival and ameliorates lung injury in septic mice by inhibiting neutrophil pyroptosis. Notably, UNC-52-like kinase 1 (ULK1) is identified as the target of NAT10 in neutrophils. The decreased expression of NAT10 resultes in the decay of ULK1 transcripts and therefore the reduced expression of ULK1. As a regulator of STING phosphorylation, the loss of ULK1 enhances the activation of STING-IRF3 signaling and subsequently the elevated pyroptosis-inducing NLRP3 inflammasome in neutrophils. While over-expression of NAT10 restrains pyroptosis in neutrophils as well as septic lethality in mice by reversing the ULK1-STING-NLRP3 axis. The decreased expression of NAT10 are also observed in sepsis patients and its correlation with clinical severity is found. Collectively, our findings disclose that NAT10 is a negative regulator of neutrophil pyroptosis and its downregulation contributes to the progress of sepsis by exacerbating pyroptosis via the ULK1-STING-NLRP3 axis, therefore revealing a potential therapeutic target for sepsis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sirtuin 6 protects against hepatic fibrogenesis by suppressing the YAP and TAZ function</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36036554/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36036554/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Erratum in:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Erratum to &lt;a href=&#34;https://faseb.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1096/fsb2.22572&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sirtuin 6 protects against hepatic fibrogenesis by suppressing the YAP and TAZ function&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hepatic fibrosis occurs in response to prolonged tissue injury in the liver, which results in abnormal accumulation of extracellular matrix. Hepatic stellate cells (HSCs) have been suggested to play a major role in liver fibrosis. However, the molecular mechanisms remain incompletely understood. Sirtuin 6 (SIRT6), an NAD+ -dependent deacetylase, has been previously implicated in the regulation of the transforming growth factor β (TGFβ)-SMAD3 pathway that plays a significant role in liver fibrosis. In this work, we aimed to identify other important players during hepatic fibrogenesis, which are modulated by SIRT6. Yes-associated protein (YAP) and transcriptional coactivator with PDZ-binding motif (TAZ or WWTR1), key players in the Hippo pathway, have been implicated in the promotion of hepatic fibrosis. Our data show that HSC-specific Sirt6 knockout mice are more susceptible to high-fat-cholesterol-cholate diet-induced hepatic fibrosis than their wildtype counterparts. Our signaling analyses suggest that in addition to the TGFβ-SMAD3 pathway, YAP and TAZ are also highly activated in the SIRT6-deficient HSCs. As it is not clear how SIRT6 might regulate YAP and TAZ, we have decided to elucidate the mechanism underlying the regulation of YAP and TAZ by SIRT6 in HSCs. Overexpression or knockdown of SIRT6 corroborates the role of SIRT6 in the negative regulation of YAP and TAZ. Further biochemical analyses reveal that SIRT6 deacetylates YAP and TAZ and reprograms the composition of the TEA domain transcription factor complex to suppress their downstream target genes, particularly those involved in hepatic fibrosis. In conclusion, our data suggest that SIRT6 plays a critical role in the regulation of the Hippo pathway to protect against hepatic fibrosis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nucleolar protein NOC4L inhibits tumorigenesis and progression by attenuating SIRT1-mediated p53 deacetylation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36030331/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36030331/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SIRT1 is an NAD&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt;-dependent deacetylase and plays an important role in the deacetylation of both histone and non-histone proteins. Many studies revealed that SIRT1 is upregulated in a variety of tumors and tightly associated with tumorigenesis and cancer progression, but the detailed underlying mechanism of the biological processes remains unclarified. In the present study, we found a nucleolar protein NOC4L, human ortholog of yeast Noc4p, which is essential for the nuclear export of the ribosomal 40S subunit and could bind to SIRT1 to inhibit SIRT1 mediated deacetylation of p53. NOC4L interacts with SIRT1 in variety of cells under nucleolar stress and directly interacts with SIRT1 in vitro. Furthermore, we determined the C-terminal of NOC4L and the catalytic domain of SIRT1 were required for their interaction. Overexpression of NOC4L did not change the protein levels of SIRT1 or p53, but increased the acetylation of p53 and promoted cell apoptosis. Additionally, NOC4L inhibited tumor cell proliferation in a p53-dependent manner and restrained tumor growth in a nude mice xenograft model. Clinically, colorectal cancer patients with the high expression of NOC4L had a better prognosis as &lt;em&gt;TP53&lt;/em&gt; was normally expressed, but no significant difference was observed in survival with mutant &lt;em&gt;TP53&lt;/em&gt;. Taken together, our results identified a novel SIRT1 regulatory protein and broaden our understanding of the molecular mechanism of how nucleolar protein NOC4L regulates p53 under nucleolar stress. This research provides an insight into tumorigenesis and cell self-protection in the early stage of DNA damage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mitochondrial PKM2 deacetylation by procyanidin B2-induced SIRT3 upregulation alleviates lung ischemia/reperfusion injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35821123/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35821123/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apoptosis is a critical event in the pathogenesis of lung ischemia/reperfusion (I/R) injury. Sirtuin 3 (SIRT3), an important deacetylase predominantly localized in mitochondria, regulates diverse physiological processes, including apoptosis. However, the detailed mechanisms by which SIRT3 regulates lung I/R injury remain unclear. Many polyphenols strongly regulate the sirtuin family. In this study, we found that a polyphenol compound, procyanidin B2 (PCB2), activated SIRT3 in mouse lungs. Due to this effect, PCB2 administration attenuated histological lesions, relieved pulmonary dysfunction, and improved the survival rate of the murine model of lung I/R injury. Additionally, this treatment inhibited hypoxia/reoxygenation (H/R)-induced A549 cell apoptosis and rescued Bcl-2 expression. Using Sirt3-knockout mice and specific SIRT3 knockdown in vitro, we further found that SIRT3 strongly protects against lung I/R injury. Sirt3 deficiency or enzymatic inactivation substantially aggravated lung I/R-induced pulmonary lesions, promoted apoptosis, and abolished PCB2-mediated protection. Mitochondrial pyruvate kinase M2 (PKM2) inhibits apoptosis by stabilizing Bcl-2. Here, we found that PKM2 accumulates and is hyperacetylated in mitochondria upon lung I/R injury. By screening the potential sites of PKM2 acetylation, we found that SIRT3 deacetylates the K433 residue of PKM2 in A549 cells. Transfection with a deacetylated mimic plasmid of PKM2 noticeably reduced apoptosis, while acetylated mimic transfection abolished the protective effect of PKM2. Furthermore, PKM2 knockdown or inhibition in vivo significantly abrogated the antiapoptotic effects of SIRT3 upregulation. Collectively, this study provides the first evidence that the SIRT3/PKM2 pathway is a protective target for the suppression of apoptosis in lung I/R injury. Moreover, this study identifies K433 deacetylation of PKM2 as a novel modification that regulates its anti-apoptotic activity. In addition, PCB2-mediated modulation of the SIRT3/PKM2 pathway may significantly protect against lung I/R injury, suggesting a novel prophylactic strategy for lung I/R injury.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gene set enrichment analysis: a knowledge-based approach for interpreting genome-wide expression profiles</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35673580/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35673580/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background and Purpose:&lt;/em&gt; Myocardial infarction (MI) in diabetic patients results in higher mortality and morbidity. We and others have previously shown that bone marrow-endothelial progenitor cells (EPCs) promote cardiac neovascularization and attenuate ischemic injury. Lately, small extracellular vesicles (EVs) have emerged as major paracrine effectors mediating the benefits of stem cell therapy. Modest clinical outcomes of autologous cell-based therapies suggest diabetes-induced EPC dysfunction and may also reflect their EV derivatives. Moreover, studies suggest that post-translational histone modifications promote diabetes-induced vascular dysfunctions. Therefore, we tested the hypothesis that diabetic EPC-EVs may lose their post-injury cardiac reparative function by modulating histone modification in endothelial cells (ECs).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; We collected EVs from the culture medium of EPCs isolated from non-diabetic (db/+) and diabetic (db/db) mice and examined their effects on recipient ECs and cardiomyocytes &lt;em&gt;in vitro&lt;/em&gt;, and their reparative function in permanent ligation of left anterior descending (LAD) coronary artery and ischemia/reperfusion (I/R) myocardial ischemic injuries &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; Compared to db/+ EPC-EVs, db/db EPC-EVs promoted EC and cardiomyocyte apoptosis and repressed tube-forming capacity of ECs. &lt;em&gt;In vivo&lt;/em&gt;, db/db EPC-EVs depressed cardiac function, reduced capillary density, and increased fibrosis compared to db/+ EPC-EV treatments after MI. Moreover, in the I/R MI model, db/+ EPC-EV-mediated acute cardio-protection was lost with db/db EPC-EVs, and db/db EPC-EVs increased immune cell infiltration, infarct area, and plasma cardiac troponin-I. Mechanistically, histone 3 lysine 9 acetylation (H3K9Ac) was significantly decreased in cardiac ECs treated with db/db EPC-EVs compared to db/+ EPC-EVs. The H3K9Ac chromatin immunoprecipitation sequencing (ChIP-Seq) results further revealed that db/db EPC-EVs reduced H3K9Ac level on angiogenic, cell survival, and proliferative genes in cardiac ECs. We found that the histone deacetylase (HDAC) inhibitor, valproic acid (VPA), partly restored diabetic EPC-EV-impaired H3K9Ac levels, tube formation and viability of ECs, and enhanced cell survival and proliferative genes, &lt;em&gt;Pdgfd&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Sox12&lt;/em&gt;, expression. Moreover, we observed that VPA treatment improved db/db EPC-mediated post-MI cardiac repair and functions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; Our findings unravel that diabetes impairs EPC-EV reparative function in the ischemic heart, at least partially, through HDACs-mediated H3K9Ac downregulation leading to transcriptional suppression of angiogenic, proliferative and cell survival genes in recipient cardiac ECs. Thus, HDAC inhibitors may potentially be used to restore the function of diabetic EPC and other stem cells for autologous cell therapy applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Epigenetic regulation of CXCR4 signaling in cancer pathogenesis and progression</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/35346802/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/35346802/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Signaling involving chemokine receptor CXCR4 and its ligand SDF-1/CXL12 has been investigated for many years for its possible role in cancer progression and pathogenesis. Evidence emerging from clinical studies in recent years has further established diagnostic as well as prognostic importance of CXCR4 signaling. CXCR4 and SDF-1 are routinely reported to be elevated in tumors, distant metastases, which correlates with poor survival of patients. These findings have kindled interest in the mechanisms that regulate CXCR4/SDF-1 expression. Of note, there is a particular interest in the epigenetic regulation of CXCR4 signaling that may be responsible for upregulated CXCR4 in primary as well as metastatic cancers. This review first lists the clinical evidence supporting CXCR4 signaling as putative cancer diagnostic and/or prognostic biomarker, followed by a discussion on reported epigenetic mechanisms that affect CXCR4 expression. These mechanisms include regulation by non-coding RNAs, such as, microRNAs, long non-coding RNAs and circular RNAs. Additionally, we also discuss the regulation of CXCR4 expression through methylation and acetylation. Better understanding and appreciation of epigenetic regulation of CXCR4 signaling can invariably lead to identification of novel therapeutic targets as well as therapies to regulate this oncogenic signaling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Regulation of Dystroglycan Gene Expression in Early Myoblast Differentiation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35330913/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35330913/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dystroglycan, a component of the dystrophin-associated glycoprotein complex, connects the extracellular matrix and cytoskeleton to maintain muscle membrane integrity. As such, abnormalities of dystroglycan are linked to different types of muscular dystrophies. In an effort to develop therapeutic approaches to re-establish signal integration for muscle repair and homeostasis, we have previously determined that a clinically approved agonist of retinoid X receptor enhances myoblast differentiation through direct regulation of gene expression of the muscle master regulator MyoD. Using comprehensive omics and molecular analyses, we found that dystroglycan gene expression is responsive to retinoid X receptor-selective signaling in early myoblast differentiation. In addition, the dystroglycan gene is a MyoD target, and residue-specific histone acetylation coincides with the occupancy of histone acetyltransferase p300 at the MyoD binding sites. Consequently, the p300 function is important for rexinoid-augmented dystroglycan gene expression. Finally, dystroglycan plays a role in myoblast differentiation. Our study sheds new light on dystroglycan regulation and function in myoblast differentiation and presents a potential avenue for re-establishing signal integration of a specific chromatin state pharmacologically to overcome muscle pathology and identify additional myogenic interactions for therapeutic applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Epigenetic modifications in spinal ligament aging</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/35218968/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/35218968/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spinal ligament aging is a complex process involving genetic, epigenetic, and environmental factors.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;DNA methylation, histone modifications and ncRNAs exert vital functions in spinal ligament aging.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Epigenetic alterations provide promising diagnostic and therapeutic targets for spinal ligament aging.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spinal stenosis is a common degenerative spine disorder in the aged population and the spinal ligament aging is a main contributor to this chronic disease. However, the underlying mechanisms of spinal ligament aging remain unclear. Epigenetics is the study of heritable and reversible changes in the function of a gene or genome that occur without any alteration in the primary DNA sequence. Epigenetic alterations have been demonstrated to play crucial roles in age-related diseases and conditions, and they are recently studied as biomarkers and therapeutic targets in the field of cancer research. The main epigenetic modifications, including DNA methylation alteration, histone modifications as well as dysregulated noncoding RNA modulation, have all been implicated in spinal ligament aging diseases. DNA methylation modulates the expression of critical genes including WNT5A, GDNF, ACSM5, miR-497 and miR-195 during spinal ligament degeneration. Histone modifications widely affect gene expression and obvious histone modification abnormalities have been found in spinal ligament aging. MicroRNAs (miRNAs), long noncoding RNAs (lncRNAs) and circular RNAs (circRNAs) exert crucial regulating effects on spinal ligament aging conditions via targeting various osteogenic or fibrogenic differentiation related genes. To our knowledge, there is no systematic review yet to summarize the involvement of epigenetic mechanisms of spinal ligament aging in degenerative spinal diseases. In this study, we systematically discussed the different epigenetic modifications and their potential functions in spinal ligament aging process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HIPK2 phosphorylates HDAC3 for NF-κB acetylation to ameliorate colitis-associated colorectal carcinoma and sepsis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34244427/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34244427/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although inflammation is critical for the clearance of pathogens, uncontrolled inflammation also contributes to the development of multiple diseases such as cancer and sepsis. Since NF-κB-mediated transactivation in the nucleus is pivotal downstream of various stimuli to induce inflammation, searching the nuclear-localized targets specifically regulating NF-κB activation will provide important therapeutic application. Here, we have identified that homeodomain-interacting protein kinase 2 (HIPK2), a nuclear serine/threonine kinase, increases its expression in inflammatory macrophages. Importantly, HIPK2 deficiency or overexpression could enhance or inhibit inflammatory responses in LPS-stimulated macrophages, respectively. HIPK2-deficient mice were more susceptible to LPS-induced endotoxemia and CLP-induced sepsis. Adoptive transfer of &lt;em&gt;Hipk2&lt;sup&gt;+/-&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; bone marrow cells (BMs) also aggravated AOM/DSS-induced colorectal cancer. Mechanistically, HIPK2 bound and phosphorylated histone deacetylase 3 (HDAC3) at serine 374 to inhibit its enzymatic activity, thus reducing the deacetylation of p65 at lysine 218 to suppress NF-κB activation. Notably, the HDAC3 inhibitors protected wild-type or &lt;em&gt;Hipk2&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; BMs-reconstituted mice from LPS-induced endotoxemia. Our findings suggest that the HIPK2-HDAC3-p65 module in macrophages restrains excessive inflammation, which may represent a new layer of therapeutic mechanism for colitis-associated colorectal cancer and sepsis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SIRT3-mediated deacetylation of NLRC4 promotes inflammasome activation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33664876/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33664876/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Salmonella typhimurium&lt;/em&gt; (&lt;em&gt;S. typhimurium&lt;/em&gt;) infection of macrophage induces NLRC4 inflammasome-mediated production of the pro-inflammatory cytokines IL-1β. Post-translational modifications on NLRC4 are critical for its activation. Sirtuin3 (SIRT3) is the most thoroughly studied mitochondrial nicotinamide adenine dinucleotide (NAD&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt;) -dependent deacetylase. We wondered whether SIRT3 mediated-deacetylation could take part in NLRC4 inflammasome activation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Methods:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; We initially tested IL-1β production and pyroptosis after cytosolic transfection of flagellin or &lt;em&gt;S. typhimurium&lt;/em&gt; infection in wild type and SIRT3-deficient primary peritoneal macrophages via immunoblotting and ELISA assay. These results were confirmed in SIRT3-deficient immortalized bone marrow derived macrophages (iBMDMs) which were generated by CRISPR-Cas9 technology. In addition, in vivo experiments were conducted to confirm the role of SIRT3 in &lt;em&gt;S. typhimurium&lt;/em&gt;-induced cytokines production. Then NLRC4 assembly was analyzed by immune-fluorescence assay and ASC oligomerization assay. Immunoblotting, ELISA and flow cytometry were performed to clarify the role of SIRT3 in NLRP3 and AIM2 inflammasomes activation. To further investigate the mechanism of SIRT3 in NLRC4 activation, co-immunoprecipitation (Co-IP), we did immunoblot, cellular fractionation and in-vitro deacetylation assay. Finally, to clarify the acetylation sites of NLRC4, we performed liquid chromatography-mass spectrometry (LC-MS) and immunoblotting analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Results:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; SIRT3 deficiency led to significantly impaired NLRC4 inflammasome activation and pyroptosis both &lt;em&gt;in vitro&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt;. Furthermore, SIRT3 promotes NLRC4 inflammasome assembly by inducing more ASC speck formation and ASC oligomerization. However, SIRT3 is dispensable for NLRP3 and AIM2 inflammasome activation. Moreover, SIRT3 interacts with and deacetylates NLRC4 to promote its activation. Finally, we proved that deacetylation of NLRC4 at Lys71 or Lys272 could promote its activation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; Our study reveals that SIRT3 mediated-deacetylation of NLRC4 is pivotal for NLRC4 activation and the acetylation switch of NLRC4 may aid the clearance of &lt;em&gt;S. typhimurium&lt;/em&gt; infection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A novel SIRT6 activator ameliorates neuroinflammation and ischemic brain injury via EZH2/FOXC1 axis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33777677/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33777677/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ischemic stroke is the second leading cause of death worldwide with limited medications and neuroinflammation was recognized as a critical player in the progression of stroke, but how to control the overactive neuroinflammation is still a long-standing challenge. Here, we designed a novel SIRT6 activator MDL-811 which remarkably inhibited inflammatory response in lipopolysaccharide (LPS)-stimulated RAW264.7 macrophages and primary mouse microglia, which were abolished by silencing SIRT6. RNA-seq screening identified the forkhead box C1 (Foxc1) is a key gene evoked by MDL-811 stimulation and is required for the anti-inflammatory effects of MDL-811. We found MDL-811-activated SIRT6 directly interacted with enhancer of zeste homolog 2 (EZH2) and promoted deacetylation of EZH2 which could bind to the promoter of Foxc1 and upregulate its expression to modulate inflammation. Moreover, our data demonstrated that MDL-811 not only ameliorated sickness behaviors in neuroinflammatory mice induced by LPS, but also markedly reduced the brain injury in ischemic stroke mice in addition to promoting long-term functional recovery. Importantly, MDL-811 also exhibited strong anti-inflammatory effects in human monocytes isolated from ischemic stroke patients, underlying an interesting translational perspective. Taken together, MDL-811 could be an alternative therapeutic candidate for ischemic stroke and other brain disorders associated with neuroinflammation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
