<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Acetylation | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/acetylation/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/acetylation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Acetylation</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 02 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Acetylation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/acetylation/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nuclear localization of mitochondrial TCA cycle enzymes modulates pluripotency via histone acetylation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36460681/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36460681/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pluripotent stem cells hold great promise in regenerative medicine and developmental biology studies. Mitochondrial metabolites, including tricarboxylic acid (TCA) cycle intermediates, have been reported to play critical roles in pluripotency. Here we show that TCA cycle enzymes including Pdha1, Pcb, Aco2, Cs, Idh3a, Ogdh, Sdha and Mdh2 are translocated to the nucleus during somatic cell reprogramming, primed-to-naive transition and totipotency acquisition. The nuclear-localized TCA cycle enzymes Pdha1, Pcb, Aco2, Cs, Idh3a promote somatic cell reprogramming and primed-to-naive transition. In addition, nuclear-localized TCA cycle enzymes, particularly nuclear-targeted Pdha1, facilitate the 2-cell program in pluripotent stem cells. Mechanistically, nuclear Pdha1 increases the acetyl-CoA and metabolite pool in the nucleus, leading to chromatin remodeling at pluripotency genes by enhancing histone H3 acetylation. Our results reveal an important role of mitochondrial TCA cycle enzymes in the epigenetic regulation of pluripotency that constitutes a mitochondria-to-nucleus retrograde signaling mode in different states of pluripotent acquisition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dietary ketone body-escalated histone acetylation in megakaryocytes alleviates chemotherapy-induced thrombocytopenia</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36449600/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36449600/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chemotherapy-induced thrombocytopenia (CIT) is a severe complication in patients with cancer that can lead to impaired therapeutic outcome and survival. Clinically, therapeutic options for CIT are limited by severe adverse effects and high economic burdens. Here, we demonstrate that ketogenic diets alleviate CIT in both animals and humans without causing thrombocytosis. Mechanistically, ketogenic diet-induced circulating β-hydroxybutyrate (β-OHB) increased histone H3 acetylation in bone marrow megakaryocytes. Gain- and loss-of-function experiments revealed a distinct role of 3-β-hydroxybutyrate dehydrogenase (BDH)-mediated ketone body metabolism in promoting histone acetylation, which promoted the transcription of platelet biogenesis genes and induced thrombocytopoiesis. Genetic depletion of the megakaryocyte-specific ketone body transporter monocarboxylate transporter 1 (MCT1) or pharmacological targeting of MCT1 blocked β-OHB-induced thrombocytopoiesis in mice. A ketogenesis-promoting diet alleviated CIT in mouse models. Moreover, a ketogenic diet modestly increased platelet counts without causing thrombocytosis in healthy volunteers, and a ketogenic lifestyle inversely correlated with CIT in patients with cancer. Together, we provide mechanistic insights into a ketone body-MCT1-BDH-histone acetylation-platelet biogenesis axis in megakaryocytes and propose a nontoxic, low-cost dietary intervention for combating CIT.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Control of immediate early gene expression by CPEB4-repressor complex-mediated mRNA degradation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36096941/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36096941/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Cytoplasmic polyadenylation element-binding protein 4 (CPEB4) is known to associate with cytoplasmic polyadenylation elements (CPEs) located in the 3&amp;rsquo; untranslated region (UTR) of specific mRNAs and assemble an activator complex promoting the translation of target mRNAs through cytoplasmic polyadenylation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; Here, we find that CPEB4 is part of an alternative repressor complex that mediates mRNA degradation by associating with the evolutionarily conserved CCR4-NOT deadenylase complex. We identify human CPEB4 as an RNA-binding protein (RBP) with enhanced association to poly(A) RNA upon inhibition of class I histone deacetylases (HDACs), a condition known to cause widespread degradation of poly(A)-containing mRNA. Photoactivatable ribonucleoside-enhanced crosslinking and immunoprecipitation (PAR-CLIP) analysis using endogenously tagged CPEB4 in HeLa cells reveals that CPEB4 preferentially binds to the 3&amp;rsquo;UTR of immediate early gene mRNAs, at G-containing variants of the canonical U- and A-rich CPE located in close proximity to poly(A) sites. By transcriptome-wide mRNA decay measurements, we find that the strength of CPEB4 binding correlates with short mRNA half-lives and that loss of CPEB4 expression leads to the stabilization of immediate early gene mRNAs. Akin to CPEB4, we demonstrate that CPEB1 and CPEB2 also confer mRNA instability by recruitment of the CCR4-NOT complex.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; While CPEB4 was previously known for its ability to stimulate cytoplasmic polyadenylation, our findings establish an additional function for CPEB4 as the RNA adaptor of a repressor complex that enhances the degradation of short-lived immediate early gene mRNAs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NAT10 regulates neutrophil pyroptosis in sepsis via acetylating ULK1 RNA and activating STING pathway</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36068299/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36068299/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Erratum in:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author Correction: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nature.com/articles/s42003-022-04045-w&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;NAT10 regulates neutrophil pyroptosis in sepsis via acetylating ULK1 RNA and activating STING pathway&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Emerging evidence suggests that pyroptosis is involved in sepsis. However, the role of neutrophil pyroptosis in sepsis and the mechanisms remains elusive. We find that N-acetyltransferase 10 (NAT10), an acetyltransferase responsible for the N4-acetylation of Cytidine (ac4C) in mRNA, is significantly downregulated in neutrophils from septic mice. Neutrophil-specific over-expression of NAT10 improves the survival and ameliorates lung injury in septic mice by inhibiting neutrophil pyroptosis. Notably, UNC-52-like kinase 1 (ULK1) is identified as the target of NAT10 in neutrophils. The decreased expression of NAT10 resultes in the decay of ULK1 transcripts and therefore the reduced expression of ULK1. As a regulator of STING phosphorylation, the loss of ULK1 enhances the activation of STING-IRF3 signaling and subsequently the elevated pyroptosis-inducing NLRP3 inflammasome in neutrophils. While over-expression of NAT10 restrains pyroptosis in neutrophils as well as septic lethality in mice by reversing the ULK1-STING-NLRP3 axis. The decreased expression of NAT10 are also observed in sepsis patients and its correlation with clinical severity is found. Collectively, our findings disclose that NAT10 is a negative regulator of neutrophil pyroptosis and its downregulation contributes to the progress of sepsis by exacerbating pyroptosis via the ULK1-STING-NLRP3 axis, therefore revealing a potential therapeutic target for sepsis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HIPK2 phosphorylates HDAC3 for NF-κB acetylation to ameliorate colitis-associated colorectal carcinoma and sepsis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34244427/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34244427/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although inflammation is critical for the clearance of pathogens, uncontrolled inflammation also contributes to the development of multiple diseases such as cancer and sepsis. Since NF-κB-mediated transactivation in the nucleus is pivotal downstream of various stimuli to induce inflammation, searching the nuclear-localized targets specifically regulating NF-κB activation will provide important therapeutic application. Here, we have identified that homeodomain-interacting protein kinase 2 (HIPK2), a nuclear serine/threonine kinase, increases its expression in inflammatory macrophages. Importantly, HIPK2 deficiency or overexpression could enhance or inhibit inflammatory responses in LPS-stimulated macrophages, respectively. HIPK2-deficient mice were more susceptible to LPS-induced endotoxemia and CLP-induced sepsis. Adoptive transfer of &lt;em&gt;Hipk2&lt;sup&gt;+/-&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; bone marrow cells (BMs) also aggravated AOM/DSS-induced colorectal cancer. Mechanistically, HIPK2 bound and phosphorylated histone deacetylase 3 (HDAC3) at serine 374 to inhibit its enzymatic activity, thus reducing the deacetylation of p65 at lysine 218 to suppress NF-κB activation. Notably, the HDAC3 inhibitors protected wild-type or &lt;em&gt;Hipk2&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; BMs-reconstituted mice from LPS-induced endotoxemia. Our findings suggest that the HIPK2-HDAC3-p65 module in macrophages restrains excessive inflammation, which may represent a new layer of therapeutic mechanism for colitis-associated colorectal cancer and sepsis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SIRT3-mediated deacetylation of NLRC4 promotes inflammasome activation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33664876/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33664876/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Salmonella typhimurium&lt;/em&gt; (&lt;em&gt;S. typhimurium&lt;/em&gt;) infection of macrophage induces NLRC4 inflammasome-mediated production of the pro-inflammatory cytokines IL-1β. Post-translational modifications on NLRC4 are critical for its activation. Sirtuin3 (SIRT3) is the most thoroughly studied mitochondrial nicotinamide adenine dinucleotide (NAD&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt;) -dependent deacetylase. We wondered whether SIRT3 mediated-deacetylation could take part in NLRC4 inflammasome activation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Methods:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; We initially tested IL-1β production and pyroptosis after cytosolic transfection of flagellin or &lt;em&gt;S. typhimurium&lt;/em&gt; infection in wild type and SIRT3-deficient primary peritoneal macrophages via immunoblotting and ELISA assay. These results were confirmed in SIRT3-deficient immortalized bone marrow derived macrophages (iBMDMs) which were generated by CRISPR-Cas9 technology. In addition, in vivo experiments were conducted to confirm the role of SIRT3 in &lt;em&gt;S. typhimurium&lt;/em&gt;-induced cytokines production. Then NLRC4 assembly was analyzed by immune-fluorescence assay and ASC oligomerization assay. Immunoblotting, ELISA and flow cytometry were performed to clarify the role of SIRT3 in NLRP3 and AIM2 inflammasomes activation. To further investigate the mechanism of SIRT3 in NLRC4 activation, co-immunoprecipitation (Co-IP), we did immunoblot, cellular fractionation and in-vitro deacetylation assay. Finally, to clarify the acetylation sites of NLRC4, we performed liquid chromatography-mass spectrometry (LC-MS) and immunoblotting analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Results:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; SIRT3 deficiency led to significantly impaired NLRC4 inflammasome activation and pyroptosis both &lt;em&gt;in vitro&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt;. Furthermore, SIRT3 promotes NLRC4 inflammasome assembly by inducing more ASC speck formation and ASC oligomerization. However, SIRT3 is dispensable for NLRP3 and AIM2 inflammasome activation. Moreover, SIRT3 interacts with and deacetylates NLRC4 to promote its activation. Finally, we proved that deacetylation of NLRC4 at Lys71 or Lys272 could promote its activation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; Our study reveals that SIRT3 mediated-deacetylation of NLRC4 is pivotal for NLRC4 activation and the acetylation switch of NLRC4 may aid the clearance of &lt;em&gt;S. typhimurium&lt;/em&gt; infection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
