<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Necroptosis | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/necroptosis/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/necroptosis/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Necroptosis</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Necroptosis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/necroptosis/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>ADAR1 and ZBP1 in innate immunity, cell death, and disease</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/36710220/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/36710220/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ADAR1 and ZBP1 are the only two mammalian proteins that contain Zα domains, which are thought to bind to nucleic acids in the Z-conformation. These two molecules are crucial in regulating diverse biological processes. While ADAR1-mediated RNA editing supports host survival and development, ZBP1-mediated immune responses provide host defense against infection and disease. Recent studies have expanded our understanding of the functions of ADAR1 and ZBP1 beyond their classical roles and established their fundamental regulation of innate immune responses, including NLRP3 inflammasome activation, inflammation, and cell death. Their roles in these processes have physiological impacts across development, infectious and inflammatory diseases, and cancer. In this review, we discuss the functions of ADAR1 and ZBP1 in regulating innate immune responses in development and disease.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evaluation of Caspase Activation to Assess Innate Immune Cell Death</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36744800/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36744800/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Innate immunity provides the critical first line of defense in response to pathogens and sterile insults. A key mechanistic component of this response is the initiation of innate immune programmed cell death (PCD) to eliminate infected or damaged cells and propagate immune responses. However, excess PCD is associated with inflammation and pathology. Therefore, understanding the activation and regulation of PCD is a central aspect of characterizing innate immune responses and identifying new therapeutic targets across the disease spectrum. This protocol provides methods for characterizing innate immune PCD activation by monitoring caspases, a family of cysteine-dependent proteases that are often associated with diverse PCD pathways, including apoptosis, pyroptosis, necroptosis, and PANoptosis. Initial reports characterized caspase-2, caspase-8, caspase-9, and caspase-10 as initiator caspases and caspase-3, caspase-6, and caspase-7 as effector caspases in apoptosis, while later studies found the inflammatory caspases, caspase-1, caspase-4, caspase-5, and caspase-11, drive pyroptosis. It is now known that there is extensive crosstalk between the caspases and other innate immune and cell death molecules across the previously defined PCD pathways, identifying a key knowledge gap in the mechanistic understanding of innate immunity and PCD and leading to the characterization of PANoptosis. PANoptosis is a unique innate immune inflammatory PCD pathway regulated by PANoptosome complexes, which integrate components, including caspases, from other cell death pathways. Here, methods for assessing the activation of caspases in response to various stimuli are provided. These methods allow for the characterization of PCD pathways both in vitro and in vivo, as activated caspases undergo proteolytic cleavage that can be visualized by western blotting using optimal antibodies and blotting conditions. A protocol and western blotting workflow have been established that allow for the assessment of the activation of multiple caspases from the same cellular population, providing a comprehensive characterization of the PCD processes. This method can be applied across research areas in development, homeostasis, infection, inflammation, and cancer to evaluate PCD pathways throughout cellular processes in health and disease.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ZIF-8 Nanoparticles Evoke Pyroptosis for High-Efficiency Cancer Immunotherapy</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36629270/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36629270/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although zeolitic imidazolate framework-8 (ZIF-8) has been applied in various tumor therapies, the intrinsic immunogenicity remains unclear. Here, we initiatively discover that ZIF-8 nanoparticles (NPs) can intrinsically induce pyroptosis by a caspase-1/gasdermin D (GSDMD)-dependent pathway. The pyroptotic cell death is accompanied by necrosis and immunogenic cell death (ICD) simultaneously for efficient in situ immunity initiation. Meanwhile, carbonyl cyanide m-chlorophenyl hydrazone (CCCP), a mitochondrial depolarizing agent, is successfully loaded into ZIF-8 NPs and found to further enhance the pyroptosis process. Collectively, the obtained Pluronic F127-modified CCCP-incorporated ZIF-8 NPs (F127ZIF-8CCCP NPs) activate antitumor immunity and reprogram immunosuppressive tumor microenvironment (TME), realizing high-efficiency tumor growth inhibition. This work will facilitate biomedicine applications of ZIF-8 and provide good inspiration for pyroptosis-induced cancer therapy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OASL phase condensation induces amyloid-like fibrillation of RIPK3 to promote virus-induced necroptosis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36604592/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36604592/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;RIPK3-ZBP1-MLKL-mediated necroptosis is a proinflammatory cell death process that is crucial for antiviral host defence. RIPK3 self-oligomerization and autophosphorylation are prerequisites for executing necroptosis, yet the underlying mechanism of virus-induced RIPK3 activation remains elusive. Interferon-inducible 2&amp;rsquo;-5&amp;rsquo; oligoadenylate synthetase-like (OASL) protein is devoid of enzymatic function but displays potent antiviral activity. Here we describe a role of OASL as a virus-induced necroptosis promoter that scaffolds the RIPK3-ZBP1 non-canonical necrosome via liquid-like phase condensation. This liquid-like platform of OASL recruits RIPK3 and ZBP1 via protein-protein interactions to provide spatial segregation for RIPK3 nucleation. This process facilitates the amyloid-like fibril formation and activation of RIPK3 and thereby MLKL phosphorylation for necroptosis. Mice deficient in Oasl1 exhibit severely impaired necroptosis and attenuated inflammation after viral infection, resulting in uncontrolled viral dissemination and lethality. Our study demonstrates an interferon-induced innate response whereby OASL scaffolds RIPK3-ZBP1 assembly via its phase-separated liquid droplets to facilitate necroptosis-mediated antiviral immunity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Role of necroptosis in kidney health and disease</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/36596919/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/36596919/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Key points&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Necroptosis is a form of programmed cell death that leads to cell lysis and an inflammatory response in neighbouring tissues; dysregulation of the pathway is widely implicated in kidney diseases.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The core regulators of the necroptosis pathway are the kinases, RIPK1 and RIPK3, and the executioner pseudokinase, MLKL; each of these proteins is regulated by diverse interactions and modifications.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Most experimental studies of necroptosis in kidney diseases have been performed in rodent models of disease; further studies are therefore essential to define the contribution of this cell death mode to human kidney diseases.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RIPK1 inhibitors are currently being explored in clinical trials to treat neuronal and inflammatory diseases, but so far, the results have not been convincing; future trials are required to establish the viability of targeting necroptosis in kidney diseases.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cell death, particularly that of tubule epithelial cells, contributes critically to the pathophysiology of kidney disease. A body of evidence accumulated over the past 15 years has ascribed a central pathophysiological role to a particular form of regulated necrosis, termed necroptosis, to acute tubular necrosis, nephron loss and maladaptive renal fibrogenesis. Unlike apoptosis, which is a non-immunogenic process, necroptosis results in the release of cellular contents and cytokines, which triggers an inflammatory response in neighbouring tissue. This necroinflammatory environment can lead to severe organ dysfunction and cause lasting tissue injury in the kidney. Despite evidence of a link between necroptosis and various kidney diseases, there are no available therapeutic options to target this process. Greater understanding of the molecular mechanisms, triggers and regulators of necroptosis in acute and chronic kidney diseases may identify shortcomings in current approaches to therapeutically target necroptosis regulators and lead to the development of innovative therapeutic approaches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PANoptosis-like cell death in ischemia/reperfusion injury of retinal neurons</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35900430/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35900430/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We screened small molecules to identify two compounds, which we named RSL3 and RSL5, that have increased lethality in the presence of oncogenic RAS. Counter screening with biologically active compounds defined aspects of the mechanism of action for RSL3 and RSL5, such as a nonapoptotic, MEK-dependent, and iron-dependent oxidative cell death. Erastin, a previously reported compound with RAS-selective lethality, showed similar properties. RNA interference experiments targeting voltage-dependent anion channel 3 (VDAC3), a target of erastin, demonstrated that RSL5 is a scaffold that acts through VDACs to activate the observed pathway. RSL3 activated a similar death mechanism but in a VDAC-independent manner. We found that cells transformed with oncogenic RAS have increased iron content relative to their normal cell counterparts through upregulation of transferrin receptor 1 and downregulation of ferritin heavy chain 1 and ferritin light chain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Necroptosis signaling and NLRP3 inflammasome cross-talking in epithelium facilitate Pseudomonas aeruginosa mediated lung injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36470578/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36470578/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Recently, although there is an amount of research just focus on ALI/ ARDS pathophysiological analysis, the development of therapies based on specific molecular targets are still lacking.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cross-talking between necroptosis and inflammasome in epithelium promotes pathological damage of ALI.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ROS inhibitor Mito-TEMPO blocks inflammasome to alleviate inflammation of ALI, which could be a potential therapeutic target for acute lung injury.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pseudomonas aeruginosa induced acute lung injury is such a serious risk to public health, but the pathological regulation remains unclear. Here, we reported that PA mediated epithelial necroptosis plays an important role in pathological process. Pharmacological and genomic ablation of necroptosis signaling ameliorate PA mediated ALI and pulmonary inflammation. Our results further proved NLRP3 inflammasome to involve in the process. Mechanism investigation revealed the cross-talking between inflammasome activation and necroptosis that MLKL-dependent necroptosis signaling promotes the change of mitochondrial membrane potential for the release of reactive oxygen species (ROS), which is the important trigger for functional inflammasome activation. Furthermore, antioxidants such as Mito-TEMPO was confirmed to significantly restrain inflammasome activation in epithelium, resulting in a reduction in PA induced pulmonary inflammation. Taken together, our findings revealed that necroptosis-triggered NLRP3 inflammasome in epithelium plays a crucial role in PA mediated injury, which could be a potential therapeutic target for pulmonary inflammation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cannabinoid Receptor 2-Centric Molecular Feedback Loop Drives Necroptosis in Diabetic Heart Injuries</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36448459/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36448459/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Diabetic heart dysfunction is a common complication of diabetes. Cell death is a core event that leads to diabetic heart dysfunction. However, the time sequence of cell death pathways and the precise time to intervene of particular cell death type remain largely unknown in the diabetic heart. This study aims to identify the particular cell death type that is responsible for diabetic heart dysfunction and to propose a promising therapeutic strategy by intervening in the cell death pathway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; Type 2 diabetes models were established using db/db leptin receptor-deficient mice and high-fat diet/streptozotocin-induced mice. The type 1 diabetes model was established in streptozotocin-induced mice. Apoptosis and programmed cell necrosis (necroptosis) were detected in diabetic mouse hearts at different ages. G protein-coupled receptor-targeted drug library was searched to identify potential receptors regulating the key cell death pathway. Pharmacological and genetic approaches that modulate the expression of targets were used. Stable cell lines and a homemade phosphorylation antibody were prepared to conduct mechanistic studies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; Necroptosis was activated after apoptosis at later stages of diabetes and was functionally responsible for cardiac dysfunction. Cannabinoid receptor 2 (CB2R) was a key regulator of necroptosis. Mechanically, during normal glucose levels, CB2R inhibited S6 kinase-mediated phosphorylation of BACH2 at serine 520, thereby leading to BACH2 translocation to the nucleus, where BACH2 transcriptionally repressed the necroptosis genes Rip1, Rip3, and Mlkl. Under hyperglycemic conditions, high glucose induced CB2R internalization in a β-arrestin 2-dependent manner; thereafter, MLKL (mixed lineage kinase domain-like), but not receptor-interacting protein kinase 1 or 3, phosphorylated CB2R at serine 352 and promoted CB2R degradation by ubiquitin modification. Cardiac re-expression of CB2R rescued diabetes-induced cardiomyocyte necroptosis and heart dysfunction, whereas cardiac knockout of Bach2 diminished CB2R-mediated beneficial effects. In human diabetic hearts, both CB2R and BACH2 were negatively associated with diabetes-induced myocardial injuries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; CB2R transcriptionally repressed necroptosis through interaction with BACH2; in turn, MLKL formed a negative feedback to phosphorylate CB2R. Our study provides the integrative view of a novel molecular mechanism loop for regulation of necroptosis centered by CB2R, which represents a promising alternative strategy for controlling diabetic heart dysfunction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mitochondrial citrate accumulation drives alveolar epithelial cell necroptosis in lipopolysaccharide-induced acute lung injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36443565/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36443565/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Necroptosis is the major cause of death in alveolar epithelial cells (AECs) during acute lung injury (ALI). Here, we report a previously unrecognized mechanism for necroptosis. We found an accumulation of mitochondrial citrate (citratemt) in lipopolysaccharide (LPS)-treated AECs because of the downregulation of Idh3α and citrate carrier (CIC, also known as Slc25a1). shRNA- or inhibitor-mediated inhibition of Idh3α and Slc25a1 induced citratemt accumulation and necroptosis in vitro. Mice with AEC-specific Idh3α and Slc25a1 deficiency exhibited exacerbated lung injury and AEC necroptosis. Interestingly, the overexpression of Idh3α and Slc25a1 decreased citratemt levels and rescued AECs from necroptosis. Mechanistically, citratemt accumulation induced mitochondrial fission and excessive mitophagy in AECs. Furthermore, citratemt directly interacted with FUN14 domain-containing protein 1 (FUNDC1) and promoted the interaction of FUNDC1 with dynamin-related protein 1 (DRP1), leading to excessive mitophagy-mediated necroptosis and thereby initiating and promoting ALI. Importantly, necroptosis induced by citratemt accumulation was inhibited in FUNDC1-knockout AECs. We show that citratemt accumulation is a novel target for protection against ALI involving necroptosis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Single cell analysis of PANoptosome cell death complexes through an expansion microscopy method</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36169732/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36169732/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In response to infection or sterile insults, inflammatory programmed cell death is an essential component of the innate immune response to remove infected or damaged cells. PANoptosis is a unique innate immune inflammatory cell death pathway regulated by multifaceted macromolecular complexes called PANoptosomes, which integrate components from other cell death pathways. Growing evidence shows that PANoptosis can be triggered in many physiological conditions, including viral and bacterial infections, cytokine storms, and cancers. However, PANoptosomes at the single cell level have not yet been fully characterized. Initial investigations have suggested that key pyroptotic, apoptotic, and necroptotic molecules including the inflammasome adaptor protein ASC, apoptotic caspase-8 (CASP8), and necroptotic RIPK3 are conserved components of PANoptosomes. Here, we optimized an immunofluorescence procedure to probe the highly dynamic multiprotein PANoptosome complexes across various innate immune cell death-inducing conditions. We first identified and validated antibodies to stain endogenous mouse ASC, CASP8, and RIPK3, without residual staining in the respective knockout cells. We then assessed the formation of PANoptosomes across innate immune cell death-inducing conditions by monitoring the colocalization of ASC with CASP8 and/or RIPK3. Finally, we established an expansion microscopy procedure using these validated antibodies to image the organization of ASC, CASP8, and RIPK3 within the PANoptosome. This optimized protocol, which can be easily adapted to study other multiprotein complexes and other cell death triggers, provides confirmation of PANoptosome assembly in individual cells and forms the foundation for a deeper molecular understanding of the PANoptosome complex and PANoptosis to facilitate therapeutic targeting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>E-prostanoid 3 receptor deficiency on myeloid cells protects against ischemic acute kidney injury via breaking the auto-amplification loop of necroinflammation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36087809/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36087809/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Necroinflammation plays an important role in disease settings such as acute kidney injury (AKI). We and others have elucidated that prostaglandins, which are critically involved in inflammation, may activate E-prostanoid 3 receptor (EP3) at low concentrations. However, how EP3 blockade interacts with regulated cell death and affects AKI remains unknown. In this study, AKI was induced by ischemia-reperfusion (30 minutes/24 hours) in Ep3 knockout (&lt;em&gt;Ep3&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt;), bone marrow chimeric, myeloid conditional EP3 knockout and corresponding control mice. The production of prostaglandins E2 and I2 was markedly increased after ischemia-reperfusion, and either abrogation or antagonism of EP3 ameliorated the injury. EP3 deficiency curbed inflammatory cytokine release, neutrophil infiltration and serum high-mobility group box 1 levels, but additional TLR4 inhibition with TAK-242 did not offer further protection against the injury and inflammation. The protection of &lt;em&gt;Ep3&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; was predominantly mediated by suppressing Mixed Lineage Kinase domain-Like-dependent necroptosis, resulting from the inhibition of cytokine generation and the switching of cell death modality from necroptosis to apoptosis through caspase-8 up-regulation, in part due to the restraint of IL-6/JAK2/STAT3 signaling. EP3 deficiency failed to further alleviate the injury when necroptosis was inhibited. &lt;em&gt;Ep3&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; in bone marrow-derived cells, particularly that in myeloid cells, protected kidneys to the same extent as that of global EP3 deletion. Thus, our results demonstrate that EP3 deficiency especially that on myeloid cells, ameliorates ischemic AKI via curbing inflammation and breaking the auto-amplification loop of necroinflammation. Hence, EP3 may be a promising target for the prevention and/or treatment of AKI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Acteoside attenuates RSV-induced lung injury by suppressing necroptosis and regulating metabolism</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36059973/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36059973/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Necroptosis and inflammation are closely related to the pathogenesis of respiratory syncytial virus (RSV). Acteoside (AC), a natural phenylpropanoid glycoside from Kuding Tea, has significant anti-RSV effect. However, the roles of AC on RSV-induced lung necroptosis and inflammation are yet to be elucidated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; The effects of AC were investigated in BALB/c mice and A549 cells. Lung histopathology was observed through H&amp;amp;E staining. The viral titer was assessed via plaque assay. The RSV-F expression was determined by RT-qPCR and immunohistochemistry assay. The levels of cytokines were detected by ELISA and RT-qPCR. The necroptosis rate and mitochondrial membrane potential were evaluated via flow cytometry. The expressions of HMGB1/NF-κB and RIP1/RIP3/MLKL/PGAM5/DRP1 were detected by western blot. Additionally, untargeted metabolomics was conducted to investigate the metabolic profiles and related metabolic pathways via Gas Chromatography-Mass Spectrometry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; The results showed that compared with the RSV-infected group, AC treatment significantly attenuated lung pathological damage, virus replication, and cytokines levels. AC also alleviated RSV-induced necroptosis and mitochondrial dysfunction &lt;em&gt;in vitro&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt;. Moreover, AC treatment down-regulated the expression of HMGB1, p-Iκbα/Iκbα, p-p65/p65, RIP1, RIP3, MLKL, PGAM5, and DRP1. Furthermore, metabolomic analyses suggested that the perturbations in major metabolites of AC therapy were related to variations in amino acid and energy metabolism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/em&gt; Our findings validated the beneficial effects of AC in suppressing necroptosis and regulating metabolism, suggesting AC may be a new drug candidate for RSV infection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Identification of programmed cell death-related gene signature and associated regulatory axis in cerebral ischemia/reperfusion injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35991562/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35991562/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Numerous studies have suggested that programmed cell death (PCD) pathways play vital roles in cerebral ischemia/reperfusion (I/R) injury. However, the specific mechanisms underlying cell death during cerebral I/R injury have yet to be completely clarified. There is thus a need to identify the PCD-related gene signatures and the associated regulatory axes in cerebral I/R injury, which should provide novel therapeutic targets against cerebral I/R injury.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; We analyzed transcriptome signatures of brain tissue samples from mice subjected to middle cerebral artery occlusion/reperfusion (MCAO/R) and matched controls, and identified differentially expressed genes related to the three types of PCD(apoptosis, pyroptosis, and necroptosis). We next performed functional enrichment analysis and constructed PCD-related competing endogenous RNA (ceRNA) regulatory networks. We also conducted hub gene analysis to identify hub nodes and key regulatory axes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; Fifteen PCD-related genes were identified. Functional enrichment analysis showed that they were particularly associated with corresponding PCD-related biological processes, inflammatory response, and reactive oxygen species metabolic processes. The apoptosis-related ceRNA regulatory network was constructed, which included 24 long noncoding RNAs (lncRNAs), 41 microRNAs (miRNAs), and 4 messenger RNAs (mRNAs); the necroptosis-related ceRNA regulatory network included 16 lncRNAs, 20 miRNAs, and 6 mRNAs; and the pyroptosis-related ceRNA regulatory network included 15 lncRNAs, 18 miRNAs, and 6 mRNAs. Hub gene analysis identified hub nodes in each PCD-related ceRNA regulatory network and seven key regulatory axes in total, namely, lncRNA Malat1/miR-181a-5p/Mapt, lncRNA Malat1/miR-181b-5p/Mapt, lncRNA Neat1/miR-181a-5p/Mapt, and lncRNA Neat1/miR-181b-5p/Mapt for the apoptosis-related ceRNA regulatory network; lncRNA Neat1/miR-181a-5p/Tnf for the necroptosis-related ceRNA regulatory network; lncRNA Malat1/miR-181c-5p/Tnf for the pyroptosis-related ceRNA regulatory network; and lncRNAMalat1/miR-181a-5p for both necroptosis-related and pyroptosis-related ceRNA regulatory networks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/em&gt; The results of this study supported the hypothesis that these PCD pathways (apoptosis, necroptosis, pyroptosis, and PANoptosis) and crosstalk among them might be involved in ischemic stroke and that the key nodes and regulatory axes identified in this study might play vital roles in regulating the above processes. This may offer new insights into the potential mechanisms underlying cell death during cerebral I/R injury and provide new therapeutic targets for neuroprotection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Necroptosis-Mediated eCIRP Release in Sepsis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35873387/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35873387/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Erratum in:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Erratum: &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.2147/JIR.S383613&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Necroptosis-Mediated eCIRP Release in Sepsis&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Introduction:&lt;/em&gt; Extracellular cold-inducible RNA-binding protein (eCIRP) is an endogenous pro-inflammatory mediator that exacerbates injury in inflammation and sepsis. The mechanisms in which eCIRP is released have yet to be fully explored. Necroptosis is a programmed cell death that is dependent on the activation of mixed lineage kinase domain-like pseudo kinase (MLKL) which causes the release of damage-associated molecular patterns. We hypothesize that eCIRP is released through necroptosis and intensifies inflammation in sepsis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; RAW264.7 cells were treated with pan-caspase inhibitor z-VAD (15 μM) 1 h before stimulation with LPS (1 μg/mL). Necroptosis inhibitor, Necrostatin-1 (Nec-1) (10 μM) was added to the cells with LPS simultaneously. After 24 h of LPS stimulation, cytotoxicity was determined by LDH assay. eCIRP levels in the culture supernatants and phospho-MLKL (p-MLKL) from cell lysates were assessed by Western blot. p-MLKL interaction with the cell membrane was visualized by immunofluorescence. Sepsis was induced in C57BL/6 mice by cecal ligation and puncture (CLP). Mice were treated with Nec-1 (1 mg/kg) or DMSO. 20 h post-surgery, serum and peritoneal fluid levels of eCIRP, TNF-α and IL-6 were determined by ELISA. H&amp;amp;E staining of lung tissue sections was performed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; We found that in RAW264.7 cells, LPS+z-VAD induces necroptosis as evidenced by an increase in p-MLKL levels and causes eCIRP release. Nec-1 reduces both p-MLKL activation and eCIRP release in LPS+z-VAD-treated RAW264.7 cells. Nec-1 also inhibits the release of eCIRP, TNF-α and IL-6 in the serum and peritoneal fluid in CLP-induced septic mice. We predicted a transient interaction between eCIRP and MLKL using a computational model, suggesting that eCIRP may exit the cell via the pores formed by p-MLKL.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/em&gt; Necroptosis is a novel mechanism of eCIRP release in sepsis. Targeting necroptosis may ameliorate inflammation and injury in sepsis by inhibiting eCIRP release.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Innate Immune Cell Death in Neuroinflammation and Alzheimer&#39;s Disease</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/35741014/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/35741014/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alzheimer&amp;rsquo;s disease (AD) is a neurodegenerative disorder molecularly characterized by the formation of amyloid β (Aβ) plaques and type 2 microtubule-associated protein (Tau) abnormalities. Multiple studies have shown that many of the brain&amp;rsquo;s immunological cells, specifically microglia and astrocytes, are involved in AD pathogenesis. Cells of the innate immune system play an essential role in eliminating pathogens but also regulate brain homeostasis and AD. When activated, innate immune cells can cause programmed cell death through multiple pathways, including pyroptosis, apoptosis, necroptosis, and PANoptosis. The cell death often results in the release of proinflammatory cytokines that propagate the innate immune response and can eliminate Aβ plaques and aggregated Tau proteins. However, chronic neuroinflammation, which can result from cell death, has been linked to neurodegenerative diseases and can worsen AD. Therefore, the innate immune response must be tightly balanced to appropriately clear these AD-related structural abnormalities without inducing chronic neuroinflammation. In this review, we discuss neuroinflammation, innate immune responses, inflammatory cell death pathways, and cytokine secretion as they relate to AD. Therapeutic strategies targeting these innate immune cell death mechanisms will be critical to consider for future preventive or palliative treatments for AD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MG53 Inhibits Necroptosis Through Ubiquitination-Dependent RIPK1 Degradation for Cardiac Protection Following Ischemia/Reperfusion Injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35711363/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35711363/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rationale:&lt;/em&gt; While reactive oxygen species (ROS) has been recognized as one of the main causes of cardiac injury following myocardial infarction, the clinical application of antioxidants has shown limited effects on protecting hearts against ischemia-reperfusion (I/R) injury. Thus, the precise role of ROS following cardiac injury remains to be fully elucidated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Objective:&lt;/em&gt; We investigated the role of mitsugumin 53 (MG53) in regulating necroptosis following I/R injury to the hearts and the involvement of ROS in MG53-mediated cardioprotection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods and results:&lt;/em&gt; Antioxidants were used to test the role of ROS in MG53-mediated cardioprotection in the mouse model of I/R injury and induced human pluripotent stem cells (hiPSCs)-derived cardiomyocytes subjected to hypoxia or re-oxygenation (H/R) injury. Western blotting and co-immunoprecipitation were used to identify potential cell death pathways that MG53 was involved in. CRISPR/Cas 9-mediated genome editing and mutagenesis assays were performed to further identify specific interaction amino acids between MG53 and its ubiquitin E3 ligase substrate. We found that MG53 could protect myocardial injury via inhibiting the necroptosis pathway. Upon injury, the generation of ROS in the infarct zone of the hearts promoted interaction between MG53 and receptor-interacting protein kinase 1 (RIPK1). As an E3 ubiquitin ligase, MG53 added multiple ubiquitin chains to RIPK1 at the sites of K316, K604, and K627 for proteasome-mediated RIPK1 degradation and inhibited necroptosis. The application of N-acetyl cysteine (NAC) disrupted the interaction between MG53 and RIPK1 and abolished MG53-mediated cardioprotective effects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; Taken together, this study provided a molecular mechanism of a potential beneficial role of ROS following acute myocardial infarction. Thus, fine-tuning ROS levels might be critical for cardioprotection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Osmotic stress activates RIPK3/MLKL-mediated necroptosis by increasing cytosolic pH through a plasma membrane Na&#43;/H&#43; exchanger</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35580168/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35580168/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Necroptosis is a form of cell death triggered by stimuli such as the tumor necrosis factor family of cytokines, which induce necrotic cell death through the RIPK1-RIPK3-MLKL pathway. We report here that necroptosis is also activated by extracellular osmotic stresses. Unlike the previously identified inducers of necroptosis, osmotic stress stimulated necroptosis through the direct activation of the kinase activity of RIPK3 by an increase in cytosolic pH mediated by the Na&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt;/H&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; exchanger SLC9A1. Knockout, knockdown, or chemical inhibition of SLC9A1 blocked necroptosis induced by osmotic stresses. Moreover, setting intracellular pH at above-physiological values directly activated RIPK3 and necroptosis. The activation of RIPK3 by osmotic stresses did not require its RHIM domain, the protein-interacting domain required for the activation of RIPK3 when cells respond to other previously identified necroptotic stimuli. These results thus delineate a pathway that activates necroptosis in response to osmotic stresses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A novel small molecule Hsp90 inhibitor, C-316-1, attenuates acute kidney injury by suppressing RIPK1-mediated inflammation and necroptosis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35588657/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35588657/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Acute kidney injury (AKI) is marked by a fast deterioration of the kidney function that may be caused by a variety of factors and there is still no effective treatment for AKI.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A novel small molecule Hsp90 inhibitor, C-316-1, prevented necroptosis and inflammation in cisplatin- and ischemia/reperfusion-induced in vitro and in vivo via binding with R46, E47 and S50 in Cdc37 binding site of Hsp90.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;C-316-1 is a novel Hsp90 inhibitor with high efficiency in treatment of AKI and Hsp90 may serve as a potential therapeutic target for AKI.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acute kidney injury (AKI) is marked by a fast deterioration of the kidney function that may be caused by a variety of factors. Recently, although our group found that PPBICA alleviated programmed cell death in AKI, poor water solubility limited its bioavailability. In this research, we screened a series of derivatives and found that C-316-1 had the best suppressive effect on preventing necroptosis and inflammation in cisplatin- and ischemia/reperfusion-induced AKI in vitro and in vivo with lower toxicity and better water solubility. Mass spectrometry results showed that C-316-1 bound to heat shock protein 90 (Hsp90), which was further confirmed by molecular docking and surface plasmon resonance. Additionally, the Hsp90 expression was upregulated in the blood and tissues of AKI patients. We discovered that C-316-1 decreased the RIPK1 protein level without affecting its mRNA expression. The proteasome inhibitor, MG132 restored the level of RIPK1 reduced by C-316-1, suggesting that C-316-1 limits necroptosis by promoting the degradation of RIPK1 rather than by reducing its production. Immunoprecipitation further showed that pretreatment with C-316-1 disrupted the Hsp90-Cdc37 protein-protein Interactions (PPIs). Thereby, C-316-1 inhibited the Hsp90-Cdc37 complex formation and led to a significant decrease in RIPK1, which in turn reduced necroptosis. Moreover, C-316-1 treatment did not protect against kidney injury in vivo and in vitro when Hsp90 was knocked down and R46, E47, and S50 in Cdc37 binding site of Hsp90 might form an important active pocket with C-316-1. These findings suggest that C-316-1 is a potential therapeutic agent against RIPK1-Mediated Necroptosis in AKI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DEAD/H-Box Helicases in Immunity, Inflammation, Cell Differentiation, and Cell Death and Disease</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/35626643/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/35626643/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DEAD/H-box proteins are the largest family of RNA helicases in mammalian genomes, and they are present in all kingdoms of life. Since their discovery in the late 1980s, DEAD/H-box family proteins have been a major focus of study. They have been found to play central roles in RNA metabolism, gene expression, signal transduction, programmed cell death, and the immune response to bacterial and viral infections. Aberrant functions of DEAD/H-box proteins have been implicated in a wide range of human diseases that include cancer, neurodegeneration, and inherited genetic disorders. In this review, we provide a historical context and discuss the molecular functions of DEAD/H-box proteins, highlighting the recent discoveries linking their dysregulation to human diseases. We will also discuss the state of knowledge regarding two specific DEAD/H-box proteins that have critical roles in immune responses and programmed cell death, DDX3X and DDX58, also known as RIG-I. Given their importance in homeostasis and disease, an improved understanding of DEAD/H-box protein biology and protein-protein interactions will be critical for informing strategies to counteract the pathogenesis associated with several human diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cortactin loss protects against hemin-induced acute lung injury in sickle cell disease</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35503995/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35503995/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In patients with sickle cell disease (SCD), acute chest syndrome (ACS) is a common form of acute lung injury and a major cause of morbidity and mortality. The pathophysiology of ACS is complex, and hemin, the prosthetic moiety of hemoglobin, has been implicated in endothelial cell (EC) activation and subsequent acute lung injury (ALI) and ACS in vitro and in animal studies. Here, we examined the role of cortactin (CTTN), a cytoskeletal protein that regulates EC function, in response to hemin-induced ALI and ACS. Cortactin heterozygous (&lt;em&gt;Cttn&lt;sup&gt;+/-&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt;) mice (n = 8) and their wild-type siblings (n = 8) were irradiated and subsequently received bone marrow cells (BMCs) extruded from the femurs of SCD mice (SS) to generate SS &lt;em&gt;Cttn&lt;sup&gt;+/-&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; and SS &lt;em&gt;Cttn&lt;sup&gt;WT&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; chimeras. Following hemoglobin electrophoretic proof of BMC transplantation, the mice received 35 µmol/kg of hemin. Within 24 h, surviving mice were euthanized, and bronchoalveolar fluid (BAL) and lung samples were analyzed. For in vitro studies, human lung microvascular endothelial cells (HLMVECs) were used to determine hemin-induced changes in gene expression and reactive oxygen species (ROS) generation in cortactin deficiency and control conditions. When compared with wild-type littermates, the mortality for SS &lt;em&gt;Cttn&lt;sup&gt;+/-&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; mice trended to be lower after hemin infusion and these mice exhibited less severe lung injury and less necroptotic cell death. In vitro studies confirmed that cortactin deficiency is protective against hemin-induced injury in HMLVECs, by decreasing protein expression of p38/HSP27, improving cell barrier function, and decreasing the production of ROS. Further studies examining the role of CTTN in ACS are warranted and may open a new avenue of potential treatment for this devastating disease.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It&#39;s All in the PAN: Crosstalk, Plasticity, Redundancies, Switches, and Interconnectedness Encompassed by PANoptosis Underlying the Totality of Cell Death-Associated Biological Effects</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/35563804/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/35563804/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The innate immune system provides the first line of defense against cellular perturbations. Innate immune activation elicits inflammatory programmed cell death in response to microbial infections or alterations in cellular homeostasis. Among the most well-characterized programmed cell death pathways are pyroptosis, apoptosis, and necroptosis. While these pathways have historically been defined as segregated and independent processes, mounting evidence shows significant crosstalk among them. These molecular interactions have been described as &amp;lsquo;crosstalk&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;plasticity&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;redundancies&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;molecular switches&amp;rsquo;, and more. Here, we discuss the key components of cell death pathways and note several examples of crosstalk. We then explain how the diverse descriptions of crosstalk throughout the literature can be interpreted through the lens of an integrated inflammatory cell death concept, PANoptosis. The totality of biological effects in PANoptosis cannot be individually accounted for by pyroptosis, apoptosis, or necroptosis alone. We also discuss PANoptosomes, which are multifaceted macromolecular complexes that regulate PANoptosis. We consider the evidence for PANoptosis, which has been mechanistically characterized during influenza A virus, herpes simplex virus 1, Francisella novicida, and Yersinia infections, as well as in response to altered cellular homeostasis, in inflammatory diseases, and in cancers. We further discuss the role of IRF1 as an upstream regulator of PANoptosis and conclude by reexamining historical studies which lend credence to the PANoptosis concept. Cell death has been shown to play a critical role in infections, inflammatory diseases, neurodegenerative diseases, cancers, and more; therefore, having a holistic understanding of cell death is important for identifying new therapeutic strategies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>L-OPA1 deficiency aggravates necroptosis of alveolar epithelial cells through impairing mitochondrial function during acute lung injury in mice</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35478455/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35478455/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Necroptosis, a recently described form of programmed cell death, is the main way of alveolar epithelial cells (AECs) death in acute lung injury (ALI). While the mechanism of how to trigger necroptosis in AECs during ALI has been rarely evaluated. Long optic atrophy protein 1 (L-OPA1) is a crucial mitochondrial inner membrane fusion protein, and its deficiency impairs mitochondrial function. This study aimed to investigate the role of L-OPA1 deficiency-mediated mitochondrial dysfunction in AECs necroptosis. We comprehensively investigated the detailed contribution and molecular mechanism of L-OPA1 deficiency in AECs necroptosis by inhibiting or activating L-OPA1. First, our data showed that L-OPA1 expression was downregulated in the lungs and AECs under the lipopolysaccharide (LPS) challenge. Furthermore, inhibition of L-OPA1 aggravated the pathological injury, inflammatory response, and necroptosis in the lungs of LPS-induced ALI mice. In vitro, inhibition of L-OPA1 induced necroptosis of AECs, while activation of L-OPA1 alleviated necroptosis of AECs under the LPS challenge. Mechanistically, inhibition of L-OPA1 aggravated necroptosis of AECs by inducing mitochondrial fragmentation and reducing mitochondrial membrane potential. While activation of L-OPA1 had the opposite effects. In summary, these findings indicate for the first time that L-OPA1 deficiency mediates mitochondrial fragmentation, induces necroptosis of AECs, and exacerbates ALI in mice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TLR2/caspase-5/Panx1 pathway mediates necrosis-induced NLRP3 inflammasome activation in macrophages during acute kidney injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35473933/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35473933/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acute kidney injury (AKI) is characterized by necroinflammation formed by necrotic tubular epithelial cells (TECs) and interstitial inflammation. In necroinflammation, macrophages are key inflammatory cells and can be activated and polarized into proinflammatory macrophages. Membranous Toll-like receptors (TLRs) can cooperate with intracellular NOD-like receptor protein 3 (NLRP3) to recognize danger signals from necrotic TECs and activate proinflammatory macrophages by assembling NLRP3 inflammasome. However, the cooperation between TLRs and NLRP3 is still unclear. Using conditioned medium from necrotic TECs, we confirmed that necrotic TECs could release danger signals to activate NLRP3 inflammasome in macrophages. We further identified that necrotic TECs-induced NLRP3 inflammasome activation was dependent on ATP secretion via Pannexin-1 (Panx1) channel in macrophages. Next, we verified that TLR2 was required for the activation of Panx1 and NLRP3 in macrophages. Mechanistically, we indicated that caspase-5 mediated TLR2-induced Panx1 activation. In addition, we showed that necrotic TECs-induced activation of TLR2/caspase-5/Panx1 axis could be decreased in macrophages when TECs was protected by N-acetylcysteine (NAC). Overall, we demonstrate that danger signals from necrotic TECs could activate NLRP3 inflammasome in macrophages via TLR2/caspase-5/Panx1 axis during AKI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cineole alleviates the BPA-inhibited NETs formation by regulating the p38 pathway-mediated programmed cell death</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35483150/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35483150/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;BPA inhibited the release of NETs by inducing necroptosis and apoptosis.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CIN can alleviate the oxidative stress and programmed cell death induced by BPA.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CIN via p38 pathway alleviates BPA-induced neutrophil injury.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enriched the research on toxicology of BPA and detoxification mechanism of CIN.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bisphenol A (BPA) is an endocrine disruptor, that can cause immune dysfunction. Cineole (CIN) has that effect of regulating immune function and resist oxidation. Neutrophil extracellular traps (NETs) are one of the ways to resist pathogen invasion. In order to explore the effects of BPA and CIN on the release of chicken NETs and the antagonistic effect of CIN, take chicken peripheral blood neutrophils as object of study, grouping as NC, CIN, BPA + CIN and BPA. SEM, flow cytometry, RT-PCR, Western-blot and other methods were used to detect related indicators. The results showed that BPA inhibited the activities of GPX, SOD and CAT, increased the contents of MDA and NO, increased the activity of iNOS. BPA exposure inhibited the expression of myeloperoxidase (MPO), neutrophil elastase (NE) and histone, and inhibited the release of NETs. BPA activated downstream apoptosis and necroptosis through the p38 mitogen-activated protein kinase (p38-MAPK) pathway, which increased the expression of cytochrome C (CytC), bcl-2 associated K protein gene (bak), cysteinyl aspartate specific proteinase 3 (caspase-3), cysteinyl aspartate specific proteinase 9 (caspase-9), receptor-interacting protein kinase 1 (RIPK1), receptor-interacting protein kinase 1 (RIPK3) and mixed lineage kinase domain-like protein (MLKL), decreased the expression of B-cell lymphoma-2 (bcl-2). However, the co-exposure of CIN and BPA partially recovered the release of NETs, alleviated BPA-induced oxidative stress, and inhibited the activation of p38-MAPK pathway, necroptosis, and mitochondrial apoptosis pathway. These results indicated that CIN modulated p38 pathway alleviated BPA-induced neutrophil necroptosis and apoptosis, and increased NETs formation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Impairment of Mitochondrial ATP Synthesis Induces RIPK3-dependent Necroptosis in Lung Epithelial Cells During Lung Injury by Lung Inflammation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35573150/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35573150/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dysfunction of mitochondrial metabolism is implicated in cellular injury and cell death. While mitochondrial dysfunction is associated with lung injury by lung inflammation, the mechanism by which the impairment of mitochondrial ATP synthesis regulates necroptosis during acute lung injury (ALI) by lung inflammation is unclear. Here, we showed that the impairment of mitochondrial ATP synthesis induces receptor interacting serine/threonine kinase 3 (RIPK3)-dependent necroptosis during lung injury by lung inflammation. We found that the impairment of mitochondrial ATP synthesis by oligomycin, an inhibitor of ATP synthase, resulted in increased lung injury and RIPK3 levels in lung tissues during lung inflammation by LPS in mice. The elevated RIPK3 and RIPK3 phosphorylation levels by oligomycin resulted in high mixed lineage kinase domain-like (MLKL) phosphorylation, the terminal molecule in necroptotic cell death pathway, in lung epithelial cells during lung inflammation. Moreover, the levels of protein in bronchoalveolar lavage fluid (BALF) were increased by the activation of necroptosis via oligomycin during lung inflammation. Furthermore, the levels of ATP5A, a catalytic subunit of the mitochondrial ATP synthase complex for ATP synthesis, were reduced in lung epithelial cells of lung tissues from patients with acute respiratory distress syndrome (ARDS), the most severe form of ALI. The levels of RIPK3, RIPK3 phosphorylation and MLKL phosphorylation were elevated in lung epithelial cells in patients with ARDS. Our results suggest that the impairment of mitochondrial ATP synthesis induces RIPK3-dependent necroptosis in lung epithelial cells during lung injury by lung inflammation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A strategy for attenuation of acute radiation-induced lung injury using crocetin from gardenia fruit</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35366531/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35366531/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Crocetin effectively alleviates acute radiation-induced lung injury in mice.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tnfrsf10b&lt;/em&gt; gene-mediated necroptosis is involved in radiation-induced lung injury.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Crocetin inhibits necroptosis through &lt;em&gt;Tnfrsf10b&lt;/em&gt; gene.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Purpose:&lt;/em&gt; Radiation-induced lung injury limits the implementation of radiotherapy plans and severely impairs the quality of life. Crocetin has the capability to protect against radiation. This study is aimed at estimate the preventive effect and mechanism of crocetin on acute radiation induced lung injury.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods and materials:&lt;/em&gt; In this study, we offer a strategy for radiation-induced lung injury by using crocetin, an extract of gardenia fruit. Histopathology, transcriptomics, flow cytometry, and other methods have served to examine the effect and mechanism of crocetin on acute radiation-induced lung injury.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; Crocetin effectively alleviates radiation-induced alveolar wall thickening and alveolar destruction. The number of normal alveoli and lung structure of mice is well protected by the prevention of crocetin. It is found that crocetin inhibits necroptosis to achieve effective radioprotection by down regulating the &lt;em&gt;Tnfrsf10b&lt;/em&gt; gene in vitro.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/em&gt; Crocetin inhibits necroptosis through transcriptional regulation of the &lt;em&gt;Tnfrsf10b&lt;/em&gt; gene, thereby preventing radiation-induced lung injury. This work may provide a new strategy for the prevention of lung radiation injury by the extract from Chinese herbal medicine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beneficial effects of aloperine on inflammation and oxidative stress by suppressing necroptosis in lipopolysaccharide-induced acute lung injury mouse model</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35397283/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35397283/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rationale:&lt;/em&gt; Alveolar epithelial cell death, inflammation, and oxidative stress are typical features of acute lung injury (ALI). Aloperine (Alo), an alkaloid isolated from Sophora alopecuroides, has been reported to display various biological effects, such as anti-inflammatory, immunoregulatory, and anti-oxidant properties. In this study, we investigated the effects and mechanisms of Alo in treating a lipopolysaccharide (LPS)-induced ALI in a murine model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; The effects of Alo in LPS-induced ALI were investigated in C57BL/6 mice. The RIPK1 inhibitor (Nec-1) and the RIPK3 inhibitor (GSK&#39;872) were used to evaluate the relationship of necroptosis, NF-κB activation, and PDC subunits in LPS-treated mouse alveolar epithelial cells (MLE-12). Then the effects of Alo on necroptosis, inflammation, and oxidative stress of LPS-stimulated MLE-12 cells were evaluated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; Alo significantly attenuated histopathological lung injuries and reduced lung wet/dry ratio in LPS-induced ALI mice. Alo also remarkedly reduced total protein and neutrophils recruitment in bronchoalveolar lavage fluid of ALI mice. Meanwhile, Alo ameliorated the LPS-induced necroptosis in the lungs of ALI mice. The RIPK3 inhibitor GSK&#39;872, but not the RIPK1 inhibitor Nec-1, reversed LPS-induced p65 phosphorylation and translocation to the nucleus in MLE-12 cells. GSK&#39;872 also reversed the LPS-induced increase in ROS and binding of RIPK3 and PDC subunits in MLE-12 cells. Moreover, Alo down-regulated the levels of p-RIPK1, p-RIPK3, p-MLKL, p-p65, the translocation of p65 to the nucleus, and reduced the expression of IL-6 and IL-8 in LPS-stimulated MLE-12 cells. Alo also inhibited the binding of RIPK3 and PDC-E1α, PDC-E1β, PDC-E2, and PDC-E3 and the ROS production in LPS-treated MLE-12 cells.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/em&gt; The present study validated the beneficial effects of Alo on LPS-induced ALI , suggesting Alo may be a new drug candidate against ALI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NLRC4 Deficiency Leads to Enhanced Phosphorylation of MLKL and Necroptosis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35301258/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35301258/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hosts rely on the innate immune system to clear pathogens in response to infection. Pathogen-associated molecular patterns bind to innate immune receptors and engage activation of downstream signaling to initiate a host immune response to fight infection. A key component of this innate response is programmed cell death. Recent work has highlighted significant cross-talk and functional redundancy between cell death pathways, leading to the discovery of PANoptosis, an inflammatory programmed cell death pathway dependent on PANoptosomes, which are innate immune danger-sensing complexes that activate inflammatory cell death and contain caspases with or without inflammasome components and receptor interacting protein homotypic interaction motif-containing proteins. Although PANoptosis has been characterized in response to a growing number of pathogens, inflammatory diseases, and cancer, its role and the functional consequences of PANoptotic component modulation during NLR family CARD domain-containing protein 4 (NLRC4) activation by &lt;em&gt;Pseudomonas aeruginosa&lt;/em&gt; infection remain unknown. In this study, we show that P. aeruginosa can induce PANoptosis in mouse bone marrow-derived macrophages (BMDMs). Only the combined deletion of caspase-1, -11, -8, and RIPK3 protected mouse BMDMs from cell death. Moreover, we showed that PANoptotic components act in a compensatory manner; in the absence of NAIP5 and NLRC4 during P. aeruginosa challenge, activation of caspase-1, -3, -7, and -8 was reduced, whereas alternative cell death molecules such as RIPK1 and MLKL were activated in mouse BMDMs. Taken together, these data highlight the extensive cross-talk between cell death signaling molecules and showcase the plasticity of the system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Osteopontin aggravates acute lung injury in influenza virus infection by promoting macrophages necroptosis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35246529/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35246529/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Infection with influenza A virus (IAV) can trigger pulmonary inflammation and lung damage. Osteopontin (OPN) is an essential regulator of cell death and immunity. However, the role and underlying mechanism of OPN in cell death in IAV-induced pulmonary injury remain poorly understood. Here, we demonstrated that OPN-deficient (OPN-/-) mice were insensitive to IAV, exhibiting decreased viral loads and attenuated lung injury after IAV infection compared to those in wild-type (WT) mice. Moreover, macrophage necroptosis was significantly reduced in OPN-/- mice infected with IAV compared to that in infected WT mice. OPN increased the expression of necroptosis-related genes and exacerbated macrophage necroptosis in IAV-infected THP1 cells. Notably, adoptive transfer of WT bone marrow-derived macrophages (BMDMs) or OPN-/- BMDMs into mice restored resistance to influenza infection, and the rescue effect of OPN-/- BMDMs was better than that of WT BMDMs. Collectively, these results suggest that OPN deficiency in macrophages reduces necroptosis, which leads to a decrease in viral titers and protects against IAV infection. Therefore, OPN is a potential target for the treatment of IAV infection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Phosphorylated NFS1 weakens oxaliplatin-based chemosensitivity of colorectal cancer by preventing PANoptosis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35221331/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35221331/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Metabolic enzymes have an indispensable role in metabolic reprogramming, and their aberrant expression or activity has been associated with chemosensitivity. Hence, targeting metabolic enzymes remains an attractive approach for treating tumors. However, the influence and regulation of cysteine desulfurase (NFS1), a rate-limiting enzyme in iron-sulfur (Fe-S) cluster biogenesis, in colorectal cancer (CRC) remain elusive. Here, using an in vivo metabolic enzyme gene-based clustered regularly interspaced short palindromic repeats (CRISPR)-Cas9 library screen, we revealed that loss of NFS1 significantly enhanced the sensitivity of CRC cells to oxaliplatin. In vitro and in vivo results showed that NFS1 deficiency synergizing with oxaliplatin triggered PANoptosis (apoptosis, necroptosis, pyroptosis, and ferroptosis) by increasing the intracellular levels of reactive oxygen species (ROS). Furthermore, oxaliplatin-based oxidative stress enhanced the phosphorylation level of serine residues of NFS1, which prevented PANoptosis in an S293 phosphorylation-dependent manner during oxaliplatin treatment. In addition, high expression of NFS1, transcriptionally regulated by MYC, was found in tumor tissues and was associated with poor survival and hyposensitivity to chemotherapy in patients with CRC. Overall, the findings of this study provided insights into the underlying mechanisms of NFS1 in oxaliplatin sensitivity and identified NFS1 inhibition as a promising strategy for improving the outcome of platinum-based chemotherapy in the treatment of CRC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Salt-inducible kinases inhibitor HG-9-91-01 targets RIPK3 kinase activity to alleviate necroptosis-mediated inflammatory injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35217652/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35217652/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Receptor-interacting protein kinase 3 (RIPK3) functions as a central regulator of necroptosis, mediating signaling transduction to activate pseudokinase mixed lineage kinase domain-like protein (MLKL) phosphorylation. Increasing evidences show that RIPK3 contributes to the pathologies of inflammatory diseases including multiple sclerosis, infection and colitis. Here, we identified a novel small molecular compound Salt-inducible Kinases (SIKs) inhibitor HG-9-91-01 inhibiting necroptosis by targeting RIPK3 kinase activity. We found that SIKs inhibitor HG-9-91-01 could block TNF- or Toll-like receptors (TLRs)-mediated necroptosis independent of SIKs. We revealed that HG-9-91-01 dramatically decreased cellular activation of RIPK3 and MLKL. Meanwhile, HG-9-91-01 inhibited the association of RIPK3 with MLKL and oligomerization of downstream MLKL. Interestingly, we found that HG-9-91-01 also trigger RIPK3-RIPK1-caspase 1-caspase 8-dependent apoptosis, which activated cleavage of GSDME leading to its dependent pyroptosis. Mechanistic studies revealed that SIKs inhibitor HG-9-91-01 directly inhibited RIPK3 kinase activity to block necroptosis and interacted with RIPK3 and recruited RIPK1 to activate caspases leading to cleave GSDME. Importantly, mice pretreated with HG-9-91-01 showed resistance to TNF-induced systemic inflammatory response syndrome. Consistently, HG-9-91-01 treatment protected mice against Staphylococcus aureus-mediated lung damage through targeting RIPK3 kinase activity. Overall, our results revealed that SIKs inhibitor HG-9-91-01 is a novel inhibitor of RIPK3 kinase and a potential therapeutic target for the treatment of necroptosis-mediated inflammatory diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NR4A1 Promotes LPS-Induced Acute Lung Injury through Inhibition of Opa1-Mediated Mitochondrial Fusion and Activation of PGAM5-Related Necroptosis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35222801/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35222801/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mitochondrial dysfunction and necroptosis have been perceived as the primary molecular mechanisms underscoring acute lung injury. Meanwhile, nuclear receptor subfamily 4 group A member 1 (NR4A1) is considered a regulator of inflammation-related endothelial injury in lung tissue although the downstream molecular events remain elusive. In this study, we employed NR4A1-/- mice to decipher the role of NR4A1 in the onset and progression of acute lung injury with a focus on mitochondrial damage and necroptosis. Our results demonstrated that NR4A1 was significantly upregulated in lipopolysaccharide- (LPS-) treated lung tissues. Knockout of NR4A1 overtly improved lung tissue morphology, inhibited inflammation, and reduced oxidative stress in LPS-treated lung tissue. A cell signaling study suggested that NR4A1 deletion repressed levels of PGAM5 and attenuated LPS-mediated necroptosis in primary murine alveolar epithelial type II (ATII) cells, the effects of which were mitigated by PGAM5 overexpression. Moreover, LPS-mediated mitochondrial injury including mitochondrial membrane potential collapse and mitochondrial oxidative stress was drastically improved by NR4A1 deletion. Furthermore, NR4A1 deletion preserved mitochondrial homeostasis through activation of Opa1-related mitochondrial fusion. Silencing of Opa1 triggered mitochondrial dysfunction in NR4A1-deleted ATII cells. Taken together, our data identified NR4A1 as a novel regulator of LPS-related acute lung injury through regulation of mitochondrial fusion and necroptosis, indicating therapeutic promises of targeting NR4A1 in the treatment of acute lung injury in clinical practice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vitamin C Deficiency Causes Cell Type-Specific Epigenetic Reprogramming and Acute Tubular Necrosis in a Mouse Model</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34983833/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34983833/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Vitamin C deficiency is found in patients with variable kidney diseases. However, the role of vitamin C as an epigenetic regulator in renal homeostasis and pathogenesis remains largely unknown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; We showed that vitamin C deficiency leads to acute tubular necrosis (ATN) using a vitamin C-deficient mouse model (Gulo knock-out). DNA/RNA epigenetic modifications and injured S3 proximal tubule cells were identified in the vitamin C-deficient kidneys using whole-genome bisulfite sequencing, methylated RNA immunoprecipitation sequencing, and single-cell RNA sequencing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; Integrated evidence suggested that epigenetic modifications affected the proximal tubule cells and fenestrated endothelial cells, leading to tubule injury and hypoxia through transcriptional regulation. Strikingly, loss of DNA hydroxymethylation and DNA hypermethylation in vitamin C-deficient kidneys preceded the histologic sign of tubule necrosis, indicating the causality of vitamin C-induced epigenetic modification in ATN. Consistently, prophylactic supplementation of an oxidation-resistant vitamin C derivative, ascorbyl phosphate magnesium, promoted DNA demethylation and prevented the progression of cisplatin-induced ATN.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; Vitamin C played a critical role in renal homeostasis and pathogenesis in a mouse model, suggesting vitamin supplementation may be an approach to lower the risk of kidney injury.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Viral manipulation of host cell necroptosis and pyroptosis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/34933805/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/34933805/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cell death forms an essential component of the antiviral immune response. Viral infection elicits different forms of host cell death, including the lytic and inflammatory cell death modes necroptosis or pyroptosis. The induction of both types of cell death not only eliminates virus-infected cells but also contributes to the development of innate and adaptive immunity through the release of inflammatory mediators. The importance of necroptosis and pyroptosis in host defence is evident from the numerous viral evasion mechanisms that suppress these cell death pathways. Here, we review the emerging principles by which viruses antagonise host cell necroptosis and pyroptosis to promote their spread and block host immunity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exercise-Induced Cardiac Troponin Elevations: From Underlying Mechanisms to Clinical Relevance</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/34898243/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/34898243/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Serological assessment of cardiac troponins (cTn) is the gold standard to assess myocardial injury in clinical practice. A greater magnitude of acutely or chronically elevated cTn concentrations is associated with lower event-free survival in patients and the general population. Exercise training is known to improve cardiovascular function and promote longevity, but exercise can produce an acute rise in cTn concentrations, which may exceed the upper reference limit in a substantial number of individuals. Whether exercise-induced cTn elevations are attributable to a physiological or pathological response and if they are clinically relevant has been debated for decades. Thus far, exercise-induced cTn elevations have been viewed as the only benign form of cTn elevations. However, recent studies report intriguing findings that shed new light on the underlying mechanisms and clinical relevance of exercise-induced cTn elevations. We will review the biochemical characteristics of cTn assays, key factors determining the magnitude of postexercise cTn concentrations, the release kinetics, underlying mechanisms causing and contributing to exercise-induced cTn release, and the clinical relevance of exercise-induced cTn elevations. We will also explain the association with cardiac function, correlates with (subclinical) cardiovascular diseases and exercise-induced cTn elevations predictive value for future cardiovascular events. Last, we will provide recommendations for interpretation of these findings and provide direction for future research in this field.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From pyroptosis, apoptosis and necroptosis to PANoptosis: A mechanistic compendium of programmed cell death pathways</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/34504660/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/34504660/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pyroptosis, apoptosis and necroptosis are the most genetically well-defined programmed cell death (PCD) pathways, and they are intricately involved in both homeostasis and disease. Although the identification of key initiators, effectors and executioners in each of these three PCD pathways has historically delineated them as distinct, growing evidence has highlighted extensive crosstalk among them. These observations have led to the establishment of the concept of PANoptosis, defined as an inflammatory PCD pathway regulated by the PANoptosome complex with key features of pyroptosis, apoptosis and/or necroptosis that cannot be accounted for by any of these PCD pathways alone. In this review, we provide a brief overview of the research history of pyroptosis, apoptosis and necroptosis. We then examine the intricate crosstalk among these PCD pathways to discuss the current evidence for PANoptosis. We also detail the molecular evidence for the assembly of the PANoptosome complex, a molecular scaffold for contemporaneous engagement of key molecules from pyroptosis, apoptosis, and/or necroptosis. PANoptosis is now known to be critically involved in many diseases, including infection, sterile inflammation and cancer, and future discovery of novel PANoptotic components will continue to broaden our understanding of the fundamental processes of cell death and inform the development of new therapeutics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>E3 ligase TRIM25 ubiquitinates RIP3 to inhibit TNF induced cell necrosis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33953350/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33953350/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Receptor interacting protein kinase 3 (RIP3 or RIPK3), the critical executor of cell programmed necrosis, plays essential roles in maintaining immune responses and appropriate tissue homeostasis. Although the E3 ligases CHIP and PELI1 are reported to promote RIP3 degradation, however, how post-translational modification regulates RIP3 activity and stability is poorly understood. Here, we identify the tripartite motif protein TRIM25 as a negative regulator of RIP3-dependent necrosis. TRIM25 directly interacts with RIP3 through its SPRY domain and mediates the K48-linked polyubiquitination of RIP3 on residue K501. The RING domain of TRIM25 facilitates the polyubiquitination chain on RIP3, thereby promoting proteasomal degradation of RIP3. Also, TRIM25 deficiency inhibited the ubiquitination of RIP3, thus promoting TNF-induced cell necrosis. Our current finding reveals the regulating mechanism of polyubiquitination on RIP3, which might be a potential therapeutic target for the intervention of RIP3-dependent necrosis-related diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The PANoptosome: A Deadly Protein Complex Driving Pyroptosis, Apoptosis, and Necroptosis (PANoptosis)</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/32582562/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/32582562/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Programmed cell death is regulated by evolutionarily conserved pathways that play critical roles in development and the immune response. A newly recognized pathway for proinflammatory programmed cell death called PANoptosis is controlled by a recently identified cytoplasmic multimeric protein complex named the PANoptosome. The PANoptosome can engage, in parallel, three key modes of programmed cell death-pyroptosis, apoptosis, and necroptosis. The PANoptosome components have been implicated in a wide array of human diseases including autoinflammatory diseases, neurodegenerative diseases, cancer, microbial infections, and metabolic diseases. Here, we review putative components of the PANoptosome and present a phylogenetic analysis of their molecular domains and interaction motifs that support complex assembly. We also discuss genetic data that suggest PANoptosis is coordinated by scaffolding and catalytic functions of the complex components and propose mechanistic models for PANoptosome assembly. Overall, this review presents potential mechanisms governing PANoptosis based on evolutionary analysis of the PANoptosome components.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Identification of the PANoptosome: A Molecular Platform Triggering Pyroptosis, Apoptosis, and Necroptosis (PANoptosis)</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32547960/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32547960/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Programmed cell death plays crucial roles in organismal development and host defense. Recent studies have highlighted mechanistic overlaps and extensive, multifaceted crosstalk between pyroptosis, apoptosis, and necroptosis, three programmed cell death pathways traditionally considered autonomous. The growing body of evidence, in conjunction with the identification of molecules controlling the concomitant activation of all three pathways by pathological triggers, has led to the development of the concept of PANoptosis. During PANoptosis, inflammatory cell death occurs through the collective activation of pyroptosis, apoptosis, and necroptosis, which can circumvent pathogen-mediated inhibition of individual death pathways. Many of the molecular details of this emerging pathway are unclear. Here, we describe the activation of PANoptosis by bacterial and viral triggers and report protein interactions that reveal the formation of a PANoptosome complex. Infection of macrophages with influenza A virus, vesicular stomatitis virus, Listeria monocytogenes, or Salmonella enterica serovar Typhimurium resulted in robust cell death and the hallmarks of PANoptosis activation. Combined deletion of the PANoptotic components caspase-1 (CASP1), CASP11, receptor-interacting serine/threonine-protein kinase 3 (RIPK3), and CASP8 largely protected macrophages from cell death induced by these pathogens, while deletion of individual components provided reduced or no protection. Further, molecules from the pyroptotic, apoptotic, and necroptotic cell death pathways interacted to form a single molecular complex that we have termed the PANoptosome. Overall, our study identifies pathogens capable of activating PANoptosis and the formation of a PANoptosome complex.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Z-nucleic-acid sensing triggers ZBP1-dependent necroptosis and inflammation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32296175/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32296175/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Erratum in:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Publisher Correction: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-020-2207-y&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Z-nucleic-acid sensing triggers ZBP1-dependent necroptosis and inflammation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The biological function of Z-DNA and Z-RNA, nucleic acid structures with a left-handed double helix, is poorly understood. Z-DNA-binding protein 1 (ZBP1; also known as DAI or DLM-1) is a nucleic acid sensor that contains two Zα domains that bind Z-DNA and Z-RNA. ZBP1 mediates host defence against some viruses by sensing viral nucleic acids. RIPK1 deficiency, or mutation of its RIP homotypic interaction motif (RHIM), triggers ZBP1-dependent necroptosis and inflammation in mice. However, the mechanisms that induce ZBP1 activation in the absence of viral infection remain unknown. Here we show that Zα-dependent sensing of endogenous ligands induces ZBP1-mediated perinatal lethality in mice expressing RIPK1 with mutated RHIM (&lt;em&gt;Ripk1&lt;sup&gt;mR/mR&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt;), skin inflammation in mice with epidermis-specific RIPK1 deficiency (RIPK1&lt;sup&gt;E-KO&lt;/sup&gt;) and colitis in mice with intestinal epithelial-specific FADD deficiency (FADD&lt;sup&gt;IEC-KO&lt;/sup&gt;). Consistently, functional Zα domains were required for ZBP1-induced necroptosis in fibroblasts that were treated with caspase inhibitors or express RIPK1 with mutated RHIM. Inhibition of nuclear export triggered the Zα-dependent activation of RIPK3 in the nucleus resulting in cell death, which suggests that ZBP1 may recognize nuclear Z-form nucleic acids. We found that ZBP1 constitutively bound cellular double-stranded RNA in a Zα-dependent manner. Complementary reads derived from endogenous retroelements were detected in epidermal RNA, which suggests that double-stranded RNA derived from these retroelements may act as a Zα-domain ligand that triggers the activation of ZBP1. Collectively, our results provide evidence that the sensing of endogenous Z-form nucleic acids by ZBP1 triggers RIPK3-dependent necroptosis and inflammation, which could underlie the development of chronic inflammatory conditions-particularly in individuals with mutations in &lt;em&gt;RIPK1&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;CASP8&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Caspase-8 is the molecular switch for apoptosis, necroptosis and pyroptosis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/31748744/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/31748744/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Caspase-8 is the initiator caspase of extrinsic apoptosis and inhibits necroptosis mediated by RIPK3 and MLKL. Accordingly, caspase-8 deficiency in mice causes embryonic lethality, which can be rescued by deletion of either &lt;em&gt;Ripk3&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;Mlkl&lt;/em&gt;. Here we show that the expression of enzymatically inactive CASP8(C362S) causes embryonic lethality in mice by inducing necroptosis and pyroptosis. Similar to &lt;em&gt;Casp8&lt;sup&gt;−/−&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; mice, &lt;em&gt;Casp8&lt;sup&gt;C362S/C362S&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; mouse embryos died after endothelial cell necroptosis leading to cardiovascular defects. MLKL deficiency rescued the cardiovascular phenotype but unexpectedly caused perinatal lethality in &lt;em&gt;Casp8&lt;sup&gt;C362S/C362S&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; mice, indicating that CASP8(C362S) causes necroptosis-independent death at later stages of embryonic development. Specific loss of the catalytic activity of caspase-8 in intestinal epithelial cells induced intestinal inflammation similar to intestinal epithelial cell-specific &lt;em&gt;Casp8&lt;/em&gt; knockout mice. Inhibition of necroptosis by additional deletion of &lt;em&gt;Mlkl&lt;/em&gt; severely aggravated intestinal inflammation and caused premature lethality in &lt;em&gt;Mlkl&lt;/em&gt; knockout mice with specific loss of caspase-8 catalytic activity in intestinal epithelial cells. Expression of CASP8(C362S) triggered the formation of ASC specks, activation of caspase-1 and secretion of IL-1β. Both embryonic lethality and premature death were completely rescued in &lt;em&gt;Casp8&lt;sup&gt;C362S/C362S&lt;/sup&gt;Mlkl&lt;sup&gt;−/−&lt;/sup&gt;Asc&lt;sup&gt;−/−&lt;/sup&gt;sup&amp;gt;&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;Casp8&lt;sup&gt;C362S/C362S&lt;/sup&gt;Mlkl&lt;sup&gt;−/−&lt;/sup&gt;Casp1&lt;sup&gt;−/−&lt;/sup&gt;sup&amp;gt;&lt;/em&gt; mice, indicating that the activation of the inflammasome promotes CASP8(C362S)-mediated tissue pathology when necroptosis is blocked. Therefore, caspase-8 represents the molecular switch that controls apoptosis, necroptosis and pyroptosis, and prevents tissue damage during embryonic development and adulthood.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Coming Decade of Cell Death Research: Five Riddles</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/31100266/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/31100266/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Active cell death, in its many forms, is a fundamental biological process. Studies over the past several decades have explored the functions and consequences of cellular demise and elucidated several of the key cell death pathways. Here, I pose five questions, or riddles, that might provide a guide to the next decade of cell death research. Focusing mainly on four types of active cell death (apoptosis, necroptosis, pyroptosis, and ferroptosis) mainly in mammals, this Perspective explores the possible research directions that might answer these riddles, or at least prompt new ones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
