<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Bone | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/bone/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/bone/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Bone</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Bone</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/bone/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gasdermin D maintains bone mass by rewiring the endo-lysosomal pathway of osteoclastic bone resorption</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36243012/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36243012/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gasdermin D (GSDMD)-mediated pyroptosis induces immunogenic cell death and promotes inflammation. However, the functions of GSDMD in tissue homeostasis remain unclear. Here, we identify a physiological function of GSDMD in osteoclasts via a non-lytic p20-generated protein, which prevents bone loss to maintain bone homeostasis. In the late stage of RANKL-induced osteoclastogenesis, GSDMD underwent cleavage, which is dependent on RIPK1 and caspase-8/-3, to yield this p20 product. Gsdmd-deficient osteoclasts showed normal differentiation but enhanced bone resorption with excessive lysosomal activity. Mice with complete or myeloid-specific Gsdmd deletion exhibited increased trabecular bone loss and more severe aging/ovariectomy-induced osteoporosis. GSDMD p20 was preferentially localized to early endosomes and limited endo-lysosomal trafficking and maturation, relying on its oligomerization and control of phosphoinositide conversion by binding to phosphatidylinositol 3-phosphate (PI(3)P). We have thus identified an anti-osteoclastic function of GSDMD as a checkpoint for lysosomal maturation and secretion and linked this to bone homeostasis and endosome-lysosome biology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Propionate and butyrate attenuate macrophage pyroptosis and osteoclastogenesis induced by CoCrMo alloy particles</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35996168/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35996168/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Wear particles-induced osteolysis is a major long-term complication after total joint arthroplasty. Up to now, there is no effective treatment for wear particles-induced osteolysis except for the revision surgery, which is a heavy psychological and economic burden to patients. A metabolite of gut microbiota, short chain fatty acids (SCFAs), has been reported to be beneficial for many chronic inflammatory diseases. This study aimed to investigate the therapeutic effect of SCFAs on osteolysis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; A model of inflammatory osteolysis was established by applying CoCrMo alloy particles to mouse calvarium. After two weeks of intervention, the anti-inflammatory effects of SCFAs on wear particle-induced osteolysis were evaluated by Micro-CT analysis and immunohistochemistry staining. In vitro study, lipopolysaccharide (LPS) primed bone marrow-derived macrophages (BMDMs) and Tohoku Hospital Pediatrics-1 (THP-1) macrophages were stimulated with CoCrMo particles to activate inflammasome in the presence of acetate (C2), propionate (C3), and butyrate (C4). Western blotting, Enzyme-linked immunosorbent assay, and immunofluorescence were used to detect the activation of NLRP3 inflammasome. The effects of SCFAs on osteoclasts were evaluate by qRT-PCR, Western blotting, immunofluorescence, and tartrate-resistant acid phosphatase (TRAP) staining. Additionally, histone deacetylase (HDAC) inhibitors, agonists of GPR41, GPR43, and GPR109A were applied to confirm the underlying mechanism of SCFAs on the inflammasome activation of macrophages and osteoclastogenesis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; C3 and C4 but not C2 could alleviate wear particles-induced osteolysis with fewer bone erosion pits (P &amp;lt; 0.001), higher level of bone volume to tissue volume (BV/TV, P &amp;lt; 0.001), bone mineral density (BMD, P &amp;lt; 0.001), and a lower total porosity (P &amp;lt; 0.001). C3 and C4 prevented CoCrMo alloy particles-induced ASC speck formation and nucleation-induced oligomerization, suppressing the cleavage of caspase-1 (P &amp;lt; 0.05) and IL-1β (P &amp;lt; 0.05) stimulated by CoCrMo alloy particles. C3 and C4 also inhibited the generation of Gasdermin D-N-terminal fragment (GSDMD-NT) to regulate pyroptosis. Besides, C3 and C4 have a negative impact on osteoclast differentiation (P &amp;lt; 0.05) and its function (P &amp;lt; 0.05), affecting the podosome arrangement and morphologically normal podosome belts formation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/em&gt; Our work showed that C3 and C4 are qualified candidates for the treatment of wear particle-induced osteolysis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Circular RNA circFIRRE drives osteosarcoma progression and metastasis through tumorigenic-angiogenic coupling</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35986280/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35986280/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Disappointing clinical efficacy of standard treatment has been proven in refractory metastatic osteosarcoma, and the emerging anti-angiogenic regimens are still in the infantile stage. Thus, there is an urgent need to develop novel therapeutic approach for osteosarcoma lung metastasis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;circFIRRE was selected from RNA-sequencing of 4 matched osteosarcoma and adjacent samples. The expression of circFIRRE was verified in clinical osteosarcoma samples and cell lines via quantitative real-time polymerase chain reaction (RT-qPCR). The effect of circFIRRE was investigated in cell lines in vitro models, ex vivo models and in vivo xenograft tumor models, including proliferation, invasion, migration, metastasis and angiogenesis. Signaling regulatory mechanism was evaluated by RT-qPCR, Western blot, RNA pull-down and dual-luciferase reporter assays.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article, a novel circular RNA, circFIRRE (hsa_circ_0001944) was screened out and identified from RNA-sequencing, and was upregulated in both osteosarcoma cell lines and tissues. Clinically, aberrantly upregulated circFIRRE portended higher metastatic risk and worse prognosis in osteosarcoma patients. Functionally, in vitro, ex vivo and in vivo experiments demonstrated that circFIRRE could drive primary osteosarcoma progression and lung metastasis by inducing both tumor cells and blood vessels, we call as “tumorigenic-angiogenic coupling”. Mechanistically, upregulated circFIRRE was induced by transcription factor YY1, and partially boosted the mRNA and protein level of LUZP1 by sponging miR-486-3p and miR-1225-5p.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We identified circFIRRE as a master regulator in the tumorigenesis and angiogenesis of osteosarcoma, which could be purposed as a novel prognostic biomarker and therapeutic target for refractory osteosarcoma.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Circular RNA circNFKB1 promotes osteoarthritis progression through interacting with ENO1 and sustaining NF-κB signaling</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35945200/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35945200/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inflammatory cytokines-induced activation of the nuclear factor κB (NF-κB) pathway plays a critical role in the pathogenesis of osteoarthritis (OA). Circular RNA (circRNA) has been identified as important epigenetic factor in numerous diseases. However, the biological roles of inflammation-related circRNAs in regulating OA pathogenesis remain elusive. Here, we revealed circRNA expression profiles in human primary chondrocytes with interleukin-1β (IL-1β) stimulation by circRNA sequencing. We identified a highly upregulated circRNA, termed as circNFKB1 in inflamed chondrocytes and osteoarthritic cartilage. As a circRNA derived from exon 2-5 of NFKB1, circNFKB1 is located in both cytoplasm and nucleus of chondrocytes. Furthermore, knockdown of circNFKB1 inhibited extracellular matrix (ECM) catabolism and rescued IL-1β impaired ECM anabolism whereas ectopic expression of circNFKB1 significantly promoted chondrocytes degradation in vitro. Moreover, intraarticular injection of adenovirus-circNFKB1 in mouse joints triggered spontaneous cartilage loss and OA development. Mechanistically, circNFKB1 interacted with α-enolase (ENO1), regulated the expression of its parental gene NFKB1 and sustained the activation of NF-κB signaling pathway in chondrocytes. Therefore, this study highlights a novel ENO1-interacting circNFKB1 in OA pathogenesis, and provides valuable insights into understanding the regulatory mechanism of NF-κB signaling in chondrocytes and a promising therapeutic target for the treatment of OA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Targeting macrophagic SHP2 for ameliorating osteoarthritis via TLR signaling</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35865095/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35865095/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therapeutics that discriminate between the genetic makeup of normal cells and tumour cells are valuable for treating and understanding cancer. Small molecules with oncogene-selective lethality may reveal novel functions of oncoproteins and enable the creation of more selective drugs. Here we describe the mechanism of action of the selective anti-tumour agent erastin, involving the RAS-RAF-MEK signalling pathway functioning in cell proliferation, differentiation and survival. Erastin exhibits greater lethality in human tumour cells harbouring mutations in the oncogenes HRAS, KRAS or BRAF. Using affinity purification and mass spectrometry, we discovered that erastin acts through mitochondrial voltage-dependent anion channels (VDACs)&amp;ndash;a novel target for anti-cancer drugs. We show that erastin treatment of cells harbouring oncogenic RAS causes the appearance of oxidative species and subsequent death through an oxidative, non-apoptotic mechanism. RNA-interference-mediated knockdown of VDAC2 or VDAC3 caused resistance to erastin, implicating these two VDAC isoforms in the mechanism of action of erastin. Moreover, using purified mitochondria expressing a single VDAC isoform, we found that erastin alters the permeability of the outer mitochondrial membrane. Finally, using a radiolabelled analogue and a filter-binding assay, we show that erastin binds directly to VDAC2. These results demonstrate that ligands to VDAC proteins can induce non-apoptotic cell death selectively in some tumour cells harbouring activating mutations in the RAS-RAF-MEK pathway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Circular RNA AFF4 modulates osteogenic differentiation in BM-MSCs by activating SMAD1/5 pathway through miR-135a-5p/FNDC5/Irisin axis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34145212/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34145212/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bone marrow-derived mesenchymal stem cells (BM-MSCs), the common progenitor cells of adipocytes and osteoblasts, have been recognized as the key mediator during bone formation. Herein, our study aim to investigate molecular mechanisms underlying circular RNA (circRNA) AFF4 (circ_AFF4)-regulated BM-MSCs osteogenesis. BM-MSCs were characterized by FACS, ARS, and ALP staining. Expression patterns of circ_AFF4, miR-135a-5p, FNDC5/Irisin, SMAD1/5, and osteogenesis markers, including ALP, BMP4, RUNX2, Spp1, and Colla1 were detected by qRT-PCR, western blot, or immunofluorescence staining, respectively. Interactions between circ_AFF4 and miR-135a-5p, FNDC5, and miR-135a-5p were analyzed using web tools including TargetScan, miRanda, and miRDB, and further confirmed by luciferase reporter assay and RNA pull-down. Complex formation between Irisin and Integrin αV was verified by Co-immunoprecipitation. To further verify the functional role of circ_AFF4 in vivo during bone formation, we conducted animal experiments harboring circ_AFF4 knockdown, and born samples were evaluated by immunohistochemistry, hematoxylin and eosin, and Masson staining. Circ_AFF4 was upregulated upon osteogenic differentiation induction in BM-MSCs, and miR-135a-5p expression declined as differentiation proceeds. Circ_AFF4 knockdown significantly inhibited osteogenesis potential in BM-MSCs. Circ_AFF4 stimulated FNDC5/Irisin expression through complementary binding to its downstream target molecule miR-135a-5p. Irisin formed an intermolecular complex with Integrin αV and activated the SMAD1/5 pathway during osteogenic differentiation. Our work revealed that circ_AFF4, acting as a sponge of miR-135a-5p, triggers the promotion of FNDC5/Irisin via activating the SMAD1/5 pathway to induce osteogenic differentiation in BM-MSCs. These findings gained a deeper insight into the circRNA-miRNA regulatory system in the bone marrow microenvironment and may improve our understanding of bone formation-related diseases at physiological and pathological levels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
