<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Endosome | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/endosome/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/endosome/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Endosome</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Endosome</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/endosome/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Endosomal lipid signaling reshapes the endoplasmic reticulum to control mitochondrial function</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36520888/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36520888/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;INTRODUCTION&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cells need to react appropriately to nutritional cues. Defects in the rewiring of metabolism in response to alterations in nutrient supply have been linked to human diseases ranging from diabetes to muscle atrophy. Starvation represses anabolic pathways and facilitates catabolic ones, such as the degradation of macromolecules by autophagy and endolysosomes. Starvation also promotes the β-oxidation of fatty acids in mitochondria to produce adenosine triphosphate (ATP). Within cells, organelles including lysosomes and mitochondria undergo changes in shape and dynamics. These processes are often regulated by phosphoinositide lipids. Phosphoinositides are also involved in the formation of membrane contacts between organelles and in the response of cells and tissues to growth and nutrient signals. How the adaptive changes that protect mammalian cells and tissues from starvation-induced damage are coordinated on a cell-wide scale is unknown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;RATIONALE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Endolysosomal membrane dynamics and function are controlled by phosphoinositide signaling lipids, most notably by the synthesis and turnover of phosphatidylinositol 3-phosphate [PI(3)P]. Patients carrying mutations in the gene encoding the lipid phosphatase MTM1, an enzyme that mediates endosomal PI(3)P turnover, suffer from X-linked centronuclear myopathy (XLCNM), a severe neuromuscular disease characterized by muscle atrophy, disorganization of mitochondria, and defects in the organization of the muscle endoplasmic reticulum (ER). Given that PI(3)P is a hallmark of endosomes, we hypothesized that the control of early endosomal PI(3)P by MTM1 might serve to orchestrate adaptive changes in the dynamics of the ER and mitochondria in response to altering nutrient supply.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;RESULTS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Working with XLCNM patient–derived myoblasts and engineered cell lines, we found that nutrient starvation (for example, lack of amino acids) induced the hydrolysis of PI(3)P by endosomal recruitment of MTM1. Concomitantly, tubular ER membranes were observed to be converted into ER sheets by live super-resolution light microscopy. Mechanistically, loss of early endosomal PI(3)P upon starvation was found to reduce membrane contacts between peripheral ER tubules and early endosomes. These contacts function as physical tethers that may transmit pulling forces from highly motile peripheral endosomes to the tubular ER. Using proximity labeling proteomic and functional cell biological experiments we demonstrated that the ER–endosome contacts were mediated by binding of the related ER membrane proteins RRBP1 and kinectin 1 to PI(3)P on endosomes. To study the role of starvation-induced reshaping of tubular ER membranes into sheets on mitochondrial form and function, we combined live imaging with three-dimensional focused ion beam milling scanning electron microscopy (FIB-SEM) and proteomic analysis. We found that starvation-induced ER reshaping by MTM1 reduced the rate of mitochondrial fission and promoted the formation of a hyperfused mitochondrial network. Genetic manipulations that resulted in ER sheet expansion caused the formation of an enlarged mitochondrial network even in fed cells. Conversely, impaired ER reshaping and reduced mitochondrial network formation were observed in starved myoblasts from XLCNM patients. Mitochondrial network formation appeared to be critical for the delivery of fatty acids from lipid droplets to mitochondria and for oxidative ATP production to sustain energy supply in nutrient-deprived cells.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CONCLUSION&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our data unravel a crucial role for early endosomal lipid signaling in controlling ER morphology and, thereby, mitochondrial form and function to orchestrate the adaptive response of cells to alterations in nutrient (e.g., amino acid) supply. This mechanism operates independent of autophagy, a cellular self-eating process typically induced by prolonged starvation. Rather, it resembles an organellar conveyor belt, in which the tubular ER serves as a membrane conduit that transmits nutrient-triggered changes in endosomal PI(3)P levels to metabolic organelles to enable metabolic rewiring. How early endosomal PI(3)P levels and MTM1 function are controlled by cellular nutrient status is currently unknown. Defects in ER shape, mitochondrial morphogenesis, and cellular ATP depletion caused by loss of MTM1 function can explain the observed myofiber hypotrophy and defective ER organization in animal models of XLCNM and in human patients who often appear undernourished. We therefore hypothesize that dysregulated organelle remodeling may underlie XLCNM caused by MTM1 mutations in humans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Distinct changes in endosomal composition promote NLRP3 inflammasome activation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36443515/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36443515/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inflammasome complexes are pivotal in the innate immune response. The NLR family pyrin domain containing protein 3 (NLRP3) inflammasome is activated in response to a broad variety of cellular stressors. However, a primary and converging sensing mechanism by the NLRP3 receptor initiating inflammasome assembly remains ill defined. Here, we demonstrate that NLRP3 inflammasome activators primarily converge on disruption of endoplasmic reticulum-endosome membrane contact sites (EECS). This defect causes endosomal accumulation of phosphatidylinositol 4-phosphate (PI4P) and a consequent impairment of endosome-to-trans-Golgi network trafficking (ETT), necessary steps for endosomal recruitment of NLRP3 and subsequent inflammasome activation. Lowering endosomal PI4P levels prevents endosomal association of NLRP3 and inhibits inflammasome activation. Disruption of EECS or ETT is sufficient to enhance endosomal PI4P levels, to recruit NLRP3 to endosomes and to potentiate NLRP3 inflammasome activation. Mice with defects in ETT in the myeloid compartment are more susceptible to lipopolysaccharide-induced sepsis. Our study thus identifies a distinct cellular mechanism leading to endosomal NLRP3 recruitment and inflammasome activation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clathrin-associated AP-1 controls termination of STING signalling</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36261523/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36261523/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stimulator of interferon genes (STING) functions downstream of cyclic GMP-AMP synthase in DNA sensing or as a direct receptor for bacterial cyclic dinucleotides and small molecules to activate immunity during infection, cancer and immunotherapy. Precise regulation of STING is essential to ensure balanced immune responses and prevent detrimental autoinflammation. After activation, STING, a transmembrane protein, traffics from the endoplasmic reticulum to the Golgi, where its phosphorylation by the protein kinase TBK1 enables signal transduction. The mechanism that ends STING signalling at the Golgi remains unknown. Here we show that adaptor protein complex 1 (AP-1) controls the termination of STING-dependent immune activation. We find that AP-1 sorts phosphorylated STING into clathrin-coated transport vesicles for delivery to the endolysosomal system, where STING is degraded. We identify a highly conserved dileucine motif in the cytosolic C-terminal tail (CTT) of STING that, together with TBK1-dependent CTT phosphorylation, dictates the AP-1 engagement of STING. A cryo-electron microscopy structure of AP-1 in complex with phosphorylated STING explains the enhanced recognition of TBK1-activated STING. We show that suppression of AP-1 exacerbates STING-induced immune responses. Our results reveal a structural mechanism of negative regulation of STING and establish that the initiation of signalling is inextricably associated with its termination to enable transient activation of immunity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A shared, stochastic pathway mediates exosome protein budding along plasma and endosome membranes</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35988652/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35988652/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Exosomes are small extracellular vesicles of ∼30 to 150 nm that are secreted by all cells, abundant in all biofluids, and play important roles in health and disease. However, details about the mechanism of exosome biogenesis are unclear. Here, we carried out a cargo-based analysis of exosome cargo protein biogenesis in which we identified the most highly enriched exosomal cargo proteins and then followed their biogenesis, trafficking, and exosomal secretion to test different hypotheses for how cells make exosomes. We show that exosome cargo proteins bud from cells (i) in exosome-sized vesicles regardless of whether they are localized to plasma or endosome membranes, (ii) ∼5-fold more efficiently when localized to the plasma membrane, (iii) ∼5-fold less efficiently when targeted to the endosome membrane, (iv) by a stochastic process that leads to ∼100-fold differences in their abundance from one exosome to another, and (v) independently of small GTPase Rab27a, the ESCRT complex-associated protein Alix, or the cargo protein CD63. Taken together, our results demonstrate that cells use a shared, stochastic mechanism to bud exosome cargoes along the spectrum of plasma and endosome membranes and far more efficiently from the plasma membrane than the endosome. Our observations also indicate that the pronounced variation in content between different exosome-sized vesicles is an inevitable consequence of a stochastic mechanism of small vesicle biogenesis, that the origin membrane of exosome-sized extracellular vesicles simply cannot be determined, and that most of what we currently know about exosomes has likely come from studies of plasma membrane-derived vesicles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Golgi-derived vesicle potentiates PtdIns4P to PtdIns3P conversion for endosome fission</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34183801/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34183801/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Endosome fission is essential for cargo sorting and targeting in the endosomal system. However, whether organelles other than the endoplasmic reticulum (ER) participate in endosome fission through membrane contacts is unknown. Here, we characterize a Golgi-derived vesicle, the SEC14L2 compartment, that plays a unique role in facilitating endosome fission through ternary contacts with endosomes and the ER. Localized to the ER-mediated endosome fission site, the phosphatidylinositol transfer protein SEC14L2 promotes phosphatidylinositol 4-phosphate (PtdIns4P) to phosphatidylinositol 3-phosphate (PtdIns3P) conversion before endosome fission. In the absence of SEC14L2, endosome fission is attenuated and more enlarged endosomes arise due to endosomal accumulation of PtdIns4P and reduction in PtdIns3P. Collectively, our data suggest roles of the Golgi network in ER-associated endosome fission and a mechanism involving ER-endosome contacts in the regulation of endosomal phosphoinositide conversion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
