<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Parainfluenza Virus | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/parainfluenza-virus/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/parainfluenza-virus/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Parainfluenza Virus</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Parainfluenza Virus</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/parainfluenza-virus/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vimentin inhibits α-tubulin acetylation via enhancing α-TAT1 degradation to suppress the replication of human parainfluenza virus type 3</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36108090/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36108090/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We previously found that, among human parainfluenza virus type 3 (HPIV3) proteins, the interaction of nucleoprotein (N) and phosphoprotein (P) provides the minimal requirement for the formation of cytoplasmic inclusion bodies (IBs), which are sites of RNA synthesis, and that acetylated α-tubulin enhances IB fusion and viral replication. In this study, using immunoprecipitation and mass spectrometry assays, we determined that vimentin (VIM) specifically interacted with the N-P complex of HPIV3, and that the head domain of VIM was responsible for this interaction, contributing to the inhibition of IB fusion and viral replication. Furthermore, we found that VIM promoted the degradation of α-tubulin acetyltransferase 1 (α-TAT1), through its head region, thereby inhibiting the acetylation of α-tubulin, IB fusion, and viral replication. In addition, we identified a 20-amino-acid peptide derived from the head region of VIM that participated in the interaction with the N-P complex and inhibited viral replication. Our findings suggest that VIM inhibits the formation of HPIV3 IBs by downregulating α-tubulin acetylation via enhancing the degradation of α-TAT1. Our work sheds light on a new mechanism by which VIM suppresses HPIV3 replication.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
