<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Protein | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/protein/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/protein/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Protein</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Protein</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/protein/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Encyclopedia of transcription factor</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tool/2021-08-06-en-tf/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/tool/2021-08-06-en-tf/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://services.healthtech.dtu.dk/service.php?Promoter-2.0&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Promoter2.0&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; predicts transcription start sites of vertebrate PolII promoters in DNA sequences. It has been developed as an evolution of simulated transcription factors that interact with sequences in promoter regions. i It builds on principles that are common to neural networks and genetic algorithms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://jaspar.genereg.net/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;JASPAR&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a regularly maintained open-access database storing manually curated transcription factors (TF) binding profiles as position frequency matrices (PFMs). PFMs summarize occurrences of each nucleotide at each position in a set of observed TF-DNA interactions. PFMs can be transformed to probabilistic or energistic models to construct position weight matrices (PWMs) or position-specific scoring matrices (PSSMs), which can be used to scan any DNA sequence to predict TF binding sites (TFBSs). The &lt;a href=&#34;https://jaspar.genereg.net/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;JASPAR&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; database provides TFBSs predicted using the profiles in the CORE collection.
The motifs in &lt;a href=&#34;https://jaspar.genereg.net/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;JASPAR&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; are collected in two ways:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Internally: de novo generated motifs, by analyzing ChIP-seq/-exo sequences using a custom motif discovery pipeline (check the code at our repository).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Externally: motifs taken directly from other publications and/or resources.
In both cases, the selected motifs are manually curated. Specifically, our curators assess the quality of the motif and search for an orthogonal publication providing support to the motif as the bona fide motif recognized by the TF of interest (e.g., a motif found in ChIP-seq peaks looks similar to one found by SELEX-seq). The Pubmed ID associated with the orthogonal support is provided in the TF profile metadata.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://jaspar.genereg.net/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;JASPAR&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is the only database with this scope where the data can be used with no restrictions (open source). For a comprehensive review of models and how they can be used, please see the following reviews:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/25045190/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Modeling the specificity of protein-DNA interactions Quant Biol. 2013 Jun;1(2):115-130&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/15131651/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Applied bioinformatics for the identification of regulatory elements Nat Rev Genet. 2004 Apr;5(4):276-87&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;http://motifmap.ics.uci.edu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MotifMap&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; system provides comprehensive maps of candidate regulatory elements encoded in the genomes of model species using databases of transcription factor binding motifs, refined genome alignments, and a comparative genomic statistical approach- Bayesian Branch Length Score. Users can filter the results by various criteria and export them to severals file formats or view them directly in the UCSC genome browser.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://gene-regulation.com/pub/databases.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TRANSFAC&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; provides data on eukaryotic transcription factors, their experimentally-proven binding sites, consensus binding sequences (positional weight matrices) and regulated genes. TRANSCompel contains data on eukaryotic transcription factors experimentally proven to act together in a synergistic or antagonistic manner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;http://the_brain.bwh.harvard.edu/uniprobe/index.php&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UniPROBE (Universal PBM Resource for Oligonucleotide Binding Evaluation)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; database hosts data generated by universal protein binding microarray (PBM) technology on the in vitro DNA binding specificities of proteins. This initial release of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://the_brain.bwh.harvard.edu/uniprobe/index.php&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UniPROBE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; database provides a centralized resource for accessing comprehensive data on the preferences of proteins for all possible sequence variants (&amp;lsquo;words&amp;rsquo;) of length k (&amp;lsquo;k-mers&amp;rsquo;), as well as position weight matrix (PWM) and graphical sequence logo representations of the k-mer data. In total, the database currently hosts DNA binding data for 726 nonredundant proteins and complexes from a diverse collection of organisms, including the prokaryote Vibrio harveyi, the eukaryotic malarial parasite Plasmodium falciparum, the parasitic Apicomplexan Cryptosporidium parvum, the yeast Saccharomyces cerevisiae, the worm Caenorhabditis elegans, mouse, and human. The database&amp;rsquo;s web tools (on the right) include a text-based search, a function for assessing motif similarity between user-entered data and database PWMs, and a function for locating putative binding sites along user-entered nucleotide sequences. Please click on each tool&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;help&amp;rdquo; link for more information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;http://bioinfo.wilmer.jhu.edu/PDI/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Human Protein-DNA Interactome (hPDI)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; database holds experimental protein-DNA interaction data for humans identified by protein microarray assays. The current release of &lt;a href=&#34;http://bioinfo.wilmer.jhu.edu/PDI/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;hPDI&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; contains 17,718 protein-DNA interactions for 1013 human DNA-binding proteins. These DNA-binding proteins include 493 human transcription factors (TFs) and 520 unconventional DNA binding proteins (uDBPs). Here TFs are defined as proteins either are annotated as &amp;ldquo;regulation of transcription&amp;rdquo; defined by GO database or contain known DNA binding domains defined by Pfam database and, uDBPs are defined proteins that have not been previously found to binding DNA specifically.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://v1.factorbook.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Factorbook&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a transcription factor (TF)-centric web-based repository of integrative analysis associated with ENCODE ChIP-seq data. It includes de novo discovered motifs, chromatin features surrounding ChIP-seq peaks (histone modification patterns, DNase I cleavage footprints, and nucleosome positioning profiles), deep-learned models of sequence features driving TF binding, and integration with GWAS variants and the ENCODE Registry of candidate cis-regulatory elements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://hocomoco.autosome.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HOmo sapiens COmprehensive MOdel COllection (HOCOMOCO)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; v11 provides transcription factor (TF) binding models for 680 human and 453 mouse TFs. Since v11, &lt;a href=&#34;https://hocomoco.autosome.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HOCOMOCO&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is complemented by MoLoTool, an interactive web tool to mark motif occurrences in a given set of DNA sequences. In addition to basic mononucleotide position weight matrices (PWMs), &lt;a href=&#34;https://hocomoco.autosome.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HOCOMOCO&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; provides dinucleotide position weight matrices based on ChIP-Seq data. All the models were produced by the ChIPMunk motif discovery tool. Model quality ratings are results of a comprehensive cross-validation benchmark. ChIP-Seq data for motif discovery was extracted from GTRD database of BioUML platform, that also provides an interface for motif finding (sequence scanning) with &lt;a href=&#34;https://hocomoco.autosome.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HOCOMOCO&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; models.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://meme-suite.org/meme/index.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MEME&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; discovers novel, ungapped motifs (recurring, fixed-length patterns) in your sequences (sample output from sequences). &lt;a href=&#34;https://meme-suite.org/meme/index.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MEME&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; splits variable-length patterns into two or more separate motifs. A motif is an approximate sequence pattern that occurs repeatedly in a group of related sequences. &lt;a href=&#34;https://meme-suite.org/meme/index.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MEME&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; represents motifs as position-dependent letter-probability matrices that describe the probability of each possible letter at each position in the pattern. Individual &lt;a href=&#34;https://meme-suite.org/meme/index.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MEME&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; motifs do not contain gaps. Patterns with variable-length gaps are split by &lt;a href=&#34;https://meme-suite.org/meme/index.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MEME&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; into two or more separate motifs. &lt;a href=&#34;https://meme-suite.org/meme/index.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MEME&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; takes as input a group of sequences and outputs as many motifs as requested. &lt;a href=&#34;https://meme-suite.org/meme/index.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MEME&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; uses statistical modeling techniques to automatically choose the best width, number of occurrences, and description for each motif. &lt;a href=&#34;https://meme-suite.org/meme/index.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MEME&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; on the web can take a second (control) set of input sequences and then discovers motifs that are enriched in the primary set relative to the control set. This is called discriminative motif discovery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://cistrome.org/db/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cistrome DB&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; uses the standard analysis pipeline ChiLin (1) to process all chromatin profiling reads.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Transcription factors (TFs) as key regulators could modulate the expression of target genes by binding to specific DNA sequences of their promoter(s) or enhancer(s). The spatiotemporal TF-target regulations play vital roles throughout the life course of organisms, especially for human beings. Thus, the identification of TF-target regulation in human is a basis for understanding the molecular regulatory mechanisms underlying biological processes including the development and pathogenesis. &lt;a href=&#34;http://bioinfo.life.hust.edu.cn/hTFtarget#!/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;hTFtarget&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; has curated comprehensive TF-target regulations from large-scale of ChIP-Seq data of human TFs (7,190 experiment samples of 659 TFs) in 569 conditions (399 types of cell line, 129 classes of tissues or cells, and 141 kinds of treatments). &lt;a href=&#34;http://bioinfo.life.hust.edu.cn/hTFtarget#!/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;hTFtarget&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; customized an analysis workflow to detect reliable TF-target regulations, which integrated the peak information of ChIP-Seq data with epigenomic modification status (Details in Document page). hTFtarget could help users to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Browse and investigate the target gene(s) of TF(s);&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Explore which TF(s) could regulate the query gene(s);&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Survey public ChIP-Seq samples for the query TF(s);&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;View ChIP-Seq peaks of the query TF(s) in user-defined manner;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Investigate potential co-associations between TFs in selected cell line(s);&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Inquire candidate co-regulation of TFs for the query gene(s);&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Predict binding sites of TF(s) on given sequence(s).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://alggen.lsi.upc.es/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PROMO&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a virtual laboratory for the identification of putative transcription factor binding sites (TFBS) in DNA sequences from a species or groups of species of interest. TFBS defined in the TRANSFAC database are used to construct specific binding site weight matrices for TFBS prediction. The user can inspect the result of the search through a graphical interface and downloadable text files.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;www.softberry.com&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Softberry&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, Inc. is a leading developer of software tools for genomic research focused on computational methods of high throughput biomedical data analysis, including software to support next generation sequencing technologies, transcriptome analysis (with RNASeq data), SNP detection and selection of disease specific SNP subsets. Its research-oriented programs have been used in thousand research projects. For example, fgenesh eukaryotic gene identification program is cited in more than 3000 articles, bprom, bacterial promoter prediction is cited in ~700 research papers. Just in 2015 our software applications have been used in more then 2000 research publications. Hundreds software applications developed in &lt;a href=&#34;www.softberry.com&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Softberry&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; can be executed on-line at &lt;a href=&#34;www.softberry.com&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Softberry&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; or downloaded for free academic usage. &lt;a href=&#34;www.softberry.com&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Softberry&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; started its commercial activities on May 1997 and is headquartered in Mount Kisco, NY, USA, with a satellite office in Novosibirsk, Russia. It participated in a number of academic collaborations on various research projects around the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://promirna.molgen.mpg.de/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PROmiRNA&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a program for annotating miRNA promoters in human, as well as other species. It uses deepCAGE data from the FANTOM4 Consortium and integrated cage tag counts and other promoter features, such as CpG content, conservation and TATA box affinity, to score the potential of a candidate regions to be a promoter. Given a list of genomic regions of interest, in the form of a gff file, &lt;a href=&#34;http://promirna.molgen.mpg.de/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PROmiRNA&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; returns the most probable promoter locations, together with the posterior probabilities calculated by the model. More informations on how to run &lt;a href=&#34;http://promirna.molgen.mpg.de/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PROmiRNA&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; on your regions of interest can be found in the README file inside the &lt;a href=&#34;http://promirna.molgen.mpg.de/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PROmiRNA&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; directory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/tag/databases/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Databases&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/tool/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Tools &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integrated Protein-Protein Interaction and Weighted Gene Co-expression Network Analysis Uncover Three Key Genes in Hepatoblastoma</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33718368/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33718368/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hepatoblastoma (HB) is the most common liver tumor in the pediatric population, with typically poor outcomes for advanced-stage or chemotherapy-refractory HB patients. The objective of this study was to identify genes involved in HB pathogenesis via microarray analysis and subsequent experimental validation. We identified 856 differentially expressed genes (DEGs) between HB and normal liver tissue based on two publicly available microarray datasets (GSE131329 and GSE75271) after data merging and batch effect correction. Protein-protein interaction (PPI) analysis and weighted gene co-expression network analysis (WGCNA) were conducted to explore HB-related critical modules and hub genes. Subsequently, Gene Ontology (GO) analysis was used to reveal critical biological functions in the initiation and progression of HB. Kyoto Encyclopedia of Genes and Genomes (KEGG) analysis showed that genes involved in cell cycle phase transition and the PI3K/AKT signaling were associated with HB. The intersection of hub genes identified by both PPI and WGCNA analyses revealed five potential candidate genes. Based on receiver operating characteristic (ROC) curve analysis and reports in the literature, we selected CCNA2, CDK1, and CDC20 as key genes of interest to validate experimentally. CCNA2, CDK1, or CDC20 small interfering RNA (siRNA) knockdown inhibited aggressive biological properties of both HepG2 and HuH-6 cell lines in vitro. In conclusion, we identified CCNA2, CDK1, and CDC20 as new potential therapeutic biomarkers for HB, providing novel insights into important and viable targets in future HB treatment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transcriptome-wide profiles of circular RNA and RNA-binding protein interactions reveal effects on circular RNA biogenesis and cancer pathway expression</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33287884/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33287884/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Circular RNAs (circRNAs) are stable, often highly expressed RNA transcripts with potential to modulate other regulatory RNAs. A few circRNAs have been shown to bind RNA-binding proteins (RBPs); however, little is known about the prevalence and distribution of these interactions in different biological contexts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; We conduct an extensive screen of circRNA-RBP interactions in the ENCODE cell lines HepG2 and K562. We profile circRNAs in deep-sequenced total RNA samples and analyze circRNA-RBP interactions using a large set of eCLIP data with binding sites of 150 RBPs. We validate interactions for select circRNAs and RBPs by performing RNA immunoprecipitation and functionally characterize our most interesting candidates by conducting knockdown studies followed by RNA-Seq.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; We generate a comprehensive catalog of circRNA-RBP interactions in HepG2 and K562 cells. We show that KHSRP binding sites are enriched in flanking introns of circRNAs and that KHSRP depletion affects circRNA biogenesis. We identify circRNAs that are highly covered by RBP binding sites and experimentally validate individual circRNA-RBP interactions. We show that circCDYL, a highly expressed circRNA with clinical and functional implications in bladder cancer, is almost completely covered with GRWD1 binding sites in HepG2 cells, and that circCDYL depletion counteracts the effect of GRWD1 depletion. Furthermore, we confirm interactions between circCDYL and RBPs in bladder cancer cells and demonstrate that circCDYL depletion affects hallmarks of cancer and perturbs the expression of key cancer genes, e.g., TP53. Finally, we show that elevated levels of circCDYL are associated with overall survival of bladder cancer patients.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; Our study demonstrates transcriptome-wide and cell-type-specific circRNA-RBP interactions that could play important regulatory roles in tumorigenesis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prediction of kinase-specific phosphorylation sites in proteins</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tool/2020-04-12-pkspsp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/tool/2020-04-12-pkspsp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In eukaryotes, protein phosphorylation is specifically catalyzed by numerous protein kinases (PKs), faithfully orchestrates various biological processes, and reversibly determines cellular dynamics and plasticity. Here we report an updated algorithm of &lt;a href=&#34;%28http://gps.biocuckoo.cn/%29&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Group-based Prediction System (PGS)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 5.0 to improve the performance for predicting kinase-specific phosphorylation sites (p-sites). Two novel methods, position weight determination (PWD) and scoring matrix optimization (SMO), were developed. Compared with other existing tools, &lt;a href=&#34;http://gps.biocuckoo.cn/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GPS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 5.0 exhibits a highly competitive accuracy. Besides serine/threonine or tyrosine kinases, &lt;a href=&#34;http://gps.biocuckoo.cn/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GPS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 5.0 also supports the prediction of dual-specificity kinase-specific p-sites. In the classical module of &lt;a href=&#34;http://gps.biocuckoo.cn/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GPS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 5.0, 617 individual predictors were constructed for predicting p-sites of 479 human PKs. To extend the application of &lt;a href=&#34;http://gps.biocuckoo.cn/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GPS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 5.0, a species-specific module was implemented to predict kinase-specific p-sites for 44,795 PKs in 161 eukaryotes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.phosphonet.ca/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PhosphoNET&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is an open-access, online resource developed by Kinexus Bioinformatics Corporation to foster the study of cell signalling systems to advance biomedical research in academia and industry. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.phosphonet.ca/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PhosphoNET&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is the worlds largest repository of known and predicted information on human phosphorylation sites, their evolutionary conservation, the identities of protein kinases that may target these sites and related phosphosites. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.phosphonet.ca/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PhosphoNET&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; presently holds data on over 950,000 known and putative phosphorylation sites (P-sites) in over 20,000 human proteins that have been collected from the scientific literature and other reputable websites. Over 19% of these phosphosites have been experimentally validated. The rest have been predicted with a novel P-Site Predictor algorithm developed at Kinexus with academic partners at the University of British Columbia and Simon Fraser University.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;With the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.phosphonet.ca/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PhosphoNET&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Evolution module, this website also provides information about cognate proteins in over 20 other species that may share these human phosphosites. This helps to define the most functionally important phosphosites as these are expected to be highly conserved in nature.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;With the Kinase Predictor module, listings are provided for the top 50 human protein kinases that are likely to phosphorylate each of these phosphosites using another proprietary kinase substrate prediction algorithm developed at Kinexus.  Our kinase substrate predictions are based on deduced consensus phosphorylation site amino acid frequency scoring matrices that we have determined for each of ~500 different human protein kinases. The specificity matrices are generated directly from the primary amino acid sequences of the catalytic domains of these kinases, and when available, have proven to correlate strongly with substrate prediction matrices based on alignment of known substrates of these kinases. The higher the score, the better the prospect that a kinase will phosphorylate a given site. Over 30 million kinase-substrate phosphosite pairs are quantified in &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.phosphonet.ca/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PhosphoNET&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Kinexus Bioinformatics Corporation has the capability to test most of these putative interactions in vitro for our clients.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;With the Phosphosite Match module, we have identified those phosphosites that show the greatest amino acid identity to a selected target human phosphosite. This tool is useful to identify related phosphosites that might be targeted the same protein kinases, phosphatases and/or adapter proteins. This type of query might also help identify potential off-targets for cross-reactive proteins that are detected with phosphosite-specific antibodies that were generated to recognize target phosphosites.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/tag/databases/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Databases&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/tool/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Tools &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A reference map of the human binary protein interactome</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32296183/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32296183/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Global insights into cellular organization and genome function require comprehensive understanding of the interactome networks that mediate genotype-phenotype relationships. Here we present a human &amp;lsquo;all-by-all&amp;rsquo; reference interactome map of human binary protein interactions, or &amp;lsquo;HuRI&amp;rsquo;. With approximately 53,000 protein-protein interactions, HuRI has approximately four times as many such interactions as there are high-quality curated interactions from small-scale studies. The integration of HuRI with genome, transcriptome and proteome data enables cellular function to be studied within most physiological or pathological cellular contexts. We demonstrate the utility of HuRI in identifying the specific subcellular roles of protein-protein interactions. Inferred tissue-specific networks reveal general principles for the formation of cellular context-specific functions and elucidate potential molecular mechanisms that might underlie tissue-specific phenotypes of Mendelian diseases. HuRI is a systematic proteome-wide reference that links genomic variation to phenotypic outcomes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Discovery of Protein-RNA Interactions</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tool/2019-10-25-pri/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/tool/2019-10-25-pri/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://s.tartaglialab.com/page/catrapid_group&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;catRAPID&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is an algorithm to estimate the binding propensity of protein-RNA pairs. By combining secondary structure, hydrogen bonding and van der Waals contributions, &lt;a href=&#34;http://s.tartaglialab.com/page/catrapid_group&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;catRAPID&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; predicts protein-RNA associations with great accuracy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://circinteractome.nia.nih.gov/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;CircInteractome&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; predicts the miRNAs which can potentially target the circRNAs using the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.targetscan.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Targetscan&lt;/a&gt; prediction tool. This computational tool enables the prediction and mapping of binding sites for RBPs and miRNAs on reported circRNAs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights of &lt;a href=&#34;%28https://circinteractome.nia.nih.gov/%29&#34;&gt;CircInteractome&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Searches circRNAs name&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Searches the genomic position and best-matching transcripts of the circRNA&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Retrieves genomic and mature circRNA sequences&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Searches RBPs binding to a circRNA and to sequences upstream/downstream of the circRNA&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Identifies RBPs binding to the circRNA junctions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Identifies miRNAs targeting a circRNA&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Designs divergent primers for circRNAs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Designs siRNAs Specific to circRNA&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://starbase.sysu.edu.cn/index.php&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;ENCORI (The Encyclopedia of RNA Interactomes)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is an openly licensed and state-of-the-art platform to decode the cellular interaction networks among thousands of RNA binding proteins (RBPs) and various RNAs. We have identified millions of RBP-RNA and RNA-RNA interactions through analyzing thousands of CLIP-seq and various high-throughput sequencing data by developing new software and tools, and studied their functions and mechanisms in human diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/tag/databases/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Databases&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/tool/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Tools &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Explore protein-protein interaction networks with online dababases</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tool/2018-06-12-ppi/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/tool/2018-06-12-ppi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://string-db.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;STRING&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a database of known and predicted protein-protein interactions. The interactions include direct (physical) and indirect (functional) associations; they stem from computational prediction, from knowledge transfer between organisms, and from interactions aggregated from other (primary) databases. The &lt;a href=&#34;https://string-db.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;STRING&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; database currently covers 24,584,628 proteins from 5,090 organisms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/tag/databases/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Databases&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/tool/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Tools &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Swiss bioinformatics resource portal</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tool/2018-04-08-expasy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/tool/2018-04-08-expasy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.expasy.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Expasy&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is the bioinformatics resource portal of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sib.swiss/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Swiss Institute of Bioinformatics (SIB)&lt;/a&gt;. It is an extensible and integrative portal which provides access to over 160 databases and software tools, developed by SIB Groups and supporting a range of life science and clinical research domains, from genomics, proteomics and structural biology, to evolution and phylogeny, systems biology and medical chemistry. Thanks to a user-friendly search engine, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.expasy.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Expasy&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; allows users to seamlessly：&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;query in parallel a subset of SIB databases through a single search.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;surface related information and knowledge from the complete set of &amp;gt;160 resources on the portal.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.expasy.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Expasy&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; provides information that is automatically aligned with the most recent release of each resources, thereby ensuring up-to-date information. The terms used in &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.expasy.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Expasy&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; are based on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://academic.oup.com/bioinformatics/article/29/10/1325/255660&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;EDAM comprehensive ontology&lt;/a&gt;, which was published on &lt;a href=&#34;https://academic.oup.com/bioinformatics&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Bioinformatics&lt;/a&gt; in 2013. The article about can also be accessed and downloaded on &lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/23479348/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/tag/databases/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Databases&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/tool/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Tools &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Universal protein data bank</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tool/2017-08-05-uni-prot-data-bank/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/tool/2017-08-05-uni-prot-data-bank/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h4 id=&#34;tabletrtd-bgcolora4d3eefont-size5worldwide-protein-data-bank-wwpdbfonttdtrtable&#34;&gt;&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td bgcolor=#A4D3EE&gt;&lt;font size=5&gt;Worldwide Protein Data Bank (wwPDB)&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since 1971, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.rcsb.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Protein Data Bank archive (PDB)&lt;/a&gt; has served as the single repository of information about the 3D structures of proteins, nucleic acids, and complex assemblies. The &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wwpdb.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Worldwide PDB (wwPDB)&lt;/a&gt; organization manages the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.rcsb.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;PDB&lt;/a&gt; archive and ensures that the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.rcsb.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;PDB&lt;/a&gt; is freely and publicly available to the global community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vision&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sustain freely accessible, interoperating Core Archives of structure data and metadata for biological macromolecules as an enduring public good to promote basic and applied research and education across the sciences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mission&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Manage the wwPDB Core Archives as a public good according to the FAIR Principles.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Provide expert deposition, validation, biocuration, and remediation services at no charge to Data Depositors worldwide.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ensure universal open access to public domain structural biology data with no limitations on usage.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Develop and promote community-endorsed data standards for archiving and exchange of global structural biology data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;tabletrtd-bgcolora4d3eefont-size5rcsb-protein-data-bank-pdbfonttdtrtable&#34;&gt;&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td bgcolor=#A4D3EE&gt;&lt;font size=5&gt;RCSB Protein Data Bank (PDB)&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.rcsb.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;PDB&lt;/a&gt; was established in 1971 at Brookhaven National Laboratory under the leadership of Walter Hamilton and originally contained 7 structures. After Hamilton&amp;rsquo;s untimely death, Tom Koetzle began to lead the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.rcsb.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;PDB&lt;/a&gt; in 1973, and then Joel Sussman in 1994. Led by Helen M. Berman, the Research Collaboratory for Structural Bioinformatics (RCSB) became responsible for the management of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.rcsb.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;PDB&lt;/a&gt; in 1998 in response to an RFP and a lengthy review process. Three institutions were involved: Rutgers, UCSD/SDSC, and CARB/NIST. In 2003, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wwpdb.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Worldwide Protein Data Bank (wwPDB)&lt;/a&gt; was formed to maintain a single &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.rcsb.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;PDB&lt;/a&gt; archive of macromolecular structural data that is freely and publicly available to the global community. It consists of organizations that act as deposition, data processing and distribution centers for &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.rcsb.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;PDB&lt;/a&gt; data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;tabletrtd-bgcolora4d3eefont-size5protein-data-bank-in-europe-pdbefonttdtrtable&#34;&gt;&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td bgcolor=#A4D3EE&gt;&lt;font size=5&gt;Protein Data Bank in Europe (PDBe)&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ebi.ac.uk/pdbe/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;PDBe&lt;/a&gt; is a founding member of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wwpdb.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Worldwide Protein Data Bank&lt;/a&gt; which collects, organises and disseminates data on biological macromolecular structures. In collaboration with &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wwpdb.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;the other Worldwide Protein Data Bank (wwPDB)&lt;/a&gt; partners, we work to collate, maintain and provide access to the global repository of macromolecular structure models, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.rcsb.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Protein Data Bank (PDB)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Objectives&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To provide an integrated resource of high-quality macromolecular structures and related data and make it available to the biomedical community via intuitive user interfaces.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To maintain in-house expertise in all the major structure-determination techniques (X-ray, NMR and EM) in order to stay abreast of technical and methodological developments in these fields, and to work with the community on issues of mutual interest (such as data representation, harvesting, formats and standards, or validation of structural data).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To provide high-quality deposition and annotation facilities for structural data as a wwPDB and EMDataBank deposition site.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;tabletrtd-bgcolora4d3eefont-size5protein-data-bank-japan-pdbjfonttdtrtable&#34;&gt;&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td bgcolor=#A4D3EE&gt;&lt;font size=5&gt;Protein Data Bank Japan (PDBj)&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://pdbj.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;PDBj (Protein Data Bank Japan)&lt;/a&gt; maintains the single global &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.rcsb.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;PDB&lt;/a&gt;/BMRB/&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ebi.ac.uk/emdb/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;EMDB&lt;/a&gt; archives of macromolecular structures and provide integrated tools, under the Joint Usage and Research activities of the Institute for Protein Research. The database is supported by JST-NBDC (JPMJND2205) and AMED-BINDS. &lt;a href=&#34;https://pdbj.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;PDBj&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s logo design incorporates cytochrome c (PDBID: 1cyc), which was the first structure determined in Japan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;tabletrtd-bgcolora4d3eefont-size5electron-microscopy-data-bank-emdbfonttdtrtable&#34;&gt;&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td bgcolor=#A4D3EE&gt;&lt;font size=5&gt;Electron Microscopy Data Bank (EMDB)&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ebi.ac.uk/emdb/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Electron Microscopy Data Bank (EMDB)&lt;/a&gt; is a public repository for electron cryo-microscopy volume maps and tomograms of macromolecular complexes and subcellular structures. It covers a variety of techniques, including single-particle analysis, electron tomography, and electron crystallography. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ebi.ac.uk/emdb/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;EMDB&lt;/a&gt; was founded at EMBL-EBI in 2002 under the leadership of Kim Henrick. From 2007, the archive has been operated jointly by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ebi.ac.uk/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;EMBL-EBI&lt;/a&gt; and the Research Collaboratory for Structural Bioinformatics (RCSB). In 2013, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://pdbj.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Protein Data Bank Japan (PDBj)&lt;/a&gt; also became involved in &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ebi.ac.uk/emdb/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;EMDB&lt;/a&gt;. As of the first of January, 2021, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ebi.ac.uk/emdb/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;EMDB&lt;/a&gt; is an archive operated under the aegis of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wwpdb.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Worldwide Protein Data Bank (wwPDB)&lt;/a&gt;, and has also joined that organisation as a full member.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Results of cryo-EM studies are archived in three collaborating archives:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ebi.ac.uk/emdb/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;EMDB&lt;/a&gt; stores the processed 3D volumes and tomograms.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ebi.ac.uk/emdb/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;EMDB&lt;/a&gt; stores the processed 3D volumes and tomograms.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ebi.ac.uk/empiar/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;EMPIAR (Electron Microscopy Public Image Archive)&lt;/a&gt; stores the raw EM data underpinning the data in &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ebi.ac.uk/emdb/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;EMDB&lt;/a&gt;/&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.rcsb.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;PDB&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data for &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ebi.ac.uk/emdb/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;EMDB&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.rcsb.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;PDB&lt;/a&gt; can be deposited through the wwPDB deposition and annotation system OneDep. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ebi.ac.uk/empiar/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;EMPIAR&lt;/a&gt; is a companion archive to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ebi.ac.uk/emdb/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;EMDB&lt;/a&gt;, founded at and operated by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ebi.ac.uk/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;EMBL-EBI&lt;/a&gt;, and with a mirror site at &lt;a href=&#34;https://pdbj.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;PDBj&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;tabletrtd-bgcolora4d3eefont-size5bmrbfonttdtrtable&#34;&gt;&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td bgcolor=#A4D3EE&gt;&lt;font size=5&gt;BMRB&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://bmrb.io/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;BMRB&lt;/a&gt; collects, annotates, archives, and disseminates spectral and quantitative data derived from NMR spectroscopic investigations of biological macromolecules and metabolites. &lt;a href=&#34;https://bmrb.io/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;BMRB&lt;/a&gt; makes bio-NMR data FAIR, Findable, Accessible, Interoperable, Re-usable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;tabletrtd-bgcolora4d3eefont-size5emdataresourcefonttdtrtable&#34;&gt;&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td bgcolor=#A4D3EE&gt;&lt;font size=5&gt;EMDataResource&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cryo electron microscopy enables the determination of 3D structures of macromolecular complexes and cells from 2 to 100 Å resolution. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.emdataresource.org/index.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;EMDataResource&lt;/a&gt; is the unified global portal for one-stop deposition and retrieval of 3DEM density maps, atomic models and associated metadata, and is a joint effort among investigators of the Stanford/SLAC CryoEM Facility and the Research Collaboratory for Structural Bioinformatics (RCSB) at Rutgers, in collaboration with the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ebi.ac.uk/emdb/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;EMDB&lt;/a&gt; team at the European Bioinformatics Institute. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.emdataresource.org/index.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;EMDataResource&lt;/a&gt; also serves as a resource for news, events, software tools, data standards, and validation methods for the 3DEM community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The major goal of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.emdataresource.org/index.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;EMDataResource&lt;/a&gt; project in the current funding period is to work with the 3DEM community to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;establish data-validation methods that can be used in the process of structure determination&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;define the key indicators of a well-determined structure that should accompany every deposition&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;implement appropriate validation procedures for maps and map-derived models into a 3DEM validation pipeline&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The EM Validation Task Force (EM VTF) made initial recommendations to guide development of 3DEM validation criteria. The aim is to facilitate the many processes needed to assess, establish, and disseminate validation methods and standards, including organization of community challenge activities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;tabletrtd-bgcolora4d3eefont-size5universal-protein-resource-uniprotfonttdtrtable&#34;&gt;&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td bgcolor=#A4D3EE&gt;&lt;font size=5&gt;Universal Protein Resource (UniProt)&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.uniprot.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;UniProt&lt;/a&gt; is a comprehensive resource for protein sequence and annotation data. The &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.uniprot.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;UniProt&lt;/a&gt; databases are the &lt;strong&gt;UniProt Knowledgebase (UniProtKB)&lt;/strong&gt;, the &lt;strong&gt;UniProt Reference Clusters (UniRef)&lt;/strong&gt;, and the &lt;strong&gt;UniProt Archive (UniParc)&lt;/strong&gt;. The &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.uniprot.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;UniProt&lt;/a&gt; consortium and host institutions &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ebi.ac.uk/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;EMBL-EBI&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sib.swiss/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;SIB&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://proteininformationresource.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;PIR&lt;/a&gt; are committed to the long-term preservation of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.uniprot.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;UniProt&lt;/a&gt; databases. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.uniprot.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;UniProt&lt;/a&gt; is a collaboration between the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ebi.ac.uk/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;European Bioinformatics Institute (EMBL-EBI)&lt;/a&gt;, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sib.swiss/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Swiss Institute of Bioinformatics (SIB)&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&#34;https://proteininformationresource.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Protein Information Resource (PIR)&lt;/a&gt;. Across the three institutes more than 100 people are involved through different tasks such as database curation, software development and support.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ebi.ac.uk/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;EMBL-EBI&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sib.swiss/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;SIB&lt;/a&gt; together used to produce Swiss-Prot and TrEMBL, while &lt;a href=&#34;https://proteininformationresource.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;PIR&lt;/a&gt; produced the Protein Sequence Database (PIR-PSD). These two data sets coexisted with different protein sequence coverage and annotation priorities. TrEMBL (Translated EMBL Nucleotide Sequence Data Library) was originally created because sequence data was being generated at a pace that exceeded Swiss-Prot&amp;rsquo;s ability to keep up. Meanwhile, &lt;a href=&#34;https://proteininformationresource.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;PIR&lt;/a&gt; maintained the PIR-PSD and related databases, including iProClass, a database of protein sequences and curated families. In 2002 the three institutes decided to pool their resources and expertise and formed the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.uniprot.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;UniProt&lt;/a&gt; consortium.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;tabletrtd-bgcolora4d3eefont-size5the-human-protein-atlasfonttdtrtable&#34;&gt;&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td bgcolor=#A4D3EE&gt;&lt;font size=5&gt;The Human Protein Atlas&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.proteinatlas.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Human Protein Atlas&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a Swedish-based program initiated in 2003 with the aim to map all the human proteins in cells, tissues, and organs using an integration of various omics technologies, including antibody-based imaging, mass spectrometry-based proteomics, transcriptomics, and systems biology. All the data in the knowledge resource is open access to allow scientists both in academia and industry to freely access the data for exploration of the human proteome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/tag/databases/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Databases&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/tool/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Tools &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The harmonizome: a collection of processed datasets gathered to serve and mine knowledge about genes and proteins</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/27374120/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/27374120/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Thanks to technological advances in genomics, transcriptomics, proteomics, metabolomics, and related fields, projects that generate a large number of measurements of the properties of cells, tissues, model organisms, and patients are becoming commonplace in biomedical research. In addition, curation projects are making great progress mining biomedical literature to extract and aggregate decades worth of research findings into online databases. Such projects are generating a wealth of information that potentially can guide research toward novel biomedical discoveries and advances in healthcare. To facilitate access to and learning from biomedical Big Data, we created the &lt;a href=&#34;https://maayanlab.cloud/Harmonizome/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Harmonizome&lt;/a&gt;: a collection of information about genes and proteins from 112 datasets provided by 65 online resources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!---more---&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Genomics, epigenomics, transcriptomics, proteomics and metabolomics efforts rapidly generate a plethora of data on the activity and levels of biomolecules within mammalian cells. At the same time, curation projects that organize knowledge from the biomedical literature into online databases are expanding. Hence, there is a wealth of information about genes, proteins and their associations, with an urgent need for data integration to achieve better knowledge extraction and data reuse. For this purpose, we developed the &lt;a href=&#34;https://maayanlab.cloud/Harmonizome/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Harmonizome&lt;/a&gt;: a collection of processed datasets gathered to serve and mine knowledge about genes and proteins from over 70 major online resources. We extracted, abstracted and organized data into ∼72 million functional associations between genes/proteins and their attributes. Such attributes could be physical relationships with other biomolecules, expression in cell lines and tissues, genetic associations with knockout mouse or human phenotypes, or changes in expression after drug treatment. We stored these associations in a relational database along with rich metadata for the genes/proteins, their attributes and the original resources. The freely available &lt;a href=&#34;https://maayanlab.cloud/Harmonizome/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Harmonizome&lt;/a&gt; web portal provides a graphical user interface, a web service and a mobile app for querying, browsing and downloading all of the collected data. To demonstrate the utility of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://maayanlab.cloud/Harmonizome/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Harmonizome&lt;/a&gt;, we computed and visualized gene–gene and attribute–attribute similarity networks, and through unsupervised clustering, identified many unexpected relationships by combining pairs of datasets such as the association between kinase perturbations and disease signatures. We also applied supervised machine learning methods to predict novel substrates for kinases, endogenous ligands for G-protein coupled receptors, mouse phenotypes for knockout genes, and classified unannotated transmembrane proteins for likelihood of being ion channels. The &lt;a href=&#34;https://maayanlab.cloud/Harmonizome/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Harmonizome&lt;/a&gt; is a comprehensive resource of knowledge about genes and proteins, and as such, it enables researchers to discover novel relationships between biological entities, as well as form novel data-driven hypotheses for experimental validation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
