<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Protein | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/protein/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/protein/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Protein</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Protein</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/protein/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>SGPPI: structure-aware prediction of protein-protein interactions in rigorous conditions with graph convolutional network</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36682013/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36682013/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While deep learning (DL)-based models have emerged as powerful approaches to predict protein-protein interactions (PPIs), the reliance on explicit similarity measures (e.g. sequence similarity and network neighborhood) to known interacting proteins makes these methods ineffective in dealing with novel proteins. The advent of AlphaFold2 presents a significant opportunity and also a challenge to predict PPIs in a straightforward way based on monomer structures while controlling bias from protein sequences. In this work, we established Structure and Graph-based Predictions of Protein Interactions (SGPPI), a structure-based DL framework for predicting PPIs, using the graph convolutional network. In particular, SGPPI focused on protein patches on the protein-protein binding interfaces and extracted the structural, geometric and evolutionary features from the residue contact map to predict PPIs. We demonstrated that our model outperforms traditional machine learning methods and state-of-the-art DL-based methods using non-representation-bias benchmark datasets. Moreover, our model trained on human dataset can be reliably transferred to predict yeast PPIs, indicating that SGPPI can capture converging structural features of protein interactions across various species.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Co-evolution-based prediction of metal-binding sites in proteomes by machine learning</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36593274/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36593274/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Metal ions have various important biological roles in proteins, including structural maintenance, molecular recognition and catalysis. Previous methods of predicting metal-binding sites in proteomes were based on either sequence or structural motifs. Here we developed a co-evolution-based pipeline named &amp;lsquo;MetalNet&amp;rsquo; to systematically predict metal-binding sites in proteomes. We applied MetalNet to proteomes of four representative prokaryotic species and predicted 4,849 potential metalloproteins, which substantially expands the currently annotated metalloproteomes. We biochemically and structurally validated previously unannotated metal-binding sites in several proteins, including apo-citrate lyase phosphoribosyl-dephospho-CoA transferase citX, an Escherichia coli enzyme lacking structural or sequence homology to any known metalloprotein (Protein Data Bank (PDB) codes: 7DCM and 7DCN ). MetalNet also successfully recapitulated all known zinc-binding sites from the human spliceosome complex. The pipeline of MetalNet provides a unique and enabling tool for interrogating the hidden metalloproteome and studying metal biology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The D614G mutation redirects SARS-CoV-2 spike to lysosomes and suppresses deleterious traits of the furin cleavage site insertion mutation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36563151/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36563151/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 (SARS-CoV-2) egress occurs by lysosomal exocytosis. We show that the Spike D614G mutation enhances Spike trafficking to lysosomes, drives Spike-mediated reprogramming of lysosomes, and reduces cell surface Spike expression by ~3-fold. D614G is not a human-specific adaptation. Rather, it is an adaptation to the earlier furin cleavage site insertion (FCSI) mutation that occurred at the genesis of SARS-CoV-2. While advantageous to the virus, furin cleavage of spike has deleterious effects on spike structure and function, inhibiting its trafficking to lysosomes and impairing its infectivity by the transmembrane serine protease 2(TMPRSS2)-independent, endolysosomal pathway. D614G restores spike trafficking to lysosomes and enhances the earliest events in SARS-CoV-2 infectivity, while spike mutations that restore SARS-CoV-2&amp;rsquo;s TMPRSS2-independent infectivity restore spike&amp;rsquo;s trafficking to lysosomes. Together, these and other results show that D614G is an intragenic suppressor of deleterious traits linked to the FCSI and lend additional support to the endolysosomal model of SARS-CoV-2 egress and entry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spatial proteomics in three-dimensional intact specimens</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36563667/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36563667/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spatial molecular profiling of complex tissues is essential to investigate cellular function in physiological and pathological states. However, methods for molecular analysis of large biological specimens imaged in 3D are lacking. Here, we present DISCO-MS, a technology that combines whole-organ/whole-organism clearing and imaging, deep-learning-based image analysis, robotic tissue extraction, and ultra-high-sensitivity mass spectrometry. DISCO-MS yielded proteome data indistinguishable from uncleared samples in both rodent and human tissues. We used DISCO-MS to investigate microglia activation along axonal tracts after brain injury and characterized early- and late-stage individual amyloid-beta plaques in a mouse model of Alzheimer&amp;rsquo;s disease. DISCO-bot robotic sample extraction enabled us to study the regional heterogeneity of immune cells in intact mouse bodies and aortic plaques in a complete human heart. DISCO-MS enables unbiased proteome analysis of preclinical and clinical tissues after unbiased imaging of entire specimens in 3D, identifying diagnostic and therapeutic opportunities for complex diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Suppression of PD-L1 release from small extracellular vesicles promotes systemic anti-tumor immunity by targeting ORAI1 calcium channels</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36482876/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36482876/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blockade of immune checkpoints as a strategy of cancer cells to overcome the immune response has received ample attention in cancer research recently. In particular, expression of PD-L1 by various cancer cells has become a paradigm in this respect. Delivery of PD-L1 to its site of action occurs either by local diffusion, or else by transport via small extracellular vesicles (sEVs, commonly referred to as exosomes). Many steps of sEVs formation, their packaging with PD-L1 and their release into the extracellular space have been studied in detail. The likely dependence of release on Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt;-signaling, however, has received little attention. This is surprising, since the intracellular Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt;-concentration is known as a prominent regulator of many secretory processes. Here, we report on the roles of three Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt;-dependent proteins in regulating release of PD-L1-containing sEVs, as well as on the growth of tumors in mouse models. We show that sEVs release in cancer cell lines is Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt;-dependent and the knockdown of the gene coding the Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt;-channel protein ORAI1 reduces Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt;-signals and release of sEVs. Consequently, the T cell response is reinvigorated and tumor progression in mouse models is retarded. Furthermore, analysis of protein expression patterns in samples from human cancer tissue shows that the ORAI1 gene is significantly upregulated. Such upregulation is identified as an unfavorable prognostic factor for survival of patients with non-small-cell lung cancer. We show that reduced Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt;-signaling after knockdown of ORAI1 gene also compromises the activity of melanophilin and Synaptotagmin-like protein 2, two proteins, which are important for correct localization of secretory organelles within cancer cells and their transport to sites of exocytosis. Thus, the Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt;-channel ORAI1 and Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt;-dependent proteins of the secretion pathway emerge as important targets for understanding and manipulating immune checkpoint blockade by PD-L1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quantification of extracellular proteins, protein complexes and mRNAs in single cells by proximity sequencing</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36456784/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36456784/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We present proximity sequencing (Prox-seq) for simultaneous measurement of proteins, protein complexes and mRNAs in thousands of single cells. Prox-seq combines proximity ligation assay with single-cell sequencing to measure proteins and their complexes from all pairwise combinations of targeted proteins, providing quadratically scaled multiplexing. We validate Prox-seq and analyze a mixture of T cells and B cells to show that it accurately identifies these cell types and detects well-known protein complexes. Next, by studying human peripheral blood mononuclear cells, we discover that naïve CD8+ T cells display the protein complex CD8-CD9. Finally, we study protein interactions during Toll-like receptor (TLR) signaling in human macrophages. We observe the formation of signal-specific protein complexes, find CD36 co-receptor activity and additive signal integration under lipopolysaccharide (TLR4) and Pam2CSK4 (TLR2) stimulation, and show that quantification of protein complexes identifies signaling inputs received by macrophages. Prox-seq provides access to an untapped measurement modality for single-cell phenotyping and can discover uncharacterized protein interactions in different cell types.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Proteomic Analysis of NETosis in Trauma: Emergence of SerpinB1 as a Key Player</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36730076/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36730076/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Release of neutrophil extracellular traps (NETosis) may mediate post-injury organ dysfunction, but mechanisms remain unclear. The intracellular serine protease inhibitor (serpin) B1 is vital to neutrophil function and has been shown to restrict NETosis in inflammatory settings. In this study, we utilized discovery proteomics to identify the proteomic signature of trauma-induced NETosis. We hypothesized that serpinB1 would be a major component of this NET protein profile and associated with adverse outcomes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; This was a post hoc analysis of data collected as part of the COMBAT randomized clinical trial. Blood was collected from injured patients at a single Level I Trauma Center. Proteomic analyses were performed through targeted liquid chromatography coupled with mass spectrometry. Abundances of serpinB1 and known NETosis markers were analyzed with patient and injury characteristics, clinical data, and outcomes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; SerpinB1 levels on ED arrival were significantly correlated with proteomic markers of NETosis, including core histones, transketolase, and S100A8/A9 proteins. More severely injured patients had elevated serpinB1 and NETosis markers on ED arrival. Levels of serpinB1 and top NETosis markers were significantly elevated on ED arrival in non-survivors and patients with fewer ventilator- and ICU-free days. In proteome-wide ROC analysis, serpinB1 was consistently among the top proteins associated with adverse outcomes. Among NETosis markers, levels of serpinB1 early in the patient&amp;rsquo;s course exhibited the greatest separation between patients with fewer and greater ventilator- and ICU-free days. Gene Ontology analysis of top predictors of adverse outcomes further supports NETosis as a potential mediator of post-injury organ dysfunction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; We have identified a proteomic signature of trauma-induced NETosis, and NETosis is an early process following severe injury that may mediate organ dysfunction. In addition, serpinB1 is a major component of this NET protein profile that may serve as an early marker of excessive NETosis after injury.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Evidence:&lt;/em&gt; Level III, Prognostic/Epidemiological.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SENP1 prevents steatohepatitis by suppressing RIPK1-driven apoptosis and inflammation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36414671/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36414671/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Activation of RIPK1-driven cell death and inflammation play important roles in the progression of nonalcoholic steatohepatitis (NASH). However, the mechanism underlying RIPK1 activation in NASH remains unclear. Here we identified SENP1, a SUMO-specific protease, as a key endogenous inhibitor of RIPK1. SENP1 is progressively reduced in proportion to NASH severity in patients. Hepatocyte-specific SENP1-knockout mice develop spontaneous NASH-related phenotypes in a RIPK1 kinase-dependent manner. We demonstrate that SENP1 deficiency sensitizes cells to RIPK1 kinase-dependent apoptosis by promoting RIPK1 activation following TNFα stimulation. Mechanistically, SENP1 deSUMOylates RIPK1 in TNF-R1 signaling complex (TNF-RSC), keeping RIPK1 in check. Loss of SENP1 leads to SUMOylation of RIPK1, which re-orchestrates TNF-RSC and modulates the ubiquitination patterns and activity of RIPK1. Notably, genetic inhibition of RIPK1 effectively reverses disease progression in hepatocyte-specific SENP1-knockout male mice with high-fat-diet-induced nonalcoholic fatty liver. We propose that deSUMOylation of RIPK1 by SENP1 provides a pathophysiologically relevant cell death-restricting checkpoint that modulates RIPK1 activation in the pathogenesis of nonalcoholic steatohepatitis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Urine proteomic signatures predicting the progression from premalignancy to malignant gastric cancer</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36356476/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36356476/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Early detection of gastric cancer (GC) remains challenging. We aimed to examine urine proteomic signatures and identify protein biomarkers that predict the progression of gastric lesions and risk of GC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; A case-control study was initially designed, covering subjects with GC and gastric lesions of different stages. Subjects were aged 40-69 years, without prior diagnosis of renal or urological diseases. We enrolled a total of 255 subjects, with 123 in the discovery stage from Linqu, China, a high-risk area for GC and 132 in the validation stage from Linqu and Beijing. A prospective study was further designed for a subset of 60 subjects with gastric lesions, which were followed for 297-857 days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Findings:&lt;/em&gt; We identified 43 differentially expressed urine proteins in subjects with GC vs. mild or advanced gastric lesions. Baseline urinary levels of ANXA11, CDC42, NAPA and SLC25A4 were further positively associated with risk of gastric lesion progression. Three of them, except for SLC25A4, also had higher expression in GC than non-GC tissues. Integrating these four proteins showed outstanding performance in predicting the progression of gastric lesions (AUC (95% CI): 0.92 (0.83-1.00)) and risk of GC (AUC (95% CI): 0.81 (0.73-0.89) and 0.84 (0.77-0.92) for GC vs. mild or advanced gastric lesions respectively).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Interpretation:&lt;/em&gt; This study revealed distinct urine proteomic profiles and a panel of proteins that may predict the progression of gastric lesions and risk of GC. These biomarkers in a non-invasive approach may have translational significance for defining high-risk populations of GC and its early detection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Termination of the unfolded protein response is guided by ER stress-induced HAC1 mRNA nuclear retention</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36284099/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36284099/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cellular homeostasis is maintained by surveillance mechanisms that intervene at virtually every step of gene expression. In the nucleus, the yeast chromatin remodeler Isw1 holds back maturing mRNA ribonucleoparticles to prevent their untimely export, but whether this activity operates beyond quality control of mRNA biogenesis to regulate gene expression is unknown. Here, we identify the mRNA encoding the central effector of the unfolded protein response (UPR) HAC1, as an Isw1 RNA target. The direct binding of Isw1 to the 3&amp;rsquo; untranslated region of HAC1 mRNA restricts its nuclear export and is required for accurate UPR abatement. Accordingly, ISW1 inactivation sensitizes cells to endoplasmic reticulum (ER) stress while its overexpression reduces UPR induction. Our results reveal an unsuspected mechanism, in which binding of ER-stress induced Isw1 to HAC1 mRNA limits its nuclear export, providing a feedback loop that fine-tunes UPR attenuation to guarantee homeostatic adaptation to ER stress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Histone Lactylation Boosts Reparative Gene Activation Post-Myocardial Infarction</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36268709/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36268709/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Inflammation resolution and cardiac repair initiation after myocardial infarction (MI) require timely activation of reparative signals. Histone lactylation confers macrophage homeostatic gene expression signatures via transcriptional regulation. However, the role of histone lactylation in the repair response post-MI remains unclear. We aimed to investigate whether histone lactylation induces reparative gene expression in monocytes early and remotely post-MI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; Single-cell transcriptome data indicated that reparative genes were activated early and remotely in bone marrow and circulating monocytes before cardiac recruitment. Western blotting and immunofluorescence staining revealed increases in histone lactylation levels, including the previously identified histone H3K18 lactylation in monocyte-macrophages early post-MI. Through joint CUT&amp;amp;Tag and RNA-sequencing analyses, we identified Lrg1, Vegf-a, and IL-10 as histone H3K18 lactylation target genes. The increased modification and expression levels of these target genes post-MI were verified by chromatin immunoprecipitation-qPCR and reverse transcription-qPCR.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; We demonstrated that histone lactylation regulates the anti-inflammatory and pro-angiogenic dual activities of monocyte-macrophages by facilitating reparative gene transcription and confirmed that histone lactylation favors a reparative environment and improves cardiac function post-MI. Furthermore, we explored the potential positive role of monocyte histone lactylation in reperfused MI. Mechanistically, we provided new evidence that monocytes undergo metabolic reprogramming in the early stage of MI and demonstrated that dysregulated glycolysis and MCT1 (monocarboxylate transporter 1)-mediated lactate transport promote histone lactylation. Finally, we revealed the catalytic effect of IL (interleukin)-1β-dependent GCN5 (general control non-depressible 5) recruitment on histone H3K18 lactylation and elucidated its potential role as an upstream regulatory element in the regulation of monocyte histone lactylation and downstream reparative gene expression post-MI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; Histone lactylation promotes early remote activation of the reparative transcriptional response in monocytes, which is essential for the establishment of immune homeostasis and timely activation of the cardiac repair process post-MI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MetaLP: An integrative linear programming method for protein inference in metaproteomics</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36269761/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36269761/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Metaproteomics based on high-throughput tandem mass spectrometry (MS/MS) plays a crucial role in characterizing microbiome functions. The acquired MS/MS data is searched against a protein sequence database to identify peptides, which are then used to infer a list of proteins present in a metaproteome sample. While the problem of protein inference has been well-studied for proteomics of single organisms, it remains a major challenge for metaproteomics of complex microbial communities because of the large number of degenerate peptides shared among homologous proteins in different organisms. This challenge calls for improved discrimination of true protein identifications from false protein identifications given a set of unique and degenerate peptides identified in metaproteomics. MetaLP was developed here for protein inference in metaproteomics using an integrative linear programming method. Taxonomic abundance information extracted from metagenomics shotgun sequencing or 16s rRNA gene amplicon sequencing, was incorporated as prior information in MetaLP. Benchmarking with mock, human gut, soil, and marine microbial communities demonstrated significantly higher numbers of protein identifications by MetaLP than ProteinLP, PeptideProphet, DeepPep, PIPQ, and Sipros Ensemble. In conclusion, MetaLP could substantially improve protein inference for complex metaproteomes by incorporating taxonomic abundance information in a linear programming model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Proteomic and phosphorylated proteomic landscape of injured lung in juvenile septic rats with therapeutic application of umbilical cord mesenchymal stem cells</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36341346/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36341346/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acute lung injury (ALI) is the most common complication of sepsis. Intravenous injection of HUMSCs can regulate the level of circulating endothelial cytokines and alleviate lung injury in juvenile septic rats. In this study, we performed proteomic and phosphorylated proteomic analysis of lung tissue of juvenile septic rats after Human Umbilical Cord Mesenchymal Stem Cells (HUMSCs) intervention for the first time, and screened the potential proteins and pathways of HUMSCs for therapeutic effect. The 4D proteome quantitative technique was used to quantitatively analyze the lung tissues of septic rats 24 hours (3 biological samples) and 24 hours after HUMSCs intervention (3 biological samples). A total of 213 proteins were identified as differentially expressed proteins, and 971 phosphorylation sites changed significantly. Based on the public database, we analyzed the functional enrichment of these proteins and phosphorylated proteins. In addition, Tenascin-C may be the key differential protein and ECM receptor interaction pathway may be the main signal pathway by using various algorithms to analyze the protein-protein interaction network. Phosphorylation analysis showed that tight junction pathway was closely related to immune inflammatory reaction, and EGFR interacted most, which may be the key differential phosphorylated protein. Finally, 123 conserved motifs of serine phosphorylation site (pS) and 17 conserved motifs of threonine (pT) phosphorylation sites were identified by motif analysis of phosphorylation sites. Results from proteomics and phosphorylated proteomics, the potential new therapeutic targets of HUMSCs in alleviating lung injury in juvenile septic rats were revealed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Targeting the &#34;undruggable&#34;: RNA-binding proteins in the spotlight in cancer therapy</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/35772609/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/35772609/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tumors refractory to conventional therapy belong to specific subpopulations of cancer cells, which have acquired a higher number of mutations/epigenetic changes than the majority of cancer cells. This property provides them the ability to become resistant to therapy. Aberrant expression of certain RNA-binding proteins (RBPs) can regulate the sensitivity of tumor cells to chemotherapeutic drugs by binding to specific regions present in the 3´-UTR of certain mRNAs to promote or repress mRNA translation or by interacting with other proteins (including RBPs) and non-coding RNAs that are part of ribonucleoprotein complexes. In particular, an increasing interest in the RBPs involved in chemoresistance has recently emerged. In this review, we discuss how RBPs are not only affected by chemotherapeutic treatments, but also play an active role in therapeutic responses via the direct modulation of crucial cancer-related proteins. A special focus is being placed on the development of therapeutic strategies targeting these RBPs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>iMetaLab Suite: A one-stop toolset for metaproteomics</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/imt2.25/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/imt2.25/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A one-stop solution for metaproteomics data analysis for nonexpert.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Database search and result reports that include taxonomy and function.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Interactive tools for frequently used metaproteomics data analysis tools.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Metaproteomics is a recently thriving technique that studies the collection of proteins in complex microbiomes of the human, animal, plant, and environment. The bioinformatics workflow required for metaproteomics research, from the database search and protein quantification to downstream functional and taxonomic analysis has been challenging and thus limiting the accessibility of metaproteomics to microbiome researchers. To overcome these challenges, we have developed a set of tools named &lt;a href=&#34;https://imetalab.ca/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;iMetaLab Suite&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;https://imetalab.ca/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;iMetaLab Suite&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; includes the following components:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MetaLab Desktop, an automated database search software that facilities proteins identification and quantitation from microbiomes;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the automated iMetaReport that allows users to quickly access database search results and data set profiles;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;an interactive online toolset, iMetaShiny, covering most frequently used functional, taxonomic, and statistical analysis in metaproteomics.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://imetalab.ca/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;iMetaLab Suite&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a free, easily accessible, and actively updated toolset available to assist researchers to explore metaproteomic data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DeepWalk based method to predict lncRNA-miRNA associations via lncRNA-miRNA-disease-protein-drug graph</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35216549/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35216549/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Long non-coding RNAs (lncRNAs) play a crucial role in diverse biological processes and have been confirmed to be concerned with various diseases. Largely uncharacterized of the physiological role and functions of lncRNA remains. MicroRNAs (miRNAs), which are usually 20-24 nucleotides, have several critical regulatory parts in cells. LncRNA can be regarded as a sponge to adsorb miRNA and indirectly regulate transcription and translation. Thus, the identification of lncRNA-miRNA associations is essential and valuable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; In our work, we present DWLMI to infer the potential associations between lncRNAs and miRNAs by representing them as vectors via a lncRNA-miRNA-disease-protein-drug graph. Specifically, DeepWalk can be used to learn the behavior representation of vertices. The methods of fingerprint, k-mer and MeSH descriptors were mainly used to learn the attribute representation of vertices. By combining the above two kinds of information, unknown lncRNA-miRNA associations can be predicted by the random forest classifier. Under the five-fold cross-validation, the proposed DWLMI model obtained an average prediction accuracy of 95.22% with a sensitivity of 94.35% at the AUC of 98.56%.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; The experimental results demonstrated that DWLMI can effectively predict the potential lncRNA-miRNA associated pairs, and the results can provide a new insight for related non-coding RNA researchers in the field of combing biology big data with deep learning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Platelet-Derived Drug Targets and Biomarkers of Ischemic Stroke-The First Dynamic Human LC-MS Proteomic Study</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35268287/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35268287/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Objective:&lt;/em&gt; The aim of this dynamic LC-MS (liquid chromatography and mass spectrometry) human platelet proteomic study was to identify the potential proteins candidates for biomarkers of acute ischemic stroke (AIS), their changes during the acute phase of stroke and to define potential novel drug targets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; A total of 32 patients (18-80 years old) were investigated that presented symptoms of AIS lasting less than 24 h from the onset, confirmed by neurological examination and/or new cerebral ischemia visualized in the CT (computed-tomography) scans. The analysis of platelet proteome was performed using LC-MS at baseline, and then on the third and seventh day from the onset of symptoms. The control group was demographically matched without any clinical signs of acute brain injury.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; The differences between platelets, at 24 h after first symptoms of stroke subjects and the control group included: β-amyloid A4 and amyloid-like protein 2, coactosin-like protein, thymidine phosphorylase 4 (TYMP-4), interferon regulatory factor 7 (IRF7), vitamin K-dependent protein S, histone proteins (H2A type 1 and 1-A, H2A types 2B and J, H2Av, -z, and -x), and platelet basic protein. The dynamic changes in the platelet protein concentration involved thrombospondin-1, thrombospondin-2, filamin A, B, and C.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; This is the first human dynamic LC-MS proteomic study that differentiates platelet proteome in the acute phase of ischemic stroke in time series and compares the results with healthy controls. Identified proteins may be considered as future markers of ischemic stroke or therapeutic drug targets. Thymidine phosphorylase 4 (TYMP-4) holds promise as an interesting drug target in the management or prevention of ischemic stroke.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shedding light on the hidden human proteome expands immunopeptidome in cancer</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35189633/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35189633/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unrestrained cellular growth and immune escape of a tumor are associated with the incidental errors of the genome and transcriptome. Advances in next-generation sequencing have identified thousands of genomic and transcriptomic aberrations that generate variant peptides that assemble the hidden proteome, further expanding the immunopeptidome. Emerging next-generation sequencing technologies and a number of computational methods estimated the abundance of immune infiltration from bulk transcriptome have advanced our understanding of tumor microenvironments. Here, we will characterize several major types of tumor-specific antigens arising from single-nucleotide variants, insertions and deletions, gene fusion, alternative splicing, RNA editing and non-coding RNAs. Finally, we summarize the current state-of-the-art computational and experimental approaches or resources and provide an integrative pipeline for the identification of candidate tumor antigens. Together, the systematic investigation of the hidden proteome in cancer will help facilitate the development of effective and durable immunotherapy targets for cancer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CRBPDL: Identification of circRNA-RBP interaction sites using an ensemble neural network approach</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35051187/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35051187/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Circular RNAs (circRNAs) are non-coding RNAs with a special circular structure produced formed by the reverse splicing mechanism. Increasing evidence shows that circular RNAs can directly bind to RNA-binding proteins (RBP) and play an important role in a variety of biological activities. The interactions between circRNAs and RBPs are key to comprehending the mechanism of posttranscriptional regulation. Accurately identifying binding sites is very useful for analyzing interactions. In past research, some predictors on the basis of machine learning (ML) have been presented, but prediction accuracy still needs to be ameliorated. Therefore, we present a novel calculation model, &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/nmt315320/CRBPDL.git&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CRBPDL&lt;/a&gt;, which uses an Adaboost integrated deep hierarchical network to identify the binding sites of circular RNA-RBP. &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/nmt315320/CRBPDL.git&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CRBPDL&lt;/a&gt; combines five different feature encoding schemes to encode the original RNA sequence, uses deep multiscale residual networks (MSRN) and bidirectional gating recurrent units (BiGRUs) to effectively learn high-level feature representations, it is sufficient to extract local and global context information at the same time. Additionally, a self-attention mechanism is employed to train the robustness of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/nmt315320/CRBPDL.git&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CRBPDL&lt;/a&gt;. Ultimately, the Adaboost algorithm is applied to integrate deep learning (DL) model to improve prediction performance and reliability of the model. To verify the usefulness of &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/nmt315320/CRBPDL.git&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CRBPDL&lt;/a&gt;, we compared the efficiency with state-of-the-art methods on 37 circular RNA data sets and 31 linear RNA data sets. Moreover, results display that &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/nmt315320/CRBPDL.git&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CRBPDL&lt;/a&gt; is capable of performing universal, reliable, and robust.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Early rRNA processing is a stress-dependent regulatory event whose inhibition maintains nucleolar integrity</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34928368/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34928368/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The production of ribosomes is an energy-intensive process owing to the intricacy of these massive macromolecular machines. Each human ribosome contains 80 ribosomal proteins and four non-coding RNAs. Accurate assembly requires precise regulation of protein and RNA subunits. In response to stress, the integrated stress response (ISR) rapidly inhibits global translation. How rRNA is coordinately regulated with the rapid inhibition of ribosomal protein synthesis is not known. Here, we show that stress specifically inhibits the first step of rRNA processing. Unprocessed rRNA is stored within the nucleolus, and when stress resolves, it re-enters the ribosome biogenesis pathway. Retention of unprocessed rRNA within the nucleolus aids in the maintenance of this organelle. This response is independent of the ISR or inhibition of cellular translation but is independently regulated. Failure to coordinately control ribosomal protein translation and rRNA production results in nucleolar fragmentation. Our study unveils how the rapid translational shut-off in response to stress coordinates with rRNA synthesis production to maintain nucleolar integrity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Encyclopedia of transcription factor</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tool/2021-08-06-en-tf/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/tool/2021-08-06-en-tf/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://services.healthtech.dtu.dk/service.php?Promoter-2.0&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Promoter2.0&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; predicts transcription start sites of vertebrate PolII promoters in DNA sequences. It has been developed as an evolution of simulated transcription factors that interact with sequences in promoter regions. i It builds on principles that are common to neural networks and genetic algorithms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://jaspar.genereg.net/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;JASPAR&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a regularly maintained open-access database storing manually curated transcription factors (TF) binding profiles as position frequency matrices (PFMs). PFMs summarize occurrences of each nucleotide at each position in a set of observed TF-DNA interactions. PFMs can be transformed to probabilistic or energistic models to construct position weight matrices (PWMs) or position-specific scoring matrices (PSSMs), which can be used to scan any DNA sequence to predict TF binding sites (TFBSs). The &lt;a href=&#34;https://jaspar.genereg.net/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;JASPAR&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; database provides TFBSs predicted using the profiles in the CORE collection.
The motifs in &lt;a href=&#34;https://jaspar.genereg.net/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;JASPAR&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; are collected in two ways:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Internally: de novo generated motifs, by analyzing ChIP-seq/-exo sequences using a custom motif discovery pipeline (check the code at our repository).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Externally: motifs taken directly from other publications and/or resources.
In both cases, the selected motifs are manually curated. Specifically, our curators assess the quality of the motif and search for an orthogonal publication providing support to the motif as the bona fide motif recognized by the TF of interest (e.g., a motif found in ChIP-seq peaks looks similar to one found by SELEX-seq). The Pubmed ID associated with the orthogonal support is provided in the TF profile metadata.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://jaspar.genereg.net/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;JASPAR&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is the only database with this scope where the data can be used with no restrictions (open source). For a comprehensive review of models and how they can be used, please see the following reviews:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/25045190/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Modeling the specificity of protein-DNA interactions Quant Biol. 2013 Jun;1(2):115-130&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/15131651/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Applied bioinformatics for the identification of regulatory elements Nat Rev Genet. 2004 Apr;5(4):276-87&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;http://motifmap.ics.uci.edu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MotifMap&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; system provides comprehensive maps of candidate regulatory elements encoded in the genomes of model species using databases of transcription factor binding motifs, refined genome alignments, and a comparative genomic statistical approach- Bayesian Branch Length Score. Users can filter the results by various criteria and export them to severals file formats or view them directly in the UCSC genome browser.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://gene-regulation.com/pub/databases.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TRANSFAC&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; provides data on eukaryotic transcription factors, their experimentally-proven binding sites, consensus binding sequences (positional weight matrices) and regulated genes. TRANSCompel contains data on eukaryotic transcription factors experimentally proven to act together in a synergistic or antagonistic manner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;http://the_brain.bwh.harvard.edu/uniprobe/index.php&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UniPROBE (Universal PBM Resource for Oligonucleotide Binding Evaluation)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; database hosts data generated by universal protein binding microarray (PBM) technology on the in vitro DNA binding specificities of proteins. This initial release of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://the_brain.bwh.harvard.edu/uniprobe/index.php&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UniPROBE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; database provides a centralized resource for accessing comprehensive data on the preferences of proteins for all possible sequence variants (&amp;lsquo;words&amp;rsquo;) of length k (&amp;lsquo;k-mers&amp;rsquo;), as well as position weight matrix (PWM) and graphical sequence logo representations of the k-mer data. In total, the database currently hosts DNA binding data for 726 nonredundant proteins and complexes from a diverse collection of organisms, including the prokaryote Vibrio harveyi, the eukaryotic malarial parasite Plasmodium falciparum, the parasitic Apicomplexan Cryptosporidium parvum, the yeast Saccharomyces cerevisiae, the worm Caenorhabditis elegans, mouse, and human. The database&amp;rsquo;s web tools (on the right) include a text-based search, a function for assessing motif similarity between user-entered data and database PWMs, and a function for locating putative binding sites along user-entered nucleotide sequences. Please click on each tool&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;help&amp;rdquo; link for more information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;http://bioinfo.wilmer.jhu.edu/PDI/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Human Protein-DNA Interactome (hPDI)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; database holds experimental protein-DNA interaction data for humans identified by protein microarray assays. The current release of &lt;a href=&#34;http://bioinfo.wilmer.jhu.edu/PDI/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;hPDI&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; contains 17,718 protein-DNA interactions for 1013 human DNA-binding proteins. These DNA-binding proteins include 493 human transcription factors (TFs) and 520 unconventional DNA binding proteins (uDBPs). Here TFs are defined as proteins either are annotated as &amp;ldquo;regulation of transcription&amp;rdquo; defined by GO database or contain known DNA binding domains defined by Pfam database and, uDBPs are defined proteins that have not been previously found to binding DNA specifically.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://v1.factorbook.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Factorbook&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a transcription factor (TF)-centric web-based repository of integrative analysis associated with ENCODE ChIP-seq data. It includes de novo discovered motifs, chromatin features surrounding ChIP-seq peaks (histone modification patterns, DNase I cleavage footprints, and nucleosome positioning profiles), deep-learned models of sequence features driving TF binding, and integration with GWAS variants and the ENCODE Registry of candidate cis-regulatory elements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://hocomoco.autosome.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HOmo sapiens COmprehensive MOdel COllection (HOCOMOCO)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; v11 provides transcription factor (TF) binding models for 680 human and 453 mouse TFs. Since v11, &lt;a href=&#34;https://hocomoco.autosome.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HOCOMOCO&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is complemented by MoLoTool, an interactive web tool to mark motif occurrences in a given set of DNA sequences. In addition to basic mononucleotide position weight matrices (PWMs), &lt;a href=&#34;https://hocomoco.autosome.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HOCOMOCO&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; provides dinucleotide position weight matrices based on ChIP-Seq data. All the models were produced by the ChIPMunk motif discovery tool. Model quality ratings are results of a comprehensive cross-validation benchmark. ChIP-Seq data for motif discovery was extracted from GTRD database of BioUML platform, that also provides an interface for motif finding (sequence scanning) with &lt;a href=&#34;https://hocomoco.autosome.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HOCOMOCO&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; models.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://meme-suite.org/meme/index.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MEME&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; discovers novel, ungapped motifs (recurring, fixed-length patterns) in your sequences (sample output from sequences). &lt;a href=&#34;https://meme-suite.org/meme/index.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MEME&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; splits variable-length patterns into two or more separate motifs. A motif is an approximate sequence pattern that occurs repeatedly in a group of related sequences. &lt;a href=&#34;https://meme-suite.org/meme/index.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MEME&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; represents motifs as position-dependent letter-probability matrices that describe the probability of each possible letter at each position in the pattern. Individual &lt;a href=&#34;https://meme-suite.org/meme/index.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MEME&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; motifs do not contain gaps. Patterns with variable-length gaps are split by &lt;a href=&#34;https://meme-suite.org/meme/index.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MEME&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; into two or more separate motifs. &lt;a href=&#34;https://meme-suite.org/meme/index.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MEME&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; takes as input a group of sequences and outputs as many motifs as requested. &lt;a href=&#34;https://meme-suite.org/meme/index.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MEME&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; uses statistical modeling techniques to automatically choose the best width, number of occurrences, and description for each motif. &lt;a href=&#34;https://meme-suite.org/meme/index.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MEME&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; on the web can take a second (control) set of input sequences and then discovers motifs that are enriched in the primary set relative to the control set. This is called discriminative motif discovery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://cistrome.org/db/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cistrome DB&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; uses the standard analysis pipeline ChiLin (1) to process all chromatin profiling reads.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Transcription factors (TFs) as key regulators could modulate the expression of target genes by binding to specific DNA sequences of their promoter(s) or enhancer(s). The spatiotemporal TF-target regulations play vital roles throughout the life course of organisms, especially for human beings. Thus, the identification of TF-target regulation in human is a basis for understanding the molecular regulatory mechanisms underlying biological processes including the development and pathogenesis. &lt;a href=&#34;http://bioinfo.life.hust.edu.cn/hTFtarget#!/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;hTFtarget&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; has curated comprehensive TF-target regulations from large-scale of ChIP-Seq data of human TFs (7,190 experiment samples of 659 TFs) in 569 conditions (399 types of cell line, 129 classes of tissues or cells, and 141 kinds of treatments). &lt;a href=&#34;http://bioinfo.life.hust.edu.cn/hTFtarget#!/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;hTFtarget&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; customized an analysis workflow to detect reliable TF-target regulations, which integrated the peak information of ChIP-Seq data with epigenomic modification status (Details in Document page). hTFtarget could help users to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Browse and investigate the target gene(s) of TF(s);&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Explore which TF(s) could regulate the query gene(s);&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Survey public ChIP-Seq samples for the query TF(s);&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;View ChIP-Seq peaks of the query TF(s) in user-defined manner;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Investigate potential co-associations between TFs in selected cell line(s);&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Inquire candidate co-regulation of TFs for the query gene(s);&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Predict binding sites of TF(s) on given sequence(s).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://alggen.lsi.upc.es/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PROMO&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a virtual laboratory for the identification of putative transcription factor binding sites (TFBS) in DNA sequences from a species or groups of species of interest. TFBS defined in the TRANSFAC database are used to construct specific binding site weight matrices for TFBS prediction. The user can inspect the result of the search through a graphical interface and downloadable text files.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;www.softberry.com&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Softberry&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, Inc. is a leading developer of software tools for genomic research focused on computational methods of high throughput biomedical data analysis, including software to support next generation sequencing technologies, transcriptome analysis (with RNASeq data), SNP detection and selection of disease specific SNP subsets. Its research-oriented programs have been used in thousand research projects. For example, fgenesh eukaryotic gene identification program is cited in more than 3000 articles, bprom, bacterial promoter prediction is cited in ~700 research papers. Just in 2015 our software applications have been used in more then 2000 research publications. Hundreds software applications developed in &lt;a href=&#34;www.softberry.com&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Softberry&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; can be executed on-line at &lt;a href=&#34;www.softberry.com&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Softberry&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; or downloaded for free academic usage. &lt;a href=&#34;www.softberry.com&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Softberry&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; started its commercial activities on May 1997 and is headquartered in Mount Kisco, NY, USA, with a satellite office in Novosibirsk, Russia. It participated in a number of academic collaborations on various research projects around the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://promirna.molgen.mpg.de/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PROmiRNA&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a program for annotating miRNA promoters in human, as well as other species. It uses deepCAGE data from the FANTOM4 Consortium and integrated cage tag counts and other promoter features, such as CpG content, conservation and TATA box affinity, to score the potential of a candidate regions to be a promoter. Given a list of genomic regions of interest, in the form of a gff file, &lt;a href=&#34;http://promirna.molgen.mpg.de/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PROmiRNA&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; returns the most probable promoter locations, together with the posterior probabilities calculated by the model. More informations on how to run &lt;a href=&#34;http://promirna.molgen.mpg.de/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PROmiRNA&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; on your regions of interest can be found in the README file inside the &lt;a href=&#34;http://promirna.molgen.mpg.de/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PROmiRNA&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; directory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/tag/databases/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Databases&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/tool/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Tools &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An atlas of protein-protein interactions across mouse tissues</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34214469/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34214469/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cellular processes arise from the dynamic organization of proteins in networks of physical interactions. Mapping the interactome has therefore been a central objective of high-throughput biology. However, the dynamics of protein interactions across physiological contexts remain poorly understood. Here, we develop a quantitative proteomic approach combining protein correlation profiling with stable isotope labeling of mammals (PCP-SILAM) to map the interactomes of seven mouse tissues. The resulting maps provide a proteome-scale survey of interactome rewiring across mammalian tissues, revealing more than 125,000 unique interactions at a quality comparable to the highest-quality human screens. We identify systematic suppression of cross-talk between the evolutionarily ancient housekeeping interactome and younger, tissue-specific modules. Rewired proteins are tightly regulated by multiple cellular mechanisms and are implicated in disease. Our study opens up new avenues to uncover regulatory mechanisms that shape in vivo interactome responses to physiological and pathophysiological stimuli in mammalian systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RNA-binding protein RBM47 stabilizes IFNAR1 mRNA to potentiate host antiviral activity</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34160127/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34160127/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The type I interferon (IFN-I, IFN-α/β)-mediated immune response is the first line of host defense against invading viruses. IFN-α/β binds to IFN-α/β receptors (IFNARs) and triggers the expression of IFN-stimulated genes (ISGs). Thus, stabilization of IFNARs is important for prolonging antiviral activity. Here, we report the induction of an RNA-binding motif-containing protein, RBM47, upon viral infection or interferon stimulation. Using multiple virus infection models, we demonstrate that RBM47 has broad-spectrum antiviral activity in vitro and in vivo. RBM47 has no noticeable impact on IFN production, but significantly activates the IFN-stimulated response element (ISRE) and enhances the expression of interferon-stimulated genes (ISGs). Mechanistically, RBM47 binds to the 3&amp;rsquo;UTR of IFNAR1 mRNA, increases mRNA stability, and retards the degradation of IFNAR1. In summary, this study suggests that RBM47 is an interferon-inducible RNA-binding protein that plays an essential role in enhancing host IFN downstream signaling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Message in a Bubble: Shuttling Small RNAs and Proteins Between Cells and Interacting Organisms Using Extracellular Vesicles</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/34143650/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/34143650/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Communication between plant cells and interacting microorganisms requires the secretion and uptake of functional molecules to and from the extracellular environment and is essential for the survival of both plants and their pathogens. Extracellular vesicles (EVs) are lipid bilayer-enclosed spheres that deliver RNA, protein, and metabolite cargos from donor to recipient cells and participate in many cellular processes. Emerging evidencehas shown that both plant and microbial EVs play important roles in cross-kingdom molecular exchange between hosts and interacting microbes to modulate host immunity and pathogen virulence. Recent studies revealed that plant EVs function as a defense system by encasing and delivering small RNAs (sRNAs) into pathogens, thereby mediating cross-species and cross-kingdom RNA interference to silence virulence-related genes. This review focuses on the latest advances in our understanding of plant and microbial EVs and their roles in transporting regulatory molecules, especially sRNAs, between hosts and pathogens. EV biogenesis and secretion are also discussed, as EV function relies on these important processes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hepatitis C virus modulates signal peptide peptidase to alter host protein processing</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34035171/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34035171/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Immunoevasins are viral proteins that prevent antigen presentation on major histocompatibility complex (MHC) class I, thus evading host immune recognition. Hepatitis C virus (HCV) evades immune surveillance to induce chronic infection; however, how HCV-infected hepatocytes affect immune cells and evade immune recognition remains unclear. Herein, we demonstrate that HCV core protein functions as an immunoevasin. Its expression interfered with the maturation of MHC class I molecules catalyzed by the signal peptide peptidase (SPP) and induced their degradation via HMG-CoA reductase degradation 1 homolog, thereby impairing antigen presentation to CD8&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T cells. The expression of MHC class I in the livers of HCV core transgenic mice and chronic hepatitis C patients was impaired but was restored in patients achieving sustained virological response. Finally, we show that the human cytomegalovirus US2 protein, possessing a transmembrane region structurally similar to the HCV core protein, targets SPP to impair MHC class I molecule expression. Thus, SPP represents a potential target for the impairment of MHC class I molecules by DNA and RNA viruses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The mirror site can be freely accessed by &lt;a href=&#34;http://bioinfo.org/kobas&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;clicking here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Large-scale plasma proteomic profiling identifies a high-performance biomarker panel for Alzheimer&#39;s disease screening and staging</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34032364/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34032364/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Introduction:&lt;/em&gt; Blood proteins are emerging as candidate biomarkers for Alzheimer&amp;rsquo;s disease (AD). We systematically profiled the plasma proteome to identify novel AD blood biomarkers and develop a high-performance, blood-based test for AD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; We quantified 1160 plasma proteins in a Hong Kong Chinese cohort by high-throughput proximity extension assay and validated the results in an independent cohort. In subgroup analyses, plasma biomarkers for amyloid, tau, phosphorylated tau, and neurodegeneration were used as endophenotypes of AD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; We identified 429 proteins that were dysregulated in AD plasma. We selected 19 &amp;ldquo;hub proteins&amp;rdquo; representative of the AD plasma protein profile, which formed the basis of a scoring system that accurately classified clinical AD (area under the curve = 0.9690-0.9816) and associated endophenotypes. Moreover, specific hub proteins exhibit disease stage-dependent dysregulation, which can delineate AD stages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Discussion:&lt;/em&gt; This study comprehensively profiled the AD plasma proteome and serves as a foundation for a high-performance, blood-based test for clinical AD screening and staging.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integrated Protein-Protein Interaction and Weighted Gene Co-expression Network Analysis Uncover Three Key Genes in Hepatoblastoma</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33718368/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33718368/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hepatoblastoma (HB) is the most common liver tumor in the pediatric population, with typically poor outcomes for advanced-stage or chemotherapy-refractory HB patients. The objective of this study was to identify genes involved in HB pathogenesis via microarray analysis and subsequent experimental validation. We identified 856 differentially expressed genes (DEGs) between HB and normal liver tissue based on two publicly available microarray datasets (GSE131329 and GSE75271) after data merging and batch effect correction. Protein-protein interaction (PPI) analysis and weighted gene co-expression network analysis (WGCNA) were conducted to explore HB-related critical modules and hub genes. Subsequently, Gene Ontology (GO) analysis was used to reveal critical biological functions in the initiation and progression of HB. Kyoto Encyclopedia of Genes and Genomes (KEGG) analysis showed that genes involved in cell cycle phase transition and the PI3K/AKT signaling were associated with HB. The intersection of hub genes identified by both PPI and WGCNA analyses revealed five potential candidate genes. Based on receiver operating characteristic (ROC) curve analysis and reports in the literature, we selected CCNA2, CDK1, and CDC20 as key genes of interest to validate experimentally. CCNA2, CDK1, or CDC20 small interfering RNA (siRNA) knockdown inhibited aggressive biological properties of both HepG2 and HuH-6 cell lines in vitro. In conclusion, we identified CCNA2, CDK1, and CDC20 as new potential therapeutic biomarkers for HB, providing novel insights into important and viable targets in future HB treatment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transcriptome-wide profiles of circular RNA and RNA-binding protein interactions reveal effects on circular RNA biogenesis and cancer pathway expression</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33287884/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33287884/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Circular RNAs (circRNAs) are stable, often highly expressed RNA transcripts with potential to modulate other regulatory RNAs. A few circRNAs have been shown to bind RNA-binding proteins (RBPs); however, little is known about the prevalence and distribution of these interactions in different biological contexts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; We conduct an extensive screen of circRNA-RBP interactions in the ENCODE cell lines HepG2 and K562. We profile circRNAs in deep-sequenced total RNA samples and analyze circRNA-RBP interactions using a large set of eCLIP data with binding sites of 150 RBPs. We validate interactions for select circRNAs and RBPs by performing RNA immunoprecipitation and functionally characterize our most interesting candidates by conducting knockdown studies followed by RNA-Seq.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; We generate a comprehensive catalog of circRNA-RBP interactions in HepG2 and K562 cells. We show that KHSRP binding sites are enriched in flanking introns of circRNAs and that KHSRP depletion affects circRNA biogenesis. We identify circRNAs that are highly covered by RBP binding sites and experimentally validate individual circRNA-RBP interactions. We show that circCDYL, a highly expressed circRNA with clinical and functional implications in bladder cancer, is almost completely covered with GRWD1 binding sites in HepG2 cells, and that circCDYL depletion counteracts the effect of GRWD1 depletion. Furthermore, we confirm interactions between circCDYL and RBPs in bladder cancer cells and demonstrate that circCDYL depletion affects hallmarks of cancer and perturbs the expression of key cancer genes, e.g., TP53. Finally, we show that elevated levels of circCDYL are associated with overall survival of bladder cancer patients.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; Our study demonstrates transcriptome-wide and cell-type-specific circRNA-RBP interactions that could play important regulatory roles in tumorigenesis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modification of Proteins by Metabolites in Immunity</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/33220233/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/33220233/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Immunometabolism has emerged as a key focus for immunologists, with metabolic change in immune cells becoming as important a determinant for specific immune effector responses as discrete signaling pathways. A key output for these changes involves post-translational modification (PTM) of proteins by metabolites. Products of glycolysis and Krebs cycle pathways can mediate these events, as can lipids, amino acids, and polyamines. A rich and diverse set of PTMs in macrophages and T cells has been uncovered, altering phenotype and modulating immunity and inflammation in different contexts. We review the recent findings in this area and speculate whether they could be of use in the effort to develop therapeutics for immune-related diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Decrypting UFMylation: How Proteins Are Modified with UFM1</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/33066455/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/33066455/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Besides ubiquitin (Ub), humans have a set of ubiquitin-like proteins (UBLs) that can also covalently modify target proteins. To date, less is known about UBLs than Ub and even less is known about the UBL called ubiquitin-fold modifier 1 (UFM1). Currently, our understanding of protein modification by UFM1 (UFMylation) is like a jigsaw puzzle with many missing pieces, and in some cases it is not even clear whether these pieces of data are in the right place. Here we review the current data on UFM1 from structural biology to biochemistry and cell biology. We believe that the physiological significance of protein modification by UFM1 is currently underestimated and there is more to it than meets the eye.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prediction of kinase-specific phosphorylation sites in proteins</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tool/2020-04-12-pkspsp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/tool/2020-04-12-pkspsp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In eukaryotes, protein phosphorylation is specifically catalyzed by numerous protein kinases (PKs), faithfully orchestrates various biological processes, and reversibly determines cellular dynamics and plasticity. Here we report an updated algorithm of &lt;a href=&#34;%28http://gps.biocuckoo.cn/%29&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Group-based Prediction System (PGS)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 5.0 to improve the performance for predicting kinase-specific phosphorylation sites (p-sites). Two novel methods, position weight determination (PWD) and scoring matrix optimization (SMO), were developed. Compared with other existing tools, &lt;a href=&#34;http://gps.biocuckoo.cn/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GPS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 5.0 exhibits a highly competitive accuracy. Besides serine/threonine or tyrosine kinases, &lt;a href=&#34;http://gps.biocuckoo.cn/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GPS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 5.0 also supports the prediction of dual-specificity kinase-specific p-sites. In the classical module of &lt;a href=&#34;http://gps.biocuckoo.cn/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GPS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 5.0, 617 individual predictors were constructed for predicting p-sites of 479 human PKs. To extend the application of &lt;a href=&#34;http://gps.biocuckoo.cn/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GPS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 5.0, a species-specific module was implemented to predict kinase-specific p-sites for 44,795 PKs in 161 eukaryotes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.phosphonet.ca/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PhosphoNET&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is an open-access, online resource developed by Kinexus Bioinformatics Corporation to foster the study of cell signalling systems to advance biomedical research in academia and industry. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.phosphonet.ca/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PhosphoNET&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is the worlds largest repository of known and predicted information on human phosphorylation sites, their evolutionary conservation, the identities of protein kinases that may target these sites and related phosphosites. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.phosphonet.ca/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PhosphoNET&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; presently holds data on over 950,000 known and putative phosphorylation sites (P-sites) in over 20,000 human proteins that have been collected from the scientific literature and other reputable websites. Over 19% of these phosphosites have been experimentally validated. The rest have been predicted with a novel P-Site Predictor algorithm developed at Kinexus with academic partners at the University of British Columbia and Simon Fraser University.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;With the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.phosphonet.ca/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PhosphoNET&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Evolution module, this website also provides information about cognate proteins in over 20 other species that may share these human phosphosites. This helps to define the most functionally important phosphosites as these are expected to be highly conserved in nature.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;With the Kinase Predictor module, listings are provided for the top 50 human protein kinases that are likely to phosphorylate each of these phosphosites using another proprietary kinase substrate prediction algorithm developed at Kinexus.  Our kinase substrate predictions are based on deduced consensus phosphorylation site amino acid frequency scoring matrices that we have determined for each of ~500 different human protein kinases. The specificity matrices are generated directly from the primary amino acid sequences of the catalytic domains of these kinases, and when available, have proven to correlate strongly with substrate prediction matrices based on alignment of known substrates of these kinases. The higher the score, the better the prospect that a kinase will phosphorylate a given site. Over 30 million kinase-substrate phosphosite pairs are quantified in &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.phosphonet.ca/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PhosphoNET&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Kinexus Bioinformatics Corporation has the capability to test most of these putative interactions in vitro for our clients.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;With the Phosphosite Match module, we have identified those phosphosites that show the greatest amino acid identity to a selected target human phosphosite. This tool is useful to identify related phosphosites that might be targeted the same protein kinases, phosphatases and/or adapter proteins. This type of query might also help identify potential off-targets for cross-reactive proteins that are detected with phosphosite-specific antibodies that were generated to recognize target phosphosites.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/tag/databases/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Databases&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/tool/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Tools &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A reference map of the human binary protein interactome</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32296183/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32296183/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Global insights into cellular organization and genome function require comprehensive understanding of the interactome networks that mediate genotype-phenotype relationships. Here we present a human &amp;lsquo;all-by-all&amp;rsquo; reference interactome map of human binary protein interactions, or &amp;lsquo;HuRI&amp;rsquo;. With approximately 53,000 protein-protein interactions, HuRI has approximately four times as many such interactions as there are high-quality curated interactions from small-scale studies. The integration of HuRI with genome, transcriptome and proteome data enables cellular function to be studied within most physiological or pathological cellular contexts. We demonstrate the utility of HuRI in identifying the specific subcellular roles of protein-protein interactions. Inferred tissue-specific networks reveal general principles for the formation of cellular context-specific functions and elucidate potential molecular mechanisms that might underlie tissue-specific phenotypes of Mendelian diseases. HuRI is a systematic proteome-wide reference that links genomic variation to phenotypic outcomes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How RNA-Binding Proteins Interact with RNA: Molecules and Mechanisms</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/32243832/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/32243832/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;RNA-binding proteins (RBPs) comprise a large class of over 2,000 proteins that interact with transcripts in all manner of RNA-driven processes. The structures and mechanisms that RBPs use to bind and regulate RNA are incredibly diverse. In this review, we take a look at the components of protein-RNA interaction, from the molecular level to multi-component interaction. We first summarize what is known about protein-RNA molecular interactions based on analyses of solved structures. We additionally describe software currently available for predicting protein-RNA interaction and other resources useful for the study of RBPs. We then review the structure and function of seventeen known RNA-binding domains and analyze the hydrogen bonds adopted by protein-RNA structures on a domain-by-domain basis. We conclude with a summary of the higher-level mechanisms that regulate protein-RNA interactions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The UFMylation System in Proteostasis and Beyond</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/31703843/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/31703843/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Post-translational modifications are at the apex of cellular communication and eventually regulate every aspect of life. The identification of new post-translational modifiers is opening alternative avenues in understanding fundamental cell biology processes and may ultimately provide novel therapeutic opportunities. The ubiquitin-fold modifier 1 (UFM1) is a post-translational modifier discovered a decade ago but its biological significance has remained mostly unknown. The field has recently witnessed an explosion of research uncovering the implications of the pathway to cellular homeostasis in living organisms. We overview recent advances in the function and regulation of the UFM1 pathway, and its implications for cell physiology and disease.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Discovery of Protein-RNA Interactions</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tool/2019-10-25-pri/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/tool/2019-10-25-pri/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://s.tartaglialab.com/page/catrapid_group&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;catRAPID&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is an algorithm to estimate the binding propensity of protein-RNA pairs. By combining secondary structure, hydrogen bonding and van der Waals contributions, &lt;a href=&#34;http://s.tartaglialab.com/page/catrapid_group&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;catRAPID&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; predicts protein-RNA associations with great accuracy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://circinteractome.nia.nih.gov/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;CircInteractome&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; predicts the miRNAs which can potentially target the circRNAs using the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.targetscan.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Targetscan&lt;/a&gt; prediction tool. This computational tool enables the prediction and mapping of binding sites for RBPs and miRNAs on reported circRNAs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights of &lt;a href=&#34;%28https://circinteractome.nia.nih.gov/%29&#34;&gt;CircInteractome&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Searches circRNAs name&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Searches the genomic position and best-matching transcripts of the circRNA&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Retrieves genomic and mature circRNA sequences&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Searches RBPs binding to a circRNA and to sequences upstream/downstream of the circRNA&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Identifies RBPs binding to the circRNA junctions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Identifies miRNAs targeting a circRNA&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Designs divergent primers for circRNAs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Designs siRNAs Specific to circRNA&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://starbase.sysu.edu.cn/index.php&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;ENCORI (The Encyclopedia of RNA Interactomes)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is an openly licensed and state-of-the-art platform to decode the cellular interaction networks among thousands of RNA binding proteins (RBPs) and various RNAs. We have identified millions of RBP-RNA and RNA-RNA interactions through analyzing thousands of CLIP-seq and various high-throughput sequencing data by developing new software and tools, and studied their functions and mechanisms in human diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/tag/databases/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Databases&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/tool/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Tools &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Explore protein-protein interaction networks with online dababases</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tool/2018-06-12-ppi/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/tool/2018-06-12-ppi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://string-db.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;STRING&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a database of known and predicted protein-protein interactions. The interactions include direct (physical) and indirect (functional) associations; they stem from computational prediction, from knowledge transfer between organisms, and from interactions aggregated from other (primary) databases. The &lt;a href=&#34;https://string-db.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;STRING&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; database currently covers 24,584,628 proteins from 5,090 organisms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/tag/databases/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Databases&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/tool/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Tools &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Swiss bioinformatics resource portal</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tool/2018-04-08-expasy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/tool/2018-04-08-expasy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.expasy.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Expasy&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is the bioinformatics resource portal of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sib.swiss/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Swiss Institute of Bioinformatics (SIB)&lt;/a&gt;. It is an extensible and integrative portal which provides access to over 160 databases and software tools, developed by SIB Groups and supporting a range of life science and clinical research domains, from genomics, proteomics and structural biology, to evolution and phylogeny, systems biology and medical chemistry. Thanks to a user-friendly search engine, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.expasy.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Expasy&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; allows users to seamlessly：&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;query in parallel a subset of SIB databases through a single search.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;surface related information and knowledge from the complete set of &amp;gt;160 resources on the portal.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.expasy.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Expasy&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; provides information that is automatically aligned with the most recent release of each resources, thereby ensuring up-to-date information. The terms used in &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.expasy.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Expasy&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; are based on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://academic.oup.com/bioinformatics/article/29/10/1325/255660&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;EDAM comprehensive ontology&lt;/a&gt;, which was published on &lt;a href=&#34;https://academic.oup.com/bioinformatics&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Bioinformatics&lt;/a&gt; in 2013. The article about can also be accessed and downloaded on &lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/23479348/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/tag/databases/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Databases&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/tool/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Tools &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Universal protein data bank</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tool/2017-08-05-uni-prot-data-bank/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/tool/2017-08-05-uni-prot-data-bank/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h4 id=&#34;tabletrtd-bgcolora4d3eefont-size5worldwide-protein-data-bank-wwpdbfonttdtrtable&#34;&gt;&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td bgcolor=#A4D3EE&gt;&lt;font size=5&gt;Worldwide Protein Data Bank (wwPDB)&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since 1971, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.rcsb.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Protein Data Bank archive (PDB)&lt;/a&gt; has served as the single repository of information about the 3D structures of proteins, nucleic acids, and complex assemblies. The &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wwpdb.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Worldwide PDB (wwPDB)&lt;/a&gt; organization manages the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.rcsb.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;PDB&lt;/a&gt; archive and ensures that the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.rcsb.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;PDB&lt;/a&gt; is freely and publicly available to the global community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vision&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sustain freely accessible, interoperating Core Archives of structure data and metadata for biological macromolecules as an enduring public good to promote basic and applied research and education across the sciences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mission&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Manage the wwPDB Core Archives as a public good according to the FAIR Principles.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Provide expert deposition, validation, biocuration, and remediation services at no charge to Data Depositors worldwide.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ensure universal open access to public domain structural biology data with no limitations on usage.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Develop and promote community-endorsed data standards for archiving and exchange of global structural biology data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;tabletrtd-bgcolora4d3eefont-size5rcsb-protein-data-bank-pdbfonttdtrtable&#34;&gt;&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td bgcolor=#A4D3EE&gt;&lt;font size=5&gt;RCSB Protein Data Bank (PDB)&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.rcsb.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;PDB&lt;/a&gt; was established in 1971 at Brookhaven National Laboratory under the leadership of Walter Hamilton and originally contained 7 structures. After Hamilton&amp;rsquo;s untimely death, Tom Koetzle began to lead the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.rcsb.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;PDB&lt;/a&gt; in 1973, and then Joel Sussman in 1994. Led by Helen M. Berman, the Research Collaboratory for Structural Bioinformatics (RCSB) became responsible for the management of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.rcsb.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;PDB&lt;/a&gt; in 1998 in response to an RFP and a lengthy review process. Three institutions were involved: Rutgers, UCSD/SDSC, and CARB/NIST. In 2003, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wwpdb.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Worldwide Protein Data Bank (wwPDB)&lt;/a&gt; was formed to maintain a single &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.rcsb.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;PDB&lt;/a&gt; archive of macromolecular structural data that is freely and publicly available to the global community. It consists of organizations that act as deposition, data processing and distribution centers for &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.rcsb.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;PDB&lt;/a&gt; data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;tabletrtd-bgcolora4d3eefont-size5protein-data-bank-in-europe-pdbefonttdtrtable&#34;&gt;&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td bgcolor=#A4D3EE&gt;&lt;font size=5&gt;Protein Data Bank in Europe (PDBe)&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ebi.ac.uk/pdbe/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;PDBe&lt;/a&gt; is a founding member of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wwpdb.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Worldwide Protein Data Bank&lt;/a&gt; which collects, organises and disseminates data on biological macromolecular structures. In collaboration with &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wwpdb.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;the other Worldwide Protein Data Bank (wwPDB)&lt;/a&gt; partners, we work to collate, maintain and provide access to the global repository of macromolecular structure models, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.rcsb.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Protein Data Bank (PDB)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Objectives&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To provide an integrated resource of high-quality macromolecular structures and related data and make it available to the biomedical community via intuitive user interfaces.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To maintain in-house expertise in all the major structure-determination techniques (X-ray, NMR and EM) in order to stay abreast of technical and methodological developments in these fields, and to work with the community on issues of mutual interest (such as data representation, harvesting, formats and standards, or validation of structural data).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To provide high-quality deposition and annotation facilities for structural data as a wwPDB and EMDataBank deposition site.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;tabletrtd-bgcolora4d3eefont-size5protein-data-bank-japan-pdbjfonttdtrtable&#34;&gt;&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td bgcolor=#A4D3EE&gt;&lt;font size=5&gt;Protein Data Bank Japan (PDBj)&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://pdbj.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;PDBj (Protein Data Bank Japan)&lt;/a&gt; maintains the single global &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.rcsb.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;PDB&lt;/a&gt;/BMRB/&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ebi.ac.uk/emdb/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;EMDB&lt;/a&gt; archives of macromolecular structures and provide integrated tools, under the Joint Usage and Research activities of the Institute for Protein Research. The database is supported by JST-NBDC (JPMJND2205) and AMED-BINDS. &lt;a href=&#34;https://pdbj.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;PDBj&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s logo design incorporates cytochrome c (PDBID: 1cyc), which was the first structure determined in Japan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;tabletrtd-bgcolora4d3eefont-size5electron-microscopy-data-bank-emdbfonttdtrtable&#34;&gt;&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td bgcolor=#A4D3EE&gt;&lt;font size=5&gt;Electron Microscopy Data Bank (EMDB)&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ebi.ac.uk/emdb/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Electron Microscopy Data Bank (EMDB)&lt;/a&gt; is a public repository for electron cryo-microscopy volume maps and tomograms of macromolecular complexes and subcellular structures. It covers a variety of techniques, including single-particle analysis, electron tomography, and electron crystallography. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ebi.ac.uk/emdb/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;EMDB&lt;/a&gt; was founded at EMBL-EBI in 2002 under the leadership of Kim Henrick. From 2007, the archive has been operated jointly by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ebi.ac.uk/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;EMBL-EBI&lt;/a&gt; and the Research Collaboratory for Structural Bioinformatics (RCSB). In 2013, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://pdbj.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Protein Data Bank Japan (PDBj)&lt;/a&gt; also became involved in &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ebi.ac.uk/emdb/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;EMDB&lt;/a&gt;. As of the first of January, 2021, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ebi.ac.uk/emdb/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;EMDB&lt;/a&gt; is an archive operated under the aegis of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wwpdb.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Worldwide Protein Data Bank (wwPDB)&lt;/a&gt;, and has also joined that organisation as a full member.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Results of cryo-EM studies are archived in three collaborating archives:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ebi.ac.uk/emdb/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;EMDB&lt;/a&gt; stores the processed 3D volumes and tomograms.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ebi.ac.uk/emdb/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;EMDB&lt;/a&gt; stores the processed 3D volumes and tomograms.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ebi.ac.uk/empiar/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;EMPIAR (Electron Microscopy Public Image Archive)&lt;/a&gt; stores the raw EM data underpinning the data in &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ebi.ac.uk/emdb/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;EMDB&lt;/a&gt;/&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.rcsb.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;PDB&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data for &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ebi.ac.uk/emdb/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;EMDB&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.rcsb.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;PDB&lt;/a&gt; can be deposited through the wwPDB deposition and annotation system OneDep. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ebi.ac.uk/empiar/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;EMPIAR&lt;/a&gt; is a companion archive to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ebi.ac.uk/emdb/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;EMDB&lt;/a&gt;, founded at and operated by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ebi.ac.uk/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;EMBL-EBI&lt;/a&gt;, and with a mirror site at &lt;a href=&#34;https://pdbj.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;PDBj&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;tabletrtd-bgcolora4d3eefont-size5bmrbfonttdtrtable&#34;&gt;&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td bgcolor=#A4D3EE&gt;&lt;font size=5&gt;BMRB&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://bmrb.io/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;BMRB&lt;/a&gt; collects, annotates, archives, and disseminates spectral and quantitative data derived from NMR spectroscopic investigations of biological macromolecules and metabolites. &lt;a href=&#34;https://bmrb.io/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;BMRB&lt;/a&gt; makes bio-NMR data FAIR, Findable, Accessible, Interoperable, Re-usable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;tabletrtd-bgcolora4d3eefont-size5emdataresourcefonttdtrtable&#34;&gt;&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td bgcolor=#A4D3EE&gt;&lt;font size=5&gt;EMDataResource&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cryo electron microscopy enables the determination of 3D structures of macromolecular complexes and cells from 2 to 100 Å resolution. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.emdataresource.org/index.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;EMDataResource&lt;/a&gt; is the unified global portal for one-stop deposition and retrieval of 3DEM density maps, atomic models and associated metadata, and is a joint effort among investigators of the Stanford/SLAC CryoEM Facility and the Research Collaboratory for Structural Bioinformatics (RCSB) at Rutgers, in collaboration with the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ebi.ac.uk/emdb/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;EMDB&lt;/a&gt; team at the European Bioinformatics Institute. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.emdataresource.org/index.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;EMDataResource&lt;/a&gt; also serves as a resource for news, events, software tools, data standards, and validation methods for the 3DEM community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The major goal of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.emdataresource.org/index.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;EMDataResource&lt;/a&gt; project in the current funding period is to work with the 3DEM community to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;establish data-validation methods that can be used in the process of structure determination&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;define the key indicators of a well-determined structure that should accompany every deposition&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;implement appropriate validation procedures for maps and map-derived models into a 3DEM validation pipeline&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The EM Validation Task Force (EM VTF) made initial recommendations to guide development of 3DEM validation criteria. The aim is to facilitate the many processes needed to assess, establish, and disseminate validation methods and standards, including organization of community challenge activities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;tabletrtd-bgcolora4d3eefont-size5universal-protein-resource-uniprotfonttdtrtable&#34;&gt;&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td bgcolor=#A4D3EE&gt;&lt;font size=5&gt;Universal Protein Resource (UniProt)&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.uniprot.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;UniProt&lt;/a&gt; is a comprehensive resource for protein sequence and annotation data. The &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.uniprot.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;UniProt&lt;/a&gt; databases are the &lt;strong&gt;UniProt Knowledgebase (UniProtKB)&lt;/strong&gt;, the &lt;strong&gt;UniProt Reference Clusters (UniRef)&lt;/strong&gt;, and the &lt;strong&gt;UniProt Archive (UniParc)&lt;/strong&gt;. The &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.uniprot.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;UniProt&lt;/a&gt; consortium and host institutions &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ebi.ac.uk/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;EMBL-EBI&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sib.swiss/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;SIB&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://proteininformationresource.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;PIR&lt;/a&gt; are committed to the long-term preservation of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.uniprot.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;UniProt&lt;/a&gt; databases. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.uniprot.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;UniProt&lt;/a&gt; is a collaboration between the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ebi.ac.uk/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;European Bioinformatics Institute (EMBL-EBI)&lt;/a&gt;, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sib.swiss/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Swiss Institute of Bioinformatics (SIB)&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&#34;https://proteininformationresource.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Protein Information Resource (PIR)&lt;/a&gt;. Across the three institutes more than 100 people are involved through different tasks such as database curation, software development and support.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ebi.ac.uk/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;EMBL-EBI&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sib.swiss/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;SIB&lt;/a&gt; together used to produce Swiss-Prot and TrEMBL, while &lt;a href=&#34;https://proteininformationresource.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;PIR&lt;/a&gt; produced the Protein Sequence Database (PIR-PSD). These two data sets coexisted with different protein sequence coverage and annotation priorities. TrEMBL (Translated EMBL Nucleotide Sequence Data Library) was originally created because sequence data was being generated at a pace that exceeded Swiss-Prot&amp;rsquo;s ability to keep up. Meanwhile, &lt;a href=&#34;https://proteininformationresource.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;PIR&lt;/a&gt; maintained the PIR-PSD and related databases, including iProClass, a database of protein sequences and curated families. In 2002 the three institutes decided to pool their resources and expertise and formed the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.uniprot.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;UniProt&lt;/a&gt; consortium.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;tabletrtd-bgcolora4d3eefont-size5the-human-protein-atlasfonttdtrtable&#34;&gt;&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td bgcolor=#A4D3EE&gt;&lt;font size=5&gt;The Human Protein Atlas&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.proteinatlas.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Human Protein Atlas&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a Swedish-based program initiated in 2003 with the aim to map all the human proteins in cells, tissues, and organs using an integration of various omics technologies, including antibody-based imaging, mass spectrometry-based proteomics, transcriptomics, and systems biology. All the data in the knowledge resource is open access to allow scientists both in academia and industry to freely access the data for exploration of the human proteome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/tag/databases/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Databases&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/tool/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Tools &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The harmonizome: a collection of processed datasets gathered to serve and mine knowledge about genes and proteins</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/27374120/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/27374120/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Thanks to technological advances in genomics, transcriptomics, proteomics, metabolomics, and related fields, projects that generate a large number of measurements of the properties of cells, tissues, model organisms, and patients are becoming commonplace in biomedical research. In addition, curation projects are making great progress mining biomedical literature to extract and aggregate decades worth of research findings into online databases. Such projects are generating a wealth of information that potentially can guide research toward novel biomedical discoveries and advances in healthcare. To facilitate access to and learning from biomedical Big Data, we created the &lt;a href=&#34;https://maayanlab.cloud/Harmonizome/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Harmonizome&lt;/a&gt;: a collection of information about genes and proteins from 112 datasets provided by 65 online resources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!---more---&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Genomics, epigenomics, transcriptomics, proteomics and metabolomics efforts rapidly generate a plethora of data on the activity and levels of biomolecules within mammalian cells. At the same time, curation projects that organize knowledge from the biomedical literature into online databases are expanding. Hence, there is a wealth of information about genes, proteins and their associations, with an urgent need for data integration to achieve better knowledge extraction and data reuse. For this purpose, we developed the &lt;a href=&#34;https://maayanlab.cloud/Harmonizome/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Harmonizome&lt;/a&gt;: a collection of processed datasets gathered to serve and mine knowledge about genes and proteins from over 70 major online resources. We extracted, abstracted and organized data into ∼72 million functional associations between genes/proteins and their attributes. Such attributes could be physical relationships with other biomolecules, expression in cell lines and tissues, genetic associations with knockout mouse or human phenotypes, or changes in expression after drug treatment. We stored these associations in a relational database along with rich metadata for the genes/proteins, their attributes and the original resources. The freely available &lt;a href=&#34;https://maayanlab.cloud/Harmonizome/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Harmonizome&lt;/a&gt; web portal provides a graphical user interface, a web service and a mobile app for querying, browsing and downloading all of the collected data. To demonstrate the utility of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://maayanlab.cloud/Harmonizome/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Harmonizome&lt;/a&gt;, we computed and visualized gene–gene and attribute–attribute similarity networks, and through unsupervised clustering, identified many unexpected relationships by combining pairs of datasets such as the association between kinase perturbations and disease signatures. We also applied supervised machine learning methods to predict novel substrates for kinases, endogenous ligands for G-protein coupled receptors, mouse phenotypes for knockout genes, and classified unannotated transmembrane proteins for likelihood of being ion channels. The &lt;a href=&#34;https://maayanlab.cloud/Harmonizome/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Harmonizome&lt;/a&gt; is a comprehensive resource of knowledge about genes and proteins, and as such, it enables researchers to discover novel relationships between biological entities, as well as form novel data-driven hypotheses for experimental validation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
