<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Alphavirus | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/alphavirus/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/alphavirus/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Alphavirus</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Alphavirus</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/alphavirus/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Host Immune Responses to Arthritogenic Alphavirus Infection, with Emphasis on Type I IFN Responses</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/zoonoses-2022-0028/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/zoonoses-2022-0028/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Arthritogenic alphaviruses, such as Ross River virus, chikungunya virus and O’nyong-nyong virus, cause endemic disease globally and are a major public health concern. The hallmarks of arthritogenic alphavirus disease are debilitating pain, and potentially chronic inflammation of the muscles, thus influencing quality of life. The type I IFN response is a major component of the innate immune response against arthritogenic alphaviruses, and is essential in inhibiting viral replication and dissemination. Type I IFNs are induced during early stages of infection and are essential for the activation of the antiviral innate immune response. They also link the innate immune response and the activation of adaptive immunity. This review focuses on the host immune response, particularly that involving type I IFN, in arthritogenic alphavirus disease.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VLDLR and ApoER2 are receptors for multiple alphaviruses</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34929721/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34929721/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alphaviruses, like many other arthropod-borne viruses, infect vertebrate species and insect vectors separated by hundreds of millions of years of evolutionary history. Entry into evolutionarily divergent host cells can be accomplished by recognition of different cellular receptors in different species, or by binding to receptors that are highly conserved across species. Although multiple alphavirus receptors have been described1-3, most are not shared among vertebrate and invertebrate hosts. Here we identify the very low-density lipoprotein receptor (VLDLR) as a receptor for the prototypic alphavirus Semliki forest virus. We show that the E2 and E1 glycoproteins (E2-E1) of Semliki forest virus, eastern equine encephalitis virus and Sindbis virus interact with the ligand-binding domains (LBDs) of VLDLR and apolipoprotein E receptor 2 (ApoER2), two closely related receptors. Ectopic expression of either protein facilitates cellular attachment, and internalization of virus-like particles, a VLDLR LBD-Fc fusion protein or a ligand-binding antagonist block Semliki forest virus E2-E1-mediated infection of human and mouse neurons in culture. The administration of a VLDLR LBD-Fc fusion protein has protective activity against rapidly fatal Semliki forest virus infection in mouse neonates. We further show that invertebrate receptor orthologues from mosquitoes and worms can serve as functional alphavirus receptors. We propose that the ability of some alphaviruses to infect a wide range of hosts is a result of their engagement of evolutionarily conserved lipoprotein receptors and contributes to their pathogenesis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
