<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>TLR/NF-κB | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/tlr/nf-%CE%BAb/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/tlr/nf-%CE%BAb/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>TLR/NF-κB</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>TLR/NF-κB</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/tlr/nf-%CE%BAb/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Total glycosides of Rhodiola rosea L. attenuate LPS-induced acute lung injury by inhibiting TLR4/NF-κB pathway</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36587557/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36587557/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Total glycosides of Rhodiola rosea L. alleviate LPS-induced acute lung injury.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Total glycosides of Rhodiola rosea L. protect mice by reducing pulmonary edema.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Total glycosides of Rhodiola rosea L. inhibit the influx of inflammatory cells into the lung.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Total glycosides of Rhodiola rosea L. reduce inflammation in the lung by inhibiting TLR4/NF-κB pathway.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acute lung injury (ALI) is a common respiratory disease in clinics, which is characterized by alveolar-capillary membrane loss, plasma protein leakage, pulmonary edema, massive neutrophil infiltration, and the release of proinflammatory cytokines and mediators. Rhodiola rosea L. an adaptogenic plant rich in phenylethanoloids, phenylpropanoids, monoterpenes, has anti-inflammatory and antioxidant effects. We hope to verify the relieving effect of total glycosides of Rhodiola rosea L. (RTG) on ALI in mice and clarify its mechanism through this study. In this study, we identified the effect and mechanism of RTG on ALI through LPS-induced ALI mice. After RTG treatment, the pathological structure of lung tissue in ALI mice induced by LPS was significantly improved, and the infiltration of inflammatory cells was reduced. In addition, RTG reduced the production of IL-6, IL-1β, and TNF-α in the serum of ALI mice and reduced the content or activity of MPO, T-SOD, GSH, and MDA in lung tissue. RNAseq analysis showed that RTG ameliorated LPS-induced ALI through anti-inflammatory, reduced immune response, and anti-apoptotic activities. The western blotting analysis confirmed that RTG could down-regulate the expression levels of TLR4, MyD88, NF-κB p65, and p-IκBα/IκBα. These results suggest that RTG can attenuate LPS-induced ALI through antioxidants and inhibition of the TLR4/NF-κB pathway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BAP31 regulates the expression of ICAM-1/VCAM-1 via MyD88/NF-κB pathway in acute lung injury mice model</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36549351/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36549351/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Aims:&lt;/em&gt; The cell adhesion molecules (CAMs) that mediate neutrophil-endothelium cell adhesion are deeply involved in the pathogenesis of acute lung injury (ALI). B-cell receptor associated protein 31 (BAP31) has been reported to engage in the expression of some CAMs. This study was undertaken to explore whether BAP31 in endotheliocyte affects the pathological process of ALI by regulating CAMs, and its possible mechanism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Main methods:&lt;/em&gt; Our study used the shBAP31 endothelium cell lines and endothelial-specific BAP31 conditional knockdown mice constructed via Cre/loxP system. Hematoxylin and eosin staining was used to observe the histopathological manifestations. The adhesion of neutrophils to vascular wall was examined by intravital microscopy. The nuclear translocation of NF-κB was observed by immunofluorescence staining assay. Flow cytometric, real-time polymerase chain reaction and Western blot assay were performed to determine the expression of CAMs and key proteins in MyD88/NF-κB-related signaling pathway. Luciferase reporter and chromatin immunoprecipitation assay were analyzed for transcriptional activity of ICAM-1 and VCAM-1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Key findings:&lt;/em&gt; Mechanistic investigations indicated that endothelium-specific BAP31 depletion dramatically reduced the capacity of neutrophils adherence to endothelial cells (ECs), which was mainly attributed to the significant downregulation of ICAM-1 (&lt;em&gt;p&lt;/em&gt; &amp;lt; 0.05) and VCAM-1 (&lt;em&gt;p&lt;/em&gt; &amp;lt; 0.05) expression. Interestingly, BAP31 knockdown apparently deactivated MyD88/TRAF6-mediated TAK1/NF-κB and PI3K/Akt signaling cascades, resulting in the inhibition of NF-κB activation and nuclear translocation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Significance:&lt;/em&gt; Our data furnished convincing evidence that BAP31 deficiency performs a mitigative effect on ALI by decreasing neutrophils-ECs adhesion. These findings identified BAP31 as a promising protein for regulating the pathogenesis process of ALI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JMJD3 Is Required for Acute Pancreatitis and Pancreatitis-Associated Lung Injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36458991/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36458991/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acute pancreatitis (AP) can be complicated by inflammatory disorders of remote organs, such as lung injury, in which Jumonji domain-containing protein 3 (JMJD3) plays a vital role in proinflammatory responses. Currently, we found that JMJD3 expression was upregulated in the pancreas and lung in an AP male mouse model, which was also confirmed in AP patients. Further experiments revealed that the upregulation of JMJD3 and proinflammatory effects were possibly exerted by mitochondrial DNA (mtDNA) or oxidized-mtDNA from tissue injury caused by AP. The release of mtDNA and oxidized-mtDNA contributed to the infiltration of inflammatory monocytes in lung injury through the stimulator of IFN genes (STING)/TLR9-NF-κB-JMJD3-TNF-α pathway. The inhibition of JMJD3 or utilization of Jmjd3-cKO mice significantly alleviated pulmonary inflammation induced by AP. Blocking mtDNA oxidation or knocking down the TLR9/STING pathway effectively alleviated inflammation. Therefore, inhibition of JMJD3 or STING/TLR9 pathway blockage might be a potential therapeutic strategy to treat AP and the associated lung injury.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Uterine macrophages as treatment targets for therapy of premature rupture of membranes by modified ADSC-EVs through a circRNA/miRNA/NF-κB pathway</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36402996/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36402996/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Circular RNA (circRNA) is a type of stable non-coding RNA that modifies macrophage inflammation by sponging micro RNAs (miRNAs), binding to RNA-binding proteins, and undergoing translation into peptides. Activated M1 phenotype macrophages secrete matrix metalloproteinases to participate in softening of the cervix uteri to promote vaginal delivery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; In this study, the premature rupture of membranes (PROM) mouse model was used to analyze the role of macrophages in this process. Profiling of circRNAs was performed using a competing endogenous RNA microarray, and their functions were elucidated in vitro. Meanwhile, adipose tissue-derived stem cell-secreted extracellular vesicles (EVs) were applied as a vehicle to transport small interfering RNAs (siRNAs) targeting the circRNAs to demonstrate their biological function in vivo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; The miRNA &lt;em&gt;miR-1931&lt;/em&gt; is dependent on the nuclear factor kappa-B (NF-κB) pathway but negatively regulates its activation by targeting the NF-κB signaling transducer TRAF6 to prevent polarization of M1 macrophages and inhibit matrix metalloproteinase (MMP) secretion. The host gene of circRNA &lt;em&gt;B4GALNT1&lt;/em&gt;, also an NF-κB pathway-dependent gene, circularizes to form &lt;em&gt;circRNA_0002047&lt;/em&gt;, which sponges &lt;em&gt;miR-1931&lt;/em&gt; to maintain NF-κB pathway activation and MMP secretion in vitro. In the PROM model, EVs loaded with siRNAs targeting circRNAs demonstrated that the circRNAs reduced &lt;em&gt;miR-1931&lt;/em&gt; expression to maintain NF-κB pathway activation and MMP secretion for accelerating PROM in vivo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; Our data provide insights into understanding PROM pathogenesis and improving PROM treatment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Identification of environmental factors that promote intestinal inflammation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36266581/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36266581/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Genome-wide association studies have identified risk loci linked to inflammatory bowel disease (IBD)-a complex chronic inflammatory disorder of the gastrointestinal tract. The increasing prevalence of IBD in industrialized countries and the augmented disease risk observed in migrants who move into areas of higher disease prevalence suggest that environmental factors are also important determinants of IBD susceptibility and severity. However, the identification of environmental factors relevant to IBD and the mechanisms by which they influence disease has been hampered by the lack of platforms for their systematic investigation. Here we describe an integrated systems approach, combining publicly available databases, zebrafish chemical screens, machine learning and mouse preclinical models to identify environmental factors that control intestinal inflammation. This approach established that the herbicide propyzamide increases inflammation in the small and large intestine. Moreover, we show that an AHR-NF-κB-C/EBPβ signalling axis operates in T cells and dendritic cells to promote intestinal inflammation, and is targeted by propyzamide. In conclusion, we developed a pipeline for the identification of environmental factors and mechanisms of pathogenesis in IBD and, potentially, other inflammatory diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MiR-1249 on Endothelial Extracellular Vesicles Mediates Cigarette Smoke-Induced Pulmonary Hypertension by Inhibiting HDAC10 (Histone Deacetylase 10)-NFκB (Nuclear Factor κB)-CaSR (Calcium-Sensing Receptor) Cascade</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36252137/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36252137/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Overproduction of endothelial extracellular vesicles (eEVs) is correlated with pulmonary hypertension progression, but the precise mechanism remains largely unclear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; MicroRNA-chip and real-time polymerase chain reaction were conducted to screen and validate microRNA profiles in blood plasma eEVs of rats and human with or without cigarette smoking. Pulmonary artery smooth muscle cells were cultured to study signaling pathways. Pulmonary hypertension phenotypes were evaluated in wild-type and calcium-sensing receptor knockout rats to identify the pathophysiological significance of the microRNA pathway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; MicroR-1249 was predominant highly expressed in eEVs from plasma of rats exposed to cigarette smoking, and confirmed in eEVs from plasma of human smokers as well as in eEVs from cigarette smoke extract-treated pulmonary artery endothelial cells, but not in cigarette smoke extract-treated pulmonary artery smooth muscle cells. In cultured pulmonary artery smooth muscle cells, microR-1249 downregulated the expression of histone deacetylase 10, which in turn enhanced the acetylated form of NFκB (nuclear factor κB) level and its nuclear translocation leading to increased expression of calcium-sensing receptor. In rats, the repression of microR-1249 in eEVs by microR-1249 inhibitor, histone deacetylase 10 overexpression, or calcium-sensing receptor knockout profoundly inhibited the proliferative capacities and diminished apoptosis-resistance of pulmonary artery smooth muscle cells and pulmonary hypertension development in rats intravenously administrated with eEVs preparation from cigarette smoke extract-treated pulmonary artery endothelial cells.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; Cigarette smoke-enriched microR-1249 in endothelial extracellular vesicles facilitates the hyperproliferative and antiapoptotic status of pulmonary artery smooth muscle cells promoting pulmonary hypertension evolution through the inhibition of histone deacetylase 10-NFκB-calcium-sensing receptor cascade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Schisandrin B protects against LPS-induced inflammatory lung injury by targeting MyD88</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36270224/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36270224/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Acute lung injury (ALI) is a challenging clinical syndrome that manifests as an acute inflammatory response. Schisandrin B (Sch B), a bioactive lignan from Schisandra genus plants, has been shown to suppress inflammatory responses and oxidative stress. However, the underlying molecular mechanisms have remained elusive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Hypothesis/purpose:&lt;/em&gt; This study performed an in-depth investigation of the anti-inflammatory mechanism of Sch B in macrophages and in an animal model of ALI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; qPCR array was used to probe the differential effects and potential target of Sch B. ALI was induced by intratracheal administration of LPS in experimental mice with or without Sch B treatment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; Our studies show that Sch B differentially modulates inflammatory factor induction by LPS in macrophages by directly binding myeloid differentiation response factor-88 (MyD88), an essential adaptor protein in the toll-like receptor-4 (TLR4) pathway. Sch B spares non-MyD88-pathways downstream of TLR4. Such inhibition suppressed key signaling mediators such as TAK1, MAPKs, and NF-κB, and pro-inflammatory factor induction. Pull down assay using biotinylated-Sch B validate the direct interaction between Sch B and MyD88 in macrophages. Treatment of mice with Sch B prior to LPS challenge reduced inflammatory cell infiltration in lungs, induction of MyD88-pathway signaling proteins, and prevented inflammatory cytokine induction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/em&gt; In summary, our studies have identified MyD88 as a direct target of Sch B for its anti-inflammatory activity, and suggest that Sch B may have therapeutic value for acute lung injury and other MyD88-dependent inflammatory diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Polysaccharides from Tetrastigma Hemsleyanum Diels et Gilg attenuate LPS-induced acute lung injury by modulating TLR4/COX-2/NF-κB signaling pathway</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36182735/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36182735/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Polysaccharides from &lt;em&gt;Tetrastigma Hemsleyanum&lt;/em&gt; Diels et Gilg (SYQP) attenuated LPS-induced ALI in vivo and in vitro.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SYQP exerted anti-inflammatory and anti-oxidative stress effects in vivo and in vitro.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SYQP alleviated ALI by inhibiting TLR4/COX-2/NF-κB signaling pathway.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tetrastigma Hemsleyanum&lt;/em&gt; Diels et Gilg (Sanyeqing, SYQ), a traditional herb native to China, has been widely used in the treatment of inflammatory diseases, febrile convulsions and dysentery. Previous studies have demonstrated the hypoglycemic, anti-inflammatory and anti-pyretic effects of polysaccharides from SYQ (SYQP). However, the role of SYQP in acute lung injury (ALI) remained unknown. Our present study aimed to explore the protective effects of SYQP in ALI and explained its underlying mechanism. In vivo, Balb/c mice were intragastrically administered with SYQP and dexamethasone (DXMS) for 14 days which were intratracheally instilled (IT) with LPS at the last day. In vitro, A549 cells were pretreated with SYQP, DXMS or TAK-242, following by LPS stimulation for 24 h. The histopathological results showed that SYQP remarkably alleviated pulmonary macrophage infiltration and myeloperoxidase (MPO) levels. Additionally, SYQP evidently suppressed wet/dry (W/D) ratio of lung and white blood cells (WBC) in bronchoalveolar lavage fluid (BALF). Moreover, SYQP markedly reduced TNF-α, IL-6, IL-1β and COX-2 levels both in vivo and in vitro. Meanwhile, SYQP significantly attenuated oxidative stress through upregulating the levels of SOD and GSH-Px and downregulating the expressions of MDA and LDH in vivo, which was confirmed by in vitro results that SYQP could increase SOD activity and decrease MDA and NO contents. Importantly, a decline in protein expressions of TLR4, COX-2, NF-κB p50, phospho-NF-κB p65 and phospho-IκB-α was detected in vivo and in vitro. Taken together, our results demonstrated that SYQP ameliorated LPS-induced ALI by alleviating inflammation and oxidative stress via attenuating TLR4/COX-2/NF-κB signaling pathway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Poldip2 knockdown protects against lipopolysaccharide-induced acute lung injury via Nox4/Nrf2/NF-κB signaling pathway</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36120334/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36120334/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Polymerase δ-interacting protein 2 (Poldip2) has been reported to mediate acute lung injury (ALI); however, the underlying mechanism is not fully explored. Male C57BL/6 mice and A549 cells were used to establish the lipopolysaccharide (LPS)-induced ALI model, then the expression of Poldip2 and its effect on oxidative stress and the resulting inflammation were detected. Adeno-associated virus serotype 6 (AAV6) mediated Poldip2 knockdown was transfected into mice via intratracheal atomization. And A549 cells stimulated with LPS was used to further confirm our hypothesis in vitro. ML385, specifically inhibited the activation of the Nrf2 signaling pathway. Our data suggested that LPS stimulation remarkably increased protein levels of Nox4 and p-P65, activities of NADPH and MPO, and generation of ROS, TNF-α, and IL-1β while decreased protein levels of Nrf2 and HO-1 compared with those in NC shRNA + Saline group, which were obviously reversed by Poldip2 knockdown. Concomitantly, Poldip2 knockdown dramatically reduced contents of MDA and enhanced activities of SOD and GSH-Px compared to NC shRNA + LPS group. In vitro, we found that knockdown of Poldip2 significantly reversed LPS-induced increase protein levels of Nox4 and p-P65, activity of NADPH, and generation of ROS, TNF-α, and IL-1β, and decrease protein levels of Nrf2 and HO-1, ML385 pretreatment reversed the effects of Poldip2 knockdown mentioned above. Our study indicated that Poldip2 knockdown alleviates LPS-induced ALI via inhibiting Nox4/Nrf2/NF-κB signaling pathway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
