<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>TLR/NF-κB | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/tlr/nf-%CE%BAb/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/tlr/nf-%CE%BAb/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>TLR/NF-κB</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>TLR/NF-κB</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/tlr/nf-%CE%BAb/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Total glycosides of Rhodiola rosea L. attenuate LPS-induced acute lung injury by inhibiting TLR4/NF-κB pathway</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36587557/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36587557/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Total glycosides of Rhodiola rosea L. alleviate LPS-induced acute lung injury.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Total glycosides of Rhodiola rosea L. protect mice by reducing pulmonary edema.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Total glycosides of Rhodiola rosea L. inhibit the influx of inflammatory cells into the lung.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Total glycosides of Rhodiola rosea L. reduce inflammation in the lung by inhibiting TLR4/NF-κB pathway.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acute lung injury (ALI) is a common respiratory disease in clinics, which is characterized by alveolar-capillary membrane loss, plasma protein leakage, pulmonary edema, massive neutrophil infiltration, and the release of proinflammatory cytokines and mediators. Rhodiola rosea L. an adaptogenic plant rich in phenylethanoloids, phenylpropanoids, monoterpenes, has anti-inflammatory and antioxidant effects. We hope to verify the relieving effect of total glycosides of Rhodiola rosea L. (RTG) on ALI in mice and clarify its mechanism through this study. In this study, we identified the effect and mechanism of RTG on ALI through LPS-induced ALI mice. After RTG treatment, the pathological structure of lung tissue in ALI mice induced by LPS was significantly improved, and the infiltration of inflammatory cells was reduced. In addition, RTG reduced the production of IL-6, IL-1β, and TNF-α in the serum of ALI mice and reduced the content or activity of MPO, T-SOD, GSH, and MDA in lung tissue. RNAseq analysis showed that RTG ameliorated LPS-induced ALI through anti-inflammatory, reduced immune response, and anti-apoptotic activities. The western blotting analysis confirmed that RTG could down-regulate the expression levels of TLR4, MyD88, NF-κB p65, and p-IκBα/IκBα. These results suggest that RTG can attenuate LPS-induced ALI through antioxidants and inhibition of the TLR4/NF-κB pathway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BAP31 regulates the expression of ICAM-1/VCAM-1 via MyD88/NF-κB pathway in acute lung injury mice model</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36549351/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36549351/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Aims:&lt;/em&gt; The cell adhesion molecules (CAMs) that mediate neutrophil-endothelium cell adhesion are deeply involved in the pathogenesis of acute lung injury (ALI). B-cell receptor associated protein 31 (BAP31) has been reported to engage in the expression of some CAMs. This study was undertaken to explore whether BAP31 in endotheliocyte affects the pathological process of ALI by regulating CAMs, and its possible mechanism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Main methods:&lt;/em&gt; Our study used the shBAP31 endothelium cell lines and endothelial-specific BAP31 conditional knockdown mice constructed via Cre/loxP system. Hematoxylin and eosin staining was used to observe the histopathological manifestations. The adhesion of neutrophils to vascular wall was examined by intravital microscopy. The nuclear translocation of NF-κB was observed by immunofluorescence staining assay. Flow cytometric, real-time polymerase chain reaction and Western blot assay were performed to determine the expression of CAMs and key proteins in MyD88/NF-κB-related signaling pathway. Luciferase reporter and chromatin immunoprecipitation assay were analyzed for transcriptional activity of ICAM-1 and VCAM-1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Key findings:&lt;/em&gt; Mechanistic investigations indicated that endothelium-specific BAP31 depletion dramatically reduced the capacity of neutrophils adherence to endothelial cells (ECs), which was mainly attributed to the significant downregulation of ICAM-1 (&lt;em&gt;p&lt;/em&gt; &amp;lt; 0.05) and VCAM-1 (&lt;em&gt;p&lt;/em&gt; &amp;lt; 0.05) expression. Interestingly, BAP31 knockdown apparently deactivated MyD88/TRAF6-mediated TAK1/NF-κB and PI3K/Akt signaling cascades, resulting in the inhibition of NF-κB activation and nuclear translocation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Significance:&lt;/em&gt; Our data furnished convincing evidence that BAP31 deficiency performs a mitigative effect on ALI by decreasing neutrophils-ECs adhesion. These findings identified BAP31 as a promising protein for regulating the pathogenesis process of ALI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JMJD3 Is Required for Acute Pancreatitis and Pancreatitis-Associated Lung Injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36458991/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36458991/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acute pancreatitis (AP) can be complicated by inflammatory disorders of remote organs, such as lung injury, in which Jumonji domain-containing protein 3 (JMJD3) plays a vital role in proinflammatory responses. Currently, we found that JMJD3 expression was upregulated in the pancreas and lung in an AP male mouse model, which was also confirmed in AP patients. Further experiments revealed that the upregulation of JMJD3 and proinflammatory effects were possibly exerted by mitochondrial DNA (mtDNA) or oxidized-mtDNA from tissue injury caused by AP. The release of mtDNA and oxidized-mtDNA contributed to the infiltration of inflammatory monocytes in lung injury through the stimulator of IFN genes (STING)/TLR9-NF-κB-JMJD3-TNF-α pathway. The inhibition of JMJD3 or utilization of Jmjd3-cKO mice significantly alleviated pulmonary inflammation induced by AP. Blocking mtDNA oxidation or knocking down the TLR9/STING pathway effectively alleviated inflammation. Therefore, inhibition of JMJD3 or STING/TLR9 pathway blockage might be a potential therapeutic strategy to treat AP and the associated lung injury.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
