<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>TLR/NF-κB | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/tlr/nf-%CE%BAb/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/tlr/nf-%CE%BAb/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>TLR/NF-κB</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>TLR/NF-κB</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/tlr/nf-%CE%BAb/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Total glycosides of Rhodiola rosea L. attenuate LPS-induced acute lung injury by inhibiting TLR4/NF-κB pathway</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36587557/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36587557/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Total glycosides of Rhodiola rosea L. alleviate LPS-induced acute lung injury.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Total glycosides of Rhodiola rosea L. protect mice by reducing pulmonary edema.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Total glycosides of Rhodiola rosea L. inhibit the influx of inflammatory cells into the lung.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Total glycosides of Rhodiola rosea L. reduce inflammation in the lung by inhibiting TLR4/NF-κB pathway.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acute lung injury (ALI) is a common respiratory disease in clinics, which is characterized by alveolar-capillary membrane loss, plasma protein leakage, pulmonary edema, massive neutrophil infiltration, and the release of proinflammatory cytokines and mediators. Rhodiola rosea L. an adaptogenic plant rich in phenylethanoloids, phenylpropanoids, monoterpenes, has anti-inflammatory and antioxidant effects. We hope to verify the relieving effect of total glycosides of Rhodiola rosea L. (RTG) on ALI in mice and clarify its mechanism through this study. In this study, we identified the effect and mechanism of RTG on ALI through LPS-induced ALI mice. After RTG treatment, the pathological structure of lung tissue in ALI mice induced by LPS was significantly improved, and the infiltration of inflammatory cells was reduced. In addition, RTG reduced the production of IL-6, IL-1β, and TNF-α in the serum of ALI mice and reduced the content or activity of MPO, T-SOD, GSH, and MDA in lung tissue. RNAseq analysis showed that RTG ameliorated LPS-induced ALI through anti-inflammatory, reduced immune response, and anti-apoptotic activities. The western blotting analysis confirmed that RTG could down-regulate the expression levels of TLR4, MyD88, NF-κB p65, and p-IκBα/IκBα. These results suggest that RTG can attenuate LPS-induced ALI through antioxidants and inhibition of the TLR4/NF-κB pathway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BAP31 regulates the expression of ICAM-1/VCAM-1 via MyD88/NF-κB pathway in acute lung injury mice model</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36549351/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36549351/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Aims:&lt;/em&gt; The cell adhesion molecules (CAMs) that mediate neutrophil-endothelium cell adhesion are deeply involved in the pathogenesis of acute lung injury (ALI). B-cell receptor associated protein 31 (BAP31) has been reported to engage in the expression of some CAMs. This study was undertaken to explore whether BAP31 in endotheliocyte affects the pathological process of ALI by regulating CAMs, and its possible mechanism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Main methods:&lt;/em&gt; Our study used the shBAP31 endothelium cell lines and endothelial-specific BAP31 conditional knockdown mice constructed via Cre/loxP system. Hematoxylin and eosin staining was used to observe the histopathological manifestations. The adhesion of neutrophils to vascular wall was examined by intravital microscopy. The nuclear translocation of NF-κB was observed by immunofluorescence staining assay. Flow cytometric, real-time polymerase chain reaction and Western blot assay were performed to determine the expression of CAMs and key proteins in MyD88/NF-κB-related signaling pathway. Luciferase reporter and chromatin immunoprecipitation assay were analyzed for transcriptional activity of ICAM-1 and VCAM-1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Key findings:&lt;/em&gt; Mechanistic investigations indicated that endothelium-specific BAP31 depletion dramatically reduced the capacity of neutrophils adherence to endothelial cells (ECs), which was mainly attributed to the significant downregulation of ICAM-1 (&lt;em&gt;p&lt;/em&gt; &amp;lt; 0.05) and VCAM-1 (&lt;em&gt;p&lt;/em&gt; &amp;lt; 0.05) expression. Interestingly, BAP31 knockdown apparently deactivated MyD88/TRAF6-mediated TAK1/NF-κB and PI3K/Akt signaling cascades, resulting in the inhibition of NF-κB activation and nuclear translocation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Significance:&lt;/em&gt; Our data furnished convincing evidence that BAP31 deficiency performs a mitigative effect on ALI by decreasing neutrophils-ECs adhesion. These findings identified BAP31 as a promising protein for regulating the pathogenesis process of ALI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JMJD3 Is Required for Acute Pancreatitis and Pancreatitis-Associated Lung Injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36458991/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36458991/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acute pancreatitis (AP) can be complicated by inflammatory disorders of remote organs, such as lung injury, in which Jumonji domain-containing protein 3 (JMJD3) plays a vital role in proinflammatory responses. Currently, we found that JMJD3 expression was upregulated in the pancreas and lung in an AP male mouse model, which was also confirmed in AP patients. Further experiments revealed that the upregulation of JMJD3 and proinflammatory effects were possibly exerted by mitochondrial DNA (mtDNA) or oxidized-mtDNA from tissue injury caused by AP. The release of mtDNA and oxidized-mtDNA contributed to the infiltration of inflammatory monocytes in lung injury through the stimulator of IFN genes (STING)/TLR9-NF-κB-JMJD3-TNF-α pathway. The inhibition of JMJD3 or utilization of Jmjd3-cKO mice significantly alleviated pulmonary inflammation induced by AP. Blocking mtDNA oxidation or knocking down the TLR9/STING pathway effectively alleviated inflammation. Therefore, inhibition of JMJD3 or STING/TLR9 pathway blockage might be a potential therapeutic strategy to treat AP and the associated lung injury.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Uterine macrophages as treatment targets for therapy of premature rupture of membranes by modified ADSC-EVs through a circRNA/miRNA/NF-κB pathway</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36402996/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36402996/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Circular RNA (circRNA) is a type of stable non-coding RNA that modifies macrophage inflammation by sponging micro RNAs (miRNAs), binding to RNA-binding proteins, and undergoing translation into peptides. Activated M1 phenotype macrophages secrete matrix metalloproteinases to participate in softening of the cervix uteri to promote vaginal delivery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; In this study, the premature rupture of membranes (PROM) mouse model was used to analyze the role of macrophages in this process. Profiling of circRNAs was performed using a competing endogenous RNA microarray, and their functions were elucidated in vitro. Meanwhile, adipose tissue-derived stem cell-secreted extracellular vesicles (EVs) were applied as a vehicle to transport small interfering RNAs (siRNAs) targeting the circRNAs to demonstrate their biological function in vivo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; The miRNA &lt;em&gt;miR-1931&lt;/em&gt; is dependent on the nuclear factor kappa-B (NF-κB) pathway but negatively regulates its activation by targeting the NF-κB signaling transducer TRAF6 to prevent polarization of M1 macrophages and inhibit matrix metalloproteinase (MMP) secretion. The host gene of circRNA &lt;em&gt;B4GALNT1&lt;/em&gt;, also an NF-κB pathway-dependent gene, circularizes to form &lt;em&gt;circRNA_0002047&lt;/em&gt;, which sponges &lt;em&gt;miR-1931&lt;/em&gt; to maintain NF-κB pathway activation and MMP secretion in vitro. In the PROM model, EVs loaded with siRNAs targeting circRNAs demonstrated that the circRNAs reduced &lt;em&gt;miR-1931&lt;/em&gt; expression to maintain NF-κB pathway activation and MMP secretion for accelerating PROM in vivo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; Our data provide insights into understanding PROM pathogenesis and improving PROM treatment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Identification of environmental factors that promote intestinal inflammation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36266581/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36266581/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Genome-wide association studies have identified risk loci linked to inflammatory bowel disease (IBD)-a complex chronic inflammatory disorder of the gastrointestinal tract. The increasing prevalence of IBD in industrialized countries and the augmented disease risk observed in migrants who move into areas of higher disease prevalence suggest that environmental factors are also important determinants of IBD susceptibility and severity. However, the identification of environmental factors relevant to IBD and the mechanisms by which they influence disease has been hampered by the lack of platforms for their systematic investigation. Here we describe an integrated systems approach, combining publicly available databases, zebrafish chemical screens, machine learning and mouse preclinical models to identify environmental factors that control intestinal inflammation. This approach established that the herbicide propyzamide increases inflammation in the small and large intestine. Moreover, we show that an AHR-NF-κB-C/EBPβ signalling axis operates in T cells and dendritic cells to promote intestinal inflammation, and is targeted by propyzamide. In conclusion, we developed a pipeline for the identification of environmental factors and mechanisms of pathogenesis in IBD and, potentially, other inflammatory diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MiR-1249 on Endothelial Extracellular Vesicles Mediates Cigarette Smoke-Induced Pulmonary Hypertension by Inhibiting HDAC10 (Histone Deacetylase 10)-NFκB (Nuclear Factor κB)-CaSR (Calcium-Sensing Receptor) Cascade</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36252137/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36252137/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Overproduction of endothelial extracellular vesicles (eEVs) is correlated with pulmonary hypertension progression, but the precise mechanism remains largely unclear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; MicroRNA-chip and real-time polymerase chain reaction were conducted to screen and validate microRNA profiles in blood plasma eEVs of rats and human with or without cigarette smoking. Pulmonary artery smooth muscle cells were cultured to study signaling pathways. Pulmonary hypertension phenotypes were evaluated in wild-type and calcium-sensing receptor knockout rats to identify the pathophysiological significance of the microRNA pathway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; MicroR-1249 was predominant highly expressed in eEVs from plasma of rats exposed to cigarette smoking, and confirmed in eEVs from plasma of human smokers as well as in eEVs from cigarette smoke extract-treated pulmonary artery endothelial cells, but not in cigarette smoke extract-treated pulmonary artery smooth muscle cells. In cultured pulmonary artery smooth muscle cells, microR-1249 downregulated the expression of histone deacetylase 10, which in turn enhanced the acetylated form of NFκB (nuclear factor κB) level and its nuclear translocation leading to increased expression of calcium-sensing receptor. In rats, the repression of microR-1249 in eEVs by microR-1249 inhibitor, histone deacetylase 10 overexpression, or calcium-sensing receptor knockout profoundly inhibited the proliferative capacities and diminished apoptosis-resistance of pulmonary artery smooth muscle cells and pulmonary hypertension development in rats intravenously administrated with eEVs preparation from cigarette smoke extract-treated pulmonary artery endothelial cells.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; Cigarette smoke-enriched microR-1249 in endothelial extracellular vesicles facilitates the hyperproliferative and antiapoptotic status of pulmonary artery smooth muscle cells promoting pulmonary hypertension evolution through the inhibition of histone deacetylase 10-NFκB-calcium-sensing receptor cascade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Schisandrin B protects against LPS-induced inflammatory lung injury by targeting MyD88</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36270224/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36270224/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Acute lung injury (ALI) is a challenging clinical syndrome that manifests as an acute inflammatory response. Schisandrin B (Sch B), a bioactive lignan from Schisandra genus plants, has been shown to suppress inflammatory responses and oxidative stress. However, the underlying molecular mechanisms have remained elusive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Hypothesis/purpose:&lt;/em&gt; This study performed an in-depth investigation of the anti-inflammatory mechanism of Sch B in macrophages and in an animal model of ALI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; qPCR array was used to probe the differential effects and potential target of Sch B. ALI was induced by intratracheal administration of LPS in experimental mice with or without Sch B treatment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; Our studies show that Sch B differentially modulates inflammatory factor induction by LPS in macrophages by directly binding myeloid differentiation response factor-88 (MyD88), an essential adaptor protein in the toll-like receptor-4 (TLR4) pathway. Sch B spares non-MyD88-pathways downstream of TLR4. Such inhibition suppressed key signaling mediators such as TAK1, MAPKs, and NF-κB, and pro-inflammatory factor induction. Pull down assay using biotinylated-Sch B validate the direct interaction between Sch B and MyD88 in macrophages. Treatment of mice with Sch B prior to LPS challenge reduced inflammatory cell infiltration in lungs, induction of MyD88-pathway signaling proteins, and prevented inflammatory cytokine induction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/em&gt; In summary, our studies have identified MyD88 as a direct target of Sch B for its anti-inflammatory activity, and suggest that Sch B may have therapeutic value for acute lung injury and other MyD88-dependent inflammatory diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Polysaccharides from Tetrastigma Hemsleyanum Diels et Gilg attenuate LPS-induced acute lung injury by modulating TLR4/COX-2/NF-κB signaling pathway</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36182735/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36182735/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Polysaccharides from &lt;em&gt;Tetrastigma Hemsleyanum&lt;/em&gt; Diels et Gilg (SYQP) attenuated LPS-induced ALI in vivo and in vitro.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SYQP exerted anti-inflammatory and anti-oxidative stress effects in vivo and in vitro.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SYQP alleviated ALI by inhibiting TLR4/COX-2/NF-κB signaling pathway.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tetrastigma Hemsleyanum&lt;/em&gt; Diels et Gilg (Sanyeqing, SYQ), a traditional herb native to China, has been widely used in the treatment of inflammatory diseases, febrile convulsions and dysentery. Previous studies have demonstrated the hypoglycemic, anti-inflammatory and anti-pyretic effects of polysaccharides from SYQ (SYQP). However, the role of SYQP in acute lung injury (ALI) remained unknown. Our present study aimed to explore the protective effects of SYQP in ALI and explained its underlying mechanism. In vivo, Balb/c mice were intragastrically administered with SYQP and dexamethasone (DXMS) for 14 days which were intratracheally instilled (IT) with LPS at the last day. In vitro, A549 cells were pretreated with SYQP, DXMS or TAK-242, following by LPS stimulation for 24 h. The histopathological results showed that SYQP remarkably alleviated pulmonary macrophage infiltration and myeloperoxidase (MPO) levels. Additionally, SYQP evidently suppressed wet/dry (W/D) ratio of lung and white blood cells (WBC) in bronchoalveolar lavage fluid (BALF). Moreover, SYQP markedly reduced TNF-α, IL-6, IL-1β and COX-2 levels both in vivo and in vitro. Meanwhile, SYQP significantly attenuated oxidative stress through upregulating the levels of SOD and GSH-Px and downregulating the expressions of MDA and LDH in vivo, which was confirmed by in vitro results that SYQP could increase SOD activity and decrease MDA and NO contents. Importantly, a decline in protein expressions of TLR4, COX-2, NF-κB p50, phospho-NF-κB p65 and phospho-IκB-α was detected in vivo and in vitro. Taken together, our results demonstrated that SYQP ameliorated LPS-induced ALI by alleviating inflammation and oxidative stress via attenuating TLR4/COX-2/NF-κB signaling pathway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Selenium-enriched soybean peptides pretreatment attenuates lung injury in mice induced by fine particulate matters (PM2.5) through inhibition of TLR4/NF-κB/IκBα signaling pathway and inflammasome generation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35979800/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35979800/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This study aimed to identify and prepare peptides from selenium (Se)-enriched soybeans and determine whether dietary Se-enriched soybean peptides (Se-SPep) could inhibit lung injury in mice induced by fine particulate matter 2.5 (PM2.5). BALB/c mice were randomly divided into six groups. The mice in the prevention groups were pretreated with 378 mg kg-1 of Se-SPep, soybean peptides (SPep), and Se-enriched soybean protein (Se-SPro), respectively, for four weeks. The mice in the PM2.5 exposure group received concentrated PM2.5 (15 μg per day mice) for 1 h daily from the third week for two weeks. The results showed that the leukocyte and cytokine (IL-1β, IL-6, TNF-α) levels in the bronchoalveolar lavage fluid (BALF) of the PM2.5 exposure group were higher than those in the control group. Se-SPep pretreatment decreased the IL-1β, IL-6, and TNF-α levels compared with the PM2.5 exposure group. Additionally, Se-SPep pretreatment inhibited TLR4/NF-κB/IκBα and NLRP3/ASC/caspase-1 protein expression in the lungs. In conclusion, Se-SPep pretreatment may protect the lungs of the mice against PM2.5-induced inflammation, suggesting that Se-SPep represents a potential preventative agent to inhibit PM2.5-induced lung injury.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Na/K-ATPase suppresses LPS-induced pro-inflammatory signaling through Lyn</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36072548/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36072548/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;NKA α1 interacts with TLR4 and SFKs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;NKA α1 restricts LPS-stimulated pro-inflammatory responses in macrophages&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;NKA α1&lt;sup&gt;+/−&lt;/sup&gt; mice injected with LPS show more lung injury and lower survival rate&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Na/K-ATPase (NKA), besides its ion transporter function, is a signal transducer by regulating Src family kinases (SFK). The signaling NKA contributes to oxidized LDL-induced macrophage foam cell formation and interacts with TLR4. However, its role in lipopolysaccharides (LPS)-induced signaling and glycolytic switch in macrophages remains unclear. Using peritoneal macrophages from NKA α1 haploinsufficient mice (NKA α1&lt;sup&gt;+/-&lt;/sup&gt;), we found that NKA α1 haploinsufficiency led to enhanced LPS-stimulated NF-κB pathway, ROS signaling, and pro-inflammatory cytokines. Intraperitoneal injection of LPS resulted in more severe lung inflammation and injury with lower survival rate in NKA α1&lt;sup&gt;+/-&lt;/sup&gt; mice. Additionally, LPS induced a higher extent of the metabolic switch from oxidative phosphorylation to glycolysis. Mechanistically, NKA α1 interacted with TLR4 and Lyn. The presence of NKA α1 in this complex attenuated Lyn activation by LPS, which subsequently restricted the downstream ROS and NF-κB signaling. In conclusion, we demonstrated that NKA α1 suppresses LPS-induced macrophage pro-inflammatory signaling through Lyn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Poldip2 knockdown protects against lipopolysaccharide-induced acute lung injury via Nox4/Nrf2/NF-κB signaling pathway</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36120334/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36120334/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Polymerase δ-interacting protein 2 (Poldip2) has been reported to mediate acute lung injury (ALI); however, the underlying mechanism is not fully explored. Male C57BL/6 mice and A549 cells were used to establish the lipopolysaccharide (LPS)-induced ALI model, then the expression of Poldip2 and its effect on oxidative stress and the resulting inflammation were detected. Adeno-associated virus serotype 6 (AAV6) mediated Poldip2 knockdown was transfected into mice via intratracheal atomization. And A549 cells stimulated with LPS was used to further confirm our hypothesis in vitro. ML385, specifically inhibited the activation of the Nrf2 signaling pathway. Our data suggested that LPS stimulation remarkably increased protein levels of Nox4 and p-P65, activities of NADPH and MPO, and generation of ROS, TNF-α, and IL-1β while decreased protein levels of Nrf2 and HO-1 compared with those in NC shRNA + Saline group, which were obviously reversed by Poldip2 knockdown. Concomitantly, Poldip2 knockdown dramatically reduced contents of MDA and enhanced activities of SOD and GSH-Px compared to NC shRNA + LPS group. In vitro, we found that knockdown of Poldip2 significantly reversed LPS-induced increase protein levels of Nox4 and p-P65, activity of NADPH, and generation of ROS, TNF-α, and IL-1β, and decrease protein levels of Nrf2 and HO-1, ML385 pretreatment reversed the effects of Poldip2 knockdown mentioned above. Our study indicated that Poldip2 knockdown alleviates LPS-induced ALI via inhibiting Nox4/Nrf2/NF-κB signaling pathway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Diacerein attenuate LPS-induced acute lung injury via inhibiting ER stress and apoptosis: Impact on the crosstalk between SphK1/S1P, TLR4/NFκB/STAT3, and NLRP3/IL-1β signaling pathways</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36055546/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36055546/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Aims:&lt;/em&gt; Acute lung injury (ALI) is a life-threatening clinical problem with high mortality rate and limited treatments or preventive options that represents a major challenge for clinicians. Diacerein (DIA) is a multi-target anthraquinone derivative with potent anti-inflammatory action. The aim of this study is to assess the protective effect of DIA and its potential molecular targets against lipopolysaccharide (LPS)-induced ALI in rats.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Materials and methods:&lt;/em&gt; Adult male Sprague-Dawley rats were orally administrated DIA (50 mg/kg) for 5 consecutive days followed by a single intraperitoneal injection of LPS (5mg/kg).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Key findings:&lt;/em&gt; DIA mitigated oxidative lung injury in LPS-challenged rats via significantly decreasing lung wet/dry (W/D) ratio, inflammatory cells infiltration, and lipid peroxidation, with concomitant elevation in enzymatic and non-enzymatic antioxidant levels in lung tissue. Likewise, DIA alleviated endoplasmic reticulum stress and markedly halted inflammation triggered by LPS challenge in pulmonary tissue by suppressing NLRP3/IL-1β and TLR4/NF-κB signaling with parallel decrease in proinflammatory cytokine levels. Interestingly, DIA down regulated Sphk1/S1P axis, reduced GSK-3β and STAT3 proteins expression, and markedly decreased caspase-3 besides increasing Bcl-2 levels in lung tissue of LPS-challenged animals. These biochemical findings was simultaneously associated with marked improvement in histological alterations of lung tissue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Significance:&lt;/em&gt; These findings verify the protective effect of DIA against LPS-induced ALI through targeting oxidative stress, endoplasmic reticulum stress, and apoptosis. Importantly, DIA halted the hyperinflammatory state triggered by LPS via multi-faceted inhibitory effect on different signaling pathways, hence DIA could potentially reduce mortality in patients with ALI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eupalinolide B attenuates lipopolysaccharide-induced acute lung injury through inhibition of NF-κB and MAPKs signaling by targeting TAK1 protein</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35988521/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35988521/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Eupalinolide B (EB) inhibit LPS-induced acute lung injury in mice.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;EB directly binds to TAK1, and inhibits NF-κB and MAPKs activation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The α,γ-unsaturated lactone of EB is vital for its anti-inflammatory effect.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acute lung injury (ALI) is a life-threatening disease characterized by severe inflammatory response, which has no pharmacological therapy in clinic. In this study, we found that eupalinolide B (EB), a sesquiterpene lactone isolated from Eupatorium lindleyanum, significantly ameliorated lipopolysaccharide (LPS)-induced ALI in mice, which manifests as reduction in lung injury score, activity of myeloperoxidase, and release of cytokines interleukin (IL)-1β, IL-6, tumor necrosis factor-α (TNF-α), and monocyte chemoattractant protein-1 (MCP-1). In RAW264.7 murine macrophages, EB effectively inhibited LPS-induced production of nitric oxide (NO) and prostaglandin E2 (PGE2) by down-regulating the expression of inducible nitric oxide synthase (iNOS) and cyclooxygenase-2 (COX2), respectively. Mechanistically, EB not only blocked LPS-induced phosphorylation of inhibitor of nuclear factor kappa B kinase-α/β (IKKα/β), phosphorylation and degradation of inhibitor of nuclear factor-kappa B alpha (IκBα), and phosphorylation and nuclear translocation of nuclear factor-kappa B (NF-κB) P65, but also suppressed LPS-induced phosphorylation of mitogen-activated protein kinases (MAPKs) &lt;em&gt;in vitro&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt;. Through cellular thermal shift assay and western blotting, EB was demonstrated to target and inactivate transforming growth factor β activated kinase-1 (TAK1), which is an important upstream kinase for the activation of NF-κB and MAPKs pathways. Additionally, EB-mediated actions were markedly abolished by dithiothreitol in LPS-exposed RAW264.7 cells, suggesting a crucial role of the α,γ-unsaturated lactone for the anti-inflammatory activity of EB. In conclusion, our findings showed that EB could effectively alleviate ALI in mice, and attenuate inflammatory response by inhibiting the activation of TAK1, and TAK1-mediated activation of NF-κB and MAPKs cascades.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oxypeucedanin relieves LPS-induced acute lung injury by inhibiting the inflammation and maintaining the integrity of the lung air-blood barrier</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35985771/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35985771/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Introduction:&lt;/em&gt; Acute lung injury (ALI) is commonly accompanied by a severe inflammatory reaction process, and effectively managing inflammatory reactions is an important therapeutic approach for alleviating ALI. Macrophages play an important role in the inflammatory response, and this role is proinflammatory in the early stages of inflammation and anti-inflammatory in the late stages. Oxypeucedanin is a natural product with a wide range of pharmacological functions. This study aimed to determine the effect of oxypeucedanin on lipopolysaccharide (LPS)-induced ALI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods and results:&lt;/em&gt; In this study, the following experiments were performed based on LPS-induced models &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;in vitro&lt;/em&gt;. Using myeloperoxidase activity measurement, ELISA, qRT-PCR, and Western blotting, we found that oxypeucedanin modulated the activity of myeloperoxidase and decreased the expression levels of inflammatory mediators such as TNF-α, IL-6, IL-1β, MPO, COX-2 and iNOS in LPS-induced inflammation models. Meanwhile, oxypeucedanin inhibited the activation of PI3K/AKT and its downstream NF-κB and MAPK signaling pathways. In addition, oxypeucedanin significantly decreased the pulmonary vascular permeability, which was induced by LPSs, and the enhanced expression of tight junction proteins (Occludin and Claudin 3).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; In conclusion, this study demonstrated that the anti-inflammatory mechanism of oxypeucedanin is associated with the inhibition of the activation of PI3K/AKT/NF-κB and MAPK signaling pathways and the maintenance of the integrity of the lung air-blood barrier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MiR-192-5p/RB1/NF-κBp65 signaling axis promotes IL-10 secretion during gastric cancer EMT to induce Treg cell differentiation in the tumour microenvironment</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35969010/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35969010/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Regulatory T (Treg) cells are important components of the tumour microenvironment (TME) that play roles in gastric cancer (GC) metastasis. Although tumour cells that undergo epithelial-mesenchymal transition (EMT) regulate Treg cell function, their regulatory mechanism in GC remains unclear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; The miR-192-5p was identified by examining three Gene Expression Omnibus GC miRNA expression datasets. RNA immunoprecipitation (RIP) and dual-luciferase reporter assays were conducted to identify interactions between miR-192-5p and RB1. The role of miR-192-5p/RB1 in GC progression was evaluated based on EdU incorporation, wound healing and Transwell assays. An in vitro co-culture assay was performed to measure the effect of miR-192-5p/RB1 on Treg cell differentiation. In vivo experiments were conducted to explore the role of miR-192-5p in GC progression and Treg cell differentiation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; MiR-192-5p was overexpressed in tumour and was associated with poor prognosis in GC. MiR-192-5p bound to the RB1 3&amp;rsquo;-untranslated region, resulting in GC EMT, proliferation, migration and invasion. MiR-192-5p/RB1 mediated interleukin-10 (IL-10) secretion by regulating nuclear factor-kappaBp65 (NF-κBp65), affecting Treg cell differentiation. NF-κBp65, in turn, promoted miR-192-5p expression and formed a positive feedback loop. Furthermore, in vivo experiments confirmed that miR-192-5p/RB1 promotes GC growth and Treg cell differentiation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/em&gt; Collectively, our studies indicate that miR-192-5p/RB1 promotes EMT of tumour cells, and the miR-192-5p/RB1/NF-κBp65 signaling axis induces Treg cell differentiation by regulating IL-10 secretion in GC. Our results suggest that targeting miR-192-5p/RB1/NF-κBp65 /IL-10 may pave the way for the development of new immune treatments for GC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zanubrutinib ameliorates lipopolysaccharide-induced acute lung injury via regulating macrophage polarization</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35973369/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35973369/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Zanubrutinib could relieve LPS induced lung injuries in mice.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;JAK2/STAT1 and TLR4/MyD88/NF-κB pathway is involved in Zanubrutinib -mediated M1 macrophage polarization in RAW264.7 cells.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Zanubrutinib promotes M2 macrophage activation through regulating JAK/STAT6 and PI3K/AKT pathway in RAW264.7 cells.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acute lung injury (ALI) is a disease characterized by pulmonary diffusion dysfunction and its exacerbation stage is acute respiratory distress syndrome (ARDS), which may develop to multiple organ failure and seriously threatens human health. ALI has high mortality rates and few effective treatments, thus effective protection measures for ALI are becoming increasingly important. Macrophages play a key regulatory role in the pathogenesis of ALI, and the degree of macrophage polarization is closely related to the severity and prognosis of ALI. In this study, we evaluated the effects of Zanubrutinib (ZB), a BTK small molecule inhibitor approved by the FDA for the treatment of cell lymphoma, on macrophage polarization and acute lung injury. In the in vivo study, we constructed a mouse model of Lipopolysaccharide (LPS)-induced acute lung injury and found that ZB could improve the acute injury of mouse lungs by inhibiting the secretion of proinflammatory factors and promoting the secretion of anti-inflammatory factors, reduce the number of inflammatory cells in alveolar lavage fluid, and then alleviate the inflammatory response. In vivo and in vitro studies have shown that ZB could inhibit the M1 macrophage polarization and promote the M2 macrophage polarization. Subsequent mechanistic studies revealed that ZB could inhibit the macrophage M1 polarization via targeting BTK activation and inhibiting JAK2/STAT1 and TLR4/MyD88/NF-κB signaling pathways, and promote the macrophage M2 polarization by promoting the activation of STAT6 and PI3K / Akt signaling pathways. In summary, ZB has shown therapeutic effect in LPS-induced acute lung injury in mice, which provides a potential candidate drug to treat acute lung injury.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Allyl methyl trisulfide protected against LPS-induced acute lung injury in mice via inhibition of the NF-κB and MAPK pathways</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36003507/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36003507/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Allyl methyl trisulfide (AMTS) is one major lipid-soluble organosulfur compound of garlic. Previous studies have reported the potential therapeutic effect of garlic on acute lung injury (ALI) or its severe condition acute respiratory distress syndrome (ARDS), but the specific substances that exert the regulatory effects are still unclear. In this study, we investigate the protective effects of AMTS on lipopolysaccharide (LPS)-induced ALI mice and explored the underlying mechanisms. &lt;em&gt;In vivo&lt;/em&gt; experiments, ICR mice were pretreated with 25-100 mg/kg AMTS for 7 days and followed by intratracheal instillation of LPS (1.5 mg/kg). The results showed that AMTS significantly attenuated LPS-induced deterioration of lung pathology, demonstrated by ameliorative edema and protein leakage, and improved pulmonary histopathological morphology. Meanwhile, the expression of inflammatory mediators and the infiltration of inflammation-regulation cells induced by LPS were also inhibited. &lt;em&gt;In vitro&lt;/em&gt; experiments also revealed that AMTS could alleviate inflammation response and inhibit the exaggeration of macrophage M1 polarization in LPS-induced RAW264.7 cells. Mechanistically, we identified that AMTS treatment could attenuate the LPS-induced elevation of protein expression of p-IκBα, nuclear NF-κB-p65, COX2, iNOS, p-P38, p-ERK1/2, and p-JNK. Collectively, these data suggest that AMTS could attenuate LPS-induced ALI and the molecular mechanisms should be related to the suppression of the NF-κB and MAPKs pathways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
