<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>TLR/NF-κB | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/tlr/nf-%CE%BAb/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/tlr/nf-%CE%BAb/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>TLR/NF-κB</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>TLR/NF-κB</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/tlr/nf-%CE%BAb/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scavenger receptor BI attenuates oxidized phospholipid-induced pulmonary inflammation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36681128/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36681128/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;These studies demonstrate that scavenger receptor BI (SR-BI) limits the lung pathology and inflammation following the generation of the danger associated molecular pattern oxidized phospholipids (oxPL).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;These findings indicate that if SR-BI is dysfunctional, there is a lack of oxPL clearance, dysfunctional lipid metabolism, and increased toll-like receptor 4 signaling in the lung leading to increased lung pathologies.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Damage associated molecular patterns (DAMPs) are molecules released from dead/dying cells following toxicant and/or environmental exposures that activate the immune response through binding pattern recognition receptors (PRRs). Excessive production of DAMPs or failed clearance leads to chronic inflammation and delayed inflammation resolution. One category of DAMPs are oxidized phospholipids (oxPLs) produced upon exposure to high levels of oxidative stress, such as following ozone (O3)- induced inflammation. OxPLs are bound by multiple classes of PRRs that include scavenger receptors (SRs) such as SR class B-1 (SR-BI) and toll-like receptors (TLRs). Interactions between oxPLs and PRRs appear to regulate inflammation; however, the role of SR-BI in oxPL-induced lung inflammation has not been defined. Therefore, we hypothesize that SR-BI is critical in protecting the lung from oxPL-induced pulmonary inflammation/injury. To test this hypothesis, C57BL/6 J (WT) female mice were dosed with oxidized 1-palmitoyl-2-arachidonoyl-sn-glycero-3-phosphatidylcholine (oxPAPC) by oropharyngeal aspiration and identified increased pulmonary SR-BI expression. Following oxPAPC exposure, SR-BI deficient (SR-BI&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt;) mice exhibited increased lung pathology and inflammatory cytokine/chemokine production. Lipidomic analysis revealed that SR-BI&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt; mice had an altered pulmonary lipidome prior to and following oxPAPC exposure, which correlated with increased oxidized phosphatidylcholines (PCs). Finally, we characterized TLR4-mediated activation of NF-κB following oxPAPC exposure and discovered that SR-BI&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt; mice had increased TLR4 mRNA expression in lung tissue and macrophages, increased nuclear p65, and decreased cytoplasmic IκBα. Overall, we conclude that SR-BI is required for limiting oxPAPC-induced lung pathology by maintaining lipid homeostasis, reducing oxidized PCs, and attenuating TLR4-NF-κB activation thereby preventing excessive and persistent inflammation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exposure to polystyrene microplastics triggers lung injury via targeting toll-like receptor 2 and activation of the NF-κB signal in mice</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36641069/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36641069/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Microplastics are ubiquitous pollutants with a wide range of plastic applications. More recently, microplastics are in the air and can be inhaled into the lungs, causing respiratory diseases. Knowledge of the underlying mechanisms by which microplastics may induce respiratory disease is still limited. This study used intranasal instillation to develop a model of lung injury. The histopathology result showed that the mouse lung had severe inflammatory responses, apoptosis and collagen deposition with chronic exposure to different sizes (Small: 1–5 μm and Large: 10–20 μm) of polystyrene microplastics (PS-MPS), and the damage of smaller sizes was obvious. The expression levels of the Toll-like receptors (TLRs) family, evolutionarily conserved pattern recognition receptors, were detected, and the levels of TLR2 mRNA was significantly increased. In transfection experiments, PS-MPS increased the inflammatory response in HEK293 cells with TLR2 expression. Furthermore, exposure to small polystyrene microplastics promoted oxidative stress and apoptosis, and accelerated the process of fibrosis. Interestingly, inhibition of the NF-κB signal relieves inflammation and oxidative stress, reduces apoptosis, and thus controls the fibrosis process. These results suggested that PS-MPS targeted binding to TLR2 and further exacerbated fibrosis by facilitating inflammation, oxidative stress, and apoptosis with the activation of NF-κB signal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Onychiol B attenuates lipopolysaccharide-induced inflammation via MAPK/NF-κB pathways and acute lung injury in vivo</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36642022/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36642022/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Onychiol B inhibits the production and secretion of pro-inflammatory cytokines.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Onychiol B prevents the production of ROS and reduced the loss of mitochondrial membrane potential in LPS-stimulated RAW264.7 cells.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Onychiol B alleviates pulmonary edema, reverses inflammatory mediator TNF-α, IL-6, and IL-β secretion in lung.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acute lung injury (ALI) is a devastating respiratory disorder characterized by rapid alveolar injury, uncontrolled inflammatory response, etc. Onychiol B is a cyathane diterpene originally isolated from fern plants. In this study, onychiol B can inhibit the production and secretion of pro-inflammatory cytokines such as NO, iNOS, IL-6 and TNF-α in LPS-stimulated RAW264.7 cells by restraining the NF-κB and the p38 MAPK pathway. In addition, it prevents the production of ROS and reduces the loss of mitochondrial membrane potential in LPS-stimulated RAW264.7 cells. Furthermore, in the acute lung injury mouse model induced by LPS injected into the trachea, onychiol B alleviates pulmonary edema, reverses inflammatory mediator TNF-α, IL-6, and IL-β secretion in lung. In general, our data show that significant anti-ALI effects of onychiol B would render it a potential candidate for the treatment of inflammatory diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oleocanthal alleviated lipopolysaccharide-induced acute lung injury in chickens by inhibiting TLR4/NF-κB pathway activation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36640559/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36640559/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This study aimed to investigate the ameliorative effect of oleocanthal (OC) on lipopolysaccharide (LPS)-induced acute lung injury (ALI) in chickens and its possible mechanisms. In total, 20 chickens were randomly divided into 4 groups: control (CON) group, LPS group, LPS + OC group, and OC group. LPS + OC and OC groups were intragastrically administered a 5 mg/kg·d OC dose for 7 d. On d 8, the LPS group and LPS + OC group were intratracheally administered 2 mg/kg LPS for 12 h. It was found that OC ameliorated the pathological morphology and significantly suppressed apoptosis after OC treatment in LPS-induced ALI chicken (P &amp;lt; 0.01). Antioxidant capacity was higher in the LPS + OC group compared with the LPS group (P &amp;lt; 0.01). OC downregulated the related genes and proteins expression of toll-like receptor 4/nuclear factor-κB (TLR4/NF-κB) pathway in LPS group (P &amp;lt; 0.01). In conclusion, OC supplementation can alleviate LPS-induced ALI in chickens by suppressing apoptosis, enhancing lung antioxidant capacities and inhibiting TLR4/NF-κB pathway activation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Total glycosides of Rhodiola rosea L. attenuate LPS-induced acute lung injury by inhibiting TLR4/NF-κB pathway</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36587557/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36587557/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Total glycosides of Rhodiola rosea L. alleviate LPS-induced acute lung injury.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Total glycosides of Rhodiola rosea L. protect mice by reducing pulmonary edema.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Total glycosides of Rhodiola rosea L. inhibit the influx of inflammatory cells into the lung.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Total glycosides of Rhodiola rosea L. reduce inflammation in the lung by inhibiting TLR4/NF-κB pathway.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acute lung injury (ALI) is a common respiratory disease in clinics, which is characterized by alveolar-capillary membrane loss, plasma protein leakage, pulmonary edema, massive neutrophil infiltration, and the release of proinflammatory cytokines and mediators. Rhodiola rosea L. an adaptogenic plant rich in phenylethanoloids, phenylpropanoids, monoterpenes, has anti-inflammatory and antioxidant effects. We hope to verify the relieving effect of total glycosides of Rhodiola rosea L. (RTG) on ALI in mice and clarify its mechanism through this study. In this study, we identified the effect and mechanism of RTG on ALI through LPS-induced ALI mice. After RTG treatment, the pathological structure of lung tissue in ALI mice induced by LPS was significantly improved, and the infiltration of inflammatory cells was reduced. In addition, RTG reduced the production of IL-6, IL-1β, and TNF-α in the serum of ALI mice and reduced the content or activity of MPO, T-SOD, GSH, and MDA in lung tissue. RNAseq analysis showed that RTG ameliorated LPS-induced ALI through anti-inflammatory, reduced immune response, and anti-apoptotic activities. The western blotting analysis confirmed that RTG could down-regulate the expression levels of TLR4, MyD88, NF-κB p65, and p-IκBα/IκBα. These results suggest that RTG can attenuate LPS-induced ALI through antioxidants and inhibition of the TLR4/NF-κB pathway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BAP31 regulates the expression of ICAM-1/VCAM-1 via MyD88/NF-κB pathway in acute lung injury mice model</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36549351/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36549351/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Aims:&lt;/em&gt; The cell adhesion molecules (CAMs) that mediate neutrophil-endothelium cell adhesion are deeply involved in the pathogenesis of acute lung injury (ALI). B-cell receptor associated protein 31 (BAP31) has been reported to engage in the expression of some CAMs. This study was undertaken to explore whether BAP31 in endotheliocyte affects the pathological process of ALI by regulating CAMs, and its possible mechanism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Main methods:&lt;/em&gt; Our study used the shBAP31 endothelium cell lines and endothelial-specific BAP31 conditional knockdown mice constructed via Cre/loxP system. Hematoxylin and eosin staining was used to observe the histopathological manifestations. The adhesion of neutrophils to vascular wall was examined by intravital microscopy. The nuclear translocation of NF-κB was observed by immunofluorescence staining assay. Flow cytometric, real-time polymerase chain reaction and Western blot assay were performed to determine the expression of CAMs and key proteins in MyD88/NF-κB-related signaling pathway. Luciferase reporter and chromatin immunoprecipitation assay were analyzed for transcriptional activity of ICAM-1 and VCAM-1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Key findings:&lt;/em&gt; Mechanistic investigations indicated that endothelium-specific BAP31 depletion dramatically reduced the capacity of neutrophils adherence to endothelial cells (ECs), which was mainly attributed to the significant downregulation of ICAM-1 (&lt;em&gt;p&lt;/em&gt; &amp;lt; 0.05) and VCAM-1 (&lt;em&gt;p&lt;/em&gt; &amp;lt; 0.05) expression. Interestingly, BAP31 knockdown apparently deactivated MyD88/TRAF6-mediated TAK1/NF-κB and PI3K/Akt signaling cascades, resulting in the inhibition of NF-κB activation and nuclear translocation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Significance:&lt;/em&gt; Our data furnished convincing evidence that BAP31 deficiency performs a mitigative effect on ALI by decreasing neutrophils-ECs adhesion. These findings identified BAP31 as a promising protein for regulating the pathogenesis process of ALI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JMJD3 Is Required for Acute Pancreatitis and Pancreatitis-Associated Lung Injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36458991/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36458991/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acute pancreatitis (AP) can be complicated by inflammatory disorders of remote organs, such as lung injury, in which Jumonji domain-containing protein 3 (JMJD3) plays a vital role in proinflammatory responses. Currently, we found that JMJD3 expression was upregulated in the pancreas and lung in an AP male mouse model, which was also confirmed in AP patients. Further experiments revealed that the upregulation of JMJD3 and proinflammatory effects were possibly exerted by mitochondrial DNA (mtDNA) or oxidized-mtDNA from tissue injury caused by AP. The release of mtDNA and oxidized-mtDNA contributed to the infiltration of inflammatory monocytes in lung injury through the stimulator of IFN genes (STING)/TLR9-NF-κB-JMJD3-TNF-α pathway. The inhibition of JMJD3 or utilization of Jmjd3-cKO mice significantly alleviated pulmonary inflammation induced by AP. Blocking mtDNA oxidation or knocking down the TLR9/STING pathway effectively alleviated inflammation. Therefore, inhibition of JMJD3 or STING/TLR9 pathway blockage might be a potential therapeutic strategy to treat AP and the associated lung injury.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Uterine macrophages as treatment targets for therapy of premature rupture of membranes by modified ADSC-EVs through a circRNA/miRNA/NF-κB pathway</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36402996/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36402996/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Circular RNA (circRNA) is a type of stable non-coding RNA that modifies macrophage inflammation by sponging micro RNAs (miRNAs), binding to RNA-binding proteins, and undergoing translation into peptides. Activated M1 phenotype macrophages secrete matrix metalloproteinases to participate in softening of the cervix uteri to promote vaginal delivery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; In this study, the premature rupture of membranes (PROM) mouse model was used to analyze the role of macrophages in this process. Profiling of circRNAs was performed using a competing endogenous RNA microarray, and their functions were elucidated in vitro. Meanwhile, adipose tissue-derived stem cell-secreted extracellular vesicles (EVs) were applied as a vehicle to transport small interfering RNAs (siRNAs) targeting the circRNAs to demonstrate their biological function in vivo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; The miRNA &lt;em&gt;miR-1931&lt;/em&gt; is dependent on the nuclear factor kappa-B (NF-κB) pathway but negatively regulates its activation by targeting the NF-κB signaling transducer TRAF6 to prevent polarization of M1 macrophages and inhibit matrix metalloproteinase (MMP) secretion. The host gene of circRNA &lt;em&gt;B4GALNT1&lt;/em&gt;, also an NF-κB pathway-dependent gene, circularizes to form &lt;em&gt;circRNA_0002047&lt;/em&gt;, which sponges &lt;em&gt;miR-1931&lt;/em&gt; to maintain NF-κB pathway activation and MMP secretion in vitro. In the PROM model, EVs loaded with siRNAs targeting circRNAs demonstrated that the circRNAs reduced &lt;em&gt;miR-1931&lt;/em&gt; expression to maintain NF-κB pathway activation and MMP secretion for accelerating PROM in vivo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; Our data provide insights into understanding PROM pathogenesis and improving PROM treatment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Identification of environmental factors that promote intestinal inflammation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36266581/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36266581/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Genome-wide association studies have identified risk loci linked to inflammatory bowel disease (IBD)-a complex chronic inflammatory disorder of the gastrointestinal tract. The increasing prevalence of IBD in industrialized countries and the augmented disease risk observed in migrants who move into areas of higher disease prevalence suggest that environmental factors are also important determinants of IBD susceptibility and severity. However, the identification of environmental factors relevant to IBD and the mechanisms by which they influence disease has been hampered by the lack of platforms for their systematic investigation. Here we describe an integrated systems approach, combining publicly available databases, zebrafish chemical screens, machine learning and mouse preclinical models to identify environmental factors that control intestinal inflammation. This approach established that the herbicide propyzamide increases inflammation in the small and large intestine. Moreover, we show that an AHR-NF-κB-C/EBPβ signalling axis operates in T cells and dendritic cells to promote intestinal inflammation, and is targeted by propyzamide. In conclusion, we developed a pipeline for the identification of environmental factors and mechanisms of pathogenesis in IBD and, potentially, other inflammatory diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MiR-1249 on Endothelial Extracellular Vesicles Mediates Cigarette Smoke-Induced Pulmonary Hypertension by Inhibiting HDAC10 (Histone Deacetylase 10)-NFκB (Nuclear Factor κB)-CaSR (Calcium-Sensing Receptor) Cascade</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36252137/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36252137/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Overproduction of endothelial extracellular vesicles (eEVs) is correlated with pulmonary hypertension progression, but the precise mechanism remains largely unclear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; MicroRNA-chip and real-time polymerase chain reaction were conducted to screen and validate microRNA profiles in blood plasma eEVs of rats and human with or without cigarette smoking. Pulmonary artery smooth muscle cells were cultured to study signaling pathways. Pulmonary hypertension phenotypes were evaluated in wild-type and calcium-sensing receptor knockout rats to identify the pathophysiological significance of the microRNA pathway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; MicroR-1249 was predominant highly expressed in eEVs from plasma of rats exposed to cigarette smoking, and confirmed in eEVs from plasma of human smokers as well as in eEVs from cigarette smoke extract-treated pulmonary artery endothelial cells, but not in cigarette smoke extract-treated pulmonary artery smooth muscle cells. In cultured pulmonary artery smooth muscle cells, microR-1249 downregulated the expression of histone deacetylase 10, which in turn enhanced the acetylated form of NFκB (nuclear factor κB) level and its nuclear translocation leading to increased expression of calcium-sensing receptor. In rats, the repression of microR-1249 in eEVs by microR-1249 inhibitor, histone deacetylase 10 overexpression, or calcium-sensing receptor knockout profoundly inhibited the proliferative capacities and diminished apoptosis-resistance of pulmonary artery smooth muscle cells and pulmonary hypertension development in rats intravenously administrated with eEVs preparation from cigarette smoke extract-treated pulmonary artery endothelial cells.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; Cigarette smoke-enriched microR-1249 in endothelial extracellular vesicles facilitates the hyperproliferative and antiapoptotic status of pulmonary artery smooth muscle cells promoting pulmonary hypertension evolution through the inhibition of histone deacetylase 10-NFκB-calcium-sensing receptor cascade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Schisandrin B protects against LPS-induced inflammatory lung injury by targeting MyD88</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36270224/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36270224/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Acute lung injury (ALI) is a challenging clinical syndrome that manifests as an acute inflammatory response. Schisandrin B (Sch B), a bioactive lignan from Schisandra genus plants, has been shown to suppress inflammatory responses and oxidative stress. However, the underlying molecular mechanisms have remained elusive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Hypothesis/purpose:&lt;/em&gt; This study performed an in-depth investigation of the anti-inflammatory mechanism of Sch B in macrophages and in an animal model of ALI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; qPCR array was used to probe the differential effects and potential target of Sch B. ALI was induced by intratracheal administration of LPS in experimental mice with or without Sch B treatment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; Our studies show that Sch B differentially modulates inflammatory factor induction by LPS in macrophages by directly binding myeloid differentiation response factor-88 (MyD88), an essential adaptor protein in the toll-like receptor-4 (TLR4) pathway. Sch B spares non-MyD88-pathways downstream of TLR4. Such inhibition suppressed key signaling mediators such as TAK1, MAPKs, and NF-κB, and pro-inflammatory factor induction. Pull down assay using biotinylated-Sch B validate the direct interaction between Sch B and MyD88 in macrophages. Treatment of mice with Sch B prior to LPS challenge reduced inflammatory cell infiltration in lungs, induction of MyD88-pathway signaling proteins, and prevented inflammatory cytokine induction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/em&gt; In summary, our studies have identified MyD88 as a direct target of Sch B for its anti-inflammatory activity, and suggest that Sch B may have therapeutic value for acute lung injury and other MyD88-dependent inflammatory diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Polysaccharides from Tetrastigma Hemsleyanum Diels et Gilg attenuate LPS-induced acute lung injury by modulating TLR4/COX-2/NF-κB signaling pathway</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36182735/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36182735/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Polysaccharides from &lt;em&gt;Tetrastigma Hemsleyanum&lt;/em&gt; Diels et Gilg (SYQP) attenuated LPS-induced ALI in vivo and in vitro.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SYQP exerted anti-inflammatory and anti-oxidative stress effects in vivo and in vitro.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SYQP alleviated ALI by inhibiting TLR4/COX-2/NF-κB signaling pathway.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tetrastigma Hemsleyanum&lt;/em&gt; Diels et Gilg (Sanyeqing, SYQ), a traditional herb native to China, has been widely used in the treatment of inflammatory diseases, febrile convulsions and dysentery. Previous studies have demonstrated the hypoglycemic, anti-inflammatory and anti-pyretic effects of polysaccharides from SYQ (SYQP). However, the role of SYQP in acute lung injury (ALI) remained unknown. Our present study aimed to explore the protective effects of SYQP in ALI and explained its underlying mechanism. In vivo, Balb/c mice were intragastrically administered with SYQP and dexamethasone (DXMS) for 14 days which were intratracheally instilled (IT) with LPS at the last day. In vitro, A549 cells were pretreated with SYQP, DXMS or TAK-242, following by LPS stimulation for 24 h. The histopathological results showed that SYQP remarkably alleviated pulmonary macrophage infiltration and myeloperoxidase (MPO) levels. Additionally, SYQP evidently suppressed wet/dry (W/D) ratio of lung and white blood cells (WBC) in bronchoalveolar lavage fluid (BALF). Moreover, SYQP markedly reduced TNF-α, IL-6, IL-1β and COX-2 levels both in vivo and in vitro. Meanwhile, SYQP significantly attenuated oxidative stress through upregulating the levels of SOD and GSH-Px and downregulating the expressions of MDA and LDH in vivo, which was confirmed by in vitro results that SYQP could increase SOD activity and decrease MDA and NO contents. Importantly, a decline in protein expressions of TLR4, COX-2, NF-κB p50, phospho-NF-κB p65 and phospho-IκB-α was detected in vivo and in vitro. Taken together, our results demonstrated that SYQP ameliorated LPS-induced ALI by alleviating inflammation and oxidative stress via attenuating TLR4/COX-2/NF-κB signaling pathway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Selenium-enriched soybean peptides pretreatment attenuates lung injury in mice induced by fine particulate matters (PM2.5) through inhibition of TLR4/NF-κB/IκBα signaling pathway and inflammasome generation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35979800/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35979800/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This study aimed to identify and prepare peptides from selenium (Se)-enriched soybeans and determine whether dietary Se-enriched soybean peptides (Se-SPep) could inhibit lung injury in mice induced by fine particulate matter 2.5 (PM2.5). BALB/c mice were randomly divided into six groups. The mice in the prevention groups were pretreated with 378 mg kg-1 of Se-SPep, soybean peptides (SPep), and Se-enriched soybean protein (Se-SPro), respectively, for four weeks. The mice in the PM2.5 exposure group received concentrated PM2.5 (15 μg per day mice) for 1 h daily from the third week for two weeks. The results showed that the leukocyte and cytokine (IL-1β, IL-6, TNF-α) levels in the bronchoalveolar lavage fluid (BALF) of the PM2.5 exposure group were higher than those in the control group. Se-SPep pretreatment decreased the IL-1β, IL-6, and TNF-α levels compared with the PM2.5 exposure group. Additionally, Se-SPep pretreatment inhibited TLR4/NF-κB/IκBα and NLRP3/ASC/caspase-1 protein expression in the lungs. In conclusion, Se-SPep pretreatment may protect the lungs of the mice against PM2.5-induced inflammation, suggesting that Se-SPep represents a potential preventative agent to inhibit PM2.5-induced lung injury.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Na/K-ATPase suppresses LPS-induced pro-inflammatory signaling through Lyn</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36072548/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36072548/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;NKA α1 interacts with TLR4 and SFKs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;NKA α1 restricts LPS-stimulated pro-inflammatory responses in macrophages&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;NKA α1&lt;sup&gt;+/−&lt;/sup&gt; mice injected with LPS show more lung injury and lower survival rate&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Na/K-ATPase (NKA), besides its ion transporter function, is a signal transducer by regulating Src family kinases (SFK). The signaling NKA contributes to oxidized LDL-induced macrophage foam cell formation and interacts with TLR4. However, its role in lipopolysaccharides (LPS)-induced signaling and glycolytic switch in macrophages remains unclear. Using peritoneal macrophages from NKA α1 haploinsufficient mice (NKA α1&lt;sup&gt;+/-&lt;/sup&gt;), we found that NKA α1 haploinsufficiency led to enhanced LPS-stimulated NF-κB pathway, ROS signaling, and pro-inflammatory cytokines. Intraperitoneal injection of LPS resulted in more severe lung inflammation and injury with lower survival rate in NKA α1&lt;sup&gt;+/-&lt;/sup&gt; mice. Additionally, LPS induced a higher extent of the metabolic switch from oxidative phosphorylation to glycolysis. Mechanistically, NKA α1 interacted with TLR4 and Lyn. The presence of NKA α1 in this complex attenuated Lyn activation by LPS, which subsequently restricted the downstream ROS and NF-κB signaling. In conclusion, we demonstrated that NKA α1 suppresses LPS-induced macrophage pro-inflammatory signaling through Lyn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Poldip2 knockdown protects against lipopolysaccharide-induced acute lung injury via Nox4/Nrf2/NF-κB signaling pathway</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36120334/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36120334/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Polymerase δ-interacting protein 2 (Poldip2) has been reported to mediate acute lung injury (ALI); however, the underlying mechanism is not fully explored. Male C57BL/6 mice and A549 cells were used to establish the lipopolysaccharide (LPS)-induced ALI model, then the expression of Poldip2 and its effect on oxidative stress and the resulting inflammation were detected. Adeno-associated virus serotype 6 (AAV6) mediated Poldip2 knockdown was transfected into mice via intratracheal atomization. And A549 cells stimulated with LPS was used to further confirm our hypothesis in vitro. ML385, specifically inhibited the activation of the Nrf2 signaling pathway. Our data suggested that LPS stimulation remarkably increased protein levels of Nox4 and p-P65, activities of NADPH and MPO, and generation of ROS, TNF-α, and IL-1β while decreased protein levels of Nrf2 and HO-1 compared with those in NC shRNA + Saline group, which were obviously reversed by Poldip2 knockdown. Concomitantly, Poldip2 knockdown dramatically reduced contents of MDA and enhanced activities of SOD and GSH-Px compared to NC shRNA + LPS group. In vitro, we found that knockdown of Poldip2 significantly reversed LPS-induced increase protein levels of Nox4 and p-P65, activity of NADPH, and generation of ROS, TNF-α, and IL-1β, and decrease protein levels of Nrf2 and HO-1, ML385 pretreatment reversed the effects of Poldip2 knockdown mentioned above. Our study indicated that Poldip2 knockdown alleviates LPS-induced ALI via inhibiting Nox4/Nrf2/NF-κB signaling pathway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Diacerein attenuate LPS-induced acute lung injury via inhibiting ER stress and apoptosis: Impact on the crosstalk between SphK1/S1P, TLR4/NFκB/STAT3, and NLRP3/IL-1β signaling pathways</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36055546/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36055546/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Aims:&lt;/em&gt; Acute lung injury (ALI) is a life-threatening clinical problem with high mortality rate and limited treatments or preventive options that represents a major challenge for clinicians. Diacerein (DIA) is a multi-target anthraquinone derivative with potent anti-inflammatory action. The aim of this study is to assess the protective effect of DIA and its potential molecular targets against lipopolysaccharide (LPS)-induced ALI in rats.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Materials and methods:&lt;/em&gt; Adult male Sprague-Dawley rats were orally administrated DIA (50 mg/kg) for 5 consecutive days followed by a single intraperitoneal injection of LPS (5mg/kg).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Key findings:&lt;/em&gt; DIA mitigated oxidative lung injury in LPS-challenged rats via significantly decreasing lung wet/dry (W/D) ratio, inflammatory cells infiltration, and lipid peroxidation, with concomitant elevation in enzymatic and non-enzymatic antioxidant levels in lung tissue. Likewise, DIA alleviated endoplasmic reticulum stress and markedly halted inflammation triggered by LPS challenge in pulmonary tissue by suppressing NLRP3/IL-1β and TLR4/NF-κB signaling with parallel decrease in proinflammatory cytokine levels. Interestingly, DIA down regulated Sphk1/S1P axis, reduced GSK-3β and STAT3 proteins expression, and markedly decreased caspase-3 besides increasing Bcl-2 levels in lung tissue of LPS-challenged animals. These biochemical findings was simultaneously associated with marked improvement in histological alterations of lung tissue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Significance:&lt;/em&gt; These findings verify the protective effect of DIA against LPS-induced ALI through targeting oxidative stress, endoplasmic reticulum stress, and apoptosis. Importantly, DIA halted the hyperinflammatory state triggered by LPS via multi-faceted inhibitory effect on different signaling pathways, hence DIA could potentially reduce mortality in patients with ALI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eupalinolide B attenuates lipopolysaccharide-induced acute lung injury through inhibition of NF-κB and MAPKs signaling by targeting TAK1 protein</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35988521/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35988521/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Eupalinolide B (EB) inhibit LPS-induced acute lung injury in mice.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;EB directly binds to TAK1, and inhibits NF-κB and MAPKs activation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The α,γ-unsaturated lactone of EB is vital for its anti-inflammatory effect.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acute lung injury (ALI) is a life-threatening disease characterized by severe inflammatory response, which has no pharmacological therapy in clinic. In this study, we found that eupalinolide B (EB), a sesquiterpene lactone isolated from Eupatorium lindleyanum, significantly ameliorated lipopolysaccharide (LPS)-induced ALI in mice, which manifests as reduction in lung injury score, activity of myeloperoxidase, and release of cytokines interleukin (IL)-1β, IL-6, tumor necrosis factor-α (TNF-α), and monocyte chemoattractant protein-1 (MCP-1). In RAW264.7 murine macrophages, EB effectively inhibited LPS-induced production of nitric oxide (NO) and prostaglandin E2 (PGE2) by down-regulating the expression of inducible nitric oxide synthase (iNOS) and cyclooxygenase-2 (COX2), respectively. Mechanistically, EB not only blocked LPS-induced phosphorylation of inhibitor of nuclear factor kappa B kinase-α/β (IKKα/β), phosphorylation and degradation of inhibitor of nuclear factor-kappa B alpha (IκBα), and phosphorylation and nuclear translocation of nuclear factor-kappa B (NF-κB) P65, but also suppressed LPS-induced phosphorylation of mitogen-activated protein kinases (MAPKs) &lt;em&gt;in vitro&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt;. Through cellular thermal shift assay and western blotting, EB was demonstrated to target and inactivate transforming growth factor β activated kinase-1 (TAK1), which is an important upstream kinase for the activation of NF-κB and MAPKs pathways. Additionally, EB-mediated actions were markedly abolished by dithiothreitol in LPS-exposed RAW264.7 cells, suggesting a crucial role of the α,γ-unsaturated lactone for the anti-inflammatory activity of EB. In conclusion, our findings showed that EB could effectively alleviate ALI in mice, and attenuate inflammatory response by inhibiting the activation of TAK1, and TAK1-mediated activation of NF-κB and MAPKs cascades.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oxypeucedanin relieves LPS-induced acute lung injury by inhibiting the inflammation and maintaining the integrity of the lung air-blood barrier</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35985771/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35985771/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Introduction:&lt;/em&gt; Acute lung injury (ALI) is commonly accompanied by a severe inflammatory reaction process, and effectively managing inflammatory reactions is an important therapeutic approach for alleviating ALI. Macrophages play an important role in the inflammatory response, and this role is proinflammatory in the early stages of inflammation and anti-inflammatory in the late stages. Oxypeucedanin is a natural product with a wide range of pharmacological functions. This study aimed to determine the effect of oxypeucedanin on lipopolysaccharide (LPS)-induced ALI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods and results:&lt;/em&gt; In this study, the following experiments were performed based on LPS-induced models &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;in vitro&lt;/em&gt;. Using myeloperoxidase activity measurement, ELISA, qRT-PCR, and Western blotting, we found that oxypeucedanin modulated the activity of myeloperoxidase and decreased the expression levels of inflammatory mediators such as TNF-α, IL-6, IL-1β, MPO, COX-2 and iNOS in LPS-induced inflammation models. Meanwhile, oxypeucedanin inhibited the activation of PI3K/AKT and its downstream NF-κB and MAPK signaling pathways. In addition, oxypeucedanin significantly decreased the pulmonary vascular permeability, which was induced by LPSs, and the enhanced expression of tight junction proteins (Occludin and Claudin 3).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; In conclusion, this study demonstrated that the anti-inflammatory mechanism of oxypeucedanin is associated with the inhibition of the activation of PI3K/AKT/NF-κB and MAPK signaling pathways and the maintenance of the integrity of the lung air-blood barrier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MiR-192-5p/RB1/NF-κBp65 signaling axis promotes IL-10 secretion during gastric cancer EMT to induce Treg cell differentiation in the tumour microenvironment</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35969010/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35969010/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Regulatory T (Treg) cells are important components of the tumour microenvironment (TME) that play roles in gastric cancer (GC) metastasis. Although tumour cells that undergo epithelial-mesenchymal transition (EMT) regulate Treg cell function, their regulatory mechanism in GC remains unclear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; The miR-192-5p was identified by examining three Gene Expression Omnibus GC miRNA expression datasets. RNA immunoprecipitation (RIP) and dual-luciferase reporter assays were conducted to identify interactions between miR-192-5p and RB1. The role of miR-192-5p/RB1 in GC progression was evaluated based on EdU incorporation, wound healing and Transwell assays. An in vitro co-culture assay was performed to measure the effect of miR-192-5p/RB1 on Treg cell differentiation. In vivo experiments were conducted to explore the role of miR-192-5p in GC progression and Treg cell differentiation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; MiR-192-5p was overexpressed in tumour and was associated with poor prognosis in GC. MiR-192-5p bound to the RB1 3&amp;rsquo;-untranslated region, resulting in GC EMT, proliferation, migration and invasion. MiR-192-5p/RB1 mediated interleukin-10 (IL-10) secretion by regulating nuclear factor-kappaBp65 (NF-κBp65), affecting Treg cell differentiation. NF-κBp65, in turn, promoted miR-192-5p expression and formed a positive feedback loop. Furthermore, in vivo experiments confirmed that miR-192-5p/RB1 promotes GC growth and Treg cell differentiation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/em&gt; Collectively, our studies indicate that miR-192-5p/RB1 promotes EMT of tumour cells, and the miR-192-5p/RB1/NF-κBp65 signaling axis induces Treg cell differentiation by regulating IL-10 secretion in GC. Our results suggest that targeting miR-192-5p/RB1/NF-κBp65 /IL-10 may pave the way for the development of new immune treatments for GC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zanubrutinib ameliorates lipopolysaccharide-induced acute lung injury via regulating macrophage polarization</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35973369/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35973369/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Zanubrutinib could relieve LPS induced lung injuries in mice.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;JAK2/STAT1 and TLR4/MyD88/NF-κB pathway is involved in Zanubrutinib -mediated M1 macrophage polarization in RAW264.7 cells.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Zanubrutinib promotes M2 macrophage activation through regulating JAK/STAT6 and PI3K/AKT pathway in RAW264.7 cells.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acute lung injury (ALI) is a disease characterized by pulmonary diffusion dysfunction and its exacerbation stage is acute respiratory distress syndrome (ARDS), which may develop to multiple organ failure and seriously threatens human health. ALI has high mortality rates and few effective treatments, thus effective protection measures for ALI are becoming increasingly important. Macrophages play a key regulatory role in the pathogenesis of ALI, and the degree of macrophage polarization is closely related to the severity and prognosis of ALI. In this study, we evaluated the effects of Zanubrutinib (ZB), a BTK small molecule inhibitor approved by the FDA for the treatment of cell lymphoma, on macrophage polarization and acute lung injury. In the in vivo study, we constructed a mouse model of Lipopolysaccharide (LPS)-induced acute lung injury and found that ZB could improve the acute injury of mouse lungs by inhibiting the secretion of proinflammatory factors and promoting the secretion of anti-inflammatory factors, reduce the number of inflammatory cells in alveolar lavage fluid, and then alleviate the inflammatory response. In vivo and in vitro studies have shown that ZB could inhibit the M1 macrophage polarization and promote the M2 macrophage polarization. Subsequent mechanistic studies revealed that ZB could inhibit the macrophage M1 polarization via targeting BTK activation and inhibiting JAK2/STAT1 and TLR4/MyD88/NF-κB signaling pathways, and promote the macrophage M2 polarization by promoting the activation of STAT6 and PI3K / Akt signaling pathways. In summary, ZB has shown therapeutic effect in LPS-induced acute lung injury in mice, which provides a potential candidate drug to treat acute lung injury.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Allyl methyl trisulfide protected against LPS-induced acute lung injury in mice via inhibition of the NF-κB and MAPK pathways</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36003507/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36003507/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Allyl methyl trisulfide (AMTS) is one major lipid-soluble organosulfur compound of garlic. Previous studies have reported the potential therapeutic effect of garlic on acute lung injury (ALI) or its severe condition acute respiratory distress syndrome (ARDS), but the specific substances that exert the regulatory effects are still unclear. In this study, we investigate the protective effects of AMTS on lipopolysaccharide (LPS)-induced ALI mice and explored the underlying mechanisms. &lt;em&gt;In vivo&lt;/em&gt; experiments, ICR mice were pretreated with 25-100 mg/kg AMTS for 7 days and followed by intratracheal instillation of LPS (1.5 mg/kg). The results showed that AMTS significantly attenuated LPS-induced deterioration of lung pathology, demonstrated by ameliorative edema and protein leakage, and improved pulmonary histopathological morphology. Meanwhile, the expression of inflammatory mediators and the infiltration of inflammation-regulation cells induced by LPS were also inhibited. &lt;em&gt;In vitro&lt;/em&gt; experiments also revealed that AMTS could alleviate inflammation response and inhibit the exaggeration of macrophage M1 polarization in LPS-induced RAW264.7 cells. Mechanistically, we identified that AMTS treatment could attenuate the LPS-induced elevation of protein expression of p-IκBα, nuclear NF-κB-p65, COX2, iNOS, p-P38, p-ERK1/2, and p-JNK. Collectively, these data suggest that AMTS could attenuate LPS-induced ALI and the molecular mechanisms should be related to the suppression of the NF-κB and MAPKs pathways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>USP25 Deficiency Exacerbates Acute Pancreatitis via Up-Regulating TBK1-NF-κB Signaling in Macrophages</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35934222/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35934222/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background &amp;amp; aims:&lt;/em&gt; Severe acute pancreatitis can easily lead to systemic inflammatory response syndrome and death. Macrophages are known to be involved in the pathophysiology of acute pancreatitis (AP), and macrophage activation correlates with disease severity. In this study, we examined the role of ubiquitin-specific protease 25, a deubiquitinating enzyme and known regulator of macrophages, in the pathogenesis of AP.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; We used L-arginine, cerulein, and choline-deficient ethionine-supplemented diet-induced models of AP in &lt;em&gt;Usp25&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; mice and wild-type mice. We also generated bone marrow &lt;em&gt;Usp25&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; chimeric mice and initiated L-arginine-mediated AP. Primary acinar cells and bone marrow-derived macrophages were isolated from wild-type and &lt;em&gt;Usp25&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; mice to dissect molecular mechanisms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; Our results show that Usp25 deficiency exacerbates pancreatic and lung injury, neutrophil and macrophage infiltration, and systemic inflammatory responses in L-arginine, cerulein, and choline-deficient ethionine-supplemented diet-induced models of AP. Bone marrow &lt;em&gt;Usp25&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; chimeric mice challenged with L-arginine show that &lt;em&gt;Usp25&lt;/em&gt; deficiency in macrophages exaggerates AP by up-regulating the TANK-binding kinase 1 (TBK1)-nuclear factor-κB (NF-κB) signaling pathway. Similarly, in vitro data confirm that Usp25 deficiency enhances the TBK1-NF-κB pathway, leading to increased expression of inflammatory cytokines in bone marrow-derived macrophages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;Usp25&lt;/em&gt; deficiency in macrophages enhances TBK1-NF-κB signaling, and the induction of inflammatory chemokines and type I interferon-related genes exacerbates pancreatic and lung injury in AP.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PTPRO knockdown protects against inflammation in hemorrhage shock-induced lung injury involving the NF-κB signaling pathway</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35906634/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35906634/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Hemorrhage shock (HS) is characterized by decreased tissue oxygenation and organ damage due to severe blood loss. Protein tyrosine phosphatase receptor type O (PTPRO) is abnormally up-regulated in the rat lungs after trauma/HS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; To elucidate the regulatory mechanism of PTPRO in lung inflammation following HS, we established a rat model of HS via withdrawing blood by a catheter inserted into the femoral artery followed by resuscitation. The rats were infected with lentivirus harboring short hairpin RNA (shRNA) targeting PTPRO by intratracheal instillation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; PTPRO was significantly up-regulated in rat lungs after HS. PTPRO knockdown enhanced epithelial integrity and reduced capillary leakage by up-regulating tight junction proteins zonula occludens-1 (ZO-1) and occludin (OCC) in the lungs. Besides, HS-induced myeloperoxidase activity and inflammatory cell infiltration was mitigated by PTPRO knockdown. The expression of inflammatory cytokines/chemokines (TNF-α, IL-6, MIP-2, MCP-1, and KC) in the lungs and bronchoalveolar lavage fluid was regressed after PTPRO knockdown. The nuclear factor kappa B (NF-κB) pathway was involved in HS-induced lung inflammation. PTPRO down-regulation inhibited the NF-κB pathway activation by suppressing the phosphorylation of NF-κB and its translocation from the cytoplasm into the nucleus in HS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/em&gt; Taken together, we demonstrated that PTPRO knockdown may contribute to attenuating inflammation in HS-induced lung injury via inhibiting NF-κB pathway activation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Glaesserella parasuis induces IL-17 production might through PKC-ERK/MAPK and IκB/NF-κB signaling pathways</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35932516/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35932516/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;G. parasuis&lt;/em&gt; infections upregulated IL-17 production both in vitro and in vivo.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Virulent &lt;em&gt;G. parasuis&lt;/em&gt; strains could induced higher IL-17 production.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IL-17 expression positively correlated with degree of pathological tissue injury.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;G. parasuis&lt;/em&gt; infection induced IL-17 production through PKC-ERK/MAPK and IκB/NF-κB pathways.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In our previous study, the outer membrane protein P2 of &lt;em&gt;Glaesserella parasuis&lt;/em&gt; (&lt;em&gt;G. parasuis&lt;/em&gt;) induced the production of interleukin-17A (IL-17A) in host cells. However, how the &lt;em&gt;G. parasuis&lt;/em&gt; infection produces IL-17A in the host is unknown. In this study, at 48 hpi in piglets, the proportion of Th17 cells in the peripheral blood significantly increased as determined by flow cytometry, but the overall proportion was low. IL-17 mRNA and protein levels significantly increased in the lungs and spleens of infected piglets. Histopathological examination staining, immunohistochemistry and viability counts, revealed that IL-17 expression might be positively correlated with bacterial content and the degree of pathological injury in lung and spleen tissues. Furthermore, when infected with the &lt;em&gt;G. parasuis&lt;/em&gt; Nagasaki strain compared with avirulent strain C5, the primary porcine alveolar macrophages (PAMs) significantly produced IL-17 in a time-dose dependent manner. In addition, we demonstrated that PKC, MEK and NF-κB signaling pathways were essential for &lt;em&gt;G. parasuis&lt;/em&gt;-induced IL-17 production because the addition of corresponding inhibitors dramatically reduced IL-17 mRNA production. The phosphorylation levels of PKC, ERK1/2 and IκB in &lt;em&gt;G. parasuis&lt;/em&gt;-infected primary PAMs also increased significantly as the infection dose increased as assessed by western blotting. Thus, these finding imply that IL-17 induced by &lt;em&gt;G. parasuis&lt;/em&gt; infection is dependent on activation of PKC-ERK/MAPK and IκB/NF-κB signaling pathways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>p53/sirtuin 1/NF-κB Signaling Axis in Chronic Inflammation and Maladaptive Kidney Repair After Cisplatin Nephrotoxicity</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35874713/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35874713/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chronic inflammation contributes to maladaptive kidney repair, but its regulation is unclear. Here, we report that sirtuin 1 (SIRT1) is downregulated after repeated low-dose cisplatin (RLDC) injury, and this downregulation leads to p65 acetylation and consequent NF-κB activation resulting in a persistent inflammatory response. RLDC induced the down-regulation of SIRT1 and activation of NF-κB, which were accompanied by chronic tubular damage, tubulointerstitial inflammation, and fibrosis in mice. Inhibition of NF-κB suppressed the production of pro-inflammatory cytokines and fibrotic phenotypes in RLDC-treated renal tubular cells. SIRT1 activation by its agonists markedly reduced the acetylation of p65 (a key component of NF-κB), resulting in the attenuation of the inflammatory and fibrotic responses. Conversely, knockdown of SIRT1 exacerbated these cellular changes. At the upstream, p53 was activated after RLDC treatment to repress SIRT1, resulting in p65 acetylation, NF-κB activation and transcription of inflammatory cytokines. In mice, SIRT1 agonists attenuated RLDC-induced chronic inflammation, tissue damage, and renal fibrosis. Together, these results unveil the p53/SIRT1/NF-κB signaling axis in maladaptive kidney repair following RLDC treatment, where p53 represses SIRT1 to increase p65 acetylation for NF-κB activation, leading to chronic renal inflammation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Activation of the P62-Keap1-NRF2 Pathway Protects against Ferroptosis in Radiation-Induced Lung Injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35847598/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35847598/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Radiation-induced lung injury (RILI) is one of the most common, serious, and dose-limiting toxicities of thoracic radiotherapy. A primary cause for this is the radiation-induced cell death. Ferroptosis is a recently recognized form of regulated cell death, characterized by the accumulation of lipid peroxidation products and lethal reactive oxygen species (ROS). The ROS generated by irradiation might be the original trigger of ferroptosis in RILI. In addition, activation of the P62-Kelch-like ECH-associated protein 1 (Keap1)-nuclear factor erythroid 2-related factor 2 (NRF2) pathway has been shown to blunt ferroptosis and thus acts as a protective factor. Therefore, this study aimed to explore the protective effect of the P62-Keap1-NRF2 pathway against radiation-induced ferroptosis in alveolar epithelial cells. First, we found that radiation induced ferroptosis in vitro using a RILI cell model, which could be significantly reduced by ferrostatin-1 (Fer-1), a specific ferroptosis inhibitor. Additionally, overexpression of P62 interacted with Keap1 to facilitate the translocation of NRF2 into the nucleus and promote the expression of its target proteins, including quinone oxidoreductase 1 (NQO1), heme oxygenase 1 (HO1), and ferritin heavy chain 1 (FTH1). In summary, our results demonstrated that the activation of the P62-Keap1-NRF2 pathway prevents radiation-induced ferroptosis in RILI cells, providing a theoretical basis of finding a potential therapeutic approach for RILI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ISR8/IRF1-AS1 Is Relevant for IFNα and NF-κB Responses</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35860270/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35860270/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The study of the interferon (IFN) α-induced cell transcriptome has shown altered expression of several long non-coding RNAs (lncRNAs). ISR8/IRF1-AS1 (IFN stimulated RNA 8), located close to IFN regulatory factor 1 (&lt;em&gt;IRF1&lt;/em&gt;) coding gene, transcribes a lncRNA induced at early times after IFNα treatment or IRF1 or NF-κB activation. Depletion or overexpression of ISR8 RNA does not lead to detected deregulation of the IFN response. Surprisingly, disruption of &lt;em&gt;ISR8&lt;/em&gt; locus with CRISPR-Cas9 genome editing results in cells that fail to induce several key ISGs and pro-inflammatory cytokines after a trigger with IFNα or overexpression of IRF1 or the NF-κB subunit RELA. This suggests that the &lt;em&gt;ISR8&lt;/em&gt; locus may play a relevant role in IFNα and NF-κB pathways. Interestingly, IFNα, IRFs and NF-κB-responding luciferase reporters are normally induced in ISR8-disrupted cells when expressed from a plasmid but not when integrated into the genome. Therefore, IFNα and NF-κB pathways are functional to induce the expression of exogenous episomic transcripts but fail to activate transcription from genomic promoters. Transcription from these promoters is not restored with silencing inhibitors, by decreasing the levels of several negative regulators or by overexpression of inducers. Transcriptome analyses indicate that ISR8-disrupted cells have a drastic increase in the levels of negative regulators such as XIST and Zinc finger proteins. Our results agree with &lt;em&gt;ISR8&lt;/em&gt; loci being an enhancer region that is fundamental for proper antiviral and proinflammatory responses. These results are relevant because several SNPs located in the &lt;em&gt;ISR8&lt;/em&gt; region are associated with chronic inflammatory and autoimmune diseases including Crohn&amp;rsquo;s disease, inflammatory bowel disease, ulcerative colitis or asthma.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TLR4-SIRT3 Mechanism Modulates Mitochondrial and Redox Homeostasis and Promotes EPCs Recruitment and Survival</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35832490/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35832490/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The low survival rate of endothelial progenitor cells (EPCs) &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt; which are susceptible to adverse microenvironments including inflammation and oxidative stress has become one primary challenge of EPCs transplantation for regenerative therapy. Recent studies reported functional expression of toll-like receptor (TLR) 4 on EPCs and dose-dependent effects of lipopolysaccharide (LPS) on cellular oxidative stress and angiogenic properties. However, the involved mechanism has not yet been elucidated well, and the influence of TLR4 signaling on EPCs survival and function &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt; is unknown. In the present study, we observed the effects of LPS and TLR4/SIRT3 on EPCs mitochondrial permeability and intracellular mitochondrial superoxide. We employed the monocrotaline-induced pulmonary arteriolar injury model to observe the effects of TLR4/SIRT3 on the recruitment and survival of transplanted EPCs. We found the destructive effects of 10 μg/mL LPS on mitochondrial homeostasis, and cellular viability was mediated by TLR4/SIRT3 signals at least partially, and the TLR4 mediates the early-stage recruitment of transplanted EPCs in pulmonary arteriolar inflammation injury; however, SIRT3 has more contribution to the survival of incorporated EPCs and ameliorated arteriolar remodeling in lung vascular tissue. The study provides insights for the critical role of TLR4/SIRT3 in LPS-induced oxidative stress and mitochondrial disorder in EPCs &lt;em&gt;in vitro&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt;. The TLR4/SIRT3 signaling is important for EPCs resistance against inflammation and oxidative stress and may represent a new manipulating target for developing efficient cell therapy strategy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The protective effects of Mai-Luo-Ning injection against LPS-induced acute lung injury via the TLR4/NF-κB signalling pathway</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35793597/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35793597/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Acute lung injury (ALI) is a severe inflammatory disorder associated with high morbidity and mortality rates. Various therapeutic strategies for ALI have been proposed over the last few decades; however, the treatment options remain limited. Mai-Luo-Ning injection (MLN), a traditional Chinese medical formulation, has been extensively used for the treatment of respiratory diseases. Nevertheless, the effects of MLN on ALI remain unclear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Purpose:&lt;/em&gt; This study aimed to investigate the protective and therapeutic effects of MLN on lipopolysaccharide-induced ALI mouse models and RAW 264.7 cells, and further explore the underlying mechanism of these effects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; The therapeutic activity of MLN was evaluated using an &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt; ALI model and an in vitro model of RAW 264.7 macrophages. UHPLC-ESI-Q-TOF-MS/MS was used to investigate the chemical constituents of the MLN. The material basis and potential protective mechanism of MLN were analyzed using network pharmacology. The roles of MLN in inhibiting the Toll-like receptor 4 (TLR4)/ nuclear factor kappa B (NF-κB) signalling pathway were investigated via western blotting, real-time polymerase chain reaction, enzyme-linked immunosorbent assay, and immunofluorescence staining.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;In vivo&lt;/em&gt; experiments demonstrated that MLN ameliorated LPS-induced histological changes in lung tissues and reduced lung wet/dry weight ratio, total protein concentration in the bronchoalveolar lavage fluid and myeloperoxidase activity. Furthermore, MLN downregulated the &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt; and in vitro expression of pro-inflammatory cytokines such as tumour necrosis factor-alpha, interleukin-6, and interleukin-1β. Network pharmacology analysis revealed that MLN could act synergistically through multiple targets and pathways and exert a protective effect, possibly through inhibiting TLR4/ NF-κB signalling pathways. Western blotting and immunofluorescence experiments further confirmed that MLN could regulate the expression of TLR4, MyD88, phospho-IκB-α, and phospho-NF-κB p65 in the TLR4/NF-κB signalling pathway and decrease the translocation of phospho-NF-κB p65 into the nucleus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/em&gt; This study suggests that MLN has a potential protective effect against LPS-induced ALI, which might be associated with the inhibition of the TLR4/NF-κB signalling pathway. Therefore, MLN is worthy of further investigation as a potential candidate for the treatment of ALI in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ACT001 suppressing M1 polarization against inflammation via NF-κB and STAT1 signaling pathways alleviates acute lung injury in mice</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35728304/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35728304/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ACT001 conferred potent protection against LPS-induced acute lung injury in mice.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ACT001 inhibited M1 macrophage polarization, limiting its pro-inflammatory activity.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ACT001 suppressed NF-κB and STAT1 signaling by targeting IKKβ as well as STAT1.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ACT001 has been shown to exhibit excellent antitumor and anti-fibrosis activities. However, the role of ACT001 in acute lung injury (ALI) and the underlying mechanism remains largely unclear. The present study aimed to investigate the protective effects of ACT001 on ALI and explore the potential mechanisms. Herein, we firstly established the ALI mouse model induced by intratracheal instillation of lipopolysaccharide (LPS). ACT001 treatment significantly alleviated histopathological changes of lung tissues with lower infiltration of pulmonary M1 macrophages in ALI mice. Then, we performed in vitro experiment and found that ACT001 treatment effectively inhibited the M1 phenotype of RAW264.7 and THP-1.. Next, we performed pull-down and mass spectrometry analysis to screen the interacting proteins of ACT001, identifying IKKβ and STAT1 as the critical target proteins of ACT001. And ACT001 treatment significantly suppressed the NF-κB and STAT1 pathways, thereby inhibiting the M1 polarization against inflammation in vivo and in vitro. Finally, we used IMD 0354 (IMD) and Fludarabine (Flud) to specifically block the activity of IKKβ and STAT1, and stimulated macrophages through IKKβ and STAT1 overexpression. Our data clearly showed that ACT001-induced decrease of the M1 polarization was blocked by IMD and Flud treatment, and reversed by IKKβ and STAT1 overexpression in RAW264.7 cells. In conclusion, we discovered that ACT001 significantly alleviates inflammation and limits M1 phenotype of pulmonary macrophages via suppressing NF-κB and STAT1 signaling pathways, providing new insights for the development of drugs to treat ALI/ARDS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Long non-coding RNA SNHG5 mediates periodontal inflammation through the NF-κB signalling pathway</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35713268/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35713268/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Aim:&lt;/em&gt; We investigated the role of long non-coding RNAs and small nucleolar RNA host gene 5 (SNHG5) in the pathogenesis of periodontitis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Materials and methods:&lt;/em&gt; A ligature-induced periodontitis mouse model was established, and gingival tissues were collected from patients with periodontitis and healthy controls. Inflammatory cytokines were detected using quantitative reverse transcription-polymerase chain reaction and western blotting analyses. Direct interactions between SNHG5 and p65 were detected by RNA pull-down and RNA immunoprecipitation assays. Micro-computed tomography, haematoxylin and eosin staining, and immunohistochemical staining were used to measure periodontal bone loss.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; SNHG5 expression was down-regulated in human and mouse periodontal tissues compared to that in the healthy controls. In vitro experiments demonstrated that SNHG5 significantly ameliorated tumour necrosis factor α-induced inflammation. Mechanistically, SNHG5 directly binds to the nuclear factor-kappa B (NF-κB) p65 subunit and inhibits its translocation, thereby suppressing the NF-κB signalling pathway activation and reducing the nucleotide-binding oligomerization domain-like receptor family pyrin domain-containing three inflammasome expression. Locally injecting si-SNHG5 aggravated the periodontal destruction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/em&gt; This study revealed that SNHG5 mediates periodontal inflammation through the NF-κB signalling pathway, providing a potential therapeutic target for periodontitis treatment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gut dysbiosis promotes prostate cancer progression and docetaxel resistance via activating NF-κB-IL6-STAT3 axis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35710492/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35710492/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; The gut microbiota is reportedly involved in the progression and chemoresistance of various human malignancies. However, the underlying mechanisms behind how it exerts some effect on prostate cancer, as an extra-intestinal tumor, in a contact-independent way remain elusive and deserve exploration. Antibiotic exposure, one of the various factors affecting the gut microbiota community and capable of causing gut dysbiosis, is associated with multiple disorders. This study aims to preliminarily clarify the link between gut dysbiosis and prostate cancer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; First, we discovered that perturbing the gut microbiota by consuming broad-spectrum antibiotics in water promoted the growth of subcutaneous and orthotopic tumors in mice. Fecal microbiota transplantation could transmit the effect of antibiotic exposure on tumor growth. Then, 16S rRNA sequencing for mouse feces indicated that the relative abundance of Proteobacteria was significantly higher after antibiotic exposure. Meanwhile, intratumoral lipopolysaccharide (LPS) profoundly increased under the elevation of gut permeability. Both in vivo and in vitro experiments revealed that the NF-κB-IL6-STAT3 axis activated by intratumoral LPS facilitated prostate cancer proliferation and docetaxel chemoresistance. Finally, 16S rRNA sequencing of patients&amp;rsquo; fecal samples revealed that Proteobacteria was enriched in patients with metastatic prostate cancer and was positively correlated with plasma IL6 level, regional lymph node metastasis status, and distant metastasis status. The receiver operating characteristic (ROC) curves showed that the relative abundance of Proteobacteria had better performance than the prostate-specific antigen (PSA) level in predicting the probability of distant metastasis in prostate cancer (area under the ROC curve, 0.860; p &amp;lt; 0.001).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/em&gt; Collectively, this research demonstrated that gut dysbiosis, characterized by the enrichment of Proteobacteria due to antibiotic exposure, resulted in the elevation of gut permeability and intratumoral LPS, promoting the development of prostate cancer via the NF-κB-IL6-STAT3 axis in mice. Considering findings from human patients, Proteobacteria might act as an intestinal biomarker for progressive prostate cancer. Video Abstract.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brevilin A Ameliorates Acute Lung Injury and Inflammation Through Inhibition of NF-κB Signaling via Targeting IKKα/β</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35774606/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35774606/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acute lung injury (ALI) is life-threatening disease characterized by uncontrolled inflammatory response. IKKα/β, the key kinases in the activation of NF-κB pathway, are implicated in inflammatory pulmonary injury, and represent attractive targets for ALI therapy. Brevilin A (BVA) is a sesquiterpene lactone from Centipeda minima, a Chinese herb used to treat inflammatory diseases. This study aims to investigate the inhibition of BVA on ALI, with focus on clarifying the molecular mechanisms involved in BVA-mediated anti-inflammatory activity in macrophages. Briefly, BVA significantly inhibited the production of NO and PGE2 by suppressing iNOS and COX2 expression, and suppressed the mRNA expression of IL-1β, IL-6, and TNFα in LPS/IFNγ-stimulated RAW264.7 macrophages. The anti-inflammatory activity of BVA was further confirmed in LPS/IFNγ-stimulated BMDMs and TNFα/IFNγ-exposed RAW264.7 cells. &lt;em&gt;In vivo&lt;/em&gt;, BVA effectively attenuated LPS-induced lung damage, inflammatory infiltration, and production of pro-inflammatory cytokines, including MPO, IL-1β, IL-6, TNFα, and PGE2. Mechanistically, BVA could covalently bind to the cysteine 114 of IKKα/β, and effectively inhibiting the activity and function of IKKα/β, thereby resulting in the suppression of phosphorylation and degradation of IκBα and the subsequent activation of NF-κB signaling. Furthermore, pretreatment of DTT, a thiol ligand donor, significantly abolished BVA-mediated effects in LPS/IFNγ-stimulated RAW264.7 cells, suggesting the crucial role of the electrophilic α, β-unsaturated ketone of BVA on its anti-inflammatory activity. These results suggest that BVA ameliorates ALI through inhibition of NF-κB signaling via covalently targeting IKKα/β, raising the possibility that BVA could be effective in the treatment of ALI and other diseases harboring aberrant NF-κB signaling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RP105 protects against ischemic and septic acute kidney injury via suppressing TLR4/NF-κB signaling pathways</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35696803/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35696803/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RP105 is a member of the TLR family and its expression plays a role in cardiovascular disease but the therapeutic impact on acute kidney injury remained unclear.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We have uncovered evidence that RP105 expression in proximal tubular cells plays a kidney protective role during ischemic and septic acute kidney injury.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RP105 reduces tubular cell death, NF-κB activation and inflammatory response during AKI with a mechanism involving interaction with TLR4.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This finding may have clinical translation as kidney protection and inflammation regulation could be achieved through RP105 gene therapy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acute kidney injury (AKI) is a critical and severe clinical disease caused by a variety of factors. Toll-like receptors (TLRs) play a crucial role in pathogenesis of AKI. Radioprotective 105 kDa protein (RP105) is a member of the TLR family, but the role of RP105 in AKI is unknown. In this study, we overexpressed RP105 in renal tissue and cultured proximal tubular cells in which we then induced ischemic and septic AKI. Renal structure injuries were examined by hematoxylin eosin staining, while renal function was assessed by measuring serum blood urea nitrogen (BUN) and creatinine (SCr) levels. The TUNEL assay was used to detect apoptosis induced changes in the expression of RP105, and nuclear factor κB (NF-κB) in renal tissue detected by Western blot. Inflammatory cytokines including iNOS, IL-1β, IL-6, and TNF-α were detected by quantitative real-time PCR. The inflammatory indicators, F4/80 and MPO, were identified by IHC staining. The results showed that expression of the TLR4/NF-kB signaling pathway was enhanced in renal ischemia-reperfusion injury and septic renal injury, and that overexpression of RP105 in renal tissue alleviated ischemic and septic AKI. Moreover, RP105 gene delivery was associated with reduced renal inflammatory cells infiltration and inflammatory cytokines after AKI. RP105 overexpression also inhibited nuclear translocation of NF-κB after AKI in both in vitro and in vivo, and blunted the interaction between Myeloid Differentiation factor 2 (MD2) and TLR4. These results indicated that RP105 protected against renal ischemic and septic AKI injury by suppressing inflammatory responses mediated by TLR4 signaling pathways. This study suggests that the anti-inflammatory roles of RP105 have potential for preventing and treating renal ischemic and septic AKI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CREB1 contributes colorectal cancer cell plasticity by regulating lncRNA CCAT1 and NF-κB pathways</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35696016/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35696016/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The CREB1 gene encodes an exceptionally pleiotropic transcription factor that frequently dysregulated in human cancers. CREB1 can regulate tumor cell status of proliferation and/or migration; however, the molecular basis for this switch involvement in cell plasticity has not fully been understood yet. Here, we first show that knocking out CREB1 triggers a remarkable effect of epithelial-mesenchymal transition (EMT) and leads to the occurrence of inhibited proliferation and enhanced motility in HCT116 colorectal cancer cells. By monitoring 45 cellular signaling pathway activities, we find that multiple growth-related pathways decline significantly while inflammatory pathways including NF-κB are largely upregulated in comparing between the CREB1 wild-type and knocked out cells. Mechanistically, cells with CREB1 knocked out show downregulation of MYC as a result of impaired CREB1-dependent transcription of the oncogenic lncRNA CCAT1. Interestingly, the unbalanced competition between the coactivator CBP/p300 for CREB1 and p65 leads to the activation of the NF-κB pathway in cells with CREB1 disrupted, which induces an obvious EMT phenotype of the cancer cells. Taken together, these studies identify previously unknown mechanisms of CREB1 in CRC cell plasticity via regulating lncRNA CCAT1 and NF-κB pathways, providing a critical insight into a combined strategy for CREB1-targeted tumor therapies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TLR7 Mediates Acute Respiratory Distress Syndrome in Sepsis by Sensing Extracellular miR-146a</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35679261/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35679261/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TLR7 (Toll-like receptor 7), the sensor for single-stranded RNA, contributes to systemic inflammation and mortality in murine polymicrobial sepsis. Recent studies show that extracellular miR-146a-5p serves as a TLR7 ligand and plays an important role in regulating host innate immunity. However, the role of miR-146a-5p and TLR7 signaling in pulmonary inflammation, endothelial activation, and sepsis-associated acute respiratory distress syndrome remains unclear. Here, we show that intratracheal administration of exogenous miR-146a-5p in mice evokes lung inflammation, activates endothelium, and increases endothelial permeability via TLR7-dependent mechanisms. TLR7 deficiency attenuates pulmonary barrier dysfunction and reduces lung inflammatory response in a murine sepsis model. Moreover, the impact of miR-146a-5p-TLR7 signaling on endothelial activation appears to be a secondary effect because TLR7 is undetectable in the human pulmonary artery and microvascular endothelial cells (ECs), which show no response to direct miR-146a-5p treatment &lt;em&gt;in vitro&lt;/em&gt;. Both conditioned media of miR-146a-5p-treated macrophages (Mϕ) and septic sera of wild-type mice induce a marked EC barrier disruption &lt;em&gt;in vitro&lt;/em&gt;, whereas Mϕ conditioned media or septic sera of &lt;em&gt;TLR7&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; mice do not exhibit such effect. Cytokine array and pathway enrichment analysis of the Mϕ conditioned media and septic sera identify TNFα (tumor necrosis factor α) as the main downstream effector of miR-146a-5p-TLR7 signaling responsible for the EC barrier dysfunction, which is further supported by neutralizing anti-TNFα antibody intervention. Together, these data demonstrate that TLR7 activation elicits pulmonary inflammation and endothelial barrier disruption by sensing extracellular miR-146a-5p and contributes to sepsis-associated acute respiratory distress syndrome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ginkgolide C Alleviates Acute Lung Injury Caused by Paraquat Poisoning via Regulating the Nrf2 and NF- κ B Signaling Pathways</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35707280/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35707280/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paraquat (PQ), a highly toxic herbicide and primary attack for lung, results in severe acute lung injury (ALI) appeared as evident oxidative stress, inflammation, and apoptosis. Increasing evidence elucidates that nuclear factor erythroid-2-related factor 2 (Nrf2) and its associated nuclear factor-κB (NF-κB) exhibit many merits for protection of ALI by coordinating a fine-turned response to oxidative stress, inflammation, and apoptosis. Ginkgolide C (GC) has been reported to be a safe and potent therapeutic agent against ALI. However, whether GC could protect ALI induced by PQ poisoning and the possible underlining mechanisms have remained not to be fully elucidated. A rat model of ALI and a model of acute type II alveolar epithelial cell (RLE-6TN) injury constructed by exposure to PQ were applied to discuss the protective effect of GC. Furthermore, Nrf2 gene silencing RLE-6TN cells were used to discuss the exact mechanism. We confirmed that GC significantly ameliorated the histopathological damages, ultrastructural changes, lung injury score, W/D ratio, and Hyp activity of lung tissue and inhibited polymorphonuclear neutrophil (PMN) infiltration after PQ poisoning. Further results revealed that GC remarkably activated Nrf2-based cytoprotective system and inhibited NF-κB-induced inflammatory injury as well as apoptosis. Taken together, we concluded that GC preserved protection of PQ-induced ALI via the Nrf2-NF-κB dependent signal pathway, which may provide us novel insights into the treatment strategies for PQ poisoning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Angiotensin 1-7 mitigates rhabdomyolysis induced renal injury in rats via modulation of TLR-4/NF-kB/iNOS and Nrf-2/heme‑oxygenase-1 signaling pathways</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35654118/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35654118/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RM induced kidney injury may be linked to the depletion of the ACE-2 and Ang1–7.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The ACE-2/Ang1–7/MasR axis may serve as a novel therapeutic option in RM-induced AKI.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;TLR-4/NF-kB/iNOS pathway may be involved in the renoprotective effect of Ang1–7.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Aims:&lt;/em&gt; Rhabdomyolysis (RM) is a critical condition with a high mortality rate, but effective management is still deficient. Till date, there are no studies that have addressed the effect of angiotensin 1-7 in this condition, hence, the rationale of this study was to evaluate the potential protective effect of Angiotensin 1-7 (Ang1-7), on rhabdomyolysis (RM) induced kidney injury in rats and detecting the underlying mechanistic insights.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Main methods:&lt;/em&gt; Forty adult male albino rats were divided into groups; the control group, RM group, RM+Ang1-7 group, and RM+Ang1-7+ A779 group. Sera and urine samples were collected for analysis of renal and muscle injury markers. Kidney tissues were taken for estimation of oxidative, inflammatory, and apoptotic markers as well as angiotensin-II (Ang II) and Ang1-7. Renal histology and expression of inducible nitric oxide synthase-1 (iNOS), real-time PCR for angiotensin-converting enzyme-2 (ACE-2), nuclear erythroid factor-2 (Nrf-2), Toll like receptor 4 (TLR-4) and NF-kB in kidney tissues were also measured.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Key findings:&lt;/em&gt; Induction of RM caused renal oxidative stress injury, inflammation, apoptosis and marked deterioration in kidney functions as well as reduction of Ang1-7 and raised Angiotensin-II level in kidney tissues. Administration of Ang1-7 to the RM group reversed all the affected parameters which were blocked by A779 administration (Mas receptor blocker).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Significance:&lt;/em&gt; We concluded that Ang1-7 could be a potential therapeutic agent that could mitigate RM-induced renal injury. The underlying mechanisms may involve Stimulation of the ACE-2/Ang1-7/MasR axis and modulation of TLR-4/NF-kB/iNOS and Nrf-2/heme‑oxygenase -1 pathways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hydnocarpin D attenuates lipopolysaccharide-induced acute lung injury via MAPK/NF-κB and Keap1/Nrf2/HO-1 pathway</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35537248/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35537248/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Acute lung injury (ALI) is a complex pulmonary destructive disease with limited therapeutic approaches. Hydnocarpin D (HD) is a flavonolignan isolated from Hydnocarpus wightiana which possesses antioxidant and anti-inflammatory properties. However, whether HD has beneficial effects on ALI as well as its underlying mechanism remains to be elucidated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Purpose:&lt;/em&gt; This study evaluated the protective effect of HD in ALI and the underlying molecular mechanisms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;In vivo&lt;/em&gt;, the role of HD on lipopolysaccharide (LPS)-induced ALI in mice was tested by determination of neutrophil infiltration, levels of inflammatory cytokines, lung histology and edema, vascular and alveolar barrier disruption. In vitro, murine macrophage RAW 264.7 cells were used to investigate the molecular mechanisms RESULTS: Administration of HD protected mice against LPS-induced ALI, including ameliorating the histological alterations in the lung tissues, and decreasing lung edema, protein content of bronchoalveolar lavage fluid, infiltration of inflammatory cell and secretion of cytokines. Moreover, HD blocked the phosphorylation of TLR-4, NF-κB, and ERK in LPS-induced lung injury. &lt;em&gt;In vitro&lt;/em&gt;, HD inhibited LPS-induced oxidative stress and inflammation in RAW 264.7 cells, which largely depend upon the upregulation of antioxidant defensive Nrf2 pathway, thereby suppressing LPS-activated proinflammatory mediator secretion, NLRP3 inflammasome, and MAPK/NF-κB signaling pathway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/em&gt; HD attenuates oxidative stress and inflammation against LPS-induced ALI via MAPK/NF-κB and Keap1/Nrf2/HO-1 pathway, and is a promising novel therapeutic candidate for ALI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TLR2/caspase-5/Panx1 pathway mediates necrosis-induced NLRP3 inflammasome activation in macrophages during acute kidney injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35473933/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35473933/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acute kidney injury (AKI) is characterized by necroinflammation formed by necrotic tubular epithelial cells (TECs) and interstitial inflammation. In necroinflammation, macrophages are key inflammatory cells and can be activated and polarized into proinflammatory macrophages. Membranous Toll-like receptors (TLRs) can cooperate with intracellular NOD-like receptor protein 3 (NLRP3) to recognize danger signals from necrotic TECs and activate proinflammatory macrophages by assembling NLRP3 inflammasome. However, the cooperation between TLRs and NLRP3 is still unclear. Using conditioned medium from necrotic TECs, we confirmed that necrotic TECs could release danger signals to activate NLRP3 inflammasome in macrophages. We further identified that necrotic TECs-induced NLRP3 inflammasome activation was dependent on ATP secretion via Pannexin-1 (Panx1) channel in macrophages. Next, we verified that TLR2 was required for the activation of Panx1 and NLRP3 in macrophages. Mechanistically, we indicated that caspase-5 mediated TLR2-induced Panx1 activation. In addition, we showed that necrotic TECs-induced activation of TLR2/caspase-5/Panx1 axis could be decreased in macrophages when TECs was protected by N-acetylcysteine (NAC). Overall, we demonstrate that danger signals from necrotic TECs could activate NLRP3 inflammasome in macrophages via TLR2/caspase-5/Panx1 axis during AKI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vincamine, an active constituent of Vinca rosea ameliorates experimentally induced acute lung injury in Swiss albino mice through modulation of Nrf-2/NF-κB signaling cascade</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35453074/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35453074/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Acute respiratory distress syndrome (ARDS) is a leading pulmonary inflammatory disorder.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vincamine is a novel phytochemical with promising anti-inflammatory properties.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vincamine exerted potent suppression of inflammation by reducing the expression of proinflammatory cytokines.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vincamine reduced the release of nitrite and TNF-α from lipopolysaccharide stimulated Raw 264.7 macrophages.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vincamine reduced the expression of NF-κB, TNF-α and COX-2 while increased the expression of Nrf-2.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;These findings are of potential relevance for COVID-19 related lung injury management.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acute lung injury (ALI) or acute respiratory distress syndrome (ARDS) is one of the leading pulmonary inflammatory disorders causing significant morbidity and mortality. Vincamine is a novel phytochemical with promising anti-inflammatory properties. In the current work, the protective effect of vincamine was studied in vitro (Raw 264.7 macrophages) and in vivo against lipopolysaccharide (LPS) induced ALI in Swiss albino mice. Vincamine significantly reduced nitrite and TNF-α release from the LPS stimulated macrophages and increased the levels of IL-10, indicating potent anti-inflammatory effects. It was observed that vincamine at the dose of 40 mg/kg, significantly reduced LPS induced inflammatory cell count in blood and in bronchoalveolar lavage (BAL) fluid. Further, vincamine exerted potent suppression of inflammation by reducing the expression of proinflammatory cytokines, while significantly increased (&lt;em&gt;p&lt;/em&gt; &amp;lt; 0.001) the expression of anti-inflammatory cytokine (IL-10 and IL-22). Interestingly, histological changes were reversed in vincamine treated groups in a dose-dependent manner. Immunohistochemical analysis revealed significantly enhanced expression of NF-κB, TNF-α and COX-2 while reduced expression of Nrf-2 in disease control group, which were significantly (&lt;em&gt;p&lt;/em&gt; &amp;lt; 0.001) ameliorated by vincamine. We, to the best of our knowledge, report for the first time that vincamine possesses protective potential against LPS induced inflammation and oxidative stress, possibly by inhibiting the NF-κB cascade, while positively regulating the Nrf-2 pathway. These findings are of potential relevance for COVID-19 management concerning the fact that lung injury and ARDS are its critical features.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mesencephalic astrocyte-derived neurotrophic factor attenuates acute lung injury via inhibiting macrophages&#39; activation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35405395/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35405395/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MANF was up-regulated in inflammatory lung injury.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MANF deficiency in macrophages induced lung inflammation and aggravated LPS-induced lung injury in mice.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Recombinant human MANF attenuated LPS-induced lung injury in mice.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MANF deficiency in macrophages promoted macrophages to M1differentiation in lung tissues of ALI mice.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Recombinant human MANF restricted macrophages to M1 differentiation in lung tissues of ALI mice.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acute lung injury (ALI) is an urgent respiratory disease without effective treatment. Mesencephalic astrocyte-derived neurotrophic factor (MANF)has been demonstrated to play a suppressive role in some inflammatory conditions. However, the effect of MANF on ALI has not yet been reported. In this study, we collected bronchoalveolar lavage fluid (BALF) from the patients with or without pulmonary inflammation, and used lipopolysaccharide (LPS) to induce mice ALI model. Mono-macrophage-specific MANF knockout (MKO) mice were constructed and recombinant human MANF protein was used to ALI mice. We found that the endogenous MANF protein in both human BALF and mice lung tissues was increased in inflammatory conditions. MANF level in the macrophages of inflammatory lung was higher than that in normal controls in both human and mice. MANF deficiency in macrophages induced lung inflammation and aggravated LPS-induced lung injury. MANF lowered LPS-induced lung injury, inhibited macrophage polarization to M1 functional type. Meanwhile, MANF inhibited-LPS induced activation of NF-κB signal pathway by down regulating phosphorylated p65in lung tissue and macrophages. These results indicate that MANF acts as a suppressor in ALI via negatively regulating NF-κB activation and macrophages polarization, which may be a novel potential target and shed light on ALI therapy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alkyl organophosphate flame retardants (OPFRs) induce lung inflammation and aggravate OVA-simulated asthmatic response via the NF-кB signaling pathway</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35358787/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35358787/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;TnBP and TBOEP caused pulmonary damages by inflammation and oxidative stress.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Fkbp5&lt;/em&gt;/&lt;em&gt;Nos3&lt;/em&gt;/MAPK/NF-κB signal pathway was upregulated when exposing to TnBP and TBOEP.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;TnBP aggravated OVA induced asthmatic inflammatory response with overexpression of IgE.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;TnBP facilitated OVA-induced asthma by upregulating PI3K/Akt/NF-кB signaling pathway.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alkyl organophosphate flame retardants (OPFRs), tri-n-butyl phosphate (TnBP) and tris(2-butoxyethyl) phosphate (TBOEP), are ubiquitously detected in indoor and outdoor environments and their inhalation may result in lung damage. This study examined pulmonary toxicity after exposure to TnBP or TBOEP and investigated aggravation of inflammation and immunoreaction by TnBP in an ovalbumin (OVA)-induced mice model. Transcriptomics were used to further reveal the underlying mechanism. Exposure to TnBP or TBOEP resulted in pathological damage, including edema and thickened alveolar septum. In comparison with the control, enhanced levels of superoxide dismutase (SOD) (&lt;em&gt;p&lt;/em&gt; &amp;lt; 0.01 in TnBP (High) group and &lt;em&gt;p&lt;/em&gt; &amp;lt; 0.05 in TBOEP (High) group), glutathione peroxidase (GSH-px) (&lt;em&gt;p&lt;/em&gt; &amp;lt; 0.05), malondialdehyde (MDA) (&lt;em&gt;p&lt;/em&gt; &amp;lt; 0.01), and cytokines under a dose-dependent relationship were noted, and the expression of the Fkbp5/Nos3/MAPK/NF-кB signaling pathway (&lt;em&gt;p&lt;/em&gt; &amp;lt; 0.01) was upregulated in the TnBP and TBOEP groups. Moreover, the combined exposure of TnBP and OVA exacerbated the allergic inflammatory response, including airway hyperresponsiveness, leukocytosis, cellular exudation and infiltration, secretion of inflammatory mediators, and higher expression of IgE (&lt;em&gt;p&lt;/em&gt; &amp;lt; 0.01). Transcriptomics results demonstrated that the PI3K/Akt/NF-кB signal pathway was involved in TnBP-aggravated asthmatic mice. Exposure to TnBP or TBOEP resulted in oxidative damage and leukocyte-induced lung injury. TnBP can further facilitate OVA-induced asthma through an inflammatory response. This study is the first to reveal the pulmonary toxicity and potential mechanism induced by OPFRs through an in-vivo model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>lncRNA MEG3 restrained the M1 polarization of microglia in acute spinal cord injury through the HuR/A20/NF-κB axis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35338543/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35338543/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The M1 polarization of microglia and neuroinflammation restrict the treatment of acute spinal cord injury (ASCI), and long non-coding ribonucleic acid (lncRNA) maternally expressed gene 3 (MEG3) expression is lessened in ASCI. However, the function and mechanism of lncRNA MEG3 in the M1 polarization of microglia and neuroinflammation in ASCI are unclear. The expressions of lncRNA MEG3 in ASCI mouse spinal cord tissues and lipopolysaccharide (LPS)-treated primary microglia and BV2 cells were quantified through a quantitative real-time polymerase chain reaction. In-vitro assays were conducted to explore the function of lncRNA MEG3 in the M1 polarization of microglia and neuroinflammation in ASCI. RNA degradation, RNA immunoprecipitation, RNA pull-down, cycloheximide-chase, and ubiquitination analyses were carried out to probe into the mechanism of lncRNA MEG3 in the M1 polarization of microglia and neuroinflammation in ASCI. The lncRNA MEG3 expression was lessened in the ASCI mouse spinal cord tissues and LPS-treated primary microglia and BV2 cells, and the overexpression of lncRNA MEG3 restrained the M1 polarization of microglia and the neuroinflammation by regulating the NF-κB signaling pathway. For the investigation of the potential mechanism of such, the overexpression of lncRNA MEG3 restrained the M1 polarization of microglia through the HuR/A20/NF-κB axis and boosted the motor function recovery and neuroinflammation relief in the mice with SCI. The overexpression of lncRNA MEG3 restrained the M1 polarization of microglia through the HuR/A20/NF-κB axis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Glycyrrhizin alleviates sepsis-induced acute respiratory distress syndrome via suppressing of HMGB1/TLR9 pathways and neutrophils extracellular traps formation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35354111/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35354111/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GL attenuated inflammatory lung injury.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GL reduced the NETs formation in lung tissues.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GL inhibited the HMGB1 / TLR9 pathway.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GL improved lung function in mice with sepsis-induced ARDS.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Neutrophil extracellular traps (NETs) are involved in the development of sepsis-induced acute respiratory distress syndrome (ARDS). Glycyrrhizin (GL), the main active ingredient of the traditional Chinese medicine Glycyrrhiza glabra, has anti-inflammatory, anti-viral, and immunomodulatory effects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Objective:&lt;/em&gt; The study aims to explore the efficacy and potential mechanism of GL on sepsis-induced ARDS in mice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Materials and methods:&lt;/em&gt; Mice were randomly divided into 3 groups: Control, CLP, and GL + CLP. Mice sepsis ARDS model was induced by cecal ligation and puncture (CLP) followed by intraperitoneal GL treatment. Then, the 7-day survival rate of mice was recorded. The lung function of mice was determined by whole-body plethysmography. Lung pathology and scores were observed by hematoxylin-eosin staining. The wet/dry ratio (W/D) of the lung was measured by weighing method. The protein concentration in bronchoalveolar lavage fluid (BALF) was measured by the BCA method. NETs formation in lung tissue was detected by immunofluorescence. Furthermore, HMGB1、TLR9、MyD88 and IL6 expression in lung tissue were detected by western blot and by quantitative real-time PCR, respectively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; The results showed that GL improved the survival rate, attenuated lung tissue injury and reduced the expression of inflammatory factors in mice with CLP-induced sepsis. Meanwhile, we confirmed that GL could inhibit TLR9 / MyD88 activation from reducing NETs formation by decreasing HMGB1 expression. The formation of NETs is regulated by HMGB1/TLR9/MyD88. In addition, GL improved lung function in mice with sepsis-induced ARDS. Lung function suggested that GL increased alveolar ventilation, alleviated ventilator fatigue and reduced airway resistance in mice with ARDS induced by sepsis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; GL ameliorated sepsis-induced ARDS and reduced the NETs formation in lung tissues, which may be associated with the inhibition of the HMGB1/TLR9 pathway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Green tea peptides ameliorate diabetic nephropathy by inhibiting the TGF-β/Smad signaling pathway in mice</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35234233/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35234233/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Diabetic nephropathy (DN) is the most important cause of middle and late-stage chronic kidney disease. Green tea polypeptides are extracted from tea pomace, and exhibit various pharmacological effects. In this study, we analyzed the reno-protective effects of green tea peptides in diabetic db/db mice, and explored the underlying mechanisms. Peptide treatment for 5 weeks significantly reduced the blood glucose levels and other indices of diabetes, and alleviated renal injury measured in terms of blood creatinine, urea nitrogen and urinary albumin/urinary creatinine levels. Mechanistically, the green tea peptides downregulated p-Smad2/3, α-SMA, ZO-1 and vimentin proteins in the kidney tissues, and elevated Smad7. Thus, green tea peptides inhibited the deposition of ECM proteins by suppressing excessive activation of the TGF-β/Smad signaling pathway and reducing fibronectin levels. On the other hand, tea peptides ameliorated renal injury by inhibiting the production of inflammatory factors (iNOS and TNF-α) by suppressing the NF-κB signaling pathway. In addition, we confirmed the inhibitory effect of green tea peptides on the TGF-β/Smad signaling pathway in TGF-β1-stimulated HK-2 cells. Therefore, tea peptides can be considered as an effective candidate for alleviating DN.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Renoprotective effect of vinpocetine against ischemia/reperfusion injury: Modulation of NADPH oxidase/Nrf2, IKKβ/NF-κB p65, and cleaved caspase-3 expressions</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35315168/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35315168/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ischemia/reperfusion injury (IRI) during kidney transplantation is a serious clinical problem with a high mortality rate and a lack of therapy. Therefore, there is a need to improve the ability of the kidney to tolerate IRI during transplantation. This study aimed to investigate the possible protective effect of vinpocetine; a derivative of vincamine alkaloid; against renal IRI in rats with the elucidation of the involved mechanisms. Vinpocetine (25 mg/kg; i.p.) was administered for 10 successive days before the induction of ischemia by bilateral clamping of both renal pedicles for 45 min followed by 24 h of reperfusion. Blood and renal tissue samples were then collected for biochemical, molecular, and histopathological investigations. Vinpocetine significantly reduced serum creatinine and blood urea nitrogen levels in rats subjected to IRI. It also reduced mRNA expression of NADPH oxidase and renal content of malondialdehyde, while enhanced Nrf2 protein expression and renal content of reduced glutathione. The suppression of the provoked inflammatory response was evident by the downregulation of IKKβ and NF-κB p65 protein expressions, as well as their downstream inflammatory markers; tumor necrosis factor-α, interleukin-6, and myeloperoxidase. In addition, vinpocetine reduced protein expression of the apoptotic executioner cleaved caspase-3. These nephroprotective effects were confirmed by the improvement in histopathological features. Collectively, the protective effect of vinpocetine against IRI could be attributed to modulation of NADPH oxidase/Nrf2, IKKβ/NF-κB p65, and cleaved caspase-3 expressions. Thus, vinpocetine could improve oxidant/antioxidant balance, suppress triggered inflammatory response, and promote renal cell survival after IRI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Combined Transcriptomic and Proteomic Approach to Reveal the Effect of Mogroside V on OVA-Induced Pulmonary Inflammation in Mice</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35371026/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35371026/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mogroside V is a bioactive ingredient extracted from the natural food Siraitia grosvenorii which possesses functions that stimulate lung humidification and cough relief activities, but its underlying mechanisms were rarely studied. To estimate its potential protective effect on ovalbumin (OVA)-induced pulmonary inflammation and understand its system-wide mechanism, integrated omics was applied in this study. Mogroside V effectively reduced the levels of IgE, TNF-α, and IL-5 in OVA-induced mice. The results of RNA-seq and data-independent acquisition proteomics approach revealed that 944 genes and 341 proteins were differentially expressed in the normal control group (NC) and ovalbumin-induced control group (OC) and 449 genes and 259 proteins were differentially expressed between the OC and the group treated with 50 mg/kg mogroside V (MV). After a combined analysis of the transcriptome and the proteome, 93 major pathways were screened, and we discovered that mogroside V exerts an anti-inflammation effect in the lung via NF-κB and JAK-STAT, both of which are among the signaling pathways mentioned above. In addition, we found that the key regulatory molecules (Igha, Ighg1, NF-κB, Jak1, and Stat1) in the two pathways were activated in inflammation and inhibited by mogroside V. Thus, mogroside V may be the main bioactivity component in S. grosvenorii that exerts lung humidification and cough relief effects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fengreqing Oral Liquid Exerts Anti-Inflammatory Effects by Promoting Apoptosis and Inhibiting PI3K/AKT and NF-κB Signaling Pathways</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35370749/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35370749/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fengreqing oral liquid (FOL), a Chinese patent drug frequently used in clinical practice in China, is effective in treating inflammatory diseases of the upper respiratory tract such as colds and flu. However, its anti-inflammatory effects and mechanisms remain to be elucidated. In this study, the anti-inflammatory effects of FOL and its mechanisms on PI3K/AKT and NF-κB signaling pathways in LPS-induced RAW264.7 cells were explored, as well as the regulatory effect of FOL on apoptosis. In addition, the potential of FOL for the treatment of acute lung injury was explored in LPS-induced ALI mice. The results showed that treatment with FOL significantly reduced the levels of interleukin 1β (IL-1β), interleukin 6 (IL-6), nitric oxide (NO), and tumor necrosis factor α (TNF-α) in the supernatant of LPS-induced RAW264.7 cells, and also significantly reduced the phosphorylated protein levels of PI3K and AKT in the PI3K/AKT signaling pathway and also protein levels of NF-κB p50, phosphorylated NF-κB p65, and IκBα in the NF-κB signaling pathway. In addition, the results showed that FOL induced apoptosis in LPS-induced RAW264.7 cells at the level of 80%-90%, and significantly increased the protein expression levels of the pro-apoptotic Bax and cleaved-caspase-3. In LPS-induced ALI mice, FOL administration showed inhibition of IL-1β, IL-6, and TNF-α in Bronchoalveolar lavage fluid (BALF) and decreased protein expression levels of PI3K, AKT, NF-κB p50, and NF-κB p65, and elevated protein expression levels of Bax and cleaved-caspase-3 significantly. These results suggest that FOL may exert anti-inflammatory effects by inhibiting the PI3K/AKT signaling pathway to promote apoptosis and leading to attenuated activation of the NF-κB signaling pathway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Injury-induced inflammatory signaling and hematopoiesis in Drosophila</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35286208/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35286208/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Significance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We explore mechanisms by which stress caused by acute injury affects blood cell development and inflammatory response in &lt;em&gt;Drosophila&lt;/em&gt;. Similar to their mammalian myeloid counterparts, these cells are predisposed to sense and react to sterile injury at distant sites. Upon sterile injury, a breach of epidermis sets up a reactive oxygen species-based signal that bypasses the pathogen-sensing apparatus of septic immune challenge, but merges downstream to activate Toll. A number of autonomous and nonautonomous signaling pathways follow in a sequence and are mapped temporally by the appearance of their corresponding molecular phenotypes. A cell-type that fights deposited parasitic wasp eggs appears with sterile injury without the immune challenge, perhaps in anticipation, because in nature injury is usually followed by infection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inflammatory response in &lt;em&gt;Drosophila&lt;/em&gt; to sterile (axenic) injury in embryos and adults has received some attention in recent years, and most concentrate on the events at the injury site. Here we focus on the effect sterile injury has on the hematopoietic organ, the lymph gland, and the circulating blood cells in the larva, the developmental stage at which major events of hematopoiesis are evident. In mammals, injury activates Toll-like receptor/NF-κB signaling in macrophages, which then express and secrete secondary, proinflammatory cytokines. In &lt;em&gt;Drosophila&lt;/em&gt; larvae, distal puncture injury of the body wall epidermis causes a rapid activation of Toll and Jun kinase (JNK) signaling throughout the hematopoietic system and the differentiation of a unique blood cell type, the lamellocyte. Furthermore, we find that Toll and JNK signaling are coupled in their activation. Secondary to this Toll/JNK response, a cytokine, Upd3, is induced as a Toll pathway transcriptional target, which then promotes JAK/STAT signaling within the blood cells. Toll and JAK/STAT signaling are required for the emergence of the injury-induced lamellocytes. This is akin to the derivation of specialized macrophages in mammalian systems. Upstream, at the injury site, a Duox- and peroxide-dependent signal causes the activation of the proteases Grass and SPE, needed for the activation of the Toll-ligand Spz, but microbial sensors or the proteases most closely associated with them during septic injury are not involved in the axenic inflammatory response.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TRAF6 autophagic degradation by avibirnavirus VP3 inhibits antiviral innate immunity via blocking NFKB/NF-κB activation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35266845/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35266845/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ubiquitination is an important reversible post-translational modification. Many viruses hijack the host ubiquitin system to enhance self-replication. In the present study, we found that Avibirnavirus VP3 protein was ubiquitinated during infection and supported virus replication by ubiquitination. Mass spectrometry and mutation analysis showed that VP3 was ubiquitinated at residues K73, K135, K158, K193, and K219. Virus rescue showed that ubiquitination at sites K73, K193, and K219 on VP3 could enhance the replication abilities of infectious bursal disease virus (IBDV), and that K135 was essential for virus survival. Binding of the zinc finger domain of TRAF6 (TNF receptor associated factor 6) to VP3 mediated K11- and K33-linked ubiquitination of VP3, which promoted its nuclear accumulation to facilitate virus replication. Additionally, VP3 could inhibit TRAF6-mediated NFKB/NF-κB (nuclear factor kappa B) activation and IFNB/IFN-β (interferon beta) production to evade host innate immunity by inducing TRAF6 autophagic degradation in an SQSTM1/p62 (sequestosome 1)-dependent manner. Our findings demonstrated a macroautophagic/autophagic mechanism by which Avibirnavirus protein VP3 blocked NFKB-mediated IFNB production by targeting TRAF6 during virus infection, and provided a potential drug target for virus infection control.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amelioration of Endotoxin-Induced Acute Lung Injury and Alveolar Epithelial Cells Apoptosis by Simvastatin Is Associated with Up-Regulation of Survivin/NF-kB/p65 Pathway</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35269738/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35269738/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Disruption of the alveolar-endothelial barrier caused by inflammation leads to the progression of septic acute lung injury (ALI). In the present study, we investigated the beneficial effects of simvastatin on the endotoxin lipopolysaccharide (LPS)-induced ALI and its related mechanisms. A model of ALI was induced within experimental sepsis developed by intraperitoneal injection of a single non-lethal LPS dose after short-term simvastatin pretreatment (10-40 mg/kg orally). The severity of the lung tissue inflammatory injury was expressed as pulmonary damage scores (PDS). Alveolar epithelial cell apoptosis was confirmed by TUNEL assay (DNA fragmentation) and expressed as an apoptotic index (AI), and immunohistochemically for cleaved caspase-3, cytochrome C, and anti-apoptotic Bcl-xL, an inhibitor of apoptosis, survivin, and transcriptional factor, NF-kB/p65. Severe inflammatory injury of pulmonary parenchyma (PDS 3.33 ± 0.48) was developed after the LPS challenge, whereas simvastatin significantly and dose-dependently protected lung histology after LPS (&lt;em&gt;p&lt;/em&gt; &amp;lt; 0.01). Simvastatin in a dose of 40 mg/kg showed the most significant effects in amelioration alveolar epithelial cells apoptosis, demonstrating this as a marked decrease of AI (&lt;em&gt;p&lt;/em&gt; &amp;lt; 0.01 vs. LPS), cytochrome C, and cleaved caspase-3 expression. Furthermore, simvastatin significantly enhanced the expression of Bcl-xL and survivin. Finally, the expression of survivin and its regulator NF-kB/p65 in the alveolar epithelium was in strong positive correlation across the groups. Simvastatin could play a protective role against LPS-induced ALI and apoptosis of the alveolar-endothelial barrier. Taken together, these effects were seemingly mediated by inhibition of caspase 3 and cytochrome C, a finding that might be associated with the up-regulation of cell-survival survivin/NF-kB/p65 pathway and Bcl-xL.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Piperazine ferulate attenuates gentamicin-induced acute kidney injury via the NF-κB/NLRP3 pathway</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35286937/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35286937/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Piperazine ferulate (PF) is widely used in chronic nephritis and nephrotic syndrome in clinic. PF can improve diseases related inflammation by inhibiting the activation of nuclear factor kappa-B (NF-κB) signal. Acute kidney injury (AKI) is usually associated with the occurrence and development of renal inflammation. However, the nephroprotective effect and anti-inflammatory mechanisms of PF on AKI are not clear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Purpose:&lt;/em&gt; This study aimed to investigate the nephroprotective effects of PF on gentamicin (GM) induced AKI in rats and its potential mechanisms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; Male Sprague Dawley (SD) rats were intraperitoneally injected with GM (100 mg/kg/day) with or without PF (50 and 100 mg/kg/day) for 7 consecutive days. In vitro, the NRK-52e cells were exposed to GM (7 mg/ml) with or without PF (62.5 μg/ml) treatment. The renal injury and cell damage were assessed subsequently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; Our findings showed that PF treatment can significantly improve renal function, reduce renal pathological changes, and attenuate inflammatory response in rats treated with gentamicin. Besides, PF could significantly reduce the cell damage and cellular inflammatory response. In terms of mechanisms, our study revealed that PF can evidently inhibit the activation of NF-κB and nod-like receptor family pyrin domain protein 3 (NLRP3) inflammasome. Meanwhile, it could down regulate the expressions of protein and gene of p-IKKα, p-IKKβ, p-p65, p65, p50, p105, NLRP3 and IL-1β.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/em&gt; Our findings showed that PF may improve inflammation by inhibiting the NF-κB/NLRP3 pathway, so as to attenuate AKI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ras guanine nucleotide-releasing protein-4 promotes renal inflammatory injury in type 2 diabetes mellitus</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35218794/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35218794/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Introduction:&lt;/em&gt; Ras guanine nucleotide-releasing protein-4 (RasGRP4) is an activator of Ras protein, which plays significant roles in both the inflammatory response and immune activation. This study determined the role of RasGRP4 in diabetic kidney disease (DKD) progression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; CRISPR/Cas9 technology was used to establish RasGRP4 knockout (KO) mice. Diabetes was induced by a high-fat diet combined with five consecutive daily intraperitoneal injections of streptozotocin (60 mg/kg) in C57BL/6J wild-type (WT) mice and RasGRP4 KO mice. Hematoxylin and eosin, periodic acid-Schiff, and Masson&amp;rsquo;s trichrome staining were used to observe the histology of pathological injury. Immunohistochemical staining was used to analyze inflammatory cell infiltration. Quantitative PCR and Western blotting were used to detect the expression of inflammatory mediators and the activation of signaling pathways in renal tissues. In vitro cell co-culture experiments were performed to explore the interactions between peripheral blood mononuclear cells (PBMCs) and glomerular endothelial cells (GEnCs).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; RasGRP4 KO mice developed less severe diabetic kidney injury compared to WT mice, exhibiting lower proteinuria, reduced CD3+ T lymphocyte and F4/80+ macrophage infiltration, less inflammatory mediator expression including interleukin 6, tumor necrosis alpha, intercellular adhesion molecule-1, and vascular cell adhesion molecule-1, and lower expression levels of critical signal transduction molecules in the NLR family pyrin domain-containing 3 inflammasome and mitogen-activated protein kinase (MAPK)/nuclear factor kappa B (NF-κB) signaling pathways in the diabetic kidney. In vitro experiments showed that the adhesion function of PBMCs of RasGRP4 KO mice was reduced compared to that of WT mice. Moreover, the expression of adhesion molecules and critical signal transduction molecules in the NLRP3 inflammasome and MAPK/NF-κB signaling pathways in GEnCs was stimulated by the supernatant of PBMCs, which were derived from RasGRP4 KO mice treated with high glucose and were also significantly reduced compared to those derived from WT mice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/em&gt; RasGRP4 promotes the inflammatory injury mediated by PBMCs in diabetes, probably by regulating the interaction between PBMCs and GEnCs and further activating the NLRP3 inflammasome and MAPK/NF-κB signaling pathways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quercetin-3-Rutinoside alleviates radiation-induced lung inflammation and fibrosis via regulation of NF-κB/TGF-β1 signaling</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35219007/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35219007/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Radiation exposure to lungs during nuclear catastrophes or radiotherapy poses long-term side effects and can induce pulmonary injury sufficient for causing death. The strategies for preventing or reversing radiation-induced lung injuries have not been yet developed. Quercetin-3-Rutinoside (Q-3-R), a polyphenolic bioflavonoid, has shown multifaceted pharmacological applications due to its high antioxidant and anti-inflammatory properties.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Purpose:&lt;/em&gt; In the current study, the potential of Q-3-R against radiation-induced lung pneumonitis/fibrosis and the possible underlying mechanism was investigated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Study design: To evaluate the effect of Q-3-R against lung damage, C57Bl/6 mice were administered with Q-3-R (10 mg/kg b.wt.) and irradiated with a single dose of gamma radiation (12 Gy) at thoracic region.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; 16 weeks after irradiation lung damage was seen by histopathological studies and staining for collagen deposition. Expression of Nuclear factor kappa-B (NF-κB), transforming growth factor-β1 (TGF-β1), Smad3, intercellular adhesion molecule 1 (ICAM-1), α-smooth muscle actin protein (α-SMA), Aquaporin 5 (AQP 5), Interleukins (IL-6, IL-18, IL-1β), tumor necrosis factor-α (TNF-α) and caspase-3 was evaluated by immunohistochemistry/western blot/Elisa. Reactive oxygen species (ROS)/ Nitric oxide (NO) scavenging potential of Q-3-R and inhibition of cell death in irradiated lungs were also assessed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; Mice showed signs of pneumonitis and fibrotic changes in lungs following radiation treatment. A dramatic increase in inflammatory cells and cytokines contributing to lung disease pathogenesis was observed. Furthermore, expression of NF-κB, TGF-β1, Smad3, ICAM-1, AQP5and α-SMA was found markedly up-regulated. However, pretreatment of Q-3-R significantly attenuated radiation-induced pneumonitis and fibrosis. Histological examination revealed less structural and fibrotic changes with down-regulation of AQP 5, ICAM-1, α-SMA and caspase-3 in Q-3-R pretreated irradiated groups. The formulation significantly relieved lung injury by suppressing inflammatory and pro-fibrotic cytokines such as IL-6, IL-18, IL-1β, TNF-α and TGF-β1 via inhibition of NF-κB. Q-3-R also curtailed radiation-induced ROS/NO generation and minimized DNA damage in the irradiated lungs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/em&gt; The findings from the current study clearly demonstrate that Q-3-R provides radioprotection to the lungs by regulating NF-κB/TGF-β1 signaling, scavenging free radicals, preventing perivascular infiltration and prolonged inflammatory cascade which could otherwise lead to chronic radiation fibrosis. Q-3-R can be proved as a potential therapeutic agent for alleviating radiation-induced lung injury in case of planned or unplanned radiation exposure scenario.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Effect of α-tocopherol in alleviating the lipopolysaccharide-induced acute lung injury via inhibiting nuclear factor kappa-B signaling pathways</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35112986/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35112986/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acute respiratory distress syndrome (ARDS) leads to the acute lung injury (ALI), a form of diffused alveolars injury, accompanied by severe inflammation and oxidative damage of alveolar epithelial cells. α-Tocopherol (α-TOH), one of the eight isoforms of vitamin E, is a natural antioxidant-free radical. We aimed to understand the effect of α-TOH and mechanism involved in inducing the ALI. Lipopolysaccharide (LPS) is injected into the trachea of mice to generate ALI mouse models. α-TOH was used to administrate the mice intragastrically to detect the expression of inflammatory factors and antioxidant molecules by enzyme linked immunosorbent assay, hematoxylin-eosin staining and immunohistochemical staining. Mouse alveolar epithelial cell line (MLE-12 cells) was used to determine the effect of α-TOH on alveolar epithelial cells. Inflammatory factors such as, interleukin (IL)-1β, IL-6, and tumor necrosis factor (TNF)-α shows significant increase in the lung tissues of the mice induced by LPS and reduction in the expressions of superoxide dismutase (SOD)1/2 and glutathione peroxidase (GSH-Px). After treatment with α-TOH, the inflammation and oxidative stress levels shows substantial reduction in the lung tissues of the mice. Moreover, α-TOH also increases the proliferation ability of MLE-12 cells in vitro and reduces apoptosis level. In addition, α-TOH reduces p65 phosphorylation and nuclear translocation in alveolar epithelial cells &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;in vitro&lt;/em&gt;, thus, inhibiting the activity of the nuclear factor kappa-B (NF-κB) signaling pathway. α-TOH reduces the inflammation and oxidative stress of lung tissue by inhibiting the NF-κB signaling pathway, thereby alleviating the LPS-induced ALI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nanocurcumin Potently Inhibits SARS-CoV-2 Spike Protein-Induced Cytokine Storm by Deactivation of MAPK/NF-κB Signaling in Epithelial Cells</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35112841/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35112841/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interleukin-mediated deep cytokine storm, an aggressive inflammatory response to SARS-CoV-2 virus infection in COVID-19 patients, is correlated directly with lung injury, multi-organ failure, and poor prognosis of severe COVID-19 patients. Curcumin (CUR), a phenolic antioxidant compound obtained from turmeric (&lt;em&gt;Curcuma longa L.&lt;/em&gt;), is well-known for its strong anti-inflammatory activity. However, its &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt; efficacy is constrained due to poor bioavailability. Herein, we report that CUR-encapsulated polysaccharide nanoparticles (CUR-PS-NPs) potently inhibit the release of cytokines, chemokines, and growth factors associated with damage of SARS-CoV-2 spike protein (CoV2-SP)-stimulated liver Huh7.5 and lung A549 epithelial cells. Treatment with CUR-PS-NPs effectively attenuated the interaction of ACE2 and CoV2-SP. The effects of CUR-PS-NPs were linked to reduced NF-κB/MAPK signaling which in turn decreased CoV2-SP-mediated phosphorylation of p38 MAPK, p42/44 MAPK, and p65/NF-κB as well as nuclear p65/NF-κB expression. The findings of the study strongly indicate that organic NPs of CUR can be used to control hyper-inflammatory responses and prevent lung and liver injuries associated with CoV2-SP-mediated cytokine storm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A novel nordihydroguaiaretic acid analog, compound 3a, alleviates acute lung injury by exerting antiapoptotic and antiinflammatory effects</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35085517/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35085517/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acute lung injury (ALI) is a continuum of pulmonary changes caused by various lung insults. Previously, we synthesized a series of nordihydroguaiaretic acid analogs; of these, compound 3a exhibited excellent antioxidant capacity in a murine model of middle cerebral artery occlusion. However, it remains unclear whether compound 3a can modulate lipopolysaccharide (LPS)-induced ALI. ALI was induced via tracheal LPS administration, and the pathological changes were assessed. The level of inflammation was verified by immunofluorescence and immunohistochemical analyses. Apoptosis was measured by terminal deoxynucleotidyl transferase dUTP nick-end labeling assays and Western blotting. Changes in the levels of mitogen-activated protein kinase (MAPK)/nuclear factor-κB (NF-κB) pathway proteins were assessed by immunofluorescence assays and Western blotting. In vitro, RAW 264.7 cells were treated with compound 3a prior to LPS challenge, and the intracellular level of inflammation was assessed by quantitative PCR (qPCR). Relevant proteins were detected via immunofluorescence assays and Western blotting. Mice developed extensive lung inflammation by 24 h after LPS challenge. Histological examination revealed signs typical of ALI. Preadministration of compound 3a markedly ameliorated the histopathological changes and reduced fluid exudation into the alveolar space. Compound 3a also greatly reduced the levels of inflammation and apoptosis both in vivo and in vitro. Moreover, compound 3a markedly reduced phosphorylation of MAPK/NF-κB pathway-related proteins and p65 translocation, consistent with the in vitro observations. In summary, administration of compound 3a prior to LPS suppressed ALI via inhibition of the MAPK/NF-κB pathway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The dynamic interplay between AMPK/NFκB signaling and NLRP3 is a new therapeutic target in inflammation: Emerging role of dapagliflozin in overcoming lipopolysaccharide-mediated lung injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35032769/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35032769/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;AMPK/NFκB and NLRP3 interplay is a new therapeutic target in inflammation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dapagliflozin mitigated lipopolysaccharide-mediated lung injury.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dapagliflozin anti-inflammatory effects were mediated through AMPK/NFĸB regulation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dapagliflozin inhibited NLRP3 inflammasome and caspase-1 activity.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acute lung injury (ALI) is one the most common causes of morbidity and mortality in critically ill patients. In this study, we examined for first time the role of dapagliflozin (DPGZ) in lipopolysaccharide (LPS)-induced ALI in rats and determined the underlying molecular mechanisms by evaluating the effects of DPGZ on adenosine monophosphate kinase (AMPK), nuclear transcription factor kappa B, nucleotide-binding and oligomerization domain-like receptor 3 inflammasome activation. Treatment of acute lung injured rats with either low dose (5 mg/kg) or high dose (10 mg/kg) DPGZ significantly decreased oxidative stress by decreasing malondialdehyde and nitric oxide tissue levels with a significant increase in spectrophotometric measurements of superoxide dismutase, catalase, and reduced glutathione levels. DPGZ treatment resulted in a significant anti-inflammatory effect as indicated by suppression in myeloperoxidase activity, MCP-1, IL-1β, IL-18, and TNF-α levels. DPGZ treatment also increased p-AMPK/t-AMPK with a significant reduction in NF-kB P65 binding activity and NFĸB p65 (pSer536) levels. These effects of DPGZ were accompanied by a significant reduction in NLRP3 levels and NLRP3 gene expression and a significant decrease in caspase-1 activity, which were also confirmed by histopathological examinations. We conclude that DPGZ antioxidant and anti-inflammatory activity may occur through regulation of AMPK/NFĸB pathway and inhibition of NLRP3 activation. These results suggest that DPGZ represents a promising intervention for the treatment of ALI, particularly in patients with type 2 diabetes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-developed NF-κB inhibitor 270 protects against LPS-induced acute kidney injury and lung injury through improving inflammation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35026488/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35026488/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Compound 270, a self-developed NF-κB inhibitor, possess anti-inflammation activity in vitro.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;NF-κB inhibitor 270 has protective effects against LPS-induced septic AKI and ALI in vivo.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;NF-κB inhibitor 270 is a potential candidate medicine in the treatment of AKI and ALI.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;NF-κB inhibitor 270 could be used in inflammatory associated diseases.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sepsis-induced acute kidney injury (AKI) and acute lung injury (ALI) have high morbidity and mortality, with no effective clinically available drugs. Anti-inflammation is effective strategy in the therapy of AKI and ALI. NF-κB is a target for the development of anti‑inflammatory agents. The purpose of the study is to evaluate the effect of 270, self-developed NF-κB inhibitor, in LPS-induced AKI and ALI. LPS-induced macrophages were used to examine the anti-inflammation activity of 270 in vitro. Sepsis-induced AKI and ALI mice models were established by intraperitoneal injection of LPS (10 mg/kg) for 24 h. Oral administration 270 for 14 days before LPS stimulation. Plasma, kidney and lung tissues were collected and used for histopathology, biochemical assay, ELISA, RT-PCR, and western blot analyses. In vitro, we showed that 270 suppressed the inflammation response in LPS-induced RAW 264.7 macrophages and bone marrow derived macrophages. In vivo, we found that 270 ameliorated LPS-induced AKI and ALI, as evidenced by improving various pathological changes, reducing the expression of pro-inflammation genes, blocking the activation of NF-κB and JNK pathways, attenuating the elevated myeloperoxidase (MPO) activity and malondialdehyde (MDA) content, ameliorating the activated ER stress, reversing the inhibition effect on autophagy in kidney and lung tissues, and alleviating the enhanced plasma level of creatinine (Crea), blood urea nitrogen (BUN) and pro-inflammation cytokines. Our investigations provides evidence that NF-κB inhibitor 270 is a potential drug that against LPS-induced AKI and ALI in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ATXN2-mediated translation of TNFR1 promotes esophageal squamous cell carcinoma via m6A-dependent manner</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34995801/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34995801/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;N&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;-methyladenosine (m&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;A) is the most prevalent RNA modification, and the effect of its dysregulation on esophageal squamous cell carcinoma (ESCC) development remains unclear. Here, by performing transcriptome-wide m&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;A sequencing in 16 ESCC tissue samples, we identified the key roles of m&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;A in TNFRSF1A (also known as TNFR1)-mediated MAPK and NF-κB activation in ESCC. Mechanistically, a functional protein involved in m&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;A methylation, ATXN2, is identified that augments the translation of TNFRSF1A by binding to m&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;A-modified TNFRSF1A mRNA. Upregulation of the TNFRSF1A protein level, a vital upstream switch for TNFRSF1A-mediated signaling events, activates the NF-κB and MAPK pathways and thus promotes ESCC development. Furthermore, TNFRSF1A m&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;A modifications and protein levels are upregulated in ESCC, and high levels of TNFRSF1A m&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;A and protein are correlated with poor ESCC patient survival. These results collectively indicate that the m&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;A-TNFRSF1A axis is critical for ESCC development and thus may serve as a potential druggable target.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JFNE-A isolated from Jing-Fang n-butanol extract attenuates lipopolysaccharide-induced acute lung injury by inhibiting oxidative stress and the NF-κB signaling pathway via promotion of autophagy</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35026506/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35026506/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Jing-Fang powder consists of Jingjie (Nepeta tenuifolia Benth, (Lamiaceae)). and Fangfeng (Saposhnikovia divaricata (Turcz.) Schischk, (Apiaceae)) Previous studies have revealed that the Jing-Fang powder n-butanol extract (JFNE) has anti-acute lung injury (ALI) and anti-inflammatory properties; however, the active ingredient and mechanism remain unknown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Purpose:&lt;/em&gt; In the present study, we investigated the anti-inflammatory effect of a bioactive fraction obtained from JFNE(JFNE-A) on lipopolysaccharide (LPS)-induced ALI in mice and explored the underlying mechanism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Study design:&lt;/em&gt; The anti-acute lung injury effect and mechanism of JFNE-A was investigated by prophylactic administration of JFNE-A in mice with LPS-induced acute lung injury.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; The expression levels of myeloperoxidase(MPO) in lung tissues of mice and interleukin(IL)-6, tumor necrosis factor(TNF)-α, IL-1β, IL-5, interferon (IFN)-γ, monocyte chemotactic protein (MCP)-1, macrophage colony stimulating factor (M-CSF), macrophage inflammatory protein (MIP)-1α, and MIP-1β in bronchi alveolar lavage fluid (BALF) were detected by reagent kit and the histological changes were examined by hematoxylin and eosin (H &amp;amp; E) for general histopathological conditions under a light microscope. In addition, the ultrastructure of the cells in lung tissues were observed and photographed under a transmission electron microscope. The expression levels of protein were detected via Western blotting and the mRNA expression of relative genes were determined of via reverse transcriptase polymerase chain reaction (RT-PCR). What&amp;rsquo;s more, we also further clarified the potential targets of JFNE-A through network pharmacology analysis, which could be utilized in ALI treatment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; Our results showed that pretreatment with JFNE-A for 7 days significantly reduced the lung pathological injury score, alleviated pulmonary edema, and decreased the lung tissue MPO level. Mechanistically, JFNE-A dramatically downregulated the protein levels of IL-6, TNF-α, IL-1β, M-CSF, and IFN-γ in BALF and mRNA expression levels of IL-6, TNF-α, IL-1β, and IFN-γ in lung tissues. JFNE-A also significantly lowered the protein levels of iNOS and phosphorylated NF-κB (p65) and mRNA expression levels of iNOS, Rela, CHUK, and NF-κB1, and also elevated the protein expression levels of Nrf2, HO-1, and SOD1 and the mRNA expression levels of Nrf2, Hmox1, and Keap-1 in the lungs. Moreover, JFNE-A significantly decreased the protein expression of p62 and increased the ratio of LC3II/LC3I. It also upregulated the mRNA expression levels of Atg5 and Beclin-1, whereas it reduced the mRNA expression level of SQSTM1 and increased autophagosome structures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/em&gt; Overall, treatment with JFNE-A ameliorated LPS-induced ALI in mice by suppressing the NF-κB signaling pathways and promoting Nrf2 signaling pathways by accelerating autophagy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The deubiquitinase OTUD1 inhibits colonic inflammation by suppressing RIPK1-mediated NF-κB signaling</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34876703/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34876703/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The E3 ubiquitin ligase (E3)-mediated ubiquitination and deubiquitinase (DUB)-mediated deubiquitination processes are closely associated with the occurrence and development of colonic inflammation. Ovarian tumor deubiquitinase 1 (OTUD1) is involved in immunoregulatory functions linked to infectious diseases. However, the effect of OTUD1 on intestinal immune responses during colonic inflammatory disorders such as inflammatory bowel disease (IBD) remains unclear. Here, we show that loss of OTUD1 in mice contributes to the pathogenesis of dextran sulfate sodium (DSS)-induced colitis via excessive release of proinflammatory cytokines. In addition, bone marrow transplantation experiments revealed that OTUD1 in hematopoietic cells plays a dominant role in protection against colitis. Mechanistically, OTUD1 physically interacts with receptor-interacting serine/threonine-protein kinase 1 (RIPK1) and selectively cleaves K63-linked polyubiquitin chains from RIPK1 to inhibit the recruitment of NF-κB essential modulator (NEMO). Moreover, the expression of OTUD1 in mucosa samples from ulcerative colitis (UC) patients was lower than that in mucosa samples from healthy controls. Furthermore, we demonstrate that the UC-associated OTUD1 G430V mutation abolishes the ability of OTUD1 to inhibit RIPK1-mediated NF-κB activation and intestinal inflammation. Taken together, our study unveils a previously unexplored role of OTUD1 in moderating intestinal inflammation by inhibiting RIPK1-mediated NF-κB activation, suggesting that the OTUD1-RIPK1 axis could be a potential target for the treatment of IBD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ruscogenin alleviates LPS-triggered pulmonary endothelial barrier dysfunction through targeting NMMHC IIA to modulate TLR4 signaling</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35530141/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35530141/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Erratum in:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Erratum: Author correction to &amp;lsquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S2211383522001629&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ruscogenin alleviates LPS-triggered pulmonary endothelial barrier dysfunction through targeting NMMHC IIA to modulate TLR4 signaling&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo; [Acta Pharmaceutica Sinica B 12 (2022) 1198-1212].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pulmonary endothelial barrier dysfunction is a hallmark of clinical pulmonary edema and contributes to the development of acute lung injury (ALI). Here we reported that ruscogenin (RUS), an effective steroidal sapogenin of Radix Ophiopogon japonicus, attenuated lipopolysaccharides (LPS)-induced pulmonary endothelial barrier disruption through mediating non-muscle myosin heavy chain IIA (NMMHC IIA)‒Toll-like receptor 4 (TLR4) interactions. By in vivo and in vitro experiments, we observed that RUS administration significantly ameliorated LPS-triggered pulmonary endothelial barrier dysfunction and ALI. Moreover, we identified that RUS directly targeted NMMHC IIA on its N-terminal and head domain by serial affinity chromatography, molecular docking, biolayer interferometry, and microscale thermophoresis analyses. Downregulation of endothelial NMMHC IIA expression in vivo and in vitro abolished the protective effect of RUS. It was also observed that NMMHC IIA was dissociated from TLR4 and then activating TLR4 downstream Src/vascular endothelial cadherin (VE-cadherin) signaling in pulmonary vascular endothelial cells after LPS treatment, which could be restored by RUS. Collectively, these findings provide pharmacological evidence showing that RUS attenuates LPS-induced pulmonary endothelial barrier dysfunction by inhibiting TLR4/Src/VE-cadherin pathway through targeting NMMHC IIA and mediating NMMHC IIA‒TLR4 interactions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
