<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Pancreas | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/pancreas/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/pancreas/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Pancreas</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Pancreas</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/pancreas/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Targeting Src reactivates pyroptosis to reverse chemoresistance in lung and pancreatic cancer models</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36630483/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36630483/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pancreatic and lung cancers frequently develop resistance to chemotherapy-induced cell apoptosis during the treatment, indicating that targeting nonapoptotic-related pathways, such as pyroptosis, can be an alternative cancer treatment strategy. Pyroptosis is a gasdermin-driven lytic programmed cell death triggered by inflammatory caspases when initiated by canonical or noncanonical pathways that has been recently seen as a potential therapeutic target in cancer treatment. However, overcoming chemoresistance in cancers by modulating pyroptosis has not been explored. Here, we demonstrate that β5-integrin represses chemotherapy-induced canonical pyroptosis to confer cancer chemoresistance through ASAH2-driven sphingolipid metabolic reprogramming. Clinically, high β5-integrin expression associates with poor patient prognosis and chemotherapeutic responses in cancers. In addition, chemoresistant cells in vitro fail to undergo chemotherapy-induced pyroptosis, which is controlled by β5-integrin. Mechanistically, proteomic and lipidomic analyses indicate that β5-integrin up-regulates sphingolipid metabolic enzyme ceramidase (ASAH2) expression through Src-signal transducer and activator of transcription 3 (STAT3) signaling, which then reduces the metabolite ceramide concentration and subsequent ROS production to prohibit chemotherapy-induced canonical pyroptosis. Using cancer cell lines, patient-derived tumor organoids, and orthotopic lung and pancreatic animal models, we show that administration of a Src or ceramidase inhibitor rescues the response of chemoresistant pancreatic and lung cancer cells to chemotherapy by reactivating pyroptosis in vitro and in vivo. Overall, our results suggest that pyroptosis-based therapy is a means to improve cancer treatment and warrants further investigation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gut microbiome dysregulation drives bone damage in broiler tibial dyschondroplasia by disrupting glucose homeostasis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36596826/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36596826/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tibial dyschondroplasia (TD) with multiple incentives is a metabolic skeletal disease that occurs in fast-growing broilers. Perturbations in the gut microbiota (GM) have been shown to affect bone homoeostasis, but the mechanisms by which GM modulates bone metabolism in TD broilers remain unknown. Here, using a broiler model of TD, we noted elevated blood glucose (GLU) levels in TD broilers, accompanied by alterations in the pancreatic structure and secretory function and damaged intestinal barrier function. Importantly, faecal microbiota transplantation (FMT) of gut microbes from normal donors rehabilitated the GM and decreased the elevated GLU levels in TD broilers. A high GLU level is a predisposing factor to bone disease, suggesting that GM dysbiosis-mediated hyperglycaemia might be involved in bone regulation. 16S rRNA gene sequencing and short-chain fatty acid analysis revealed that the significantly increased level of the metabolite butyric acid derived from the genera &lt;em&gt;Blautia&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Coprococcus&lt;/em&gt; regulated GLU levels in TD broilers by binding to GPR109A in the pancreas. Tibial studies showed reduced expression of vascular regulatory factors (including PI3K, AKT and VEFGA) based on transcriptomics analysis and reduced vascular distribution, contributing to nonvascularization of cartilage in the proximal tibial growth plate of TD broilers with elevated GLU levels. Additionally, treatment with the total flavonoids from Rhizoma drynariae further validated the improvement in bone homoeostasis in TD broilers by regulating GLU levels through the regulation of GM to subsequently improve intestinal and pancreatic function. These findings clarify the critical role of GM-mediated changes in GLU levels via the gut–pancreas axis in bone homoeostasis in TD chickens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>β-hydroxybutyrate inhibits ferroptosis-mediated pancreatic damage in acute liver failure through the increase of H3K9bhb</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36543135/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36543135/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ferroptosis contributes to pancreatic injury after acute liver failure (ALF)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;β-hydroxybutyrate (β-HB) restoration alleviates pancreatic injury after ALF&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;β-HB induces enrichment of H3K9bhb in the promotor regions of ferroptosis-suppressor genes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;β-HB regulates chromatin accessibility and mRNA expression of ferroptosis-suppressor genes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acute pancreatitis and hyperamylasemia are often seen in patients with acute liver failure (ALF). However, the underlying mechanisms remain elusive. This study describes pancreatic tissue damage and exocrine dysfunction in a mouse model of major-liver-resection-induced ALF. The analysis of 1,264 clinical cases of liver failure (LF) showed that the incidence of hyperamylasemia and hyperlipasemia in patients with LF is 5.5% and 20%, respectively. Metabolomic studies indicate that glutathione (GSH)-deficiency-caused ferroptosis contributes to pancreatic damage in mouse ALF. β-hydroxybutyrate (β-HB) is the only metabolite downregulated in the liver, serum, and pancreas. Our data suggest that β-HB protects pancreatic cells and tissues from GSH-deficiency-caused ferroptosis. β-HB administration in ALF mice restores the expression of ferroptosis-suppressor genes through histone H3 lysine 9 β-hydroxybutyrylation (H3K9bhb)-mediated chromatin opening. Our findings highlight β-HB as an endogenous metabolite regulating ferroptosis in the pancreas and extend our understanding of the pathophysiology of ALF-induced pancreatitis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interplay of four types of RNA modification writers revealed distinct tumor microenvironment and biological characteristics in pancreatic cancer</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36601127/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36601127/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Pancreatic cancer (PC) is one of the most lethal malignancies and carries a dismal mortality and morbidity. Four types of RNA modification (namely m6A, m1A, APA and A-to-I) could be catalyzed by distinct enzymatic compounds (“writers”), mediating numerous epigenetic events in carcinogenesis and immunomodulation. We aim to investigate the interplay mechanism of these writers in immunogenomic features and molecular biological characteristics in PC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; We first accessed the specific expression pattern and transcriptional variation of 26 RNA modification writers in The Cancer Genome Atlas (TCGA) dataset. Unsupervised consensus clustering was performed to divide patients into two RNA modification clusters. Then, based on the differentially expressed genes (DEGs) among two clusters, RNA modification score (WM-Score) model was established to determine RNA modification-based subtypes and was validated in International Cancer Genome Consortium (ICGC) dataset. What’s more, we manifested the unique status of WM-Score in transcriptional and post-transcriptional regulation, molecular biological characteristics, targeted therapies and immunogenomic patterns.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; We documented the tight-knit correlations between transcriptional expression and variation of RNA modification writers. We classified patients into two distinct RNA modification patterns (WM-Score-high and -low), The WM-Score_high subgroup was correlated with worse prognosis, Th2/Th17 cell polarization and oncogenic pathways (&lt;em&gt;e.g.&lt;/em&gt; EMT, TGF-β, and mTORC1 signaling pathways), whereas the WM-Score-low subgroup associated with favorable survival rate and Th1 cell trend. WM-Score model also proved robust predictive power in interpreting transcriptional and post-transcriptional events. Additionally, the potential targeted compounds with related pathways for the WM-Score model were further identified.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; Our research unfolds a novel horizon on the interplay network of four RNA modifications in PC. This WM-Score model demonstrated powerful predictive capacity in epigenetic, immunological and biological landscape, providing a theoretical basis for future clinical judgments of PC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JMJD3 Is Required for Acute Pancreatitis and Pancreatitis-Associated Lung Injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36458991/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36458991/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acute pancreatitis (AP) can be complicated by inflammatory disorders of remote organs, such as lung injury, in which Jumonji domain-containing protein 3 (JMJD3) plays a vital role in proinflammatory responses. Currently, we found that JMJD3 expression was upregulated in the pancreas and lung in an AP male mouse model, which was also confirmed in AP patients. Further experiments revealed that the upregulation of JMJD3 and proinflammatory effects were possibly exerted by mitochondrial DNA (mtDNA) or oxidized-mtDNA from tissue injury caused by AP. The release of mtDNA and oxidized-mtDNA contributed to the infiltration of inflammatory monocytes in lung injury through the stimulator of IFN genes (STING)/TLR9-NF-κB-JMJD3-TNF-α pathway. The inhibition of JMJD3 or utilization of Jmjd3-cKO mice significantly alleviated pulmonary inflammation induced by AP. Blocking mtDNA oxidation or knocking down the TLR9/STING pathway effectively alleviated inflammation. Therefore, inhibition of JMJD3 or STING/TLR9 pathway blockage might be a potential therapeutic strategy to treat AP and the associated lung injury.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Differential integrated stress response and asparagine production drive symbiosis and therapy resistance of pancreatic adenocarcinoma cells</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36411320/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36411320/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The pancreatic tumor microenvironment drives deregulated nutrient availability. Accordingly, pancreatic cancer cells require metabolic adaptations to survive and proliferate. Pancreatic cancer subtypes have been characterized by transcriptional and functional differences, with subtypes reported to exist within the same tumor. However, it remains unclear if this diversity extends to metabolic programming. Here, using metabolomic profiling and functional interrogation of metabolic dependencies, we identify two distinct metabolic subclasses among neoplastic populations within individual human and mouse tumors. Furthermore, these populations are poised for metabolic cross-talk, and in examining this, we find an unexpected role for asparagine supporting proliferation during limited respiration. Constitutive GCN2 activation permits ATF4 signaling in one subtype, driving excess asparagine production. Asparagine release provides resistance during impaired respiration, enabling symbiosis. Functionally, availability of exogenous asparagine during limited respiration indirectly supports maintenance of aspartate pools, a rate-limiting biosynthetic precursor. Conversely, depletion of extracellular asparagine with PEG-asparaginase sensitizes tumors to mitochondrial targeting with phenformin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thiram-induced hyperglycemia causes tibial dyschondroplasia by triggering aberrant ECM remodeling via the gut-pancreas axis in broiler chickens</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36423455/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36423455/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pesticide thiram is widely used in agriculture and has been demonstrated to cause tibial dyschondroplasia (TD) in birds. However, the underlying mechanism remains unclear. This work used multi-omics analysis to evaluate the molecular pathways of TD in broilers that were exposed to low level of thiram. Integrative analysis of transcriptomic, proteomic, and metabolomic revealed thiram activity in enhancing pathological ECM remodeling via attenuating the glycolysis pathway and activating the hexosamine and glucuronic acid pathways. Intriguingly, we found hyperglycemia as a crucial factor for ECM overproduction, which resulted in the development of TD. We further demonstrated that high glucose levels are caused by islet secretion dysfunction in thiram-treated broilers. A combination of factors, including lipid disorder, low-grade inflammation, and gut flora disturbance, might contribute to the dysregulation of insulin secretion. The current work revealed the underlying toxicological mechanisms of thiram-induced tibial dyschondroplasia through blood glucose disorder via the gut-pancreas axis in chickens for the first time, which makes it easier to figure out the health risks of pesticides for worldwide policy decisions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Activation of Pancreatic Acinar FXR Protects against Pancreatitis via Osgin1-Mediated Restoration of Efficient Autophagy</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36405253/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36405253/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pancreatitis is the leading cause of hospitalization in gastroenterology, and no medications are available for treating this disease in current clinical practice. FXR plays an anti-inflammatory role in diverse inflammatory diseases, while its function in pancreatitis remains unknown. In this study, we initially observed a marked increase of nuclear FXR in pancreatic tissues of human patients with pancreatitis. Deleting the FXR in pancreatic acinar cells (FXR&lt;sup&gt;acinarΔ/Δ &lt;/sup&gt;) led to more severe pancreatitis in mouse models of caerulein-induced acute and chronic pancreatitis, while the FXR agonist GW4064 significantly attenuated pancreatitis in caerulein or arginine-induced acute pancreatitis and caerulein-induced chronic pancreatitis. FXR deletion impaired the viability and stress responses of pancreatic exocrine organoids (PEOs) in vitro. Utilizing RNA-seq and ChIP-seq of PEOs, we identified &lt;em&gt;Osgin1&lt;/em&gt; as a direct target of FXR in the exocrine pancreas, which was also increasingly expressed in human pancreatitis tissues compared to normal pancreatic tissues. Pancreatic knockdown of &lt;em&gt;Osgin1&lt;/em&gt; by AAV-pan abolished the therapeutic effects of FXR activation on pancreatitis, whereas pancreatic overexpression of &lt;em&gt;Osgin1&lt;/em&gt; effectively alleviated caerulein-induced pancreatitis. Mechanistically, we found that the FXR-OSGIN1 axis stimulated autophagic flux in the pancreatic tissues and cell lines, which was considered as the intrinsic mechanisms through which FXR-OSGIN1 protecting against pancreatitis. Our results highlight the protective role of the FXR-OSGIN1 axis in pancreatitis and provided a new target for the treatment of this disease.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hypoxia-induced exosomal circPDK1 promotes pancreatic cancer glycolysis via c-myc activation by modulating miR-628-3p/BPTF axis and degrading BIN1</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36068586/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36068586/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; circRNA has been established to play a pivotal role in tumorigenesis development in a variety of cancers; nevertheless, the biological functions and molecular mechanisms of hypoxia-induced exosomal circRNAs in pancreatic cancer remain largely unknown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; Differentially expressed circRNAs in exosomes between hypoxic exosomes and normoxic exosomes in PC cells were verified by RNA sequencing. The expression of circPDK1 in PC tumors and PC patients was evaluated by qRT-PCR and ISH, and the biological functions of circPDK1 in PC were verified through a series of in vitro and in vivo experiments. Using Western blotting, Co-IP, RNA pull-down, ChIP, RIP, dual-luciferase assays, and rescue experiments, the underlying mechanism of circPDK1 was verified.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; CircPDK1 was highly abundant in PC tumor tissues and serum exosomes and was associated with poor survival. Exosomal circPDK1 significantly promoted PC cell proliferation, migration, and glycolysis both in vitro and in vivo. Mechanistically, circPDK1 could be activated by HIF1A at the transcriptional level and sponges miR-628-3p to activate the BPTF/c-myc axis. In addition, circPDK1 serves as a scaffold that enhances the interaction between UBE2O and BIN1, inducing the UBE2O-mediated degradation of BIN1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; We found that circPDK1 was activated by HIF1A at the transcriptional level by modulating the miR-628-3p/BPTF axis and degrading BIN1. Exosomal circPDK1 is a promising biomarker for PC diagnosis and prognosis and represents a potential therapeutic target for PC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LINC00941 promotes pancreatic cancer malignancy by interacting with ANXA2 and suppressing NEDD4L-mediated degradation of ANXA2</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35977942/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35977942/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently, long non-coding RNAs (lncRNA) have been proven to regulate pancreatic cancer (PC) progression. We aimed to explore the pathogenesis of LINC00941 in PC regarding protein binding. By using PCR analysis, we found that LINC00941 was overexpressed in PC tissues and was higher in patients with liver metastasis than in patients without liver metastasis. In addition, high LINC00941 expression was associated with a poor prognosis. Functional experiments and mice models were respectively used to evaluate PC cell proliferation and migration in vitro and in vivo. The results suggested that LINC00941 overexpression promoted PC proliferation and metastasis. Subsequently, RNA pull-down, mass spectrometry (MS), and RNA-binding protein immunoprecipitation (RIP) were performed to identify LINC00941-interacting proteins. The results suggested that ANXA2 was the potential LINC00941-interacting protein. Nucleotides 500-1390 of LINC00941 could bind to the Annexin 1 domain of ANXA2. LINC00941-mediated malignant phenotype of PC was reversed by ANXA2 depletion. Co-immunoprecipitation (Co-IP) followed by MS was conducted to determine the potential interacting protein of LINC00941. The results illustrated that NEDD4L, an E3 ligase involved in ubiquitin-mediated protein degradation, bound to the Annexin 1 domain of ANXA2 and promoted its degradation. Mechanically, LINC00941 functioned as a decoy to bind to ANXA2 and suppressed its degradation by enclosing the domain that binds to NEDD4L. Eventually, LINC00941 upregulated ANXA2 and activated FAK/AKT signaling, increasing PC cell proliferation and metastasis. This study indicates that LINC00941 promotes PC proliferation and metastasis by binding ANXA2 and potentiating its stability, leading to the activation of FAK/AKT signaling. Our data demonstrate that LINC00941 may serve as a novel target for prognosis and therapy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Acadesine alleviates acute pancreatitis-related lung injury by mediating the barrier protective function of pulmonary microvascular endothelial cells</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35987144/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35987144/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pretreatment with acadesine shows therapeutic potential SAP-ALI in vivo and vitro.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Endothelial injury is critical for the initiation and progression of severe acute pancreatitis-related acute lung injury.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The beneficial effects of acadesine may involve reducing ROS accumulation and inhibiting apoptosis.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Acadesine inhibits the impairment of SAP-ALI by activating the AMPK/Nrf2 pathway.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Severe acute pancreatitis (SAP) is a condition characterized by highly fatal acute inflammation and is usually associated with multiple organ dysfunction syndrome. Acute lung injury (ALI) is the most common complications of SAP, which is the accelerator of other organ dysfunction caused by SAP and the primary cause of early death due to SAP. Acadesine, an adenosine analog and an AMPK activator, has been discovered to modulate glucose and lipid metabolism, and inhibit the production of pro-inflammatory cytokines and iNOS. However, its role in SAP-ALI and its mechanism remains unclear and need to be explored. Herein, we discovered that acadesine mitigated the generation of reactive oxygen species (ROS) in human pulmonary microvascular endothelial cells (HPMECs), alleviated apoptosis and recovered barrier integrity, thereby contributing to anti-inflammatory effects in vitro and in vivo. Moreover, Nrf2 deficiency partially eliminated the effects of acadesine-induced antioxidant effects and thus weakened the protective effects on cells and Nrf2-knockout (Nrf2&lt;Sup&gt;-/-&lt;/Sup&gt;) mice. This study demonstrates that acadesine attenuated SAP-ALI associated inflammation and tissue damage by modulating the Nrf2-dependent antioxidant pathway by triggering AMPK. These findings are of great significance for the treatment of SAP-related lung injury.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>USP25 Deficiency Exacerbates Acute Pancreatitis via Up-Regulating TBK1-NF-κB Signaling in Macrophages</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35934222/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35934222/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background &amp;amp; aims:&lt;/em&gt; Severe acute pancreatitis can easily lead to systemic inflammatory response syndrome and death. Macrophages are known to be involved in the pathophysiology of acute pancreatitis (AP), and macrophage activation correlates with disease severity. In this study, we examined the role of ubiquitin-specific protease 25, a deubiquitinating enzyme and known regulator of macrophages, in the pathogenesis of AP.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; We used L-arginine, cerulein, and choline-deficient ethionine-supplemented diet-induced models of AP in &lt;em&gt;Usp25&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; mice and wild-type mice. We also generated bone marrow &lt;em&gt;Usp25&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; chimeric mice and initiated L-arginine-mediated AP. Primary acinar cells and bone marrow-derived macrophages were isolated from wild-type and &lt;em&gt;Usp25&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; mice to dissect molecular mechanisms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; Our results show that Usp25 deficiency exacerbates pancreatic and lung injury, neutrophil and macrophage infiltration, and systemic inflammatory responses in L-arginine, cerulein, and choline-deficient ethionine-supplemented diet-induced models of AP. Bone marrow &lt;em&gt;Usp25&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; chimeric mice challenged with L-arginine show that &lt;em&gt;Usp25&lt;/em&gt; deficiency in macrophages exaggerates AP by up-regulating the TANK-binding kinase 1 (TBK1)-nuclear factor-κB (NF-κB) signaling pathway. Similarly, in vitro data confirm that Usp25 deficiency enhances the TBK1-NF-κB pathway, leading to increased expression of inflammatory cytokines in bone marrow-derived macrophages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;Usp25&lt;/em&gt; deficiency in macrophages enhances TBK1-NF-κB signaling, and the induction of inflammatory chemokines and type I interferon-related genes exacerbates pancreatic and lung injury in AP.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Colchicine improves severe acute pancreatitis-induced acute lung injury by suppressing inflammation, apoptosis and oxidative stress in rats</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36076491/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36076491/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Inflammation, apoptosis and oxidative stress play critical roles in severe acute pancreatitis (SAP).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Colchicine (COL) mitigates severe acute pancreatitis-associated lung injury (SAP-ALI) in rats model.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Colchicine limits inflammation, apoptosis and oxidative stress in SAP-ALI.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Inflammation, apoptosis and oxidative stress contribute to the development of severe acute pancreatitis-associated acute lung injury (SAP-ALI). Currently, there is no curative treatment for SAP-ALI in the clinic. This study investigated the potential therapeutic role and mechanisms of colchicine in a rat model of SAP-ALI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; Male Sprague-Dawley rats were randomized and administrated intragastrically with vehicle saline or colchicine (0.5 mg/kg/day) for seven days, followed by injecting sodium taurocholate to induce SAP-ALI. Together with a healthy control group of rats, their pancreatic and lung tissues and plasma samples were collected for histology, enzyme-linked immunosorbent assay (ELISA), immunoblot, immunohistochemistry, and immunofluorescence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; Compared with the sham controls, the SAP group of rats with vehicle saline treatment displayed severe damages, inflammation with many neutrophil and macrophage infiltrates in pancreatic and lung tissues, accompanied by elevated levels of plasma interleukin-1β (IL-1β), IL-6 and tumor necrosis factor (TNF)-α, which were significantly mitigated in colchicine-treated SAP + COL group of rats. Furthermore, colchicine treatment significantly attenuated nuclear factor kappa-B (NF-κB)-p65, signal transducer and activator of transcription 3 (STAT3) and protein kinase B (AKT) phosphorylation, reduced inducible nitric oxide synthase (iNOS) and 4-Hydroxynonenal expression, ROS production and cell apoptosis by decreasing caspase-3 cleavage, Bax expression, but increasing Bcl-2, nuclear factor erythroid 2-related factor 2 (Nrf2) and heme oxygenase-1 (HO-1) expression in pancreatic and lung tissues, relative to the SAP group of rats.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/em&gt; Colchicine treatment significantly mitigated the severity of SAP-ALI by inhibiting inflammation, oxidative stress and cell apoptosis in rats.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>KRAS mutant-driven SUMOylation controls extracellular vesicle transmission to trigger lymphangiogenesis in pancreatic cancer</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35579947/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35579947/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lymph node (LN) metastasis occurs frequently in pancreatic ductal adenocarcinoma (PDAC) and predicts poor prognosis for patients. The KRASG12D mutation confers an aggressive PDAC phenotype that is susceptible to lymphatic dissemination. However, the regulatory mechanism underlying KRASG12D mutation-driven LN metastasis in PDAC remains unclear. Herein, we found that PDAC with the KRASG12D mutation (KRASG12D PDAC) sustained extracellular vesicle-mediated (EV-mediated) transmission of heterogeneous nuclear ribonucleoprotein A1 (hnRNPA1) in a SUMOylation-dependent manner and promoted lymphangiogenesis and LN metastasis in vitro and in vivo. Mechanistically, hnRNPA1 bound with SUMO2 at the lysine 113 residue via KRASG12D-induced hyperactivation of SUMOylation, which enabled its interaction with TSG101 to enhance hnRNPA1 packaging and transmission via EVs. Subsequently, SUMOylation induced EV-packaged-hnRNPA1 anchoring to the adenylate- and uridylate-rich elements of PROX1 in lymphatic endothelial cells, thus stabilizing PROX1 mRNA. Importantly, impeding SUMOylation of EV-packaged hnRNPA1 dramatically inhibited LN metastasis of KRASG12D PDAC in a genetically engineered KrasG12D/+ Trp53R172H/+ Pdx-1-Cre (KPC) mouse model. Our findings highlight the mechanism by which KRAS mutant-driven SUMOylation triggers EV-packaged hnRNPA1 transmission to promote lymphangiogenesis and LN metastasis, shedding light on the potential application of hnRNPA1 as a therapeutic target in patients with KRASG12D PDAC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The gut-lung axis in severe acute Pancreatitis-associated lung injury: The protection by the gut microbiota through short-chain fatty acids</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/35752356/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/35752356/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The role of gut microbiota in regulating the intestinal homeostasis, as well as the pathogenesis of severe acute pancreatitis-associated lung injury (PALI) is widely recognized. The bioactive functions of metabolites with small molecule weight and the detail molecular mechanisms of PALI mediated by &amp;ldquo;gut-lung axis&amp;rdquo; have gradually raised the attentions of researchers. Several studies have proved that short-chain fatty acids (SCFAs) produced by gut microbiome play crucial roles and varied activities in the process of PALI. However, relevant reviews reporting SCFAs in the involvement of PALI is lacking. In this review, we firstly introduced the synthetic and metabolic pathways of SCFAs, as well as the transport and signal transduction routes in brief. Afterwards, we focused on the possible mechanisms and clues of SCFAs to participate in the fight against PALI which referred to the inhibition of pathogen proliferation, anti-inflammatory effects, enhancement of intestinal barrier functions, and the maintenance and regulation of immune homeostasis via pathogen-associated molecular patterns (PAMPs) and damage-associated molecular patterns (DAMPs). In addition, the latest reported pathological and physiological mechanisms of the gut-lung axis involved in PALI were reviewed. Finally, we summarized the potential therapeutic interventions of PALI by targeting SCFAs, including dietary fiber supplementation, direct supplementation of SCFAs/prebiotics/probiotics, and drugs administration, which is expected to provide new sights for clinical use in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LncRNA-PACERR induces pro-tumour macrophages via interacting with miR-671-3p and m6A-reader IGF2BP2 in pancreatic ductal adenocarcinoma</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35526050/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35526050/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; LncRNA-PACERR plays critical role in the polarization of tissue-associated macrophages (TAMs). In this study, we found the function and molecular mechanism of PACERR in TAMs to regulate pancreatic ductal adenocarcinoma (PDAC) progression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; We used qPCR to analyse the expression of PACERR in TAMs and M1-tissue-resident macrophages (M1-NTRMs) which were isolated from 46 PDAC tissues. The function of PACERR on macrophages polarization and PDAC proliferation, migration and invasion were confirmed through in vivo and in vitro assays. The molecular mechanism of PACERR was discussed via fluorescence in situ hybridization (FISH), RNA pull-down, ChIP-qPCR, RIP-qPCR and luciferase assays.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; LncRNA-PACERR was high expression in TAMs and associated with poor prognosis in PDAC patients. Our finding validated that LncRNA-PACERR increased the number of M2-polarized cells and facilized cell proliferation, invasion and migration in vitro and in vivo. Mechanistically, LncRNA-PACERR activate KLF12/p-AKT/c-myc pathway by binding to miR-671-3p. And LncRNA-PACERR which bound to IGF2BP2 acts as an m6A-dependent manner to enhance the stability of KLF12 and c-myc in cytoplasm. In addition, the promoter of LncRNA-PACERR was a target of KLF12 and LncRNA-PACERR recruited EP300 to increase the acetylation of histone by interacting with KLF12 in nucleus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; This study found that LncRNA-PACERR functions as key regulator of TAMs in PDAC microenvironment and revealed the novel mechanisms in cytoplasm and in nucleus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Circular RNA circ-MTHFD1L induces HR repair to promote gemcitabine resistance via the miR-615-3p/RPN6 axis in pancreatic ductal adenocarcinoma</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35459186/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35459186/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Chemoresistance of pancreatic cancer is the main reason for the poor treatment effect of pancreatic cancer patients. Exploring chemotherapy resistance-related genes has been a difficult and hot topic of oncology. Numerous studies implicate the key roles of circular RNAs (circRNAs) in the development of pancreatic cancer. However, the regulation of circRNAs in the process of pancreatic ductal adenocarcinoma (PDAC) chemotherapy resistance is not yet fully clear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; Based on the cross-analysis of the Gene Expression Omnibus (GEO) database and the data of our center, we explored a new molecule, hsa_circ_0078297 (circ-MTHFD1L), related to chemotherapy resistance. QRT-PCR was used to detect the expression of circRNAs, miRNAs, and mRNAs in human PDAC tissues and their matched normal tissues. The interaction between circ-MTHFD1L and miR-615-3p/RPN6 signal axis was confirmed by a series of experiments such as Dual-luciferase reporter assay, fluorescence in situ hybridization (FISH) RNA immunoprecipitation (RIP) assays.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; Circ-MTHFD1L was significantly increased in PDAC tissues and cells. And in PDAC patients, the higher the expression level of circ-MTHFD1L, the worse the prognosis. Mechanism analysis showed that circ-MTHFD1L, as an endogenous miR-615-3p sponge, upregulates the expression of RPN6, thereby promoting DNA damage repair and exerting its effect on enhancing gemcitabine chemotherapy resistance. More importantly, we also found that Silencing circ-MTHFD1L combined with olaparib can increase the sensitivity of pancreatic cancer to gemcitabine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/em&gt; Circ-MTHFD1L maintains PDAC gemcitabine resistance through the miR-615-3p/RPN6 signal axis. Circ-MTHFD1L may be a molecular marker for the effective treatment of PDAC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TSPAN1 promotes autophagy flux and mediates cooperation between WNT-CTNNB1 signaling and autophagy via the MIR454-FAM83A-TSPAN1 axis in pancreatic cancer</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32972302/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32972302/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pancreatic cancer is one of the most aggressive tumors associated with a poor clinical prognosis, weakly effective therapeutic options. Therefore, there is a strong impetus to discover new therapeutic targets in pancreatic cancer. In the present study, we first demonstrated that TSPAN1 is upregulated in pancreatic cancer and that TSPAN1 depletion decreases pancreatic cancer cell proliferation in vitro and in vivo. TSPAN1 expression was correlated with poor overall survival of pancreatic cancer patients. Moreover, we demonstrated that TSPAN1 is a novel positive regulator of macroautophagy/autophagy characterized by decreased LC3-II and SQSTM1/p62 expressions, inhibited puncta formation of GFP-LC3 and autophagic vacuoles. We also demonstrated that tspan1 mutation impaired autophagy in the zebrafish model. Furthermore, we showed that TSPAN1 promoted autophagy maturation via direct binding to LC3 by two conserved LIR motifs. Mutations in the LIR motifs of TSPAN1 resulted in a loss of the ability to induce autophagy and promote pancreatic cancer proliferation. Second, we discovered two conservative TCF/LEF binding elements present in the promoter region of the TSPAN1 gene, which was further verified through luciferase activity and ChIP assays. Furthermore, TSPAN1 was upregulated by FAM83A through the canonical WNT-CTNNB1 signaling pathway. We further demonstrated that both TSPAN1 and FAM83A are both direct targets of MIR454 (microRNA 454). Additionally, we revealed the role of MIR454-FAM83A-TSPAN1 in the proliferation of pancreatic cancer cells in vitro and in vivo. Our findings suggest that components of the MIR454-FAM83A-TSPAN1 axis may be valuable prognosis markers or therapeutic targets for pancreatic cancer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LncRNA PVT1 promotes gemcitabine resistance of pancreatic cancer via activating Wnt/β-catenin and autophagy pathway through modulating the miR-619-5p/Pygo2 and miR-619-5p/ATG14 axes</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32727463/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32727463/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pancreatic cancer is one of the most lethal malignancies and has an extremely poor diagnosis and prognosis. The development of resistance to gemcitabine is still a major challenge. The long noncoding RNA PVT1 was reported to be involved in carcinogenesis and chemoresistance; however, the mechanism by which PVT1 regulates the sensitivity of pancreatic cancer to gemcitabine remains poorly understood.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The viability of pancreatic cancer cells was assessed by MTT assay in vitro and xenograft tumor formation assay in vivo. The expression levels of PVT1 and miR-619-5p were detected by quantitative real-time polymerase chain reaction (qRT-PCR). Western blotting analysis and qRT-PCR were performed to assess the protein and mRNA levels of Pygo2 and ATG14, respectively. Autophagy was explored via autophagic flux detection under confocal microscopy and autophagic vacuole investigation under transmission electron microscopy (TEM). The functional role and mechanism of PVT1 were further investigated by gain- and loss-of-function assays in vitro.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the present study, we demonstrated that PVT1 was up-regulated in gemcitabine-resistant pancreatic cancer cell lines. Gain- and loss-of-function assays revealed that PVT1 impaired sensitivity to gemcitabine in vitro and in vivo. We further found that PVT1 up-regulated the expression of both Pygo2 and ATG14 and thus regulated Wnt/β-catenin signaling and autophagic activity to overcome gemcitabine resistance through sponging miR-619-5p. Moreover, we discovered three TCF/LEF binding elements (TBEs) in the promoter region of PVT1, and activation of Wnt/β-catenin signaling mediated by the up-regulation of Pygo2 increased PVT1 expression by direct binding to the TBE region. Furthermore, PVT1 was discovered to interact with ATG14, thus promoting assembly of the autophagy specific complex I (PtdIns3K-C1) and ATG14-dependent class III PtdIns3K activity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These data indicate that PVT1 plays a critical role in the sensitivity of pancreatic cancer to gemcitabine and highlight its potential as a valuable target for pancreatic cancer therapy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Autophagy promotes immune evasion of pancreatic cancer by degrading MHC-I</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32376951/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32376951/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Immune evasion is a major obstacle for cancer treatment. Common mechanisms of evasion include impaired antigen presentation caused by mutations or loss of heterozygosity of the major histocompatibility complex class I (MHC-I), which has been implicated in resistance to immune checkpoint blockade (ICB) therapy. However, in pancreatic ductal adenocarcinoma (PDAC), which is resistant to most therapies including ICB, mutations that cause loss of MHC-I are rarely found despite the frequent downregulation of MHC-I expression. Here we show that, in PDAC, MHC-I molecules are selectively targeted for lysosomal degradation by an autophagy-dependent mechanism that involves the autophagy cargo receptor NBR1. PDAC cells display reduced expression of MHC-I at the cell surface and instead demonstrate predominant localization within autophagosomes and lysosomes. Notably, inhibition of autophagy restores surface levels of MHC-I and leads to improved antigen presentation, enhanced anti-tumour T cell responses and reduced tumour growth in syngeneic host mice. Accordingly, the anti-tumour effects of autophagy inhibition are reversed by depleting CD8&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T cells or reducing surface expression of MHC-I. Inhibition of autophagy, either genetically or pharmacologically with chloroquine, synergizes with dual ICB therapy (anti-PD1 and anti-CTLA4 antibodies), and leads to an enhanced anti-tumour immune response. Our findings demonstrate a role for enhanced autophagy or lysosome function in immune evasion by selective targeting of MHC-I molecules for degradation, and provide a rationale for the combination of autophagy inhibition and dual ICB therapy as a therapeutic strategy against PDAC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
