<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Lactylation | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/lactylation/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/lactylation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Lactylation</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Lactylation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/lactylation/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lactylome analysis suggests lactylation-dependent mechanisms of metabolic adaptation in hepatocellular carcinoma</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36593272/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36593272/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enhanced glycolysis and accumulation of lactate is a common feature in various types of cancer. Intracellular lactate drives a recently described type of posttranslational modification, lysine lactylation (Kla), on core histones. However, the impact of lactylation on biological processes of tumour cells remains largely unknown. Here we show a global lactylome profiling on a prospectively collected hepatitis B virus-related hepatocellular carcinoma (HCC) cohort. Integrative lactylome and proteome analysis of the tumours and adjacent livers identifies 9,275 Kla sites, with 9,256 sites on non-histone proteins, indicating that Kla is a prevalent modification beyond histone proteins and transcriptional regulation. Notably, Kla preferentially affects enzymes involved in metabolic pathways, including the tricarboxylic acid cycle, and carbohydrate, amino acid, fatty acid and nucleotide metabolism. We further verify that lactylation at K28 inhibits the function of adenylate kinase 2, facilitating the proliferation and metastasis of HCC cells. Our study therefore reveals that Kla plays an important role in regulating cellular metabolism and may contribute to HCC progression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inhaled platelet vesicle-decoyed biomimetic nanoparticles attenuate inflammatory lung injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36523494/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36523494/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acute lung injury (ALI) is an inflammatory response which causes serious damages to alveolar epithelia and vasculature, and it still remains high lethality and mortality with no effective treatment. Based on the inflammatory homing of platelets and cell membrane cloaking nanotechnology, in this study we developed a biomimetic anti-inflammation nanoparticle delivery system for ALI treatment. PM@Cur-RV NPs were designed by combining the poly (lactic-co-glycolic acid) nanoparticles (NPs) coated with platelet membrane vesicles (PM) for the purpose of highly targeting delivery of curcumin (Cur) and resveratrol (RV) to inflammatory lungs. PM@Cur-RV NPs showed good biocompatibility and biosafety both in vitro and in vivo. Accumulation of NPs into lung tract was observed after inhaled NPs. Remarkably, the inhalation of PM@Cur-RV NPs effectively inhibited lung vascular injury evidenced by the decreased lung vascular permeability, and the reduced proinflammatory cytokine burden in an ALI mouse model. The analysis of infiltrated macrophages in the lungs showed that the Cur-RV-modulated macrophage polarized towards M2 phenotype and the decreased histone lactylation might contribute to their anti-inflammation effects. Together, this work highlights the potential of inhalation of biomimetic nanoparticle delivery of curcumin and resveratrol for the treatment of pulmonary diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Histone Lactylation Boosts Reparative Gene Activation Post-Myocardial Infarction</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36268709/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36268709/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Inflammation resolution and cardiac repair initiation after myocardial infarction (MI) require timely activation of reparative signals. Histone lactylation confers macrophage homeostatic gene expression signatures via transcriptional regulation. However, the role of histone lactylation in the repair response post-MI remains unclear. We aimed to investigate whether histone lactylation induces reparative gene expression in monocytes early and remotely post-MI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; Single-cell transcriptome data indicated that reparative genes were activated early and remotely in bone marrow and circulating monocytes before cardiac recruitment. Western blotting and immunofluorescence staining revealed increases in histone lactylation levels, including the previously identified histone H3K18 lactylation in monocyte-macrophages early post-MI. Through joint CUT&amp;amp;Tag and RNA-sequencing analyses, we identified Lrg1, Vegf-a, and IL-10 as histone H3K18 lactylation target genes. The increased modification and expression levels of these target genes post-MI were verified by chromatin immunoprecipitation-qPCR and reverse transcription-qPCR.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; We demonstrated that histone lactylation regulates the anti-inflammatory and pro-angiogenic dual activities of monocyte-macrophages by facilitating reparative gene transcription and confirmed that histone lactylation favors a reparative environment and improves cardiac function post-MI. Furthermore, we explored the potential positive role of monocyte histone lactylation in reperfused MI. Mechanistically, we provided new evidence that monocytes undergo metabolic reprogramming in the early stage of MI and demonstrated that dysregulated glycolysis and MCT1 (monocarboxylate transporter 1)-mediated lactate transport promote histone lactylation. Finally, we revealed the catalytic effect of IL (interleukin)-1β-dependent GCN5 (general control non-depressible 5) recruitment on histone H3K18 lactylation and elucidated its potential role as an upstream regulatory element in the regulation of monocyte histone lactylation and downstream reparative gene expression post-MI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; Histone lactylation promotes early remote activation of the reparative transcriptional response in monocytes, which is essential for the establishment of immune homeostasis and timely activation of the cardiac repair process post-MI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lactate induces metabolic and epigenetic reprogramming of pro-inflammatory Th17 cells</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36215678/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36215678/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Increased lactate levels in the tissue microenvironment are a well-known feature of chronic inflammation. However, the role of lactate in regulating T cell function remains controversial. Here, we demonstrate that extracellular lactate predominantly induces deregulation of the Th17-specific gene expression program by modulating the metabolic and epigenetic status of Th17 cells. Following lactate treatment, Th17 cells significantly reduced their IL-17A production and upregulated Foxp3 expression through ROS-driven IL-2 secretion. Moreover, we observed increased levels of genome-wide histone H3K18 lactylation, a recently described marker for active chromatin in macrophages, in lactate-treated Th17 cells. In addition, we show that high lactate concentrations suppress Th17 pathogenicity during intestinal inflammation in mice. These results indicate that lactate is capable of reprogramming pro-inflammatory T cell phenotypes into regulatory T cells.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enterobacterial LPS-inducible LINC00152 is regulated by histone lactylation and promotes cancer cells invasion and migration</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35959377/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35959377/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gut microbes participate in pathogenesis by interacting with the host genome through epigenetic mechanisms, such as long non-coding RNAs. However, the mechanisms by which the microbiota induce expression alteration of long non-coding RNAs remains unclear. Here, we quantified the transcriptome alteration of human colon cell lines after being infected by a common enteric pathogen &lt;em&gt;Salmonella typhimurium SL1344&lt;/em&gt;. We observed a widespread lncRNAs expression alteration. Among them, the elevated expression of LINC00152 was verified and proved to be induced by enteric bacteria-derived lipopolysaccharide (LPS). The inducible LINC00152 were found to inhibit Salmonella invasion and inflammation response. LINC00152 was overexpressed in tumors of the clinical CRC samples compared with adjacent normal tissues. Accordingly, we also demonstrated that overexpression of LINC00152 promoted the migration and invasion of colorectal cancer cells. Consistently, we observed an increased abundance of gram-negative bacteria and LPS in tumors tissue. Taken together, the above data implicated that enriched gram-negative bacteria in tumor tissue might promote tumor growth through modulating the expression of LINC00152. Furthermore, we demonstrated that LPS upregulated the expression of LINC00152 by introducing histone lactylation on its promoter and decreasing the binding efficiency of the repressor, YY1, to it. Our results provide new insights into how enterobacteria affect host epigenetics in human disease.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cyclic immonium ion of lactyllysine reveals widespread lactylation in the human proteome</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35761067/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35761067/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lactylation was initially discovered on human histones. Given its nascence, its occurrence on nonhistone proteins and downstream functional consequences remain elusive. Here we report a cyclic immonium ion of lactyllysine formed during tandem mass spectrometry that enables confident protein lactylation assignment. We validated the sensitivity and specificity of this ion for lactylation through affinity-enriched lactylproteome analysis and large-scale informatic assessment of nonlactylated spectral libraries. With this diagnostic ion-based strategy, we confidently determined new lactylation, unveiling a wide landscape beyond histones from not only the enriched lactylproteome but also existing unenriched human proteome resources. Specifically, by mining the public human Meltome Atlas, we found that lactylation is common on glycolytic enzymes and conserved on ALDOA. We also discovered prevalent lactylation on DHRS7 in the draft of the human tissue proteome. We partially demonstrated the functional importance of lactylation: site-specific engineering of lactylation into ALDOA caused enzyme inhibition, suggesting a lactylation-dependent feedback loop in glycolysis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tumor-Derived Lactate Creates a Favorable Niche for Tumor via Supplying Energy Source for Tumor and Modulating the Tumor Microenvironment</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/35646923/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/35646923/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tumor evolution is influenced by events involving tumor cells and the environment in which they live, known as the tumor microenvironment (TME). TME is a functional and structural niche composed of tumor cells, endothelial cells (ECs), cancer-associated fibroblasts (CAFs), mesenchymal stromal cells (MSCs), and a subset of immune cells (macrophages, dendritic cells, natural killer cells, T cells, B cells). Otto Warburg revealed the Warburg effect in 1923, a characteristic metabolic mechanism of tumor cells that performs high glucose uptake and excessive lactate formation even in abundant oxygen. Tumor tissues excrete a large amount of lactate into the extracellular microenvironment in response to TME&amp;rsquo;s hypoxic or semi-hypoxic state. High lactate concentrations in tumor biopsies have been linked to metastasis and poor clinical outcome. This indicates that the metabolite may play a role in carcinogenesis and lead to immune escape in TME. Lactate is now recognized as an essential carbon source for cellular metabolism and as a signaling molecule in TME, forming an active niche that influences tumor progression. This review summarized the advanced literature demonstrating the functional role of lactate in TME remodeling, elucidating how lactate shapes the behavior and the phenotype of both tumor cells and tumor-associated cells. We also concluded the intriguing interactions of multiple immune cells in TME. Additionally, we demonstrated how lactate functioned as a novel function factor by being used in a new histone modification, histone lysine lactylation, and to regulate gene expression in TME. Ultimately, because lactate created a favorable niche for tumor progression, we summarized potential anti-tumor strategies targeting lactate metabolism and signaling to investigate better cancer treatment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Positive feedback regulation of microglial glucose metabolism by histone H4 lysine 12 lactylation in Alzheimer&#39;s disease</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35303422/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35303422/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Histone lactylation is elevated in the brains of 5XFAD model mice and AD patients&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;H4K12la activates transcription of glycolytic genes in AD microglia&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A glycolysis/H4K12la/PKM2 positive feedback loop exacerbates microglial dysfunction&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interruption of this loop ameliorates microglial dysfunction and Aβ pathology&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The pro-inflammatory activation of microglia is a hallmark of Alzheimer&amp;rsquo;s disease (AD), and this process involves a switch from oxidative phosphorylation (OXPHOS) toward glycolysis. Here, we show how a positive feedback loop in microglia drives AD pathogenesis, and we demonstrate that inhibiting this cycle in microglia can ameliorate Aβ burden and cognitive deficits in an AD mouse model (5XFAD). After first detecting elevated histone lactylation in brain samples from both 5XFAD mice and individuals with AD, we observed that H4K12la levels are elevated in Aβ plaque-adjacent microglia. This lactate-dependent histone modification is enriched at the promoters of glycolytic genes and activates transcription, thereby increasing glycolytic activity. Ultimately, the glycolysis/H4K12la/PKM2 positive feedback loop exacerbates microglial dysfunction in AD. Pharmacologic inhibition of PKM2 attenuated microglial activation, and microglia-specific ablation of Pkm2 improved spatial learning and memory in AD mice. Thus, our study illustrates that disruption of the positive feedback loop may be a potential therapeutic approach for the treatment of AD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lung Myofibroblasts Promote Macrophage Profibrotic Activity through Lactate-induced Histone Lactylation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33074715/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33074715/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Augmented glycolysis due to metabolic reprogramming in lung myofibroblasts is critical to their profibrotic phenotype. The primary glycolysis byproduct, lactate, is also secreted into the extracellular milieu, together with which myofibroblasts and macrophages form a spatially restricted site usually described as fibrotic niche. Therefore, we hypothesized that myofibroblast glycolysis might have a non-cell autonomous effect through lactate regulating the pathogenic phenotype of alveolar macrophages. Here, we demonstrated that there was a markedly increased lactate in the conditioned media of TGF-β1 (transforming growth factor-β1)-induced lung myofibroblasts and in the BAL fluids (BALFs) from mice with TGF-β1- or bleomycin-induced lung fibrosis. Importantly, the media and BALFs promoted profibrotic mediator expression in macrophages. Mechanistically, lactate induced histone lactylation in the promoters of the profibrotic genes in macrophages, consistent with the upregulation of this epigenetic modification in these cells in the fibrotic lungs. The lactate inductions of the histone lactylation and profibrotic gene expression were mediated by p300, as evidenced by their diminished concentrations in p300-knockdown macrophages. Collectively, our study establishes that in addition to protein, lipid, and nucleic acid molecules, a metabolite can also mediate intercellular regulations in the setting of lung fibrosis. Our findings shed new light on the mechanism underlying the key contribution of myofibroblast glycolysis to the pathogenesis of lung fibrosis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TLR signaling adapter BCAP regulates inflammatory to reparatory macrophage transition by promoting histone lactylation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33199625/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33199625/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Macrophages respond to microbial ligands and various noxious cues by initiating an inflammatory response aimed at eliminating the original pathogenic insult. Transition of macrophages from a proinflammatory state to a reparative state, however, is vital for resolution of inflammation and return to homeostasis. The molecular players governing this transition remain poorly defined. Here, we find that the reparative macrophage transition is dictated by B-cell adapter for PI3K (BCAP). Mice harboring a macrophage-specific deletion of BCAP fail to recover from and succumb to dextran sulfate sodium-induced colitis due to prolonged intestinal inflammation and impaired tissue repair. Following microbial stimulation, gene expression in WT macrophages switches from an early inflammatory signature to a late reparative signature, a process that is hampered in BCAP-deficient macrophages. We find that absence of BCAP hinders inactivation of FOXO1 and GSK3β, which contributes to their enhanced inflammatory state. BCAP deficiency also results in defective aerobic glycolysis and reduced lactate production. This translates into reduced histone lactylation and decreased expression of reparative macrophage genes. Thus, our results reveal BCAP to be a critical cell-intrinsic switch that regulates transition of inflammatory macrophages to reparative macrophages by imprinting epigenetic changes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Significance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Macrophages initiate inflammation to eliminate invading microbes. Following clearance of inflammatory stimuli, macrophages down-regulate inflammatory genes and express repair genes to protect host tissues from damage. Here, we find that the adaptor B-cell adapter for PI3K (BCAP) facilitates this transition of inflammatory macrophages to reparative macrophages. Absence of BCAP in macrophages limits the ability of mice to repair intestinal tissues following inflammatory damage. Following Toll-like receptor stimulation, macrophages undergo aerobic glycolysis that results in lactate production, a process compromised in BCAP-deficient macrophages. This lactate is incorporated into histone tails and is involved in reparative macrophage transition. We find defective lactate production by BCAP-deficient macrophages results in reduced histone lactylation and expression of tissue repair genes, thus blunting their reparative transition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Metabolic regulation of gene expression by histone lactylation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/31645732/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/31645732/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Warburg effect, which originally described increased production of lactate in cancer, is associated with diverse cellular processes such as angiogenesis, hypoxia, polarization of macrophages and activation of T cells. This phenomenon is intimately linked to several diseases including neoplasia, sepsis and autoimmune diseases1,2. Lactate, which is converted from pyruvate in tumour cells, is widely known as an energy source and metabolic by-product. However, its non-metabolic functions in physiology and disease remain unknown. Here we show that lactate-derived lactylation of histone lysine residues serves as an epigenetic modification that directly stimulates gene transcription from chromatin. We identify 28 lactylation sites on core histones in human and mouse cells. Hypoxia and bacterial challenges induce the production of lactate by glycolysis, and this acts as a precursor that stimulates histone lactylation. Using M1 macrophages that have been exposed to bacteria as a model system, we show that histone lactylation has different temporal dynamics from acetylation. In the late phase of M1 macrophage polarization, increased histone lactylation induces homeostatic genes that are involved in wound healing, including Arg1. Collectively, our results suggest that an endogenous ‘lactate clock’ in bacterially challenged M1 macrophages turns on gene expression to promote homeostasis. Histone lactylation thus represents an opportunity to improve our understanding of the functions of lactate and its role in diverse pathophysiological conditions, including infection and cancer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
