<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Polyadenylation | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/polyadenylation/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/polyadenylation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Polyadenylation</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Polyadenylation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/polyadenylation/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>ipaQTL-atlas: an atlas of intronic polyadenylation quantitative trait loci across human tissues</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36043442/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36043442/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Functional interpretation of disease-associated non-coding variants remains a significant challenge in the post-GWAS era. Our recent study has identified 3&amp;rsquo;UTR alternative polyadenylation (APA) quantitative trait loci (3&amp;rsquo;aQTLs) and connects APA events with QTLs as a major driver of human traits and diseases. Besides 3&amp;rsquo;UTR, APA events can also occur in intron regions, and increasing evidence has connected intronic polyadenylation with disease risk. However, systematic investigation of the roles of intronic polyadenylation in human diseases remained challenging due to the lack of a comprehensive database across a variety of human tissues. Here, we developed &lt;a href=&#34;http://bioinfo.szbl.ac.cn/ipaQTL&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;ipaQTL-atlas&lt;/a&gt; as the first comprehensive portal for intronic polyadenylation. The &lt;a href=&#34;http://bioinfo.szbl.ac.cn/ipaQTL&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;ipaQTL-atlas&lt;/a&gt; is based on the analysis of 15 170 RNA-seq data from 838 individuals across 49 Genotype-Tissue Expression (GTEx v8) tissues and contains ∼0.98 million SNPs associated with intronic APA events. It provides an interface for ipaQTLs search, genome browser, boxplots, and data download, as well as the visualization of GWAS and ipaQTL colocalization results. &lt;a href=&#34;http://bioinfo.szbl.ac.cn/ipaQTL&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;ipaQTL-atlas&lt;/a&gt; provides a one-stop portal to access intronic polyadenylation information and could significantly advance the discovery of APA-associated disease susceptibility genes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transcript shortening via alternative polyadenylation promotes gene expression during fracture healing</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36596777/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36596777/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maturation of the 3&amp;rsquo; end of almost all eukaryotic messenger RNAs (mRNAs) requires cleavage and polyadenylation. Most mammalian mRNAs are polyadenylated at different sites within the last exon, generating alternative polyadenylation (APA) isoforms that have the same coding region but distinct 3&amp;rsquo; untranslated regions (UTRs). The 3&amp;rsquo;UTR contains motifs that regulate mRNA metabolism; thus, changing the 3&amp;rsquo;UTR length via APA can significantly affect gene expression. Endochondral ossification is a central process in bone healing, but the impact of APA on gene expression during this process is unknown. Here, we report the widespread occurrence of APA, which impacts multiple pathways that are known to participate in bone healing. Importantly, the progression of endochondral ossification involves global 3&amp;rsquo;UTR shortening, which is coupled with an increased abundance of shortened transcripts relative to other transcripts; these results highlight the role of APA in promoting gene expression during endochondral bone formation. Our mechanistic studies of transcripts that undergo APA in the fracture callus revealed an intricate regulatory network in which APA enhances the expression of the collagen, type I, alpha 1 (Col1a1) and Col1a2 genes, which encode the 2 subunits of the abundantly expressed protein collagen 1. APA exerts this effect by shortening the 3&amp;rsquo;UTRs of the Col1a1 and Col1a2 mRNAs, thus removing the binding sites of miR-29a-3p, which would otherwise strongly promote the degradation of both transcripts. Taken together, our study is the first to characterize the crucial roles of APA in regulating the 3&amp;rsquo;UTR landscape and modulating gene expression during fracture healing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The transcriptional terminator XRN2 and the RNA-binding protein Sam68 link alternative polyadenylation to cell cycle progression in prostate cancer</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36344846/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36344846/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alternative polyadenylation (APA) yields transcripts differing in their 3′-end, and its regulation is altered in cancer, including prostate cancer. Here we have uncovered a mechanism of APA regulation impinging on the interaction between the exonuclease XRN2 and the RNA-binding protein Sam68, whose increased expression in prostate cancer is promoted by the transcription factor MYC. Genome-wide transcriptome profiling revealed a widespread impact of the Sam68/XRN2 complex on APA. XRN2 promotes recruitment of Sam68 to its target transcripts, where it competes with the cleavage and polyadenylation specificity factor for binding to strong polyadenylation signals at distal ends of genes, thus promoting usage of suboptimal proximal polyadenylation signals. This mechanism leads to 3′ untranslated region shortening and translation of transcripts encoding proteins involved in G1/S progression and proliferation. Thus, our findings indicate that the APA program driven by Sam68/XRN2 promotes cell cycle progression and may represent an actionable target for therapeutic intervention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ReadZS detects cell type-specific and developmentally regulated RNA processing programs in single-cell RNA-seq</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36284317/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36284317/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;RNA processing, including splicing and alternative polyadenylation, is crucial to gene function and regulation, but methods to detect RNA processing from single-cell RNA sequencing data are limited by reliance on pre-existing annotations, peak calling heuristics, and collapsing measurements by cell type. We introduce ReadZS, an annotation-free statistical approach to identify regulated RNA processing in single cells. ReadZS discovers cell type-specific RNA processing in human lung and conserved, developmentally regulated RNA processing in mammalian spermatogenesis-including global 3&amp;rsquo; UTR shortening in human spermatogenesis. ReadZS also discovers global 3&amp;rsquo; UTR lengthening in Arabidopsis development, highlighting the usefulness of this method in under-annotated transcriptomes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alternative cleavage and polyadenylation generates downstream uncapped RNA isoforms with translation potential</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36270248/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36270248/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The human transcriptome contains thousands of uncapped poly(A) RNA transcripts (5′ UPTs)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Alternative cleavage and polyadenylation (APA) is a major driver of 5′ UPTs biogenesis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;5′ ends of 5′ UPTs are characterized by structured RNA and m6A modification&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;5′ UPTs CAP-independent translation alters the proteome and immunopeptidome repertoire&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The use of alternative promoters, splicing, and cleavage and polyadenylation (APA) generates mRNA isoforms that expand the diversity and complexity of the transcriptome. Here, we uncovered thousands of previously undescribed 5&amp;rsquo; uncapped and polyadenylated transcripts (5&amp;rsquo; UPTs). We show that these transcripts resist exonucleases due to a highly structured RNA and N6-methyladenosine modification at their 5&amp;rsquo; termini. 5&amp;rsquo; UPTs appear downstream of APA sites within their host genes and are induced upon APA activation. Strong enrichment in polysomal RNA fractions indicates 5&amp;rsquo; UPT translational potential. Indeed, APA promotes downstream translation initiation, non-canonical protein output, and consistent changes to peptide presentation at the cell surface. Lastly, we demonstrate the biological importance of 5&amp;rsquo; UPTs using Bcl2, a prominent anti-apoptotic gene whose entire coding sequence is a 5&amp;rsquo; UPT generated from 5&amp;rsquo; UTR-embedded APA sites. Thus, APA is not only accountable for terminating transcripts, but also for generating downstream uncapped RNAs with translation potential and biological impact.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Diverse cell-specific patterns of alternative polyadenylation in Drosophila</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36100597/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36100597/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most genes in higher eukaryotes express isoforms with distinct 3&amp;rsquo; untranslated regions (3&amp;rsquo; UTRs), generated by alternative polyadenylation (APA). Since 3&amp;rsquo; UTRs are predominant locations of post-transcriptional regulation, APA can render such programs conditional, and can also alter protein sequences via alternative last exon (ALE) isoforms. We previously used 3&amp;rsquo;-sequencing from diverse &lt;em&gt;Drosophila&lt;/em&gt; samples to define multiple tissue-specific APA landscapes. Here, we exploit comprehensive single nucleus RNA-sequencing data (Fly Cell Atlas) to elucidate cell-type expression of 3&amp;rsquo; UTRs across &amp;gt;250 adult &lt;em&gt;Drosophila&lt;/em&gt; cell types. We reveal the cellular bases of multiple tissue-specific APA/ALE programs, such as 3&amp;rsquo; UTR lengthening in differentiated neurons and 3&amp;rsquo; UTR shortening in spermatocytes and spermatids. We trace dynamic 3&amp;rsquo; UTR patterns across cell lineages, including in the male germline, and discover new APA patterns in the intestinal stem cell lineage. Finally, we correlate expression of RNA binding proteins (RBPs), miRNAs and global levels of cleavage and polyadenylation (CPA) factors in several cell types that exhibit characteristic APA landscapes, yielding candidate regulators of transcriptome complexity. These analyses provide a comprehensive foundation for future investigations of mechanisms and biological impacts of alternative 3&amp;rsquo; isoforms across the major cell types of this widely-studied model organism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Polyadenylation ligation-mediated sequencing (PALM-Seq) characterizes cell-free coding and non-coding RNAs in human biofluids</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35858042/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35858042/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Cell-free messenger RNA (cf-mRNA) and long non-coding RNA (cf-lncRNA) are becoming increasingly important in liquid biopsy by providing biomarkers for disease prediction, diagnosis and prognosis, but the simultaneous characterization of coding and non-coding RNAs in human biofluids remains challenging.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; Here, we developed polyadenylation ligation-mediated sequencing (PALM-Seq), an RNA sequencing strategy employing treatment of RNA with T4 polynucleotide kinase to generate cell-free RNA (cfRNA) fragments with 5&amp;rsquo; phosphate and 3&amp;rsquo; hydroxyl and RNase H to deplete abundant RNAs, achieving simultaneous quantification and characterization of cfRNAs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; Using PALM-Seq, we successfully identified well-known differentially abundant mRNA, lncRNA and microRNA in the blood plasma of pregnant women. We further characterized cfRNAs in blood plasma, saliva, urine, seminal plasma and amniotic fluid and found that the detected numbers of different RNA biotypes varied with body fluids. The profiles of cf-mRNA reflected the function of originated tissues, and immune cells significantly contributed RNA to blood plasma and saliva. Short fragments (&amp;lt;50 nt) of mRNA and lncRNA were major in biofluids, whereas seminal plasma and amniotic fluid tended to retain long RNA. Body fluids showed distinct preferences of pyrimidine at the 3&amp;rsquo; end and adenine at the 5&amp;rsquo; end of cf-mRNA and cf-lncRNA, which were correlated with the proportions of short fragments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/em&gt; Together, PALM-Seq enables a simultaneous characterization of cf-mRNA and cf-lncRNA, contributing to elucidating the biology and promoting the application of cfRNAs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Context-specific regulation and function of mRNA alternative polyadenylation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/35798852/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/35798852/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alternative cleavage and polyadenylation (APA) is a widespread mechanism to generate mRNA isoforms with alternative 3&amp;rsquo; untranslated regions (UTRs). The expression of alternative 3&amp;rsquo; UTR isoforms is highly cell type specific and is further controlled in a gene-specific manner by environmental cues. In this Review, we discuss how the dynamic, fine-grained regulation of APA is accomplished by several mechanisms, including cis-regulatory elements in RNA and DNA and factors that control transcription, pre-mRNA cleavage and post-transcriptional processes. Furthermore, signalling pathways modulate the activity of these factors and integrate APA into gene regulatory programmes. Dysregulation of APA can reprogramme the outcome of signalling pathways and thus can control cellular responses to environmental changes. In addition to the regulation of protein abundance, APA has emerged as a major regulator of mRNA localization and the spatial organization of protein synthesis. This role enables the regulation of protein function through the addition of post-translational modifications or the formation of protein-protein interactions. We further discuss recent transformative advances in single-cell RNA sequencing and CRISPR-Cas technologies, which enable the mapping and functional characterization of alternative 3&amp;rsquo; UTRs in any biological context. Finally, we discuss new APA-based RNA therapeutics, including compounds that target APA in cancer and therapeutic genome editing of degenerative diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>scAPAdb: a comprehensive database of alternative polyadenylation at single-cell resolution</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34508354/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34508354/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alternative polyadenylation (APA) is a widespread regulatory mechanism of transcript diversification in eukaryotes, which is increasingly recognized as an important layer for eukaryotic gene expression. Recent studies based on single-cell RNA-seq (scRNA-seq) have revealed cell-to-cell heterogeneity in APA usage and APA dynamics across different cell types in various tissues, biological processes and diseases. However, currently available APA databases were all collected from bulk 3′-seq and/or RNA-seq data, and no existing database has provided APA information at single-cell resolution. Here, we present a user-friendly database called &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bmibig.cn/scAPAdb&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;scAPAdb&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, which provides a comprehensive and manually curated atlas of poly(A) sites, APA events and poly(A) signals at the single-cell level. Currently, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bmibig.cn/scAPAdb&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;scAPAdb&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; collects APA information from &amp;gt; 360 scRNA-seq experiments, covering six species including human, mouse and several other plant species. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bmibig.cn/scAPAdb&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;scAPAdb&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; also provides batch download of data, and users can query the database through a variety of keywords such as gene identifier, gene function and accession number. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bmibig.cn/scAPAdb&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;scAPAdb&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; would be a valuable and extendable resource for the study of cell-to-cell heterogeneity in APA isoform usages and APA-mediated gene regulation at the single-cell level under diverse cell types, tissues and species.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
