<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Adenovirus/AAV | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/adenovirus/aav/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/adenovirus/aav/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Adenovirus/AAV</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Adenovirus/AAV</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/adenovirus/aav/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>An evolved AAV variant enables efficient genetic engineering of murine T cells</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36638795/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36638795/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A murine T cell-specific AAV variant, Ark313, is discovered through AAV6 evolution&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A genome-wide CRISPR screen identifies QA2 an essential factor for Ark313 transduction&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ark313 enables efficient transgene delivery and targeting of large DNA payloads&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Trac&lt;/em&gt; targeting of a CAR outperforms semi-random integration in a solid tumor model&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Precise targeting of large transgenes to T cells using homology-directed repair has been transformative for adoptive cell therapies and T cell biology. Delivery of DNA templates via adeno-associated virus (AAV) has greatly improved knockin efficiencies, but the tropism of current AAV serotypes restricts their use to human T cells employed in immunodeficient mouse models. To enable targeted knockins in murine T cells, we evolved Ark313, a synthetic AAV that exhibits high transduction efficiency in murine T cells. We performed a genome-wide knockout screen and identified QA2 as an essential factor for Ark313 infection. We demonstrate that Ark313 can be used for nucleofection-free DNA delivery, CRISPR-Cas9-mediated knockouts, and targeted integration of large transgenes. Ark313 enables preclinical modeling of &lt;em&gt;Trac&lt;/em&gt;-targeted CAR-T and transgenic TCR-T cells in immunocompetent models. Efficient gene targeting in murine T cells holds great potential for improved cell therapies and opens avenues in experimental T cell immunology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extracellular traps from activated vascular smooth muscle cells drive the progression of atherosclerosis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36473863/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36473863/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Extracellular DNA traps (ETs) represent an immune response by which cells release essential materials like chromatin and granular proteins. Previous studies have demonstrated that the transdifferentiation of vascular smooth muscle cells (VSMCs) plays a crucial role in atherosclerosis. This study seeks to investigate the interaction between CD68&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; VSMCs and the formation of ETs and highlight its function in atherosclerosis. Here we show that ETs are inhibited, and atherosclerotic plaque formation is alleviated in male Myh11&lt;sup&gt;Cre&lt;/sup&gt;Pad4&lt;sup&gt;flox/flox&lt;/sup&gt; mice undergoing an adeno-associated-virus-8 (AAV8) mediating overexpression of proprotein convertase subtilisin/kexin type 9 mutation (PCSK9) injection and being challenged with a high-fat diet. Obvious ETs generated from CD68&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; VSMCs are inhibited by Cl-amidine and DNase I in vitro. By utilizing VSMCs-lineage tracing technology and single-cell RNA sequencing (scRNA-seq), we demonstrate that the ETs from CD68&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; VSMCs influence the progress of atherosclerosis by regulating the direction of VSMCs&amp;rsquo; transdifferentiation through STING-SOCS1 or TLR4 signaling pathway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Activation of Pancreatic Acinar FXR Protects against Pancreatitis via Osgin1-Mediated Restoration of Efficient Autophagy</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36405253/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36405253/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pancreatitis is the leading cause of hospitalization in gastroenterology, and no medications are available for treating this disease in current clinical practice. FXR plays an anti-inflammatory role in diverse inflammatory diseases, while its function in pancreatitis remains unknown. In this study, we initially observed a marked increase of nuclear FXR in pancreatic tissues of human patients with pancreatitis. Deleting the FXR in pancreatic acinar cells (FXR&lt;sup&gt;acinarΔ/Δ &lt;/sup&gt;) led to more severe pancreatitis in mouse models of caerulein-induced acute and chronic pancreatitis, while the FXR agonist GW4064 significantly attenuated pancreatitis in caerulein or arginine-induced acute pancreatitis and caerulein-induced chronic pancreatitis. FXR deletion impaired the viability and stress responses of pancreatic exocrine organoids (PEOs) in vitro. Utilizing RNA-seq and ChIP-seq of PEOs, we identified &lt;em&gt;Osgin1&lt;/em&gt; as a direct target of FXR in the exocrine pancreas, which was also increasingly expressed in human pancreatitis tissues compared to normal pancreatic tissues. Pancreatic knockdown of &lt;em&gt;Osgin1&lt;/em&gt; by AAV-pan abolished the therapeutic effects of FXR activation on pancreatitis, whereas pancreatic overexpression of &lt;em&gt;Osgin1&lt;/em&gt; effectively alleviated caerulein-induced pancreatitis. Mechanistically, we found that the FXR-OSGIN1 axis stimulated autophagic flux in the pancreatic tissues and cell lines, which was considered as the intrinsic mechanisms through which FXR-OSGIN1 protecting against pancreatitis. Our results highlight the protective role of the FXR-OSGIN1 axis in pancreatitis and provided a new target for the treatment of this disease.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AAV vectors: The Rubik&#39;s cube of human gene therapy</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/36203359/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/36203359/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Defective genes account for ∼80% of the total of more than 7,000 diseases known to date. Gene therapy brings the promise of a one-time treatment option that will fix the errors in patient genetic coding. Recombinant viruses are highly efficient vehicles for in vivo gene delivery. Adeno-associated virus (AAV) vectors offer unique advantages, such as tissue tropism, specificity in transduction, eliciting of a relatively low immune responses, no incorporation into the host chromosome, and long-lasting delivered gene expression, making them the most popular viral gene delivery system in clinical trials, with three AAV-based gene therapy drugs already approved by the US Food and Drug Administration (FDA) or European Medicines Agency (EMA). Despite the success of AAV vectors, their usage in particular scenarios is still limited due to remaining challenges, such as poor transduction efficiency in certain tissues, low organ specificity, pre-existing humoral immunity to AAV capsids, and vector dose-dependent toxicity in patients. In the present review, we address the different approaches to improve AAV vectors for gene therapy with a focus on AAV capsid selection and engineering, strategies to overcome anti-AAV immune response, and vector genome design, ending with a glimpse at vector production methods and the current state of recombinant AAV (rAAV) at the clinical level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AAV capsid engineering identified two novel variants with improved in vivo tropism for cardiomyocytes</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35810332/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35810332/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AAV vectors are promising delivery tools for human gene therapy. However, broad tissue tropism and pre-existing immunity against natural serotypes limit their clinical use. We identified two AAV capsid variants, AAV2-THGTPAD and AAV2-NLPGSGD, by in vivo AAV2 peptide display library screening in a murine model of pressure overload-induced cardiac hypertrophy. Both variants showed significantly improved efficacy in in vivo cardiomyocyte transduction compared with the parental serotype AAV2 as indicated by a higher number of AAV vector episomes in the nucleus and significant improved transduction efficiency. Both variants also outcompeted the reference serotype AAV9 regarding cardiomyocyte tropism, reaching comparable cardiac transduction efficiencies accompanied with liver de-targeting and decreased transduction efficiency of non-cardiac cells. Capsid modification influenced immunogenicity as sera of mice treated with AAV2-THGTPAD and AAV2-NLPGSGD demonstrated a poor neutralization capacity for the parental serotype and the novel variants. In a therapeutic setting, using the long non-coding RNA H19 in low vector dose conditions, novel AAV variants mediated superior anti-hypertrophic effects and revealed a further improved target-to-noise ratio, i.e., cardiomyocyte tropism. In conclusion, AAV2-THGTPAD and AAV2-NLPGSGD are promising novel tools for cardiac-directed gene therapy outperforming AAV9 regarding the specificity and therapeutic efficiency of in vivo cardiomyocyte transduction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Soluble Receptor for Advanced Glycation End Product Is Involved in the Inflammatory Response of Human Adenovirus-Infected Patients</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35875560/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35875560/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Human adenovirus (HAdV) infection causes excessive inflammation associated with severe tissue injury, such as pneumonia. The molecules involved in the underlying inflammatory mechanisms remain to be elucidated. Receptor for advanced glycation end product (RAGE) is mainly expressed on immune cells and lung tissues, and it is a key factor in the initiation and development of inflammation. RAGE can be cleaved by metalloprotease 9 (MMP9) to release the extracellular segment, which is named soluble RAGE (sRAGE), into the intercellular space, where it can bind to RAGE ligands and block RAGE activation and subsequent inflammation. In our study, we enrolled HAdV-infected patients and their contacts to examine the relationship between sRAGE and inflammation induced by HAdV infection. The results showed that HAdV infection stimulated inflammatory cytokine secretion, increased such as high mobility group box 1 (HMGB1) levels, and suppressed sRAGE expression. sRAGE levels were significantly different between patients with or without pneumonia. We also found that MMP9 was significantly lower in patients with pneumonia, and it was positively correlated with sRAGE levels over 7 days after disease onset. The mitogen-activated protein kinase (MAPK) pathway is an important immune activation signaling pathway that is regulated by RAGE. We observed the activation of the MAPK pathway in the peripheral blood mononuclear cells (PBMCs) of patients. Negative correlations between sRAGE and phosphorylated JNK and p38 were observed. These results suggest that sRAGE is involved in HAdV-induced inflammatory responses, and might be a potential therapeutic target to alleviate the HAdV-induced excessive inflammation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Characterization of a flexible AAV-DTR/DT mouse model of acute epithelial lung injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35762632/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35762632/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Animal models are important to mimic certain pathways or biological aspects of human pathologies including acute and chronic pulmonary diseases. We developed a novel and flexible mouse model of acute epithelial lung injury based on adeno-associated virus (AAV) variant 6.2-mediated expression of the human diphtheria toxin receptor (DTR). Following intratracheal administration of diphtheria toxin (DT), a cell-specific death of bronchial and alveolar epithelial cells can be observed. In contrast to other lung injury models, the here described mouse model provides the possibility of targeted injury using specific tropisms of AAV vectors or cell-type-specific promotors to drive the human DTR expression. Also, generation of cell-specific mouse lines is not required. Detailed characterization of the AAV-DTR/DT mouse model including titration of viral genome (vg) load and administered DT amount revealed increasing cell numbers in bronchoalveolar lavage (BAL; macrophages, neutrophils, and unspecified cells) and elevation of degenerated cells and infiltrated leukocytes in lung tissue, dependent of vg load and DT dose. Cytokine levels in BAL fluid showed different patterns with higher vg load, e.g., IFNγ, TNFα, and IP10 increasing and IL-5 and IL-6 decreasing, whereas lung function was not affected. In addition, laser-capture microdissection (LCM)-based proteomics of bronchial epithelium and alveolar tissue revealed upregulated immune and inflammatory responses in all regions and extracellular matrix deposition in infiltrated alveoli. Overall, our novel AAV-DTR/DT model allows investigation of repair mechanisms following epithelial injury and resembles specific mechanistic aspects of acute and chronic pulmonary diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A circular RNA derived from the insulin receptor locus protects against doxorubicin-induced cardiotoxicity</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35758064/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35758064/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Aims:&lt;/em&gt; Cardiotoxicity leading to heart failure (HF) is a growing problem in many cancer survivors. As specific treatment strategies are not available, RNA discovery pipelines were employed and a new and powerful circular RNA (circRNA)-based therapy was developed for the treatment of doxorubicin-induced HF.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods and results:&lt;/em&gt; The circRNA sequencing was applied and the highly species-conserved circRNA insulin receptor (Circ-INSR) was identified, which participates in HF processes, including those provoked by cardiotoxic anti-cancer treatments. Chemotherapy-provoked cardiotoxicity leads to the down-regulation of Circ-INSR in rodents and patients, which mechanistically contributes to cardiomyocyte cell death, cardiac dysfunction, and mitochondrial damage. In contrast, Circ-INSR overexpression prevented doxorubicin-mediated cardiotoxicity in both rodent and human cardiomyocytes in vitro and in a mouse model of chronic doxorubicin cardiotoxicity. Breast cancer type 1 susceptibility protein (Brca1) was identified as a regulator of Circ-INSR expression. Detailed transcriptomic and proteomic analyses revealed that Circ-INSR regulates apoptotic and metabolic pathways in cardiomyocytes. Circ-INSR physically interacts with the single-stranded DNA-binding protein (SSBP1) mediating its cardioprotective effects under doxorubicin stress. Importantly, in vitro transcribed and circularized Circ-INSR mimics also protected against doxorubicin-induced cardiotoxicity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/em&gt; Circ-INSR is a highly conserved non-coding RNA which is down-regulated during cardiotoxicity and cardiac remodelling. Adeno-associated virus and circRNA mimics-based Circ-INSR overexpression prevent and reverse doxorubicin-mediated cardiomyocyte death and improve cardiac function. The results of this study highlight a novel and translationally important Circ-INSR-based therapeutic approach for doxorubicin-induced cardiac dysfunction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A High-Efficiency AAV for Endothelial Cell Transduction Throughout the Central Nervous System</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35571675/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35571675/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Endothelial cells have a crucial role in nervous system function, and mounting evidence points to endothelial impairment as a major contributor to a wide range of neurological diseases. However, tools to genetically interrogate these cells in vivo remain limited. Here, we describe AAV-BI30, a capsid that specifically and efficiently transduces endothelial cells throughout the central nervous system. At relatively low systemic doses, this vector transduces the majority of arterial, capillary, and venous endothelial cells in the brain, retina, and spinal cord vasculature of adult C57BL/6 mice. Furthermore, we show that AAV-BI30 robustly transduces endothelial cells in multiple mouse strains and rats in vivo and human brain microvascular endothelial cells in vitro. Finally, we demonstrate AAV-BI30&amp;rsquo;s capacity to achieve efficient and endothelial-specific Cre-mediated gene manipulation in the central nervous system. This combination of attributes makes AAV-BI30 uniquely well-suited to address outstanding research questions in neurovascular biology and aid the development of therapeutics to remediate endothelial dysfunction in disease.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inhibition of METTL3 attenuates renal injury and inflammation by alleviating TAB3 m6A modifications via IGF2BP2-dependent mechanisms</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35417191/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35417191/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The role of N&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;-methyladenosine (m6A) modifications in renal diseases is largely unknown. Here, we characterized the role of N&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;-adenosine-methyltransferase-like 3 (METTL3), whose expression is elevated in renal tubules in different acute kidney injury (AKI) models as well as in human biopsies and cultured tubular epithelial cells (TECs). &lt;em&gt;METTL3&lt;/em&gt; silencing alleviated renal inflammation and programmed cell death in TECs in response to stimulation by tumor necrosis factor-α (TNF-α), cisplatin, and lipopolysaccharide (LPS), whereas METTL3 overexpression had the opposite effects. Conditional knockout of &lt;em&gt;METTL3&lt;/em&gt; from mouse kidneys attenuated cisplatin- and ischemic/reperfusion (I/R)-induced renal dysfunction, injury, and inflammation. Moreover, &lt;em&gt;TAB3&lt;/em&gt; [TGF-β-activated kinase 1 (MAP3K7) binding protein 3] was identified as a target of METTL3 by m6A methylated RNA immunoprecipitation sequencing and RNA sequencing. The stability of TAB3 was increased through binding of IGF2BP2 (insulin-like growth factor 2 binding protein 2) to its m6A-modified stop codon regions. The proinflammatory effects of TAB3 were then explored both &lt;em&gt;in vitro&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt;. Adeno-associated virus 9 (AAV9)-mediated &lt;em&gt;METTL3&lt;/em&gt; silencing attenuated renal injury and inflammation in cisplatin- and LPS-induced AKI mouse models. We further identified Cpd-564 as a METTL3 inhibitor that had better protective effects against cisplatin- and ischemia/reperfusion-induced renal injury and inflammation than S-adenosyl-l-homocysteine, a previously identified METTL3 inhibitor. Collectively, METTL3 promoted m6A modifications of TAB3 and enhanced its stability via IGF2BP2-dependent mechanisms. Both genetic and pharmacological inhibition of METTL3 attenuated renal injury and inflammation, suggesting that the METTL3/TAB3 axis is a potential target for treatment of AKI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An adapted passive model of anti-MPO dependent crescentic glomerulonephritis reveals matrix dysregulation and is amenable to modulation by CXCR4 inhibition</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35032611/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35032611/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pathway analysis of the gene profiling microarray data demonstrates distinct activation of ECM-associated pathways in AAV patients.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We established and characterized an adapted and robust anti-MPO antibody-dependent murine AAV model that progresses from acute injury to glomerular and interstitial scarring.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Our AAV model presents already at the acute phase immune infiltrates, activation of immune cells, response to cytokine production and matrisomal changes that phenocopy very well the human pathology.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We identified CXCR4 as an interesting therapeutical target that decreases the activation of immune cells in the acute phase of AAV.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We developed and characterized a murine model of FNGN that recapitulates important clinical, histological and molecular features of human renal AAV.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Our model is suitable for studying chronic scarring injury and matrix remodeling.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mass spectrometry-based proteomics provide a comprehensive analysis of inflammation and altered matrisome expression occurring early in injury.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We show that our model can be used for pharmacological studies and highlight CXCR4 as a potential target.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anti-neutrophil cytoplasmic antibody (ANCA)-associated vasculitides (AAV) are severe inflammatory disorders that often involve focal necrotizing glomerulonephritis (FNGN) and consequent glomerular scarring, interstitial fibrosis, and chronic kidney disease. Robust murine models of scarring in FNGN that may help to further our understanding of deleterious processes are still lacking. Here, we present a murine model of severe FNGN based on combined administration of antibodies against the glomerular basement membrane (GBM) and myeloperoxidase (MPO), and bacterial lipopolysaccharides (LPS), that recapitulates acute injury and was adapted to investigate subsequent glomerular and interstitial scarring. Hematuria without involvement of other organs occurs consistently and rapidly, glomerular necrosis and crescent formation are evident at 12 days, and consequent glomerular and interstitial scarring at 29 days after initial treatment. Using mass-spectrometric proteome analysis, we provide a detailed overview of matrisomal and cellular changes in our model. We observed increased expression of the matrisome including collagens, fibronectin, tenascin-C, in accordance with human AAV as deduced from analysis of gene expression microarrays and tissue staining. Moreover, we observed tissue infiltration by neutrophils, macrophages, T cells and myofibroblasts upon injury. Experimental inhibition of CXCR4 using AMD3100 led to a sustained histological presence of fibrin extravasate, reduced chemokine expression and leukocyte activation, but did not markedly affect ECM composition. Altogether, we demonstrate an adapted FNGN model that enables the study of matrisomal changes both in disease and upon intervention, as exemplified via CXCR4 inhibition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Engineering adeno-associated virus vectors for gene therapy</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/32042148/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/32042148/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adeno-associated virus (AAV) vector-mediated gene delivery was recently approved for the treatment of inherited blindness and spinal muscular atrophy, and long-term therapeutic effects have been achieved for other rare diseases, including haemophilia and Duchenne muscular dystrophy. However, current research indicates that the genetic modification of AAV vectors may further facilitate the success of AAV gene therapy. Vector engineering can increase AAV transduction efficiency (by optimizing the transgene cassette), vector tropism (using capsid engineering) and the ability of the capsid and transgene to avoid the host immune response (by genetically modifying these components), as well as optimize the large-scale production of AAV.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adeno-associated virus vector as a platform for gene therapy delivery</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/30710128/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/30710128/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adeno-associated virus (AAV) vectors are the leading platform for gene delivery for the treatment of a variety of human diseases. Recent advances in developing clinically desirable AAV capsids, optimizing genome designs and harnessing revolutionary biotechnologies have contributed substantially to the growth of the gene therapy field. Preclinical and clinical successes in AAV-mediated gene replacement, gene silencing and gene editing have helped AAV gain popularity as the ideal therapeutic vector, with two AAV-based therapeutics gaining regulatory approval in Europe or the United States. Continued study of AAV biology and increased understanding of the associated therapeutic challenges and limitations will build the foundation for future clinical success.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lung-Targeted Transgene Expression of Nanocomplexed Ad5 Enhances Immune Response in the Presence of Preexisting Immunity</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36714358/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36714358/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recombinant adenovirus serotype 5 (Ad5) vector has been widely applied in vaccine development targeting infectious diseases, such as Ebola virus disease and coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19). However, the high prevalence of preexisting anti-vector immunity compromises the immunogenicity of Ad5-based vaccines. Thus, there is a substantial unmet need to minimize preexisting immunity while improving the insert-induced immunity of Ad5 vectors. Herein, we address this need by utilizing biocompatible nanoparticles to modulate Ad5-host interactions. We show that positively charged human serum albumin nanoparticles ((+)HSAnp), which are capable of forming a complex with Ad5, significantly increase the transgene expression of Ad5 in both coxsackievirus-adenovirus receptor-positive and -negative cells. Furthermore, in charge- and dose-dependent manners, Ad5/(+)HSAnp complexes achieve robust (up to 227-fold higher) and long-term (up to 60 days) transgene expression in the lungs of mice following intranasal instillation. Importantly, in the presence of preexisting anti-Ad5 immunity, complexed Ad5-based Ebola and COVID-19 vaccines significantly enhance antigen-specific humoral response and mucosal immunity. These findings suggest that viral aggregation and charge modification could be leveraged to engineer enhanced viral vectors for vaccines and gene therapies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
