<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Stomach | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/stomach/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/stomach/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Stomach</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 14 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Stomach</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/stomach/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Targeting KRAS-mutant stomach/colorectal tumors by disrupting the ERK2-p53 complex</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36641751/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36641751/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;p53 associates with phosphorylated ERK2 through a hydrophobic interaction&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mutant KRAS enables ERK2 to interact with p53 based on conformation change&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Trametinib disrupts the ERK2-p53 complex by blocking ERK2 phosphorylation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Trametinib promotes PUMA transcription by recruiting p300/CBP to p53 protein&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;KRAS is widely mutated in human cancers, resulting in unchecked tumor proliferation and metastasis, which makes identifying KRAS-targeting therapies a priority. Herein, we observe that mutant KRAS specifically promotes the formation of the ERK2-p53 complex in stomach/colorectal tumor cells. Disruption of this complex by applying MEK1/2 and ERK2 inhibitors elicits strong apoptotic responses in a p53-dependent manner, validated by genome-wide knockout screening. Mechanistically, p53 physically associates with phosphorylated ERK2 through a hydrophobic interaction in the presence of mutant KRAS, which suppresses p53 activation by preventing the recruitment of p300/CBP; trametinib disrupts the ERK2-p53 complex by reducing ERK2 phosphorylation, allowing the acetylation of p53 protein by recruiting p300/CBP; acetylated p53 activates PUMA transcription and thereby kills KRAS-mutant tumors. Our study shows an important role for the ERK2-p53 complex and provides a potential therapeutic strategy for treating KRAS-mutant cancer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updated epidemiology of gastrointestinal cancers in East Asia</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/36631716/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/36631716/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Globally, gastrointestinal cancers represent more than one-fourth of all cancer incidence and one-third of cancer-related mortality. Although there has been much progress in screening colorectal cancer, the prognosis of other gastrointestinal cancers tends to be poor. The highest burden of gastrointestinal cancers, including stomach, liver, oesophageal and gallbladder cancers, was observed in regions in East Asia. The increasing burden of gastrointestinal cancers in East Asian regions is related to population growth, ageing and the westernization of lifestyle habits in this region. Furthermore, the rising incidence of young-onset colorectal cancer is an emerging trend in East Asia. This Review provides a comprehensive and updated summary of the epidemiology of gastrointestinal cancers in East Asia, with emphasis on comparing their epidemiology in East Asia with that in Western regions, and highlights the major risk factors and implications for prevention. Overall, to optimally reduce the disease burden incurred by gastrointestinal cancers in East Asian regions, a concerted effort will be needed to modify unhealthy lifestyles, promote vaccination against the hepatitis virus, control Helicobacter pylori, liver fluke and hepatitis virus infections, increase the uptake rate of colorectal cancer screening, enhance detection of early cancers and their precursors, and improve cancer survivorship through an organized rehabilitation programme.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Key points&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is a substantial burden of gastrointestinal cancers in East Asia, with the highest incidence observed in colorectal and stomach cancer and the highest mortality in liver and stomach cancer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Compared with Western regions, East Asia has a higher burden of stomach, liver, oesophageal and gallbladder cancer, but the burden of colorectal and pancreatic cancer is increasing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is an increasing trend in young-onset colorectal, pancreatic and gallbladder cancer in East Asia attributed to the bigger increase in risk factors among the younger population.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Common modifiable risk factors for gastrointestinal cancers in East Asia include smoking, alcohol intake, diet, sedentary lifestyle, obesity and metabolic diseases.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;East Asian regions have a higher prevalence of &lt;em&gt;Helicobacter pylori&lt;/em&gt;, liver fluke, and hepatitis B and C virus infections, hot beverage consumption and biliary cyst development, which might have increased the risk of gastrointestinal cancers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Key preventive strategies for gastrointestinal cancers in the East Asian population include lifestyle modifications, hepatitis vaccination, &lt;em&gt;H. pylori&lt;/em&gt; infection control, cancer screening, early diagnosis and improving cancer survivorship.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CircPDIA4 induces gastric cancer progression by promoting ERK1/2 activation and enhancing biogenesis of oncogenic circRNAs</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36562654/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36562654/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Circular RNAs (circRNAs) are a group of non-coding, covalently uninterrupted loop transcripts, most of which remain to be functionally characterized. Here, we identified circPDIA4 as an oncogenic circRNA in gastric cancer. Clinically, circPDIA4 was significantly upregulated in malignant tissues and associated with poor survival of gastric cancer patients. The biogenesis of circPDIA4 was mediated by the RNA binding protein Quaking, which bound intron 2 and 4 of PDIA4 pre-mRNA to promote backsplicing of exons 3 and 4. Elevated expression of circPDIA4 promoted distant metastasis in various mouse xenograft models in vivo and accelerated cancer cell invasion in vitro. CircPDIA4 functioned through distinct oncogenic mechanisms in the cytoplasm and the nucleus. Cytoplasmic circPDIA4 bound to ERK1/2 and sustained hyper-activation of the MAPK pathway by preventing DUSP6-mediated ERK1/2 dephosphorylation. Notably, circPDIA4 depletion enhanced the sensitivity of gastric cancer cells to ERK inhibitors. In the nucleus, circPDIA4 interacted with DHX9 as a decoy and repressed its inhibitory functions on circRNA biogenesis to boost expression of multiple oncogenic circRNAs, which promoted gastric cancer progression. These findings reveal a dual tumor-promoting mechanism for circPDIA4 by regulating oncogenic circRNA biogenesis and increasing MAPK activity. CircPDIA4 should be investigated further as a potential prognostic biomarker and therapeutic target in gastric cancer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Urine proteomic signatures predicting the progression from premalignancy to malignant gastric cancer</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36356476/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36356476/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Early detection of gastric cancer (GC) remains challenging. We aimed to examine urine proteomic signatures and identify protein biomarkers that predict the progression of gastric lesions and risk of GC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; A case-control study was initially designed, covering subjects with GC and gastric lesions of different stages. Subjects were aged 40-69 years, without prior diagnosis of renal or urological diseases. We enrolled a total of 255 subjects, with 123 in the discovery stage from Linqu, China, a high-risk area for GC and 132 in the validation stage from Linqu and Beijing. A prospective study was further designed for a subset of 60 subjects with gastric lesions, which were followed for 297-857 days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Findings:&lt;/em&gt; We identified 43 differentially expressed urine proteins in subjects with GC vs. mild or advanced gastric lesions. Baseline urinary levels of ANXA11, CDC42, NAPA and SLC25A4 were further positively associated with risk of gastric lesion progression. Three of them, except for SLC25A4, also had higher expression in GC than non-GC tissues. Integrating these four proteins showed outstanding performance in predicting the progression of gastric lesions (AUC (95% CI): 0.92 (0.83-1.00)) and risk of GC (AUC (95% CI): 0.81 (0.73-0.89) and 0.84 (0.77-0.92) for GC vs. mild or advanced gastric lesions respectively).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Interpretation:&lt;/em&gt; This study revealed distinct urine proteomic profiles and a panel of proteins that may predict the progression of gastric lesions and risk of GC. These biomarkers in a non-invasive approach may have translational significance for defining high-risk populations of GC and its early detection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>scRNA-seq of gastric tumor shows complex intercellular interaction with an alternative T cell exhaustion trajectory</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35999201/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35999201/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tumor microenvironment (TME) in gastric cancer (GC) has been shown to be important for tumor control but the specific characteristics for GC are not fully appreciated. We generated an atlas of 166,533 cells from 10 GC patients with matched paratumor tissues and blood. Our results show tumor-associated stromal cells (TASCs) have upregulated activity of Wnt signaling and angiogenesis, and are negatively correlated with survival. Tumor-associated macrophages and LAMP3&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; DCs are involved in mediating T cell activity and form intercellular interaction hubs with TASCs. Clonotype and trajectory analysis demonstrates that Tc17 (IL-17&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt;CD8&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T cells) originate from tissue-resident memory T cells and can subsequently differentiate into exhausted T cells, suggesting an alternative pathway for T cell exhaustion. Our results indicate that IL17&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; cells may promote tumor progression through IL17, IL22, and IL26 signaling, highlighting the possibility of targeting IL17&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; cells and associated signaling pathways as a therapeutic strategy to treat GC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The role, mechanism, and application of RNA methyltransferase METTL14 in gastrointestinal cancer</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/35974338/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/35974338/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gastrointestinal cancer is the most common human malignancy characterized by high lethality and poor prognosis. Emerging evidences indicate that N6-methyladenosine (m6A), the most abundant post-transcriptional modification in eukaryotes, exerts important roles in regulating mRNA metabolism including stability, decay, splicing, transport, and translation. As the key component of the m6A methyltransferase complex, methyltransferase-like 14 (METTL14) catalyzes m6A methylation on mRNA or non-coding RNA to regulate gene expression and cell phenotypes. Dysregulation of METTL14 was deemed to be involved in various aspects of gastrointestinal cancer, such as tumorigenesis, progression, chemoresistance, and metastasis. Plenty of findings have opened up new avenues for exploring the therapeutic potential of gastrointestinal cancer targeting METTL14. In this review, we systematically summarize the recent advances regarding the biological functions of METTL14 in gastrointestinal cancer, discuss its potential clinical applications and propose the research forecast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MiR-192-5p/RB1/NF-κBp65 signaling axis promotes IL-10 secretion during gastric cancer EMT to induce Treg cell differentiation in the tumour microenvironment</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35969010/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35969010/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Regulatory T (Treg) cells are important components of the tumour microenvironment (TME) that play roles in gastric cancer (GC) metastasis. Although tumour cells that undergo epithelial-mesenchymal transition (EMT) regulate Treg cell function, their regulatory mechanism in GC remains unclear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; The miR-192-5p was identified by examining three Gene Expression Omnibus GC miRNA expression datasets. RNA immunoprecipitation (RIP) and dual-luciferase reporter assays were conducted to identify interactions between miR-192-5p and RB1. The role of miR-192-5p/RB1 in GC progression was evaluated based on EdU incorporation, wound healing and Transwell assays. An in vitro co-culture assay was performed to measure the effect of miR-192-5p/RB1 on Treg cell differentiation. In vivo experiments were conducted to explore the role of miR-192-5p in GC progression and Treg cell differentiation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; MiR-192-5p was overexpressed in tumour and was associated with poor prognosis in GC. MiR-192-5p bound to the RB1 3&amp;rsquo;-untranslated region, resulting in GC EMT, proliferation, migration and invasion. MiR-192-5p/RB1 mediated interleukin-10 (IL-10) secretion by regulating nuclear factor-kappaBp65 (NF-κBp65), affecting Treg cell differentiation. NF-κBp65, in turn, promoted miR-192-5p expression and formed a positive feedback loop. Furthermore, in vivo experiments confirmed that miR-192-5p/RB1 promotes GC growth and Treg cell differentiation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/em&gt; Collectively, our studies indicate that miR-192-5p/RB1 promotes EMT of tumour cells, and the miR-192-5p/RB1/NF-κBp65 signaling axis induces Treg cell differentiation by regulating IL-10 secretion in GC. Our results suggest that targeting miR-192-5p/RB1/NF-κBp65 /IL-10 may pave the way for the development of new immune treatments for GC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tankyrase-selective inhibitor STP1002 shows preclinical antitumour efficacy without on-target toxicity in the gastrointestinal tract</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35849876/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35849876/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Tankyrase inhibition stabilises AXINs and antagonises the Wnt/β-catenin pathway in adenomatous polyposis coli (APC)-mutated colorectal cancer (CRC), suggesting that tankyrase is a potential therapeutic target for APC-mutated CRC. However, clinical trials on reported tankyrase inhibitors have been severely limited by on-target toxicity in the gastrointestinal (GI) tract. Herein, we report a new tankyrase-selective inhibitor, STP1002, having preclinical antitumour efficacy without on-target toxicity in APC-mutated CRC models.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; STP1002 was developed and characterised using in vitro and in vivo functional studies; its pharmacokinetics, antitumour efficacy and toxicity were evaluated in vivo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; STP1002 showed potent, selective inhibition of tankyrase 1/2 but not of members of the poly (ADP-ribose) polymerase 1/2 (PARP1/2). STP1002 exerted antitumour activity by stabilising AXINs and antagonising the Wnt/β-catenin pathway in a subset of APC-mutated CRC cell lines but not in inhibitor-resistant cells and APC-wild-type CRC cell lines. STP1002 showed favourable pharmacokinetic profiles for oral administration once daily. STP1002 inhibited tumour growth of APC-mutated CRC xenograft animal models but not of APC-wild type models in a dose-dependent manner. The antitumour efficacy of STP1002 was confirmed using APC-mutated CRC patient-derived tumour xenograft models. STP1002 showed no significant on-target toxicity in the GI tract compared to G007-LK, which shows severe ileum toxicity in preclinical animal models.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; These results demonstrate that STP1002, a novel, orally active tankyrase inhibitor, shows preclinical antitumour efficacy without on-target toxicity in the GI tract. Our data provide a rationale for a clinical trial on STP1002 as a potential tankyrase-targeted drug in patients with APC-mutated CRC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LncRNA CRART16/miR-122-5p/FOS axis promotes angiogenesis of gastric cancer by upregulating VEGFD expression</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35537818/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35537818/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; We previously identified a novel lncRNA, CRART16, that could induce cetuximab resistance in colorectal cancer cells. This study explored the relationship of CRART16 expression to gastric cancer progression and the molecular mechanisms involved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; We evaluated CRART16 expression in gastric cancer tissues and adjacent normal tissues from the TCGA database and our hospital. Besides, we assessed its relationship with the overall survival (OS) of patients with gastric cancer. The effects of CRART16 on gastric cancer angiogenesis were determined by endothelial tube formation assay, spheroid sprouting assay, HUVEC invasion assay, and chick embryo chorioallantoic membrane (CAM) assay. The involvement of the lncRNA CRART16/miR-122-5p/FOS axis was analyzed by western blotting and dual-luciferase reporter assay. The functions of CRART16 were confirmed in xenograft mouse models.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; We found that CRART16 was substantially overexpressed in gastric cancer tissues compared with normal tissues, based on the TCGA database and our clinical samples. High expression of CRART16 correlated with more advanced tumor stages and poor prognosis. Overexpression of CRART16 in gastric cancer cells promoted proliferation, colony formation, angiogenesis, and bevacizumab resistance in vitro, and it promoted tumor growth and angiogenesis in vivo, and vice versa. CRART16 was found to downregulate miR-122-5p by acting as a sponge, upregulating the target oncogene FOS. Afterward, the increased FOS expression led to the upregulation of VEGFD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/em&gt; Our findings demonstrate that CRART16 promotes angiogenesis in vitro and in vivo, and CRART16 is a prognostic marker and therapeutic target in gastric cancer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Role of lncSLCO1C1 in gastric cancer progression and resistance to oxaliplatin therapy</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35474446/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35474446/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Gastric carcinoma (GC) is one of the most deadly diseases due to tumour metastasis and resistance to therapy. Understanding the molecular mechanism of tumour progression and drug resistance will improve therapeutic efficacy and develop novel intervention strategies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; Differentially expressed long non-coding RNAs (lncRNAs) in clinical specimens were identified by LncRNA microarrays and validated in different clinical cohorts by quantitative real-time polymerase chain reaction (qRT-PCR), in situ hybridisation and bioinformatics analysis. Biological functions of lncRNA were investigated by using cell proliferation assays, migration assays, xenograft tumour models and bioinformatics analysis. Effects of lncSLCO1C1 on GC cell survival were assessed by comet assays and immunofluorescence assays. Underlying molecular mechanisms were further explored by using a number of technologies including RNA pull-down, mass spectrometry analysis, RNA immunoprecipitation, co-immunoprecipitation, miRNA sequencing, luciferase reporter assays and molecular modelling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; LncSLCO1C1 was highly upregulated in GC tissue samples and associated with GC patients&amp;rsquo; poor overall survival. Overexpression of lncSLCO1C1 promoted proliferation and migration, whereas decreased lncSLCO1C1 expression produced the opposite effects. lncSLCO1C1 also mediated tumour resistance to chemotherapy with oxaliplatin by reducing DNA damage and increasing cell proliferation. Despite sequence overlapping between lncSLCO1C1 and PDE3A, alternations of PDE3A expression had no effect on the GC cell progression, indicating that lncSLCO1C1, not PDE3A, related with the progression of GC cells. Mechanistically, lncSLCO1C1 serves as a scaffold for the structure-specific recognition protein 1 (SSRP1)/H2A/H2B complex and regulates the function of SSRP1 in reducing DNA damage. Meanwhile, lncSLCO1C1 functions as a sponge to adsorb miR-204-5p and miR-211-5p that target SSRP1 mRNA, and thus increases SSRP1 expression. Patients with high expressions of both lncSLCO1C1 and SSRP1 have poor overall survival, highlighting the role of lncSLCO1C1 in GC progression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; LncSLCO1C1 promotes GC progression by enhancing cell growth and preventing DNA damage via interacting and scaffolding the SSRP1/H2A/H2b complex and absorbing both miR-211-5p and miR-204-5p to increase SSRP1 expression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PIWIL1 promotes gastric cancer via a piRNA-independent mechanism</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32848063/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32848063/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Erratum in:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Correction for Shi &lt;em&gt;et al.&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.pnas.org/doi/full/10.1073/pnas.2019929117&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;PIWIL1 promotes gastric cancer via a piRNA-independent mechanism&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Targeted cancer therapy aims to achieve specific elimination of cancerous but not normal cells. Recently, PIWI proteins, a subfamily of the PAZ-PIWI domain (PPD) protein family, have emerged as promising candidates for targeted cancer therapy. PPD proteins are essential for small noncoding RNA pathways. The Argonaute subfamily partners with microRNA and small interfering RNA, whereas the PIWI subfamily partners with PIWI-interacting RNA (piRNA). Both PIWI proteins and piRNA are mostly expressed in the germline and best known for their function in transposon silencing, with no detectable function in mammalian somatic tissues. However, PIWI proteins become aberrantly expressed in multiple types of somatic cancers, thus gaining interest in targeted therapy. Despite this, little is known about the regulatory mechanism of PIWI proteins in cancer. Here we report that one of the four PIWI proteins in humans, PIWIL1, is highly expressed in gastric cancer tissues and cell lines. Knocking out the PIWIL1 gene (&lt;em&gt;PIWIL1-KO&lt;/em&gt;) drastically reduces gastric cancer cell proliferation, migration, metastasis, and tumorigenesis. RNA deep sequencing of gastric cancer cell line SNU-1 reveals that KO significantly changes the transcriptome, causing the up-regulation of most of its associated transcripts. Surprisingly, few bona fide piRNAs exist in gastric cancer cells. Furthermore, abolishing the piRNA-binding activity of PIWIL1 does not affect its oncogenic function. Thus, PIWIL1 function in gastric cancer cells is independent of piRNA. This piRNA-independent regulation involves interaction with the UPF1-mediated nonsense-mediated mRNA decay (NMD) mechanism. Altogether, our findings reveal a piRNA-independent function of PIWIL1 in promoting gastric cancer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
