<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Stem Cell | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/stem-cell/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/stem-cell/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Stem Cell</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Stem Cell</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/stem-cell/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cortical interneuron development is affected in 4H leukodystrophy</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36729681/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36729681/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4H leukodystrophy is a rare genetic disorder classically characterized by hypomyelination, hypodontia and hypogonadotropic hypogonadism. With the discovery that 4H is caused by mutations that affect RNA polymerase III, mainly involved in the transcription of small non-coding RNAs, also patients with atypical presentations with mainly a neuronal phenotype were identified. Pathomechanisms of 4H brain abnormalities are still unknown and research is hampered by a lack of preclinical models. We aimed to identify cells and pathways that are affected by 4H mutations using induced pluripotent stem cell models. RNA sequencing analysis on induced pluripotent stem cell-derived cerebellar cells revealed several differentially expressed genes between 4H patients and control samples, including reduced ARX expression. As ARX is involved in early brain and interneuron development, we studied and confirmed interneuron changes in primary tissue of 4H patients. Subsequently, we studied interneuron changes in more depth and analyzed induced pluripotent stem cell-derived cortical neuron cultures for changes in neuronal morphology, synaptic balance, network activity and myelination. We showed a decreased percentage of GABAergic synapses in 4H, which correlated to increased neuronal network activity. Treatment of cultures with GABA antagonists led to a significant increase in neuronal network activity in control cells but not in 4H cells, also pointing to lack of inhibitory activity in 4H. Myelination and oligodendrocyte maturation in cultures with 4H neurons was normal, and treatment with sonic hedgehog agonist SAG did not improve 4H related neuronal phenotypes. qPCR analysis revealed increased expression of parvalbumin interneuron marker ERBB4, suggesting that the development rather than generation of interneurons may be affected in 4H. Together, these results indicate that interneurons are involved, possibly parvalbumin interneurons, in disease mechanisms of 4H leukodystrophy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SYF2 suppression mitigates neurodegeneration in models of diverse forms of ALS</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36736291/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36736291/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) is a fatal neurodegenerative disease caused by many diverse genetic etiologies. Although therapeutics that specifically target causal mutations may rescue individual types of ALS, such approaches cannot treat most patients since they have unknown genetic etiology. Thus, there is a critical need for therapeutic strategies that rescue multiple forms of ALS. Here, we combine phenotypic chemical screening on a diverse cohort of ALS patient-derived neurons with bioinformatic analysis of large chemical and genetic perturbational datasets to identify broadly effective genetic targets for ALS. We show that suppressing the gene-encoding, spliceosome-associated factor SYF2 alleviates TDP-43 aggregation and mislocalization, improves TDP-43 activity, and rescues C9ORF72 and causes sporadic ALS neuron survival. Moreover, Syf2 suppression ameliorates neurodegeneration, neuromuscular junction loss, and motor dysfunction in TDP-43 mice. Thus, suppression of spliceosome-associated factors such as SYF2 may be a broadly effective therapeutic approach for ALS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SGLT2 inhibitor ameliorates endothelial dysfunction associated with the common ALDH2 alcohol flushing variant</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36696485/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36696485/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The common aldehyde dehydrogenase 2 (&lt;em&gt;ALDH2&lt;/em&gt;) alcohol flushing variant known as &lt;em&gt;ALDH2*2&lt;/em&gt; affects ∼8% of the world&amp;rsquo;s population. Even in heterozygous carriers, this missense variant leads to a severe loss of ALDH2 enzymatic activity and has been linked to an increased risk of coronary artery disease (CAD). Endothelial cell (EC) dysfunction plays a determining role in all stages of CAD pathogenesis, including early-onset CAD. However, the contribution of &lt;em&gt;ALDH2*2&lt;/em&gt; to EC dysfunction and its relation to CAD are not fully understood. In a large genome-wide association study (GWAS) from Biobank Japan, &lt;em&gt;ALDH2*2&lt;/em&gt; was found to be one of the strongest single-nucleotide polymorphisms associated with CAD. Clinical assessment of endothelial function showed that human participants carrying &lt;em&gt;ALDH2*2&lt;/em&gt; exhibited impaired vasodilation after light alcohol drinking. Using human induced pluripotent stem cell-derived ECs (iPSC-ECs) and CRISPR-Cas9-corrected &lt;em&gt;ALDH2*2&lt;/em&gt; iPSC-ECs, we modeled &lt;em&gt;ALDH2*2&lt;/em&gt;-induced EC dysfunction in vitro, demonstrating an increase in oxidative stress and inflammatory markers and a decrease in nitric oxide (NO) production and tube formation capacity, which was further exacerbated by ethanol exposure. We subsequently found that sodium-glucose cotransporter 2 inhibitors (SGLT2i) such as empagliflozin mitigated &lt;em&gt;ALDH2*2&lt;/em&gt;-associated EC dysfunction. Studies in &lt;em&gt;ALDH2*2&lt;/em&gt; knock-in mice further demonstrated that empagliflozin attenuated &lt;em&gt;ALDH2*2&lt;/em&gt;-mediated vascular dysfunction in vivo. Mechanistically, empagliflozin inhibited Na+/H+-exchanger 1 (NHE-1) and activated AKT kinase and endothelial NO synthase (eNOS) pathways to ameliorate &lt;em&gt;ALDH2*2&lt;/em&gt;-induced EC dysfunction. Together, our results suggest that &lt;em&gt;ALDH2*2&lt;/em&gt; induces EC dysfunction and that SGLT2i may potentially be used as a preventative measure against CAD for &lt;em&gt;ALDH2*2&lt;/em&gt; carriers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>YAP-regulated type II alveolar epithelial cell differentiation mediated by human umbilical cord-derived mesenchymal stem cells in acute respiratory distress syndrome</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36701989/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36701989/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;hUC-MSCs reduced lung injury and inflammation in mice with LPS-induced ARDS.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dynamic YAP regulation on AECII was mediated by hUC-MSCs in LPS-induced ARDS.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Inactivation of YAP facilitated LPS-induced AECII differentiation in response to hUC-MSCs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;hUC-MSCs may have potential in the treatment of ARDS.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acute respiratory distress syndrome (ARDS) contributes to higher mortality worldwide. Human umbilical cord-derived mesenchymal stem cells (hUC-MSCs) have immunomodulatory and regenerative potential. However, the effects of hUC-MSCs as an ARDS treatment remain unclear. We investigated the role of hUC-MSCs in the differentiation of type II alveolar epithelial cells (AECII) by regulating Yes-associated protein (YAP) in ARDS. Male C57BL/6JNarl mice were intratracheally (i.t.) administered lipopolysaccharide (LPS) to induce an ARDS model, followed by a single intravenous (i.v.) dose of hUC-MSCs. hUC-MSCs improved pulmonary function, decreased inflammation on day 3, and mitigated lung injury by reducing the lung injury score and increasing lung aeration (%) in mice on day 7 (&lt;em&gt;p&lt;/em&gt; &amp;lt; 0.05). hUC-MSCs inactivated YAP on AECII and facilitated cell differentiation by decreasing Pro-surfactant protein C (Pro-SPC) and galectin 3 (LGALS3) while increasing podoplanin (T1α) in lungs of mice (&lt;em&gt;p&lt;/em&gt; &amp;lt; 0.05). In AECII MLE-12 cells, both coculture with hUC-MSCs after LPS exposure and the YAP inhibitor, verteporfin, reduced Pro-SPC and LGALS3, whereas the YAP inhibitor increased T1α expression (&lt;em&gt;p&lt;/em&gt; &amp;lt; 0.05). In conclusion, hUC-MSCs ameliorated lung injury of ARDS and regulated YAP to facilitate AECII differentiation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Human endoderm stem cells reverse inflammation-related acute liver failure through cystatin SN-mediated inhibition of interferon signaling</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36670290/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36670290/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acute liver failure (ALF) is a life-threatening disease that occurs secondary to drug toxicity, infection or a devastating immune response. Orthotopic liver transplantation is an effective treatment but limited by the shortage of donor organs, the requirement for life-long immune suppression and surgical challenges. Stem cell transplantation is a promising alternative therapy for fulminant liver failure owing to the immunomodulatory abilities of stem cells. Here, we report that when transplanted into the liver, human endoderm stem cells (hEnSCs) that are germ layer-specific and nontumorigenic cells derived from pluripotent stem cells are able to effectively ameliorate hepatic injury in multiple rodent and swine drug-induced ALF models. We demonstrate that hEnSCs tune the local immune microenvironment by skewing macrophages/Kupffer cells towards an anti-inflammatory state and by reducing the infiltrating monocytes/macrophages and inflammatory T helper cells. Single-cell transcriptomic analyses of infiltrating and resident monocytes/macrophages isolated from animal livers revealed dramatic changes, including changes in gene expression that correlated with the change of activation states, and dynamic population heterogeneity among these cells after hEnSC transplantation. We further demonstrate that hEnSCs modulate the activation state of macrophages/Kupffer cells via cystatin SN (CST1)-mediated inhibition of interferon signaling and therefore highlight CST1 as a candidate therapeutic agent for diseases that involve over-activation of interferons. We propose that hEnSC transplantation represents a novel and powerful cell therapeutic treatment for ALF.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Niche stiffness sustains cancer stemness via TAZ and NANOG phase separation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36646707/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36646707/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Emerging evidence shows that the biomechanical environment is required to support cancer stem cells (CSCs), which play a crucial role in drug resistance. However, how mechanotransduction signals regulate CSCs and its clinical significance has remained unclear. Using clinical-practice ultrasound elastography for patients&amp;rsquo; lesions and atomic force microscopy for surgical samples, we reveal that increased matrix stiffness is associated with poor responses to neoadjuvant chemotherapy, worse prognosis, and CSC enrichment in patients with breast cancer. Mechanically, TAZ activated by biomechanics enhances CSC properties via phase separation with NANOG. TAZ-NANOG phase separation, which is dependent on acidic residues in the N-terminal activation domain of NANOG, promotes the transcription of SOX2 and OCT4. Therapeutically, targeting NANOG or TAZ reduces CSCs and enhances the chemosensitivity in vivo. Collectively, this study demonstrated that the phase separation of a pluripotency transcription factor links mechanical cues in the niche to the fate of CSCs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fecal microbiota transplantation from young mice rejuvenates aged hematopoietic stem cells by suppressing inflammations</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36638348/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36638348/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hematopoietic stem cell (HSC) aging is accompanied by hematopoietic reconstitution dysfunction, including loss of regenerative and engraftment ability, myeloid differentiation bias and elevated risks of hematopoietic malignancies. Gut microbiota, a key regulator of host health and immunity, has been recently reported to impact hematopoiesis. However, there is currently limited empirical evidence elucidating the direct impact of gut microbiome on aging hematopoiesis. In this study, we performed fecal microbiota transplantation (FMT) from young mice to aged mice and observed significant increment in lymphoid differentiation and decrease in myeloid differentiation in aged recipient mice. Further, FMT from young mice rejuvenated aged HSCs with enhanced short-term and long-term hematopoietic repopulation capacity. Mechanistically, single-cell RNA sequencing deciphered that FMT from young mice mitigated inflammatory signals, upregulated FoxO signaling pathway and promoted lymphoid differentiation of HSCs during aging. Finally, integrated microbiome and metabolome analyses uncovered that FMT reshaped gut microbiota construction and metabolite landscape, and Lachnospiraceae and tryptophan-associated metabolites promoted the recovery of hematopoiesis and rejuvenated aged HSCs. Together, our study highlights the paramount importance of the gut microbiota in HSC aging and provides insights into therapeutic strategies for aging-related hematologic disorders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bioactive glass-elicited stem cell-derived extracellular vesicles regulate M2 macrophage polarization and angiogenesis to improve tendon regeneration and functional recovery</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36641814/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36641814/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Effective countermeasures for tendon injury remains unsatisfactory. Mesenchymal stem cell-derived extracellular vesicles (MSC-EVs)-based therapy via regulation of Mφ-mediated angiogenesis has emerged as a promising strategy for tissue regeneration. Still, approaches to tailor the functions of EVs to treat tendon injuries have been limited. We reported a novel strategy by applying MSC-EVs boosted with bioactive glasses (BG). BG-elicited EVs (EVB) showed up-regulation of medicinal miRNAs, including miR-199b-3p and miR-125a-5p, which play a pivotal role in M2 Mφ-mediated angiogenesis. EVB accelerated angiogenesis via the reprogrammed anti-inflammatory M2 Mφs compared with naïve MSC-EVs (EVN). In rodent Achilles tendon rupture model, EVB local administration activated anti-inflammatory responses via M2 polarization and led to a spatial correlation between M2 Mφs and newly formed blood vessels. Our results showed that EVB outperformed EVN in promoting tenogenesis and in reducing detrimental morphological changes without causing heterotopic ossification. Biomechanical test revealed that EVB significantly improved ultimate load, stiffness, and tensile modulus of the repaired tendon, along with a positive correlation between M2/M1 ratio and biomechanical properties. On the basis of the boosted nature to reprogram regenerative microenvironment, EVB holds considerable potential to be developed as a next-generation therapeutic modality for enhancing functional regeneration to achieve satisfying tendon regeneration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PTBP1-activated co-transcriptional splicing controls epigenetic status of pluripotent stem cells</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36626906/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36626906/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PTBP1 promotes co-transcriptional splicing of many introns in embryonic stem cells&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some of these introns are retained in mature mRNAs when PTBP1 is downregulated&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Retention of a PTBP1-activated intron dampens DNMT3B expression in neurons&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;DNMT3B downregulation prevents ectopic methylation of neuronal genes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many spliceosomal introns are excised from nascent transcripts emerging from RNA polymerase II (RNA Pol II). The extent of cell-type-specific regulation and possible functions of such co-transcriptional events remain poorly understood. We examined the role of the RNA-binding protein PTBP1 in this process using an acute depletion approach followed by the analysis of chromatin- and RNA Pol II-associated transcripts. We show that PTBP1 activates the co-transcriptional excision of hundreds of introns, a surprising effect given that this protein is known to promote intron retention. Importantly, some co-transcriptionally activated introns fail to complete their splicing without PTBP1. In a striking example, retention of a PTBP1-dependent intron triggers nonsense-mediated decay of transcripts encoding DNA methyltransferase DNMT3B. We provide evidence that this regulation facilitates the natural decline in DNMT3B levels in developing neurons and protects differentiation-specific genes from ectopic methylation. Thus, PTBP1-activated co-transcriptional splicing is a widespread phenomenon mediating epigenetic control of cellular identity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A DLG1-ARHGAP31-CDC42 axis is essential for the intestinal stem cell response to fluctuating niche Wnt signaling</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36640764/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36640764/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Polarity of the mammalian intestinal epithelium is independent of &lt;em&gt;Dlg1&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Loss of &lt;em&gt;Dlg1&lt;/em&gt; in ISCs results in cell death under high Wnt conditions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ISCs lacking &lt;em&gt;Dlg1&lt;/em&gt; have impaired cell division and migration&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Canonical WNT ligands activate non-canonical Wnt signaling via DLG1-ARHGAP31-CDC42&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A central factor in the maintenance of tissue integrity is the response of stem cells to variations in the levels of niche signals. In the gut, intestinal stem cells (ISCs) depend on Wnt ligands for self-renewal and proliferation. Transient increases in Wnt signaling promote regeneration after injury or in inflammatory bowel diseases, whereas constitutive activation of this pathway leads to colorectal cancer. Here, we report that Discs large 1 (&lt;em&gt;Dlg1&lt;/em&gt;), although dispensable for polarity and cellular turnover during intestinal homeostasis, is required for ISC survival in the context of increased Wnt signaling. RNA sequencing (RNA-seq) and genetic mouse models demonstrated that DLG1 regulates the cellular response to increased canonical Wnt ligands. This occurs via the transcriptional regulation of &lt;em&gt;Arhgap31&lt;/em&gt;, a GTPase-activating protein that deactivates CDC42, an effector of the non-canonical Wnt pathway. These findings reveal a DLG1-ARHGAP31-CDC42 axis that is essential for the ISC response to increased niche Wnt signaling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TRIM27 maintains gut homeostasis by promoting intestinal stem cell self-renewal</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36596873/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36596873/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dysregulation of gut homeostasis is associated with irritable bowel syndrome (IBS), a chronic functional gastrointestinal disorder affecting approximately 11.2% of the global population. The poorly understood pathogenesis of IBS has impeded its treatment. Here, we report that the E3 ubiquitin ligase tripartite motif-containing 27 (TRIM27) is weakly expressed in IBS but highly expressed in inflammatory bowel disease (IBD), a frequent chronic organic gastrointestinal disorder. Accordingly, knockout of &lt;em&gt;Trim27&lt;/em&gt; in mice causes spontaneously occurring IBS-like symptoms, including increased visceral hyperalgesia and abnormal stool features, as observed in IBS patients. Mechanistically, TRIM27 stabilizes β-catenin and thus activates Wnt/β-catenin signaling to promote intestinal stem cell (ISC) self-renewal. Consistent with these findings, &lt;em&gt;Trim27&lt;/em&gt; deficiency disrupts organoid formation, which is rescued by reintroducing TRIM27 or β-catenin. Furthermore, Wnt/β-catenin signaling activator treatment ameliorates IBS symptoms by promoting ISC self-renewal. Taken together, these data indicate that TRIM27 is critical for maintaining gut homeostasis, suggesting that targeting the TRIM27/Wnt/β-catenin axis could be a potential treatment strategy for IBS. Our study also indicates that TRIM27 might serve as a potential biomarker for differentiating IBS from IBD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RUNX2 stabilization by long non-coding RNAs contributes to hypertrophic changes in human chondrocytes</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36594090/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36594090/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Chondrocyte hypertrophy has been implicated in endochondral ossification and osteoarthritis (OA). In OA, hypertrophic chondrocytes contribute to the destruction and focal calcification of the joint cartilage. Although studies in this field have remarkably developed the modulation of joint inflammation using gene therapy and regeneration of damaged articular cartilage using cell therapy, studies that can modulate or prevent hypertrophic changes in articular chondrocytes are still lacking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;In vitro&lt;/em&gt; hypertrophic differentiation and inflammation assays were conducted using human normal chondrocyte cell lines, TC28a2 cells. Human cartilage tissues and primary articular chondrocytes were obtained from OA patients undergoing total knee arthroplasty. Long non-coding RNAs (lncRNAs), LINC02035 and LOC100130207, were selected through RNA-sequencing analysis using RNAs extracted from TC28a2 cells cultured in hypertrophic medium. The regulatory mechanism was evaluated using western blotting, real-time quantitative polymerase chain reaction, osteocalcin reporter assay, RNA-immunoprecipitation (RNA-IP), RNA-&lt;em&gt;in situ&lt;/em&gt; hybridization, and IP.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; LncRNAs are crucial regulators of various biological processes. In this study, we identified two important lncRNAs, LINC02035 and LOC100130207, which play important roles in hypertrophic changes in normal chondrocytes, through RNA sequencing. Interestingly, the expression level of RUNX2, a master regulator of chondrocyte hypertrophy, was regulated at the post-translational level during hypertrophic differentiation of the normal human chondrocyte cell line, TC28a2. RNA-immunoprecipitation proved the potential interaction between RUNX2 protein and both lncRNAs. Knockdown (KD) of LINC02035 or LOC100130207 promoted ubiquitin-mediated proteasomal degradation of RUNX2 and prevented hypertrophic differentiation of normal chondrocyte cell lines, whereas overexpression of both lncRNAs stabilized RUNX2 protein and generated hypertrophic changes. Furthermore, the KD of the two lncRNAs mitigated the destruction of important cartilage matrix proteins, COL2A1 and ACAN, by hypertrophic differentiation or inflammatory conditions. We also confirmed that the phenotypic changes raised by the two lncRNAs could be rescued by modulating &lt;em&gt;RUNX2&lt;/em&gt; expression. In addition, the KD of these two lncRNAs suppressed hypertrophic changes during chondrogenic differentiation of mesenchymal stem cells.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/em&gt; Therefore, this study suggests that LINC02035 and LOC100130207 contribute to hypertrophic changes in normal chondrocytes by regulating RUNX2, suggesting that these two novel lncRNAs could be potential therapeutic targets for delaying or preventing OA development, especially for preventing chondrocyte hypertrophy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Antisense-oligonucleotide-mediated perturbation of long non-coding RNA reveals functional features in stem cells and across cell types</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36577377/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36577377/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Molecular phenotyping shows richer functional annotation than cellular phenotyping&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Integration with chromatin interaction reveals cis- or trans-regulation of lncRNA&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;LINC02595&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;CATG00000090305.1&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;RP11-148B6.2&lt;/em&gt; modulate colony formation of iPSCs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Within the scope of the FANTOM6 consortium, we perform a large-scale knockdown of 200 long non-coding RNAs (lncRNAs) in human induced pluripotent stem cells (iPSCs) and systematically characterize their roles in self-renewal and pluripotency. We find 36 lncRNAs (18%) exhibiting cell growth inhibition. From the knockdown of 123 lncRNAs with transcriptome profiling, 36 lncRNAs (29.3%) show molecular phenotypes. Integrating the molecular phenotypes with chromatin-interaction assays further reveals cis- and trans-interacting partners as potential primary targets. Additionally, cell-type enrichment analysis identifies lncRNAs associated with pluripotency, while the knockdown of LINC02595, CATG00000090305.1, and RP11-148B6.2 modulates colony formation of iPSCs. We compare our results with previously published fibroblasts phenotyping data and find that 2.9% of the lncRNAs exhibit a consistent cell growth phenotype, whereas we observe 58.3% agreement in molecular phenotypes. This highlights that molecular phenotyping is more comprehensive in revealing affected pathways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mechanical stimulation on a microfluidic device to highly enhance small extracellular vesicle secretion of mesenchymal stem cells</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36619203/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36619203/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Small extracellular vesicles (sEVs) are recognized as promising detection biomarkers and attractive delivery vehicles, showing great potential in diagnosis and treatment of diseases. However, the applications of sEVs are usually restricted by their poor secretion amount from donor cells under routine cell culture conditions, which is especially true for mesenchymal stem cells (MSCs) due to their limited expansion and early senescence. Here, a microfluidic device is proposed for boosting sEV secretion from MSCs derived from human fetal bone marrow (BM-MSCs). As the cells rapidly pass through a microfluidic channel with a series of narrow squeezing ridges, mechanical stimulation permeabilizes the cell membrane, thus promoting them to secrete more sEVs into extracellular space. In this study, the microfluidic device demonstrates that mechanical-squeezing effect could increase the secretion amount of sEVs from the BM-MSCs by approximately 4-fold, while maintaining cellular growth state of the stem cells. Further, the secreted sEVs are efficiently taken up by immortalized human corneal epithelial cells and accelerate corneal epithelial wound healing in vitro, indicating that this technique wound not affect the functionality of sEVs and demonstrating the application potentials of this technique.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ΔNp63/p73 drive metastatic colonization by controlling a regenerative epithelial stem cell program in quasi-mesenchymal cancer stem cells</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36538894/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36538894/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ΔNp63 and p73 maintain residence in the quasi-mesenchymal breast CSC state&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ΔNp63 and p73 are required for the post-extravasation proliferation of CSCs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ΔNp63 controls distinct transcriptional programs in CSCs and normal basal SCs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Quasi-mesenchymal CSCs use autocrine EGFR signaling to enable metastatic colonization&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cancer stem cells (CSCs) may serve as the cellular seeds of tumor recurrence and metastasis, and they can be generated via epithelial-mesenchymal transitions (EMTs). Isolating pure populations of CSCs is difficult because EMT programs generate multiple alternative cell states, and phenotypic plasticity permits frequent interconversions between these states. Here, we used cell-surface expression of integrin β4 (ITGB4) to isolate highly enriched populations of human breast CSCs, and we identified the gene regulatory network operating in ITGB4+ CSCs. Specifically, we identified ΔNp63 and p73, the latter of which transactivates ΔNp63, as centrally important transcriptional regulators of quasi-mesenchymal CSCs that reside in an intermediate EMT state. We found that the transcriptional program controlled by ΔNp63 in CSCs is largely distinct from the one that it orchestrates in normal basal mammary stem cells and, instead, it more closely resembles a regenerative epithelial stem cell response to wounding. Moreover, quasi-mesenchymal CSCs repurpose this program to drive metastatic colonization via autocrine EGFR signaling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>High yield engineered nanovesicles from ADSC with enriched miR-21-5p promote angiogenesis in adipose tissue regeneration</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36528594/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36528594/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Mesenchymal stem cell-derived extracellular vesicles (MSC-EVs) have been found to have a great potential for soft tissue repair due to various biological functions, including pro-angiogenesis and low immunogenicity. However, the low yield and heterogeneity of MSC-EVs limited their clinical transformation. This study was designed to develop a novel adipose-derived stem cell engineered nanovesicles (ADSC-NVs) with high production and explore its pro-angiogenetic effect and application in adipose tissue regeneration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; Adipose-derived stem cell-derived extracellular vesicles (ADSC-EVs) were isolated from an EVs-free culture medium for human ADSCs (hADSCs). ADSC-NVs were prepared by sequentially extruding ADSCs followed by iodixanol density gradient ultracentrifugation and were compared with ADSC-EVs in morphology, size distribution, protein contents and yield. The pro-angiogenetic effect of ADSC-NVs in different doses (0, 5, 20 and 80 μg/mL) in vitro was determined using transwell assay, tube formation assay, western blot and qRT-PCR. In vivo, BALB/c nude mice were administered injection of a mixture of fat granules and different dose of ADSC-NVs and grafts were harvested at 12 weeks post-transplantation for further analysis. By analyzing the weight and volume of grafts and histological evaluation, we investigated the effect of ADSC-NVs in vessel formation and adipose tissue regeneration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; Our results showed yield of purified ADSC-NVs was approximately 20 times more than that of ADSC-EVs secreted by the same number of ADSCs. In vitro, both ADSC-NVs and ADSC-EVs exhibited a dose-dependent pro-angiogenetic effect, despite their distinct miRNA profiles. These effects of ADSC-NVs may be mediated by enriched miR-21-5p via PTEN inhibition and PI3K/p-Akt signaling activation. Furthermore, after a mixed injection of ADSC-NVs, vessel formation and adipose regeneration were observed in vivo in fat implants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; Our study developed a potent alternative of ADSC-EVs. ADSC-NVs have a high pro-angiogenesis potential and can be used as cell-free therapeutic biomaterials in soft tissue regeneration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Protection of adipose-derived mesenchymal stromal cells during acute lung injury requires autophagy maintained by mTOR</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36470863/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36470863/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Previous studies suggest that mesenchymal stem cells may represent a promising cellular therapy for acute lung injury (ALI); however, the underlying relevant molecular mechanisms remain unclear. Adipose-derived mesenchymal stem cells (ADSCs) were isolated and characterized by alizarin red staining, oil red staining, and flow cytometry. Lung injury and inflammatory cell infiltration were determined using the Evans blue method, wet/dry weight ratio, and H&amp;amp;E staining. An ELISA was used to detect the concentrations of IFN-γ, IL-2, and TNF-α. Autophagy was detected with an mRFP-GFP-LC3 dual-fluorescence autophagy indicator system, Western blotting, and electron microscopy. We first demonstrated that ADSCs did alleviate the inflammatory responses and tissue damage in lipopolysaccharide (LPS)-induced ALI. Next, we further demonstrated in vivo that autophagy plays a key role in the maintenance of ADSC therapeutic efficacy. In vitro experiments demonstrated that ADSCs co-cultured with alveolar epithelial cells depend on autophagy for significant anti-inflammatory functions. Moreover, the mammalian target of rapamycin (mTOR) is a key regulator of autophagy. Taken together, our findings demonstrate that the effect of ADSC on ALI, especially on alveolar epithelial cells, is dependent on mTOR-mediated autophagy maintenance. The significance of our study for ALI therapy is discussed with respect to a more complete understanding of the therapeutic strategy paradigm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nuclear localization of mitochondrial TCA cycle enzymes modulates pluripotency via histone acetylation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36460681/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36460681/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pluripotent stem cells hold great promise in regenerative medicine and developmental biology studies. Mitochondrial metabolites, including tricarboxylic acid (TCA) cycle intermediates, have been reported to play critical roles in pluripotency. Here we show that TCA cycle enzymes including Pdha1, Pcb, Aco2, Cs, Idh3a, Ogdh, Sdha and Mdh2 are translocated to the nucleus during somatic cell reprogramming, primed-to-naive transition and totipotency acquisition. The nuclear-localized TCA cycle enzymes Pdha1, Pcb, Aco2, Cs, Idh3a promote somatic cell reprogramming and primed-to-naive transition. In addition, nuclear-localized TCA cycle enzymes, particularly nuclear-targeted Pdha1, facilitate the 2-cell program in pluripotent stem cells. Mechanistically, nuclear Pdha1 increases the acetyl-CoA and metabolite pool in the nucleus, leading to chromatin remodeling at pluripotency genes by enhancing histone H3 acetylation. Our results reveal an important role of mitochondrial TCA cycle enzymes in the epigenetic regulation of pluripotency that constitutes a mitochondria-to-nucleus retrograde signaling mode in different states of pluripotent acquisition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ras drives malignancy through stem cell crosstalk with the microenvironment</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36450983/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36450983/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Squamous cell carcinomas are triggered by marked elevation of RAS-MAPK signalling and progression from benign papilloma to invasive malignancy. At tumour-stromal interfaces, a subset of tumour-initiating progenitors, the cancer stem cells, obtain increased resistance to chemotherapy and immunotherapy along this pathway. The distribution and changes in cancer stem cells during progression from a benign state to invasive squamous cell carcinoma remain unclear. Here we show in mice that, after oncogenic RAS activation, cancer stem cells rewire their gene expression program and trigger self-propelling, aberrant signalling crosstalk with their tissue microenvironment that drives their malignant progression. The non-genetic, dynamic cascade of intercellular exchanges involves downstream pathways that are often mutated in advanced metastatic squamous cell carcinomas with high mutational burden. Coupling our clonal skin HRAS&lt;sup&gt;G12V&lt;/sup&gt; mouse model with single-cell transcriptomics, chromatin landscaping, lentiviral reporters and lineage tracing, we show that aberrant crosstalk between cancer stem cells and their microenvironment triggers angiogenesis and TGFβ signalling, creating conditions that are conducive for hijacking leptin and leptin receptor signalling, which in turn launches downstream phosphoinositide 3-kinase (PI3K)-AKT-mTOR signalling during the benign-to-malignant transition. By functionally examining each step in this pathway, we reveal how dynamic temporal crosstalk with the microenvironment orchestrated by the stem cells profoundly fuels this path to malignancy. These insights suggest broad implications for cancer therapeutics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Uterine macrophages as treatment targets for therapy of premature rupture of membranes by modified ADSC-EVs through a circRNA/miRNA/NF-κB pathway</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36402996/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36402996/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Circular RNA (circRNA) is a type of stable non-coding RNA that modifies macrophage inflammation by sponging micro RNAs (miRNAs), binding to RNA-binding proteins, and undergoing translation into peptides. Activated M1 phenotype macrophages secrete matrix metalloproteinases to participate in softening of the cervix uteri to promote vaginal delivery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; In this study, the premature rupture of membranes (PROM) mouse model was used to analyze the role of macrophages in this process. Profiling of circRNAs was performed using a competing endogenous RNA microarray, and their functions were elucidated in vitro. Meanwhile, adipose tissue-derived stem cell-secreted extracellular vesicles (EVs) were applied as a vehicle to transport small interfering RNAs (siRNAs) targeting the circRNAs to demonstrate their biological function in vivo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; The miRNA &lt;em&gt;miR-1931&lt;/em&gt; is dependent on the nuclear factor kappa-B (NF-κB) pathway but negatively regulates its activation by targeting the NF-κB signaling transducer TRAF6 to prevent polarization of M1 macrophages and inhibit matrix metalloproteinase (MMP) secretion. The host gene of circRNA &lt;em&gt;B4GALNT1&lt;/em&gt;, also an NF-κB pathway-dependent gene, circularizes to form &lt;em&gt;circRNA_0002047&lt;/em&gt;, which sponges &lt;em&gt;miR-1931&lt;/em&gt; to maintain NF-κB pathway activation and MMP secretion in vitro. In the PROM model, EVs loaded with siRNAs targeting circRNAs demonstrated that the circRNAs reduced &lt;em&gt;miR-1931&lt;/em&gt; expression to maintain NF-κB pathway activation and MMP secretion for accelerating PROM in vivo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; Our data provide insights into understanding PROM pathogenesis and improving PROM treatment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A human kidney and liver organoid-based multi-organ-on-a-chip model to study the therapeutic effects and biodistribution of mesenchymal stromal cell-derived extracellular vesicles</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36382606/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36382606/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mesenchymal stromal cell (MSC)-derived small extracellular vesicles (sEVs) show therapeutic potential in multiple disease models, including kidney injury. Clinical translation of sEVs requires further preclinical and regulatory developments, including elucidation of the biodistribution and mode of action (MoA). Biodistribution can be determined using labelled sEVs in animal models which come with ethical concerns, are time-consuming and expensive, and may not well represent human physiology. We hypothesised that, based on developments in microfluidics and human organoid technology, in vitro multi-organ-on-a-chip (MOC) models allow us to study effects of sEVs in modelled human organs like kidney and liver in a semi-systemic manner. Human kidney- and liver organoids combined by microfluidic channels maintained physiological functions, and a kidney injury model was established using hydrogenperoxide. MSC-sEVs were isolated, and their size, density and potential contamination were analysed. These sEVs stimulated recovery of the renal epithelium after injury. Microscopic analysis shows increased accumulation of PKH67-labelled sEVs not only in injured kidney cells, but also in the unharmed liver organoids, compared to healthy control conditions. In conclusion, this new MOC model recapitulates therapeutic efficacy and biodistribution of MSC-sEVs as observed in animal models. Its human background allows for in-depth analysis of the MoA and identification of potential side effects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extracellular vesicles in the pathogenesis and treatment of acute lung injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/36316787/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/36316787/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acute lung injury (ALI) and acute respiratory distress syndrome (ARDS) are common life-threatening lung diseases associated with acute and severe inflammation. Both have high mortality rates, and despite decades of research on clinical ALI/ARDS, there are no effective therapeutic strategies. Disruption of alveolar-capillary barrier integrity or activation of inflammatory responses leads to lung inflammation and injury. Recently, studies on the role of extracellular vesicles (EVs) in regulating normal and pathophysiologic cell activities, including inflammation and injury responses, have attracted attention. Injured and dysfunctional cells often secrete EVs into serum or bronchoalveolar lavage fluid with altered cargoes, which can be used to diagnose and predict the development of ALI/ARDS. EVs secreted by mesenchymal stem cells can also attenuate inflammatory reactions associated with cell dysfunction and injury to preserve or restore cell function, and thereby promote cell proliferation and tissue regeneration. This review focuses on the roles of EVs in the pathogenesis of pulmonary inflammation, particularly ALI/ARDS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mesenchymal stem cell-derived extracellular vesicles attenuate tPA-induced blood-brain barrier disruption in murine ischemic stroke models</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36367475/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36367475/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Intracerebral hemorrhage following blood-brain barrier (BBB) disruption resulting from thrombolysis of ischemic stroke with tissue plasminogen activator (tPA) remains a critical clinical problem. Mesenchymal stem cell-derived extracellular vesicles (MSC-EVs) are promising nanotherapeutic agents that have the potential to repair the BBB after ischemic stroke; however, whether they can attenuate BBB disruption and hemorrhagic transformation after tPA thrombolysis is largely unknown. Here, we observed that MSC-EVs efficiently passed through the BBB and selectively accumulated in injured brain regions in ischemic stroke model mice in real time using aggregation-induced emission luminogens (AIEgens), which exhibit better tracking ability than the commercially available tracer DiR. Moreover, tPA administration promoted the homing of MSC-EVs to the ischemic brain and increased the uptake of MSC-EVs by astrocytes. Furthermore, the accumulated MSC-EVs attenuated the tPA-induced disruption of BBB integrity and alleviated hemorrhage by inhibiting astrocyte activation and inflammation. Mechanistically, miR-125b-5p delivered by MSC-EVs played an indispensable role in maintaining BBB integrity by targeting Toll-like receptor 4 (TLR4) and inhibiting nuclear transcription factor-kappaB (NF-κB) signaling in astrocytes. This study provides a noninvasive method for real-time tracking of MSC-EVs in the ischemic brain after tPA treatment and highlights the potential of MSC-EVs as thrombolytic adjuvants for ischemic stroke. STATEMENT OF SIGNIFICANCE: Although tPA thrombolysis is the most effective pharmaceutical strategy for acute ischemic stroke, its clinical application and therapeutic efficacy are challenged by tPA-induced BBB disruption and hemorrhagic transformation. Our study demonstrated that MSC-EVs can act as an attractive thrombolytic adjuvant to repair the BBB and improve thrombolysis in a mouse ischemic stroke model. Notably, by labeling MSC-EVs with AIEgens, we achieved accurate real-time imaging of MSC-EVs in the ischemic brain and therapeutic visualization. MSC-EVs inhibit astrocyte activation and associated inflammation through miR-125b-5p/TLR4/NF-κB pathway. Consequently, we revealed that MSC-EVs combined with tPA thrombolysis may be a promising approach for the treatment of ischemic stroke in clinical setting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DCLK1 Suppresses Tumor-Specific Cytotoxic T Lymphocyte Function Through Recruitment of MDSCs via the CXCL1-CXCR2 Axis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36309200/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36309200/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background &amp;amp; Aims&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gastrointestinal cancer stem cell marker doublecortin-like kinase (DCLK1) is strongly associated with poor outcomes in colorectal cancer (CRC). Although DCLK1’s regulatory effect on the tumor immune microenvironment has been hypothesized, its mode of action has not been shown previously in vivo, which hampers the potential intervention based on this molecule for clinical practice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To define the immunomodulatory mechanisms of DCLK1 in vivo, we generated DCLK1&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt; tumor cells by Clustered regularly interspaced short palindromic repeats (CRISPR)-CRISPR-associated protein 9 (Cas9) and developed subcutaneous and intestinal orthotopic transplantation tumor models. Tumor tissues were harvested and subjected to immunofluorescence staining, flow cytometry analysis of tumor-infiltrating immune cell populations, tumor myeloid-derived suppressor cell (MDSC) sorting by isolation kit and then co-culture with spleen T cells, and RNA sequencing for transcriptomic analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We found that DCLK1&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt; tumor cells lose their tumorigenicity under immune surveillance. Failed tumor establishment of DCLK1&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt; was associated with an increase in infiltration of CD8&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T cells and effector CD4&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T cells, and reduced numbers of MDSCs in the tumor tissue. Furthermore, DCLK1 promoted the up-regulation of C-X-C motif ligand 1, which recruits MDSCs in CRC through chemokine C-X-C motif receptor 2. The ability of in vivo tumor growth of DCLK1&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt; tumor cells was rescued by C-X-C motif ligand 1 overexpression. Collectively, we validated that DCLK1 promotes tumor growth in CRC through recruitment of T-cell–suppressive MDSCs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DCLK1-mediated immune suppression in tumor models allows escaping from the host’s antitumor response. Because DCLK1 is one of the most common markers in gastrointestinal tumors, these results identify a precise therapeutic target for related clinical interventions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Proteomic and phosphorylated proteomic landscape of injured lung in juvenile septic rats with therapeutic application of umbilical cord mesenchymal stem cells</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36341346/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36341346/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acute lung injury (ALI) is the most common complication of sepsis. Intravenous injection of HUMSCs can regulate the level of circulating endothelial cytokines and alleviate lung injury in juvenile septic rats. In this study, we performed proteomic and phosphorylated proteomic analysis of lung tissue of juvenile septic rats after Human Umbilical Cord Mesenchymal Stem Cells (HUMSCs) intervention for the first time, and screened the potential proteins and pathways of HUMSCs for therapeutic effect. The 4D proteome quantitative technique was used to quantitatively analyze the lung tissues of septic rats 24 hours (3 biological samples) and 24 hours after HUMSCs intervention (3 biological samples). A total of 213 proteins were identified as differentially expressed proteins, and 971 phosphorylation sites changed significantly. Based on the public database, we analyzed the functional enrichment of these proteins and phosphorylated proteins. In addition, Tenascin-C may be the key differential protein and ECM receptor interaction pathway may be the main signal pathway by using various algorithms to analyze the protein-protein interaction network. Phosphorylation analysis showed that tight junction pathway was closely related to immune inflammatory reaction, and EGFR interacted most, which may be the key differential phosphorylated protein. Finally, 123 conserved motifs of serine phosphorylation site (pS) and 17 conserved motifs of threonine (pT) phosphorylation sites were identified by motif analysis of phosphorylation sites. Results from proteomics and phosphorylated proteomics, the potential new therapeutic targets of HUMSCs in alleviating lung injury in juvenile septic rats were revealed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RNA-Sequencing approach for exploring the therapeutic effect of umbilical cord mesenchymal stem/stromal cells on lipopolysaccharide-induced acute lung injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36341363/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36341363/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acute lung injury (ALI) is significantly associated with morbidity and mortality in patients with critical diseases. In recent years, studies have identified that mesenchymal stem/stromal cells (MSCs) ameliorate ALI and pulmonary fibrosis. However, the mechanism underlying this outcome in ALI has not yet been investigated. In this study, RNA sequencing technology was used to analyze the gene expression profile of lung tissue in lipopolysaccharide (LPS)-induced ALI rats following treatment with human umbilical cord MSC (HUCMSC). Differential expression analyses, gene ontology annotation, Kyoto Encyclopedia of Genes and Genomes enrichment, protein-protein interaction network identification, and hub gene analysis were also performed. HUCMSC treatment decreased inflammatory factor production and alveolar exudates, and attenuated lung damage in LPS-induced ALI rats. The RNA-Seq data indicated that HUCMSC treatment activated the IL-17, JAK-STAT, NF-κB, and TNF-α signaling pathways, increased oxygen transport, and decreased extracellular matrix organization. HUCMSC exert beneficial effects on ALI via these signaling pathways by reducing inflammation, inhibiting pulmonary fibrosis, and improving lung ventilation. Moreover, our study further revealed the hub genes (&lt;em&gt;Tbx2&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Nkx2-1&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Atf5&lt;/em&gt;) and signaling pathways involved in HUCMSC treatment, thus providing novel perspectives for future research into the molecular mechanisms underlying cell treatment of ALI. HUCMSC can regulate multiple genes and signaling pathways, which can prevent LPS-induced lung damage in an ALI rat model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Expansion of T memory stem cells with superior anti-tumor immunity by Urolithin A-induced mitophagy</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36351375/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36351375/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;UA induces Pink1-dependent mitophagy in CD8&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; cells causing PGAM5 release&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cytosolic PGAM5 augments Wnt signaling to drive T&lt;sub&gt;SCM&lt;/sub&gt; formation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;T&lt;sub&gt;SCM&lt;/sub&gt; induction augments anti-tumor immunity &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Urolithin can be used for &lt;em&gt;ex vivo&lt;/em&gt; expansion of CAR-expressing T&lt;sub&gt;SCM&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;T memory stem cells (T&lt;sub&gt;SCM&lt;/sub&gt;) display increased self-renewal and prolonged survival capabilities, thus preventing T cell exhaustion and promoting effective anti-tumor T cell responses. T&lt;sub&gt;SCM&lt;/sub&gt; cells can be expanded by Urolithin A (UA), which is produced by the commensal gut microbiome from foods rich in ellagitannins and is known to improve mitochondrial health. Oral UA administration to tumor-bearing mice conferred strong anti-tumor CD8&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T cell immunity, whereas &lt;em&gt;ex vivo&lt;/em&gt; UA pre-treated T cells displayed improved anti-tumor function upon adoptive cell transfer. UA-induced T&lt;sub&gt;SCM&lt;/sub&gt; formation depended on Pink1-mediated mitophagy triggering cytosolic release of the mitochondrial phosphatase Pgam5. Cytosolic Pgam5 dephosphorylated β-catenin, which drove Wnt signaling and compensatory mitochondrial biogenesis. Collectively, we unravel a critical signaling pathway linking mitophagy to T&lt;sub&gt;SCM&lt;/sub&gt; formation and suggest that the well-tolerated metabolic compound UA represents an attractive option to improve immune therapy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New mechanism for mesenchymal stem cell microvesicle to restore lung permeability: intracellular S1P signaling pathway independent of S1P receptor-1</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36209115/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36209115/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Microvesicles (MVs) derived from human bone marrow mesenchymal stem cell (MSC) were demonstrated to restore lung protein permeability and attenuate acute lung injury. In our previous study, we found that MSC MV increased sphingosine-1-phosphate (S1P) kinase1 mRNA levels in injured human lung microvascular endothelial cells (HLMVEC) significantly. However, the role of S1P signaling in MSC MV to restore lung protein permeability is unknown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; In this study, we hypothesized that MSC MV might restore lung permeability in part through increasing intracellular S1P signaling pathway in injured HLMVEC independent of S1P receptors. We used the transwell co-culture system to study the effect of MSC MV on protein permeability of Lipopolysaccharide (LPS) damaged HLMVEC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; Our results showed that LPS significantly increased the permeability of HLMVEC to FITC-dextran (70 kDa) within 24 h. MSC MV restores this permeability and, to a large extent, prevents the cytoskeleton protein F-actin from recombining into &amp;ldquo;actin stress fibers,&amp;rdquo; and restores the positions of tight junctions and adhesion junctions in the damaged HLMVEC. This therapeutic effect of MSC MV was related to the increase in the S1P level in injured HLMVEC and was not eliminated when adding the antagonist of S1P receptor, suggesting that MSC MV to restore lung permeability was independent of S1P receptors on HLMVEC. Laser confocal further observed that Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt; mobilization and Rac1 activation in LPS injured HLMVEC were increased in parallel with the increase in intracellular S1P level after MSC MV treatment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; In short, MSC MV partially restored protein permeability across HLMVEC through the intracellular S1P signaling pathway independent of S1P receptor-1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Influenza A virus infection instructs hematopoiesis to megakaryocyte-lineage output</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36198277/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36198277/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IAV infection transiently activates CD41+ HSCs, while EPCR+ CD41− HSCs remain quiescent&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CD41+ HSCs produce megakaryocytes in IAV-induced emergency megakaryopoiesis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Platelets generated by IAV-induced emergency megakaryopoiesis are pro-coagulant&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IAV-induced emergency megakaryopoiesis is attenuated in IL1R1-deficient mice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Respiratory tract infections are among the deadliest communicable diseases worldwide. Severe cases of viral lung infections are often associated with a cytokine storm and alternating platelet numbers. We report that hematopoietic stem and progenitor cells (HSPCs) sense a non-systemic influenza A virus (IAV) infection via inflammatory cytokines. Irrespective of antiviral treatment or vaccination, at a certain threshold of IAV titer in the lung, CD41-positive hematopoietic stem cells (HSCs) enter the cell cycle while endothelial protein C receptor-positive CD41-negative HSCs remain quiescent. Active CD41-positive HSCs represent the source of megakaryocytes, while their multi-lineage reconstitution potential is reduced. This emergency megakaryopoiesis is thrombopoietin independent and attenuated in IAV-infected interleukin-1 receptor-deficient mice. Newly produced platelets during IAV infection are immature and hyper-reactive. After viral clearance, HSC quiescence is re-established. Our study reveals that non-systemic viral respiratory infection has an acute impact on HSCs via inflammatory cytokines to counteract IAV-induced thrombocytopenia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gut microbiota-stem cell niche crosstalk: A new territory for maintaining intestinal homeostasis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/imt2.54/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/imt2.54/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Intestinal stem cells (ISCs) are protected by their niche and are regulated by Wnt, bone morphogenetic protein, and Notch.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ISCs and their relationship with intestinal microbiota provide a feasible pathway to alleviate intestinal diseases.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Diverse bacteria-related postbiotics regulate ISCs and maintain their homeostasis.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Intestinal epithelium undergoes rapid cellular turnover, relying on the local niche, to support intestinal stem cells (ISCs) function and self-renewal. Research into the association between ISCs and disease continues to expand at a rapid rate. However, the detailed interaction of ISCs and gut microbes remains to be elucidated. Thus, this review witnessed major advances in the crosstalk between ISCs and gut microbes, delivering key insights into (1) construction of ISC niche and molecular mechanism of how to jointly govern epithelial homeostasis and protect against intestinal diseases with the participation of Wnt, bone morphogenetic protein, and Notch; (2) differentiation fate of ISCs affect the gut microbiota. Meanwhile, the presence of intestinal microbes also regulates ISC function; (3) microbiota regulation on ISCs by Wnt and Notch signals through pattern recognition receptors; (4) how do specific microbiota-related postbiotics influence ISCs to maintain intestinal epithelial regeneration and homeostasis that provide insights into a promising alternative therapeutic method for intestinal diseases. Considering the detailed interaction is still unclear, it is necessary to further explore the regulatory role of gut microbiota on ISCs to utilize microbes to alleviate gut disorders. Furthermore, these major advances collectively drive us ever closer to breakthroughs in regenerative medicine and cancer treatment by microbial transplantation in the clinic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Study of immunomodulatory effects of mesenchymal stem cell-derived exosomes in a mouse model of LPS induced systemic inflammation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36150466/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36150466/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Sepsis is a debilitating systemic inflammation that resulted from infection or injury. Despite many advances in treatment, the resulting mortality rate has remained high due to increasing antibiotic resistance and aging communities. The present study investigated the effects of stem cell-derived exosomes in a mouse model of LPS-induced systemic inflammation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Materials and methods:&lt;/em&gt; To induce sepsis, the LPS model was used. Mice were divided into three groups: normal, patient group (LPS + PBS), and treatment group (LPS + exosome). The treatment group received an intravenous exosome 1 h after induction of the model. Patient and treatment groups were sacrificed at 4, 6, 24, and 48 h after induction of the model, and their tissues were isolated. Blood samples were taken from animal hearts to perform biochemical and immunological tests. The study results were analyzed using Graph Pad Prism software version 9.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; Mesenchymal stem cell-derived exosomes decreased serum levels of ALT and AST liver enzymes, decreased neutrophil to lymphocyte ratio (NLR), and improved kidney, liver, and lung tissue damage at 4, 6, and 24 h after model induction. At 24 h, the exosomes were able to reduce serum urea levels. This study revealed decreased levels of inflammatory cytokines such as IL-6, IL-1β, and TNF-α after exosome injection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/em&gt; Our findings suggest that treating mice with stem cell-derived exosomes can ameliorate the destructive effects of inflammation caused by sepsis by reducing inflammatory factors and tissue damage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mesenchymal Stem Cells and Formyl Peptide Receptor 2 Activity in Hyperoxia-Induced Lung Injury in Newborn Mice</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36142517/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36142517/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Formyl peptide receptor (FPR) 2 is known to play a critical role in regulating inflammation, including either the pro-inflammatory or pro-resolving effects. However, its role in neonatal hyperoxia-induced lung injury has not been delineated. In this study, we investigate whether mesenchymal stem cells (MSCs) attenuate hyperoxia-induced neonatal lung injury by regulating FPR2 activity. We observed a significant increase in FPR2 levels in alveolar macrophages (RAW264.7 cells) after H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;-induced stress, which decreased after MSC treatment. In the H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;-induction model, increased levels of inflammatory cytokines (IL-1α and TNF-α) were significantly reduced in RAW264.7 cells after treatment with WRW4, an inhibitor of FPR2, or MSCs. Viability of lung epithelial cells and endothelial cells was significantly improved when cultured in the conditioned media of RAW264.7 cells treated with WRW4 or MSCs, compared to when cultured in the conditioned media of control RAW265.7 cells exposed to H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;. For the in vivo study, wild-type and FPR2 knockout (FPR2&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt;) C57/BL6 mouse pups were randomly exposed to 80% oxygen or room air from postnatal day (P) 1 to P14. At P5, 2 × 10&lt;sup&gt;5&lt;/sup&gt; MSCs were transplanted intratracheally. MSCs reduced the elevated FPR2 activity at P7 and improved the decreased FPR2 activity as well as the increased immuno-stained FPR2 activity in alveolar macrophages in hyperoxic lungs at P14. Both FPR&lt;sup&gt;2-/-&lt;/sup&gt; and MSCs similarly attenuated impaired alveolarization and angiogenesis, and increased apoptosis and inflammation of hyperoxic lungs without synergistic effects. Our findings suggest that the protective effects of MSCs in hyperoxic lung injury might be related to indirect modulation of FPR2 activity, at least of alveolar macrophages in neonatal mice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Roles and current applications of S-nitrosoglutathione in anti-infective biomaterials</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/36105674/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/36105674/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bacterial infections can compromise the physical and biological functionalities of humans and pose a huge economical and psychological burden on infected patients. Nitric oxide (NO) is a broad-spectrum antimicrobial agent, whose mechanism of action is not affected by bacterial resistance. S-nitrosoglutathione (GSNO), an endogenous donor and carrier of NO, has gained increasing attention because of its potent antibacterial activity and efficient biocompatibility. Significant breakthroughs have been made in the application of GSNO in biomaterials. This review is based on the existing evidence that comprehensively summarizes the progress of antimicrobial GSNO applications focusing on their anti-infective performance, underlying antibacterial mechanisms, and application in anti-infective biomaterials. We provide an accurate overview of the roles and applications of GSNO in antibacterial biomaterials and shed new light on the avenues for future studies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exosome from BMMSC Attenuates Cardiopulmonary Bypass-Induced Acute Lung Injury Via YAP/β-Catenin Pathway: Downregulation of Pyroptosis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36063391/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36063391/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acute lung injury (ALI) accompanied with systemic inflammatory response is an important complication after cardiopulmonary bypass (CPB). Pyroptosis, which is induced by the secretion of inflammatory factors, has been implicated in ALI. However, recent studies have suggested that bone marrow mesenchymal stem cell-derived exosomes (BMMSC-Exo) can ameliorate ALI, but the mechanism is poorly understood. Therefore, we aim to examine the effects of BMMSC-Exo in CPB-induced ALI, and its underlying mechanism. CPB rat models (male Sprague-Dawley rats) were administered BMMSC-Exo intravenously before induction of ALI. Lung tissue, bronchoalveolar lavage fluid (BALF), and alveolar macrophage (AM) were collected after the treatments for further analysis, and rat AM NR8383 cells were used for in vitro study. HE staining was performed to detect macrophage infiltration. Western blot was used to detect related proteins expression. And ELISA assay was performed to investigate secretion of inflammatory factors. These results showed that BMMSC-Exo treatment ameliorated macrophage infiltration and oxidative stress, and downregulated expression of pyroptosis-related proteins, including NLRP3, cleaved caspase-1, and GSDMD-N, in the lung tissue and AM, as well as decreased the secretion of IL-18 and IL-1β in BALF. Moreover, BMMSC-Exo activated YAP/β-catenin signaling pathway. Overall, these findings of this study indicated that BMMSC-Exo suppressed CPB-induced pyroptosis in ALI by activating YAP/β-catenin axis, which could be a novel strategy for lung protection during CPB.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pyrogallol enhances therapeutic effect of human umbilical cord mesenchymal stem cells against LPS-mediated inflammation and lung injury via activation of Nrf2/HO-1 signaling</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36028178/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36028178/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main challenges in clinical applications of mesenchymal stem cells (MSCs) are attributed to their heterogeneity. It is believed that preconditioning of MSCs with active compounds may enhance the expression of potentially therapeutic molecules and thus achieve stable and effective therapeutic outcomes. In the present study, we investigated the mechanism by which pyrogallol increased the therapeutic efficacy of human umbilical cord mesenchymal stem cells (hUCMSCs) against LPS-induced acute lung injury (ALI). hUCMSCs with pyrogallol treatment increased expression of HO-1 at both mRNA and protein levels, accompanied by Kelch-Like ECH-Associated Protein 1 (Keap1) degradation, and upregulation of the Nrf2 protein levels as well as nuclear translocation of Nrf2. Moreover, the modulation of Keap1 and Nrf2 as well as HO-1 upregulation by pyrogallol was reversed by pretreatment with N-acetylcysteine (NAC) and a P38 kinase inhibitor (SB203580). Whereas, NAC pretreatment abrogated pyrogallol-mediated activation of P38 kinase, indicating that pyrogallol-derived ROS led to P38 kinase activation, thus promoting Nrf2/HO-1 signaling. Additionally, we found that the induction of p62 by the pyrogallol-mediated ROS/P38/Nrf2 axis interacted with Keap1 and resulted in autophagic degradation of Keap1, which created a positive feedback loop to further release of Nrf2. Furthermore, the increased expression of HO-1 in pyrogallol-pretreated hUCMSCs led to enhanced inhibitory effects on LPS-mediated TLR4/P-P65 signaling in BEAS-2B cells, resulting in increasing suppression of LPS-indued expression of a series of pro-inflammatory mediators. Compared to untreated hUCMSCs, Sprague-Dawley (SD) rats with pyrogallol-primed hUCMSCs transplantation showed enhanced improvements in LPS-mediated lung pathological alterations, the increased lung index (lung/body ratio), apoptosis of epithelial cells, the activation of TLR4/NF-κB signaling as well as the release of pro-inflammatory mediators. Together, these results suggested that hUCMSCs with pyrogallol pretreatment enhanced the therapeutic efficacy of hUCMSCs, which may provide a promising therapeutic strategy to maximize the therapeutic efficacy of hUCMSC-based therapy for treating LPS-associated ALI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adipose mesenchymal stem cell-derived exosomal microRNAs ameliorate polycystic ovary syndrome by protecting against metabolic disturbances</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35987860/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35987860/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Polycystic ovary syndrome (PCOS) is the most common endocrine and metabolic disorder in women of childbearing age. Adipose mesenchymal stem cells (AMSCs) secrete cytokines involved in the regulation of metabolism and immunity. However, it remains unclear whether exosomes secreted by AMSCs (AMSC-EXOs) can rescue the polycystic phenotype and metabolic dysfunction in PCOS ovaries. Here, we show that AMSC-EXOs can protect against metabolic disturbances, ameliorate ovarian polycystic, and improve fertility in a rat model of PCOS. AMSC-EXOs inhibited the expression of B-cell translocation gene 2 by transferring miR-21-5p to the livers of rats with PCOS, thus activating the IRS1/AKT pathway and increasing hepatic metabolism. The role of AMSC-EXOs in transferring miRNAs to the liver to improve metabolic dysfunction in PCOS and reproduction by rescuing a non-coding RNA pathway was also discovered. This study provides a theoretical basis for the use of rat adipose stem cells and their secreted exosomes to treat PCOS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Repair effect of photobiomodulation combined with human umbilical cord mesenchymal stem cells on rats with acute lung injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36029758/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36029758/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acute lung injury (ALI) impaired the function of blood oxygen exchange function, resulting in tissue hypoxia and patient death. Recently, human umbilical cord mesenchymal stem cells (hUCMSCs) are thought to mitigate the effects of ALI, which boosts researchers&amp;rsquo; interest in employing stem cell-based therapies to manage ALI. However, as a novel therapy, hUCMSCs still face various limitations such as migrating weakly and insufficient proliferation in vivo. Photobiomodulation (PBM) effciently promotes cell proliferation, migration and homing, which presents a promising strategy for overcoming above limitations. In this study, PBM was emerged to intervene hUCMSCs through detecting cell proliferation, oxidative stress-related factors and inflammatory factors. These results assuredly confirmed that PBM enhanced the antioxidant capacity of cells and improved cell survival in vitro experiments. In vivo, PBM-intervened hUCMSCs intuitively reduce thickness of alveolar septum, excessive secretion of inflammatory factors, relieves bleeding, edema and fibrosis. As a physical intervention, PBM further strengthens the therapeutic effect of hUCMSCs and depicted a hopeful therapy in ALI treatment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neutrophil membrane engineered HucMSC sEVs alleviate cisplatin-induced AKI by enhancing cellular uptake and targeting</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35918718/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35918718/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Human umbilical cord mesenchymal stem cells-derived small extracellular vesicles (hucMSC-sEVs) have been demonstrated as a therapeutic agent to prevent and treat cisplatin-induced acute kidney injury (AKI). However, hucMSC-sEVs still face many problems and challenges in the repair and treatment of tissue injury, including short circulation time, insufficient targeting, and low therapeutic efficacy. Therefore, we constructed engineered hybrid vesicles fused with nanovesicles derived from human neutrophil membranes and hucMSC-sEVs, named neutrophil membrane engineered hucMSC-sEVs (NEX). NEX significantly enhanced the targeting of hucMSC-sEVs to injured kidney tissues, improved the impaired renal function via reducing pro-inflammatory cytokines expression, promoted the proliferation of renal tissue cells, and inhibited renal cell apoptosis in vivo. In addition, NEX enhanced hucMSC-sEVs uptake by NRK52E cells, but inhibited its uptake by RAW264.7 cells. Moreover, administration of NEX reduced cellular oxidative stress and promoted proliferation of NRK52E cells treated with cisplatin in vitro. In summary, our findings indicate that this design of a universal approach enhances the targeting and therapeutic efficacy of hucMSC-sEVs in kidney tissue regeneration, and provides new evidence promoting its clinical application.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exosomal lncRNA TUG1 derived from human urine-derived stem cells attenuates renal ischemia/reperfusion injury by interacting with SRSF1 to regulate ASCL4-mediated ferroptosis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35841017/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35841017/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;LncRNA TUG1 carried by USC-Exo regulates cell ferroptosis.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;LncRNA TUG1 regulates the stability of ACSL4 mRNA by interacting with SRSF1.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;LncRNA TUG1 alleviates IRI-induced AKI by suppressing ACSL4-mediated ferroptosis.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Human urine-derived stem cells (USCs)-derived exosomes (USC-Exo) could improve kidney ischemia/reperfusion injury (IRI), while the underlying mechanisms of this protective effect remain unclear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; Human USCs and USC-Exo were isolated and verified by morphology and specific biomarkers. The effects of USC-Exo on ferroptosis and kidney injury were detected in the IRI-induced acute kidney injury (AKI) model in C57BL/6 mice. The effects of USC-Exo on ferroptosis and lncRNA taurine-upregulated gene 1 (TUG1) were detected in hypoxia/reoxygenation (H/R)-treated human proximal tubular epithelial cells (HK-2). The interaction of SRSF1 and TUG1, ACSL4 was checked via RNA pull-down/RIP and RNA stability assays. The effects of LncRNA TUG1 on SRSF1/ACSL4-mediated ferroptosis were verified in H/R-treated HK-2 cells and the IRI-induced AKI mouse models.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; USC-Exo treatment improved kidney injury and ameliorated ferroptosis in IRI-induced AKI mouse models. USC-Exo were rich in lncRNA TUG1, which suppressed ferroptosis in HK-2 cells exposed to H/R. Mechanistically, lncRNA TUG1 regulates the stability of ACSL4 mRNA by interacting with RNA-binding protein SRSF1. In addition, SRSF1 upregulation or ACSL4 downregulation partially reversed the protective effect of lncRNA TUG1 on ferroptosis in H/R-treated HK-2 cells. Further, ACSL4 upregulation partially reversed TUG1&amp;rsquo;s repression on kidney injury and ferroptosis in IRI-induced AKI mice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/em&gt; Collectively, lncRNA TUG1 carried by USC-Exo regulated ASCL4-mediated ferroptosis by interacting with SRSF1 and then protected IRI-induced AKI. Potentially, USC-Exo rich in lncRNA TUG1 can serve as a promising therapeutic method for IRI-AKI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advances in the Regulation of Macrophage Polarization by Mesenchymal Stem Cells and Implications for ALI/ARDS Treatment</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/35880175/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/35880175/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acute lung injury/acute respiratory distress syndrome (ALI/ARDS) is a common condition with high mortality. ALI/ARDS is caused by multiple etiologies, and the main clinical manifestations are progressive dyspnea and intractable hypoxemia. Currently, supportive therapy is the main ALI/ARDS treatment, and there remains a lack of targeted and effective therapeutic strategies. Macrophages are important components of innate immunity. M1 macrophages are pro-inflammatory, while M2 macrophages are anti-inflammatory and promote tissue repair. Mesenchymal stem cells (MSCs) are stem cells with broad application prospects in tissue regeneration due to their multi-directional differentiation potential along with their anti-inflammatory and paracrine properties. MSCs can regulate the balance of M1/M2 macrophage polarization to improve the prognosis of ALI/ARDS. In this paper, we review the mechanisms by which MSCs regulate macrophage polarization and the signaling pathways associated with polarization. This review is expected to provide new targets for the treatment of ALI/ARDS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microvesicles Derived from Human Umbilical Cord Mesenchymal Stem Cells Enhance Alveolar Type II Cell Proliferation and Attenuate Lung Inflammation in a Rat Model of Bronchopulmonary Dysplasia</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35795773/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35795773/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although it is known that exosomes derived from human umbilical cord mesenchymal stem cells (hUCMSCs) alleviate hyperoxic lung injury of bronchopulmonary dysplasia (BPD) in animal models, the role of microvesicles (MVs) derived from hUCMSCs in BPD is poorly defined. Furthermore, antenatal inflammation has been linked to high risk of BPD in preterm infants. The purpose of this study was to explore whether MVs derived from hUCMSCs can preserve lung structure and function in an antenatal lipopolysaccharide- (LPS-) induced BPD rat model and to clarify the underlying mechanism. We demonstrate that antenatal LPS induced alveolar simplification, altered lung function, and dysregulated pulmonary vasculature, which restored by hUCMSCs and MVs treatment. Furthermore, MVs were large vesicles with a diameter of 100-900 nanometers and mostly uptaken by alveolar epithelial type II cells (AT2) and macrophages. Compared with the LPS-exposed group, MVs restored the AT2 cell number and SP-C expression in vivo and promoted the proliferation of AT2 cells in vitro. MVs also restored the level of IL-6 and IL-10 in lung homogenate. Additionally, PTEN/AKT and MAPK pathways were associated with the protection of MVs. Taken together, this study suggests MVs derived from hUCMSCs improve lung architecture and function in an antenatal LPS-induced BPD rat model by promoting AT2 cell proliferation and attenuating lung inflammation; thus, MVs provide a promising therapeutic vehicle for BPD treatment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Human gingival mesenchymal stem cells retain their growth and immunomodulatory characteristics independent of donor age</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35749495/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35749495/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aging has been reported to deteriorate the quantity and quality of mesenchymal stem cells (MSCs), which affect their therapeutic use in regenerative medicine. A dearth of age-related stem cell research further restricts their clinical applications. The present study explores the possibility of using MSCs derived from human gingival tissues (GMSCs) for studying their ex vivo growth characteristics and differentiation potential with respect to donor age. GMSCs displayed decreased in vitro adipogenesis and in vitro and in vivo osteogenesis with age, but in vitro neurogenesis remained unaffected. An increased expression of p53 and SIRT1 with donor age was correlated to their ability of eliminating tumorigenic events through apoptosis or autophagy, respectively. Irrespective of donor age, GMSCs displayed effective immunoregulation and regenerative potential in a mouse model of LPS-induced acute lung injury. Thus, we suggest the potential of GMSCs for designing cell-based immunomodulatory therapeutic approaches and their further extrapolation for acute inflammatory conditions such as acute respiratory distress syndrome and COVID-19.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stub1 maintains proteostasis of master transcription factors in embryonic stem cells</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35675767/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35675767/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stub1 maintains protein homeostasis of Sox2, Oct4, and Nanog in ESCs via the proteasome&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stub1 degrades Sox2 and Nanog through K48 linkage and Oct4 through K63 linkage&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stub1 increases trigger ESC differentiation, while its attenuation enhances pluripotency&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The pluripotency and differentiation states of embryonic stem cells (ESCs) are regulated by a set of core transcription factors, primarily Sox2, Oct4, and Nanog. Although their transcriptional regulation has been studied extensively, the contribution of posttranslational modifications in Sox2, Oct4, and Nanog are poorly understood. Here, using a CRISPR-Cas9 knockout library screen in murine ESCs, we identify the E3 ubiquitin ligase Stub1 as a negative regulator of pluripotency. Manipulation of Stub1 expression in murine ESCs shows that ectopic Stub1 expression significantly reduces the protein half-life of Sox2, Oct4, and Nanog. Mechanistic investigations reveal Stub1 catalyzes the polyubiquitination and 26S proteasomal degradation of Sox2 and Nanog through K48-linked ubiquitin chains and Oct4 via K63 linkage. Stub1 deficiency positively enhances somatic cell reprogramming and delays differentiation, whereas its enforced expression triggers ESC differentiation. The discovery of Stub1 as an integral pluripotency regulator strengthens our understanding of ESC regulation beyond conventional transcriptional control mechanisms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Drosophila renal stem cells enhance fitness by delayed remodeling of adult Malpighian tubules</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35594355/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35594355/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Drosophila&lt;/em&gt; renal stem cells (RSCs) contradict the common expectation that stem cells maintain tissue homeostasis. RSCs are abundant, quiescent, and confined to the peri-ureter region of the kidney-like Malpighian tubules (MTs). Although derived during pupation-like intestinal stem cells, RSCs initially remodel the larval MTs only near the intestinal junction. However, following adult injury to the ureter by xanthine stones, RSCs remodel the damaged region in a similar manner. Thus, RSCs represent stem cells encoding a developmental redesign. The remodeled tubules have a larger luminal diameter and shorter brush border, changes linked to enhanced stone resistance. However, RSC-mediated modifications also raise salt sensitivity and reduce fecundity. Our results suggest that RSCs arose by arresting developmental progenitors to preserve larval physiology until a time in adulthood when it becomes advantageous to complete the development by RSC activation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Human pluripotent stem cell-derived kidney organoids for personalized congenital and idiopathic nephrotic syndrome modeling</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35417019/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35417019/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nephrotic syndrome (NS) is characterized by severe proteinuria as a consequence of kidney glomerular injury due to podocyte damage. In vitro models mimicking in vivo podocyte characteristics are a prerequisite to resolve NS pathogenesis. The detailed characterization of organoid podocytes resulting from a hybrid culture protocol showed a podocyte population that resembles adult podocytes and was superior compared with 2D counterparts, based on single-cell RNA sequencing, super-resolution imaging and electron microscopy. In this study, these next-generation podocytes in kidney organoids enabled personalized idiopathic nephrotic syndrome modeling, as shown by activated slit diaphragm signaling and podocyte injury following protamine sulfate, puromycin aminonucleoside treatment and exposure to NS plasma containing pathogenic permeability factors. Organoids cultured from cells of a patient with heterozygous NPHS2 mutations showed poor NPHS2 expression and aberrant NPHS1 localization, which was reversible after genetic correction. Repaired organoids displayed increased VEGFA pathway activity and transcription factor activity known to be essential for podocyte physiology, as shown by RNA sequencing. This study shows that organoids are the preferred model of choice to study idiopathic and congenital podocytopathies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Small Extracellular Vesicles Containing miR-34c Derived from Bone Marrow Mesenchymal Stem Cells Regulates Epithelial Sodium Channel via Targeting MARCKS</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35563590/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35563590/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Epithelial sodium channel (ENaC) is a pivotal regulator of alveolar fluid clearance in the airway epithelium and plays a key role in the treatment of acute lung injury (ALI), which is mainly composed of the three homologous subunits (α, β and γ). The mechanisms of microRNAs in small extracellular vesicles (sEVs) derived from mesenchymal stem cell (MSC-sEVs) on the regulation of lung ion transport are seldom reported. In this study, we aimed at investigating whether miR-34c had an effect on ENaC dysfunction induced by lipopolysaccharide and explored the underlying mechanism in this process. Primarily, the effect of miR-34c on lung edema and histopathology changes in an ALI mouse model was investigated. Then the uptake of PKH26-labeled sEVs was observed in recipient cells, and we observed that the overexpression of miR-34c in MSC-sEVs could upregulate the LPS-inhibited γ-ENaC expression. The dual luciferase reporter gene assay demonstrated that myristoylated alanine-rich C kinase substrate (MARCKS) was one of target genes of miR-34c, the protein expression of which was negatively correlated with miR-34c. Subsequently, either upregulating miR-34c or knocking down MARCKS could increase the protein expression of phospho-phosphatidylinositol 3-kinase (p-PI3K) and phospho-protein kinase B (p-AKT), implying a downstream regulation pathway was involved. All of the above suggest that miR-34c in MSC-sEVs can attenuate edematous lung injury via enhancing γ-ENaC expression, at least partially, through targeting MARCKS and activating the PI3K/AKT signaling pathway subsequently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The dual role of glioma exosomal microRNAs: glioma eliminates tumor suppressor miR-1298-5p via exosomes to promote immunosuppressive effects of MDSCs</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35501306/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35501306/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clear evidence shows that tumors could secrete microRNAs (miRNAs) via exosomes to modulate the tumor microenvironment (TME). However, the mechanisms sorting specific miRNAs into exosomes are still unclear. In order to study the biological function and characterization of exosomal miRNAs, we performed whole-transcriptome sequencing in 59 patients&amp;rsquo; whole-course cerebrospinal fluid (CSF) small extracellular vesicles (sEV) and matched glioma tissue samples. The results demonstrate that miRNAs could be divided into exosome-enriched miRNAs (ExomiRNAs) and intracellular-retained miRNAs (CLmiRNAs), and exosome-enriched miRNAs generally play a dual role. Among them, miR-1298-5p was enriched in CSF exosomes and suppressed glioma progression in vitro and vivo experiments. Interestingly, exosomal miR-1298-5p could promote the immunosuppressive effects of myeloid-derived suppressor cells (MDSCs) to facilitate glioma. Therefore, we found miR-1298-5p had different effects on glioma cells and MDSCs. Mechanically, downstream signaling pathway analyses showed that miR-1298-5p plays distinct roles in glioma cells and MDSCs via targeting SETD7 and MSH2, respectively. Moreover, reverse verification was performed on the intracellular-retained miRNA miR-9-5p. Thus, we confirmed that tumor-suppressive miRNAs in glioma cells could be eliminated through exosomes and target tumor-associated immune cells to induce tumor-promoting phenotypes. Glioma could get double benefit from it. These findings uncover the mechanisms that glioma selectively sorts miRNAs into exosomes and modulates tumor immunity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SARS-CoV-2 infection of human-induced pluripotent stem cells-derived lung lineage cells evokes inflammatory and chemosensory responses by targeting mitochondrial pathways</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35460571/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35460571/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The COVID-19 disease caused by severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 (SARS-CoV-2) primarily affects the lung, particularly the proximal airway and distal alveolar cells. NKX2.1+ primordial lung progenitors of the foregut (anterior) endoderm are the developmental precursors to all adult lung epithelial lineages and are postulated to play an important role in viral tropism. Here, we show that SARS-CoV-2 readily infected and replicated in human-induced pluripotent stem cell-derived proximal airway cells, distal alveolar cells, and lung progenitors. In addition to the upregulation of antiviral defense and immune responses, transcriptomics data uncovered a robust epithelial cell-specific response, including perturbation of metabolic processes and disruption in the alveolar maturation program. We also identified spatiotemporal dysregulation of mitochondrial heme oxygenase 1 (HMOX1), which is associated with defense against antioxidant-induced lung injury. Cytokines, such as TNF-α, INF-γ, IL-6, and IL-13, were upregulated in infected cells sparking mitochondrial ROS production and change in electron transport chain complexes. Increased mitochondrial ROS then activated additional proinflammatory cytokines leading to an aberrant cell cycle resulting in apoptosis. Notably, we are the first to report a chemosensory response resulting from SARS-CoV-2 infection similar to that seen in COVID-19 patients. Some of our key findings were validated using COVID-19-affected postmortem lung tissue sections. These results suggest that our in vitro system could serve as a suitable model to investigate the pathogenetic mechanisms of SARS-CoV-2 infection and to discover and test therapeutic drugs against COVID-19 or its consequences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The nuclear receptor THRB facilitates differentiation of human PSCs into more mature hepatocytes</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35452598/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35452598/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;THRB motif enrichment in regulomes is lower in PSC-hepatocytes than in primary hepatocytes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;THRB regulates &lt;em&gt;CYP3A4&lt;/em&gt; expression by binding to the proximal enhancer of &lt;em&gt;CYP3A4&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The pBAF component PBRM1 binds THRB and is required for THRB regulation of &lt;em&gt;CYP3A4&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;T3 promotes maturation and engraftment of in vitro differentiated hPSC-hepatocytes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To understand the mechanisms regulating the &lt;em&gt;in vitro&lt;/em&gt; maturation of hPSC-derived hepatocytes, we developed a 3D differentiation system and compared gene regulatory elements in human primary hepatocytes with those in hPSC-hepatocytes that were differentiated in 2D or 3D conditions by RNA-seq, ATAC-seq, and H3K27Ac ChIP-seq. Regulome comparisons showed a reduced enrichment of thyroid receptor THRB motifs in accessible chromatin and active enhancers without a reduced transcription of THRB. The addition of thyroid hormone T3 increased the binding of THRB to the &lt;em&gt;CYP3A4&lt;/em&gt; proximal enhancer, restored the super-enhancer status and gene expression of &lt;em&gt;NFIC&lt;/em&gt;, and reduced the expression of &lt;em&gt;AFP&lt;/em&gt;. The resultant hPSC-hepatocytes showed gene expression, epigenetic status, and super-enhancer landscape closer to primary hepatocytes and activated regulatory regions including non-coding SNPs associated with liver-related diseases. Transplanting the hPSC-hepatocytes resulted in the engraftment of human hepatocytes into the mouse liver without disrupting normal liver histology. This work implicates the environmental factor-nuclear receptor axis in regulating the maturation of hPSC-hepatocytes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Therapeutic stem cell-derived alveolar-like macrophages display bactericidal effects and resolve Pseudomonas aeruginosa-induced lung injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35441437/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35441437/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bacterial lung infections lead to greater than 4 million deaths per year with antibiotic treatments driving an increase in antibiotic resistance and a need to establish new therapeutic approaches. Recently, we have generated mouse and rat stem cell-derived alveolar-like macrophages (ALMs), which like primary alveolar macrophages (1&amp;rsquo;AMs), phagocytose bacteria and promote airway repair. Our aim was to further characterize ALMs and determine their bactericidal capabilities. The characterization of ALMs showed that they share known 1&amp;rsquo;AM cell surface markers, but unlike 1&amp;rsquo;AMs are highly proliferative in vitro. ALMs effectively phagocytose and kill laboratory strains of P. aeruginosa (P.A.), E. coli (E.C.) and S. aureus, and clinical strains of P.A. In vivo, ALMs remain viable, adapt additional features of native 1&amp;rsquo;AMs, but proliferation is reduced. Mouse ALMs phagocytose P.A. and E.C. and rat ALMs phagocytose and kill P.A. within the lung 24 h post-instillation. In a pre-clinical model of P.A.-induced lung injury, rat ALM administration mitigated weight loss and resolved lung injury observed seven days post-instillation. Collectively, ALMs attenuate pulmonary bacterial infections and promote airway repair. ALMs could be utilized as an alternative or adjuvant therapy where current treatments are ineffective against antibiotic-resistant bacteria or to enhance routine antibiotic delivery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Targeted Therapy for Inflammatory Diseases with Mesenchymal Stem Cells and Their Derived Exosomes: From Basic to Clinics</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/35469174/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/35469174/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inflammation is a beneficial and physiological process, but there are a number of inflammatory diseases which have detrimental effects on the body. In addition, the drugs used to treat inflammation have toxic side effects when used over a long period of time. Mesenchymal stem cells (MSCs) are pluripotent stem cells that can be isolated from a variety of tissues and can be differentiate into diverse cell types under appropriate conditions. They also exhibit noteworthy anti-inflammatory properties, providing new options for the treatment of inflammatory diseases. The therapeutic potential of MSCs is currently being investigated for various inflammatory diseases, such as kidney injury, lung injury, osteoarthritis (OA), rheumatoid arthritis (RA), and inflammatory bowel disease (IBD). MSCs can perform multiple functions, including immunomodulation, homing, and differentiation, to enable damaged tissues to form a balanced inflammatory and regenerative microenvironment under severe inflammatory conditions. In addition, accumulated evidence indicates that exosomes from extracellular vesicles of MSCs (MSC-Exos) play an extraordinary role, mainly by transferring their components to recipient cells. In this review, we summarize the mechanism and clinical trials of MSCs and MSC-Exos in various inflammatory diseases in detail, with a view to contributing to the treatment of MSCs and MSC-Exos in inflammatory diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HLA-A2 Promotes the Therapeutic Effect of Umbilical Cord Blood-Derived Mesenchymal Stem Cells in Hyperoxic Lung Injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35447737/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35447737/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mesenchymal stem cells (MSCs) are one of the most extensively studied stem cell types owing to their capacity for differentiation into multiple lineages as well as their ability to secrete regenerative factors and modulate immune functions. However, issues remain regarding their further application for cell therapy. Here, to demonstrate the superiority of the improvement of MSCs, we divided umbilical cord blood-derived MSCs (UCB-MSCs) from 15 donors into two groups based on efficacy and revealed donor-dependent variations in the anti-inflammatory effect of MSCs on macrophages as well as their immunoregulatory effect on T cells. Through surface marker analyses (242 antibodies), we found that HLA-A2 was positively related to the anti-inflammatory and immunoregulatory function of MSCs. Additionally, HLA-A2 mRNA silencing in MSCs attenuated their therapeutic effects in vitro; namely, the suppression of LPS-stimulated macrophages and phytohemagglutinin-stimulated T cells. Moreover, HLA-A2 silencing in MSCs significantly decreased their therapeutic effects in a rat model of hyperoxic lung damage. The present study provides novel insights into the quality control of donor-derived MSCs for the treatment of inflammatory conditions and diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Secretome of Mesenchymal Stem Cells from Consecutive Hypoxic Cultures Promotes Resolution of Lung Inflammation by Reprogramming Anti-Inflammatory Macrophages</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35457151/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35457151/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The secretome from hypoxia-preconditioned mesenchymal stem cells (MSCs) has been shown to promote resolution of inflammation and alleviate acute lung injury (ALI) through its immunomodulatory function. However, the effects of consecutive hypoxic culture on immunomodulatory function of the MSCs secretome are largely unclarified. Here, we intend to investigate the effects of consecutive hypoxia on therapeutic efficacy of conditioned medium derived from MSCs (MSCs-CM) in alleviating ALI. Human umbilical cord-derived MSCs (UC-MSCs) were consecutively cultured in 21% O2 (Nor-MSCs) or in 1% O2 (Hypo-MSCs) from passage 0. Their conditioned medium (Nor-CM and Hypo-CM respectively) was collected and administered into ALI models. Our findings confirmed that Hypo-MSCs exhibited increased proliferation ability and decreased cell senescence compared with Nor-MSCs. Consecutive hypoxia promoted UC-MSCs to secrete immunomodulatory cytokines, such as insulin-like growth factor 1(IGF1), IL10, TNFα-stimulated gene 6(TSG6), TGFβ, and prostaglandin E2 (PGE2). Both Nor-CM and Hypo-CM could effectively limit lung inflammation, promote efferocytosis and modulate anti-inflammatory polarization of lung macrophages in ALI models. Moreover, the effects of Hypo-CM were more potent than Nor-CM. Taken together, our findings indicate that consecutive hypoxic cultures could not only promote both proliferation and quality of UC-MSCs, but also enhance the therapeutic efficacy of their secretome in mitigating lung inflammation by promoting efferocytosis and anti-inflammatory polarization of macrophages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Progenitor potential of lung epithelial organoid cells in a transplantation model</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35417699/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35417699/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Alveolar organoid cells engraft into the alveolar space&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Transplanted lung alveolar cells have transcriptional signature of native AT2 cells&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Transplanted alveolar cells proliferate and retain organoid-forming capacity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Organoid cells undergo changes to transitional cell states upon transplantation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lung progenitor cells are crucial for regeneration following injury, yet it is unclear whether lung progenitor cells can be functionally engrafted after transplantation. We transplanted organoid cells derived from alveolar type II (AT2) cells enriched by SCA1-negative status (SNO) or multipotent SCA1-positive progenitor cells (SPO) into injured mouse lungs. Transplanted SNO cells are retained in the alveolar regions, whereas SPO cells incorporate into airway and alveolar regions. Single-cell transcriptomics demonstrate that transplanted SNO cells are comparable to native AT2 cells. Transplanted SPO cells exhibit transcriptional hallmarks of alveolar and airway cells, as well as transitional cell states identified in disease. Transplanted cells proliferate after re-injury of recipient mice and retain organoid-forming capacity. Thus, lung epithelial organoid cells exhibit progenitor cell functions after reintroduction to the lung. This study reveals methods to interrogate lung progenitor cell potential and model transitional cell states relevant to pathogenic features of lung disease &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Every road leads to Rome: therapeutic effect and mechanism of the extracellular vesicles of human embryonic stem cell-derived immune and matrix regulatory cells administered to mouse models of pulmonary fibrosis through different routes</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35413874/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35413874/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis (IPF) is a progressive and fatal interstitial lung disease. Whether extracellular vesicles are effective in treating IPF and what is the optimal administrative route is not clear. Our previous studies have shown that immunity and matrix regulatory cells (IMRCs) derived from human embryonic stem cells can safely treat lung injury and fibrosis in mouse models, and its mechanism of action is related to the paracrine effect. In this study, we investigated the therapeutic effects of IMRC-derived extracellular vesicles (IMRC-EVs) on a bleomycin-induced pulmonary fibrosis mouse model and explored the optimal route of administration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; To study the biodistribution of IMRC-EVs after administration via different routes, NIR labeled-IMRC-EVs were delivered by intratracheal (IT) or intravenous (IV) route, and in vivo imaging was acquired at different time points. The therapeutic effects of IMRC-EVs delivered by different routes were analyzed by assessing histology, lung function, cytokines levels, and transcriptome profiling. RNA-seq of lung tissues was performed to investigate the mechanisms of EV treatment through IT or IV administrations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; IMRC-EVs mainly reserved in the liver and spleen when administrated via IV route; and mainly retained in the lungs via the IT route. IMRC-EVs administrated via both routes demonstrated a therapeutic effect as attenuated pulmonary fibrosis, improved lung function, and histological parameters. Based on our RNA-seq results, different pathways may be affected by IMRC-EVs administrated via IT or IV routes. In addition, in vitro experiments showed that IMRC-EVs inhibited epithelial-to-mesenchymal transition induced by TGF-β.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/em&gt; IMRC-EVs administrated via IT or IV routes generate different biodistributions, but are both effective for the treatment of bleomycin-induced pulmonary fibrosis. The therapeutic mechanisms of IMRC-EVs administrated via different routes may be different.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Biomimic Trained Immunity-MSCs Delivery Microcarriers for Acute Liver Failure Regeneration</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35411651/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35411651/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mesenchymal stem cells (MSCs) have a demonstrated value for acute liver failure (ALF) regeneration, while their delivery stratagems with long-term biological functions, low immune response, and high biocompatibility are still a challenge. Here, a lipopolysaccharide (LPS)-loaded photoresponsive cryogel porous microcarrier (CPM) for MSCs delivery and colonization is presented to promote defect liver regeneration. The CPMs are fabricated with graphene oxide, poly(N-isopropylacrylamide), and gelatin methacrylate (GelMA) via droplet microfluidic technology and a gradient-cooling procedure. Benefitting from the biocompatible GelMA component and the porous microstructure of the CPMs, MSCs can be nondestructively captured and abundantly delivered. Because the LPS can be released from the CPMs under NIR irradiation, the delivered MSCs are imparted with the feature of &amp;ldquo;trained immunity.&amp;rdquo; Thus, when the MSCs-laden CPMs are tailored into the liver matched patches by bioprinting and applied in ALF rats, they display superior anti-inflammatory and more significant liver regeneration properties than the untrained MSCs. These features make the CPMs an excellent MSCs delivery system for clinical applications in tissue repair.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The ZIP8/SIRT1 axis regulates alveolar progenitor cell renewal in aging and idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35389887/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35389887/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Type 2 alveolar epithelial cells (AEC2s) function as progenitor cells in the lung. We have shown previously that failure of AEC2 regeneration results in progressive lung fibrosis in mice and is a cardinal feature of idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis (IPF). In this study, we identified deficiency of a specific zinc transporter, SLC39A8 (ZIP8), in AEC2s from both IPF lungs and lungs of old mice. Loss of ZIP8 expression was associated with impaired renewal capacity of AEC2s and enhanced lung fibrosis. ZIP8 regulation of AEC2 progenitor function was dependent on SIRT1. Replenishment with exogenous zinc and SIRT1 activation promoted self-renewal and differentiation of AEC2s from lung tissues of IPF patients and old mice. Deletion of Zip8 in AEC2s in mice resulted in impaired AEC2 renewal, increased susceptibility to bleomycin injury, and development of spontaneous lung fibrosis. Therapeutic strategies to restore zinc metabolism and appropriate SIRT1 signaling could improve AEC2 progenitor function and mitigate ongoing fibrogenesis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Potential effect of amniotic fluid-derived stem cells on hyperoxia-induced pulmonary alveolar injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35379329/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35379329/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; With the widespread of Coronavirus Disease 2019 pandemic, in spite of the newly emerging vaccines, mutated strains remain a great obstacle to supportive and preventive measures. Coronavirus 19 survivors continue to face great danger of contacting the disease again. As long as no specific treatment has yet to be approved, a great percentage of patients experience real complications, including among others, lung fibrosis. High oxygen inhalation especially for prolonged periods is per se destructive to the lungs. Nevertheless, oxygen remains the first line support for such patients. In the present study we aimed at investigating the role of amniotic fluid-mesenchymal stem cells in preventing versus treating the hyperoxia-induced lung fibrosis in rats.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; The study was conducted on adult albino rats; 5 pregnant female rats were used as amniotic fluid donors, and 64 male rats were randomly divided into two groups: Control group; where 10 rats were kept in normal atmospheric air then sacrificed after 2 months, and hyperoxia-induced lung fibrosis group, where 54 rats were exposed to hyperoxia (100% oxygen for 6 h/day) in air-tight glass chambers for 1 month, then randomly divided into the following 5 subgroups: Hyperoxia group, cell-free media-treated group, stem cells-prophylactic group, stem cells-treated group and untreated group. Isolation, culture and proliferation of stem cells were done till passage 3. Pulmonary function tests, histological examination of lung tissue under light and electron microscopes, biochemical assessment of oxidative stress, IL-6 and Rho-A levels, and statistical analysis of data were performed. F-test (ANOVA) was used for normally distributed quantitative variables, to compare between more than two groups, and Post Hoc test (Tukey) for pairwise comparisons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; Labelled amniotic fluid-mesenchymal stem cells homed to lung tissue. Stem cells administration in the stem cells-prophylactic group succeeded to maintain pulmonary functions near the normal values with no significant difference between their values and those of the control group. Moreover, histological examination of lung tissues showed that stem cells-prophylactic group were completely protected while stem cells-treated group still showed various degrees of tissue injury, namely; thickened interalveolar septa, atelectasis and interstitial pneumonia. Biochemical studies after stem cells injection also showed decreased levels of RhoA and IL-6 in the prophylactic group and to a lesser extent in the treated group, in addition to increased total antioxidant capacity and decreased malondialdehyde in the stem cells-injected groups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; Amniotic fluid-mesenchymal stem cells showed promising protective and therapeutic results against hyperoxia-induced lung fibrosis as evaluated physiologically, histologically and biochemically.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Counterintuitive production of tumor-suppressive secretomes from Oct4- and c-Myc-overexpressing tumor cells and MSCs</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35547745/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35547745/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Advanced breast cancer frequently metastasizes to bone, but inhibiting tumor progression in chemotherapy may occasionally enhance tumorigenesis. Here, we employed a counterintuitive approach of overexpressing Yamanaka factors (Oct4, c-Myc, Sox2, and Klf4) and examined a conditioned medium (CM)-based treatment option with induced tumor-suppressing cells (iTSCs).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;In vitro&lt;/em&gt; proliferation and migration assays were conducted using tumor cell lines derived from breast cancer, as well as prostate and pancreatic cancers, and osteosarcoma. The tumor-suppressing capability of iTSC-derived CM was evaluated using freshly isolated breast cancer tissues and a mouse model of mammary tumors and tumor-induced osteolysis. The regulatory mechanism was evaluated using Western blotting, immunoprecipitation, pull-down, gene overexpression, and RNA interference based on mass spectrometry-based proteomics data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; The overexpression of Oct4 and c-Myc in tumor cells and MSCs, but not Sox2 or Klf4, generated anti-tumor CM, which suppressed the progression of mammary tumors and tumor-induced bone loss. Notably, CM downregulated histone demethylase, and PDL-1, a blocker of T-cell-based immune responses. Whole-genome proteomics predicted enolase 1 (Eno1), Hsp90ab1, Eef2, and vinculin as extracellular tumor suppressors. Specifically, CD44 was co-immunoprecipitated with Eno1 and the silencing of CD44 suppressed Eno1&amp;rsquo;s anti-tumor action. The overexpression of Oct4 and c-Myc also generated secretomes that inhibited the development of bone-resorbing osteoclasts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; In analogous to cell competition in which Myc-overexpressing cells in Drosophila and mouse embryos remove neighboring cells with a lower level of Myc, this study presented the possibility of eliminating tumor cells by the secretory proteomes derived from Myc/Oc4-overexpressing iTSCs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TNF-α stimulation enhances the neuroprotective effects of gingival MSCs derived exosomes in retinal ischemia-reperfusion injury via the MEG3/miR-21a-5p axis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35378413/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35378413/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Retinal ischemia-reperfusion injury (IRI) is one of the main pathogenic mechanisms of glaucoma, which are largely unknown, including neuroinflammation and neuronal death in the pathological process. In our previous studies, mesenchymal stem cells (MSCs) have been reported to play anti-inflammatory and neuroprotective roles. Additionally, conditioned culture medium (CM) of MSCs stimulated by TNF-α have achieved better antiallergic effects in an experimental allergic conjunctivitis mouse model. However, there is an urgent need for cell-free therapy approaches, like exosomes, to reduce the side effects of autoimmunity. The present study aimed to elucidate the pathways involving TNF-α-stimulated gingival MSC (GMSC)-exosomes (TG-exos), in modulating inflammatory microglia and alleviating apoptosis. In this study, exosomes from the CM of GMSCs were isolated by ultracentrifugation and were injected into the vitreous of mice. The results showed that intraocular injection of TG-exos into mice with IRI notably reduced inflammation and cell loss than that with G-exos (GMSC-exosomes). Similar results were observed in vitro. Additionally, with the microRNA (miR) arrays, it was found that miR-21-5p acted as a crucial factor in TG-exos for neuroprotection and anti-inflammation. Following target prediction and dual-luciferase assay suggested that miR-21-5p played a role by combining with programmed cell death 4 (PDCD4), which was regulated by the long non-coding RNA (lncRNA) maternally expressed gene 3 (MEG3) as a competing endogenous RNA (ceRNA). This study demonstrates a new therapeutic pathway for neuroprotection against IRI by delivering miR-21-5p-enriched exosomes through MEG3/miR-21-5p/PDCD4 axis and paves the way for the establishment of a cell-free therapeutic approach for glaucoma.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inhaled Placental Mesenchymal Stromal Cell Secretome from Two- and Three-Dimensional Cell Cultures Promotes Survival and Regeneration in Acute Lung Injury Model in Mice</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35408778/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35408778/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acute lung injury (ALI) and acute respiratory distress syndrome (ARDS) is a common clinical problem, leading to significant morbidity and mortality, and no effective pharmacotherapy exists. The problem of ARDS causing mortality became more apparent during the COVID-19 pandemic. Biotherapeutic products containing multipotent mesenchymal stromal cell (MMSC) secretome may provide a new therapeutic paradigm for human healthcare due to their immunomodulating and regenerative abilities. The content and regenerative capacity of the secretome depends on cell origin and type of cultivation (two- or three-dimensional (2D/3D)). In this study, we investigated the proteomic profile of the secretome from 2D- and 3D-cultured placental MMSC and lung fibroblasts (LFBs) and the effect of inhalation of freeze-dried secretome on survival, lung inflammation, lung tissue regeneration, fibrin deposition in a lethal ALI model in mice. We found that three inhaled administrations of freeze-dried secretome from 2D- and 3D-cultured placental MMSC and LFB protected mice from death, restored the histological structure of damaged lungs, and decreased fibrin deposition. At the same time, 3D MMSC secretome exhibited a more pronounced trend in lung recovery than 2D MMSC and LFB-derived secretome in some measures. Taking together, these studies show that inhalation of cell secretome may also be considered as a potential therapy for the management of ARDS in patients suffering from severe pneumonia, including severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 (SARS-CoV-2), however, their effectiveness requires further investigation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AdMSC-derived exosomes alleviate acute lung injury via transferring mitochondrial component to improve homeostasis of alveolar macrophages</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35401830/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35401830/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rationale:&lt;/em&gt; Aberrant activation of macrophages with mitochondria dismiss was proved to be associated with pathogenesis of ALI (acute lung injury). Exosomes from adipose-derived mesenchymal stem cells (AdMSC-Exos) have been distinguished by their low immunogenicity, lack of tumorigenicity, and high clinical safety, but their role in treating ALI and the mechanism involved need to be defined. In this study, we sought to investigate whether the mitochondrial donation from AdMSC-Exos provides profound protection against LPS-induced ALI in mice, accompanied by improvement of macrophage mitochondrial function.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; C57BL/6 mice were orotracheally instilled with LPS (1 mg/kg). AdMSC-Exos were administered via the tail vein 4 h after LPS inhalation. Flow cytometry, H&amp;amp;E, Quantitative Real-Time PCR, immunofluorescence (IF), confocal microscopy imaging was conducted to investigate lung tissue inflammation and macrophage mitochondrial function. And further observe the transfer of exosomes and the effect on mitochondrial function of MH-S cells through &lt;em&gt;in vitro&lt;/em&gt; experiments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; AdMSC-Exos can transfer the stem cell-derived mitochondria components to alveolar macrophages in a dose-dependent manner. Likely through complementing the damaged mitochondria, AdMSC-Exos exhibited the ability to elevate the level of mtDNA, mitochondrial membrane potential (MMP), OXPHOS activity and ATP generation, while reliving mROS stress in LPS-challenged macrophages. Restoring mitochondrial integrity via AdMSC-Exos treatment enabled macrophages shifting to anti-inflammatory phenotype, as featured with the down-regulation of IL-1β, TNF-α and iNOS secretion and increase in production of anti-inflammatory cytokines IL-10 and Arg-1. As we depleted alveolar macrophages using clodronate liposomes, the protective role for AdMSC-Exos was largely abrogated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; AdMSC-Exos can effectively donate mitochondria component improved macrophages mitochondrial integrity and oxidative phosphorylation level, leading to the resumption of metabolic and immune homeostasis of airway macrophages and mitigating lung inflammatory pathology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bmi1 signaling maintains the plasticity of airway epithelial progenitors in response to persistent silica exposures</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35288261/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35288261/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Silicosis is caused by the continuous inhalation of environmental silica dust. The repetitive exposure of silica induces airway epithelial cell injury, leads proliferative exhaustion of epithelial stem cells, ultimately results in the lung remodeling and the development of silicosis. The B-cell-specific Moloney murine leukemia virus integration site 1 (Bmi1) is a pivotal transcription factor in stem cell self-renewal and proliferation of many tissues including the lung, but its role in the airway basal cell proliferation and differentiation during the pathogenesis of silicosis in lung has yet been investigated. In this study, the function of Bmi1 in airway basal cell proliferation and differentiation in response to silica challenge was investigated in lungs of silicosis mice and primary human bronchial epithelia cells (HBECs) exposed to silica dioxide (SiO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;). Results showed a decreased expression of Bmi1 protein, epithelial basal cell markers Krt14 and Krt5, club cell marker Clara cell secretory protein, and ciliated cell marker acetyl-α-tubulin in silicosis lungs, compared to healthy mice. In consistence, a persistent exposure of SiO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; reduced the capacity of cell proliferation and differentiation in HBECs, as ascertained by the reduction of differentiated epithelial cell markers and BMI1 expression, while an increased P21-positive senescent cell fraction. Moreover, an overexpression of BMI1 in HBECs reduced the SiO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;-senescent cells, enhanced the potency of cell proliferation and differentiation, and increased capacity of airway epithelial regeneration in response to the persistent exposure of SiO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;. These data suggest that Bmi1 is a key transcription factor engaging in maintaining the self-renewal, proliferation and differentiation of epithelial stem cells in lung during the development of silicosis disease.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Niclosamide induces miR-148a to inhibit PXR and sensitize colon cancer stem cells to chemotherapy</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35276090/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35276090/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;miR-148a&lt;/em&gt; expression is decreased in colon cancer stem cells&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Forced expression of &lt;em&gt;miR-148a&lt;/em&gt; inhibits colon cancer stem cell chemoresistance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;High-content screening identified niclosamide as a potent &lt;em&gt;miR-148a&lt;/em&gt; inducer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Niclosamide induces &lt;em&gt;miR-148a&lt;/em&gt; expression, inhibits PXR expression in CSCs and prevents tumor&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tumor recurrence is often attributed to cancer stem cells (CSCs). We previously demonstrated that down-regulation of Pregnane X Receptor (PXR) decreases the chemoresistance of CSCs and prevents colorectal cancer recurrence. Currently, no PXR inhibitor is usable in clinic. Here, we identify &lt;em&gt;miR-148a&lt;/em&gt; as a targetable element upstream of PXR signaling in CSCs, which when over-expressed decreases PXR expression and impairs tumor relapse after chemotherapy in mouse tumor xenografts. We then develop a fluorescent reporter screen for &lt;em&gt;miR-148a&lt;/em&gt; activators and identify the anti-helminthic drug niclosamide as an inducer of &lt;em&gt;miR-148a&lt;/em&gt; expression. Consequently, niclosamide decreased PXR expression and CSC numbers in colorectal cancer patient-derived cell lines and synergized with chemotherapeutic agents to prevent CSC chemoresistance and tumor recurrence in vivo. Our study suggests that endogenous miRNA inducers is a viable strategy to down-regulate PXR and illuminates niclosamide as a neoadjuvant repurposing strategy to prevent tumor relapse in colon cancer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comparative Effects of Bone Marrow-derived Versus Umbilical Cord Tissue Mesenchymal Stem Cells in an Experimental Model of Bronchopulmonary Dysplasia</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35298658/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35298658/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bronchopulmonary dysplasia (BPD) is a life-threatening condition in preterm infants with few effective therapies. Mesenchymal stem or stromal cells (MSCs) are a promising therapeutic strategy for BPD. The ideal MSC source for BPD prevention is however unknown. The objective of this study was to compare the regenerative effects of MSC obtained from bone marrow (BM) and umbilical cord tissue (UCT) in an experimental BPD model. In vitro, UCT-MSC demonstrated greater proliferation and expression of anti-inflammatory cytokines as compared to BM-MSC. Lung epithelial cells incubated with UCT-MSC conditioned media (CM) had better-wound healing following scratch injury. UCT-MSC CM and BM-MSC CM had similar pro-angiogenic effects on hyperoxia-exposed pulmonary microvascular endothelial cells. In vivo, newborn rats exposed to normoxia or hyperoxia (85% O&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;) from postnatal day (P) 1 to 21 were given intra-tracheal (IT) BM or UCT-MSC (1 × 10&lt;sup&gt;6，、 cells/50 μL), or placebo (PL) on P3. Hyperoxia PL-treated rats had marked alveolar simplification, reduced lung vascular density, pulmonary vascular remodeling, and lung inflammation. In contrast, administration of both BM-MSC and UCT-MSC significantly improved alveolar structure, lung angiogenesis, pulmonary vascular remodeling, and lung inflammation. UCT-MSC hyperoxia-exposed rats however had greater improvement in some morphometric measures of alveolarization and less lung macrophage infiltration as compared to the BM-MSC-treated group. Together, these findings suggest that BM-MSC and UCT-MSC have significant lung regenerative effects in experimental BPD but UCT-MSC suppresses lung macrophage infiltration and promotes lung epithelial cell healing to a greater degree.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Epigenomic and enhancer dysregulation in uterine leiomyomas</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/35199155/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/35199155/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Uterine leiomyomas, also known as uterine fibroids or myomas, are the most common benign gynecological tumors and are found in women of reproductive and postmenopausal age. There is an exceptionally high prevalence of this tumor in women by the age of 50 years. Black women are particularly affected, with an increased incidence, earlier age of onset, larger and faster growing fibroids and greater severity of symptoms as compared to White women. Although advances in identifying genetic and environmental factors to delineate these fibroids have already been made, only recently has the role of epigenomics in the pathogenesis of this disease been considered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Objective and rationale:&lt;/em&gt; Over recent years, studies have identified multiple epigenomic aberrations that may contribute to leiomyoma development and growth. This review will focus on the most recent discoveries in three categories of epigenomic changes found in uterine fibroids, namely aberrant DNA methylation, histone tail modifications and histone variant exchange, and their translation into altered target gene architecture and transcriptional outcome. The findings demonstrating how the altered 3D shape of the enhancer can regulate gene expression from millions of base pairs away will be discussed. Additionally, translational implications of these discoveries and potential roadblocks in leiomyoma treatment will be addressed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Search methods:&lt;/em&gt; A comprehensive PubMed search was performed to identify published articles containing keywords relevant to the focus of the review, such as: uterine leiomyoma, uterine fibroids, epigenetic alterations, epigenomics, stem cells, chromatin modifications, extracellular matrix [ECM] organization, DNA methylation, enhancer, histone post-translational modifications and dysregulated gene expression. Articles until September 2021 were explored and evaluated to identify relevant updates in the field. Most of the articles focused on in the discussion were published between 2015 and 2021, although some key discoveries made before 2015 were included for background information and foundational purposes. We apologize to the authors whose work was not included because of space restrictions or inadvertent omission.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Outcomes:&lt;/em&gt; Chemical alterations to the DNA structure and of nucleosomal histones, without changing the underlying DNA sequence, have now been implicated in the phenotypic manifestation of uterine leiomyomas. Genome-wide DNA methylation analysis has revealed subsets of either suppressed or overexpressed genes accompanied by aberrant promoter methylation. Furthermore, differential promoter access resulting from altered 3D chromatin structure and histone modifications plays a role in regulating transcription of key genes thought to be involved in leiomyoma etiology. The dysregulated genes function in tumor suppression, apoptosis, angiogenesis, ECM formation, a variety of cancer-related signaling pathways and stem cell differentiation. Aberrant DNA methylation or histone modification is also observed in altering enhancer architecture, which leads to changes in enhancer-promoter contact strength, producing novel explanations for the overexpression of high mobility group AT-hook 2 and gene dysregulation found in mediator complex subunit 12 mutant fibroids. While many molecular mechanisms and epigenomic features have been investigated, the basis for the racial disparity observed among those in the Black population remains unclear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Wider implications:&lt;/em&gt; A comprehensive understanding of the exact pathogenesis of uterine leiomyoma is lacking and requires attention as it can provide clues for prevention and viable non-surgical treatment. These findings will widen our knowledge of the role epigenomics plays in the mechanisms related to uterine leiomyoma development and highlight novel approaches for the prevention and identification of epigenome targets for long-term non-invasive treatment options of this significantly common disease.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sepsis promotes splenic production of a protective platelet pool with high CD40 ligand expression</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35192546/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35192546/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Platelets have a wide range of functions including critical roles in hemostasis, thrombosis, and immunity. We hypothesized that during acute inflammation, such as in life-threatening sepsis, there are fundamental changes in the sites of platelet production and phenotypes of resultant platelets. Here, we showed during sepsis that the spleen was a major site of megakaryopoiesis and platelet production. Sepsis provoked an adrenergic-dependent mobilization of megakaryocyte-erythrocyte progenitors (MEPs) from the bone marrow to the spleen, where IL-3 induced their differentiation into megakaryocytes (MKs). In the spleen, immune-skewed MKs produced a CD40 ligandhi platelet population with potent immunomodulatory functions. Transfusions of post-sepsis platelets enriched from splenic production enhanced immune responses and reduced overall mortality in sepsis-challenged animals. These findings identify a spleen-derived protective platelet population that may be broadly immunomodulatory in acute inflammatory states such as sepsis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Human Umbilical Cord-Derived Mesenchymal Stem Cells Alleviate Acute Lung Injury Caused by Severe Burn via Secreting TSG-6 and Inhibiting Inflammatory Response</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35222649/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35222649/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Objectives:&lt;/em&gt; To investigate whether hUC-MSCs attenuated severe burn-induced ALI and the effects were based on TSG-6 secreted from hUC-MSCs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Method:&lt;/em&gt; A rat model was established and evaluated as follows: cytokine expression was measured by ELISA, and both inflammatory cell infiltration and lung injury were assessed by immunohistochemistry assay.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;In vitro&lt;/em&gt;, TSG-6 levels in serum from the burn group were significantly increased compared with those from the sham group. &lt;em&gt;In vivo&lt;/em&gt;, TSG-6 levels of lung tissues and serum in the burn+hUC-MSC group were significantly increased compared with those in the burn group. Both in lung tissues and in serum, increased levels of proinflammatory cytokines (TNF-α, IL-1β, and IL-6) were remarkably decreased, but the anti-inflammatory cytokine IL-10 increased after hUC-MSC administration (&lt;em&gt;p&lt;/em&gt; &amp;lt; 0.05). These significant positive effects after hUC-MSC transplantation did not occur in the burn+siTSG-6 group.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/em&gt; The intratracheal implantation of hUC-MSCs has been an effective treatment for severe burn-induced ALI via promoting TSG-6 secretion and inhibiting inflammatory reaction in lung tissue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BCL-XL inhibition induces an FGFR4-mediated rescue response in colorectal cancer</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35172148/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35172148/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;FGFR4 inhibition sensitizes CRC cells to BCL-XL inhibition and spares normal cells&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;BCL-XL targeting BH3 mimetics induce FGF2-mediated FGFR4 pathway activation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;FGFR4 activation in CRC cells can induce apoptosis resistance by upregulating MCL-1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The heterogeneous therapy response observed in colorectal cancer is in part due to cancer stem cells (CSCs) that resist chemotherapeutic insults. The anti-apoptotic protein BCL-XL plays a critical role in protecting CSCs from cell death, where its inhibition with high doses of BH3 mimetics can induce apoptosis. Here, we screen a compound library for synergy with low-dose BCL-XL inhibitor A-1155463 to identify pathways that regulate sensitivity to BCL-XL inhibition and reveal that fibroblast growth factor receptor (FGFR)4 inhibition effectively sensitizes to A-1155463 both in vitro and in vivo. Mechanistically, we identify a rescue response that is activated upon BCL-XL inhibition and leads to rapid FGF2 secretion and subsequent FGFR4-mediated post-translational stabilization of MCL-1. FGFR4 inhibition prevents MCL-1 upregulation and thereby sensitizes CSCs to BCL-XL inhibition. Altogether, our findings suggest a cell transferable induction of a FGF2/FGFR4 rescue response in CRC that is induced upon BCL-XL inhibition and leads to MCL-1 upregulation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Renal Klotho and inorganic phosphate are extrinsic factors that antagonistically regulate hematopoietic stem cell maintenance</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35172146/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35172146/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Renal Klotho and Pi extrinsically and antagonistically regulate BM HSC maintenance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kidney-secreted soluble Klotho restrains SLC20A1-mediated Pi absorption of HSCs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Disruption of Klotho-Pi axis hyperactivates SLC20A1-PPIP5K2-Akt axis in HSCs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Disruption of Klotho-Pi axis induces expansion and Mk/myeloid bias of BM HSCs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The composition and origin of extrinsic cues required for hematopoietic stem cell (HSC) maintenance are incompletely understood. Here we identify renal Klotho and inorganic phosphate (Pi) as extrinsic factors that antagonistically regulate HSC maintenance in the bone marrow (BM). Disruption of the Klotho-Pi axis by renal Klotho deficiency or Pi excess causes Pi overload in the BM niche and Pi retention in HSCs, leading to alteration of HSC maintenance. Mechanistically, Pi retention is mediated by soluble carrier family 20 member 1 (SLC20A1) and sensed by diphosphoinositol pentakisphosphate kinase 2 (PPIP5K2) to enhance Akt activation, which then upregulates SLC20A1 to aggravate Pi retention and augments GATA2 activity to drive the expansion and megakaryocyte/myeloid-biased differentiation of HSCs. However, kidney-secreted soluble Klotho directly maintains HSC pool size and differentiation by restraining SLC20A1-mediated Pi absorption of HSCs. These findings uncover a regulatory role of the Klotho-Pi axis orchestrated by the kidneys in BM HSC maintenance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chemical-induced chromatin remodeling reprograms mouse ESCs to totipotent-like stem cells</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35143761/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35143761/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;DOT1L inhibition collapses chromocenters to induce an alternative 2C-like state&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;KDM5B inhibition promotes remodeling of broad H3K4me3 to stabilize totipotency&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;TLSCs derived from early embryos and ESCs molecularly resemble mouse 2C embryos&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;TLSCs have embryonic and extraembryonic developmental potency and can form blastoids&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Totipotent cells have more robust developmental potency than any other cell types, giving rise to both embryonic and extraembryonic tissues. Stable totipotent cell cultures and deciphering the principles of totipotency regulation would be invaluable to understand cell plasticity and lineage segregation in early development. Our approach of remodeling the pericentromeric heterochromatin and re-establishing the totipotency-specific broad H3K4me3 domains promotes the pluri-to-totipotency transition. Our protocol establishes a closer match of mouse 2-cell (2C) embryos than any other 2C-like cells. These totipotent-like stem cells (TLSCs) are stable in culture and possess unique molecular features of the mouse 2C embryo. Functionally, TLSCs are competent for germline transmission and give rise to both embryonic and extraembryonic lineages at high frequency. Therefore, TLSCs represent a highly valuable cell type for studies of totipotency and embryology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SARS-CoV-2 Infection and Lung Regeneration</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/35107300/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/35107300/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The lung is the primary site of severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 (SARS-CoV-2)-induced immunopathology whereby the virus enters the host cells by binding to angiotensin-converting enzyme 2 (ACE2). Sophisticated regeneration and repair programs exist in the lungs to replenish injured cell populations. However, known resident stem/progenitor cells have been demonstrated to express ACE2, raising a substantial concern regarding the long-term consequences of impaired lung regeneration after SARS-CoV-2 infection. Moreover, clinical treatments may also affect lung repair from antiviral drug candidates to mechanical ventilation. In this review, we highlight how SARS-CoV-2 disrupts a program that governs lung homeostasis. We also summarize the current efforts of targeted therapy and supportive treatments for COVID-19 patients. In addition, we discuss the pros and cons of cell therapy with mesenchymal stem cells or resident lung epithelial stem/progenitor cells in preventing post-acute sequelae of COVID-19. We propose that, in addition to symptomatic treatments being developed and applied in the clinic, targeting lung regeneration is also essential to restore lung homeostasis in COVID-19 patients.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adverse Mechanical Ventilation and Pneumococcal Pneumonia Induce Immune and Mitochondrial Dysfunctions Mitigated by Mesenchymal Stem Cells in Rabbits</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34965287/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34965287/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Mechanical ventilation for pneumonia may contribute to lung injury due to factors that include mitochondrial dysfunction, and mesenchymal stem cells may attenuate injury. This study hypothesized that mechanical ventilation induces immune and mitochondrial dysfunction, with or without pneumococcal pneumonia, that could be mitigated by mesenchymal stem cells alone or combined with antibiotics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; Male rabbits underwent protective mechanical ventilation (8 ml/kg tidal volume, 5 cm H2O end-expiratory pressure) or adverse mechanical ventilation (20 ml/kg tidal-volume, zero end-expiratory pressure) or were allowed to breathe spontaneously. The same settings were then repeated during pneumococcal pneumonia. Finally, infected animals during adverse mechanical ventilation received human umbilical cord-derived mesenchymal stem cells (3 × 106/kg, intravenous) and/or ceftaroline (20 mg/kg, intramuscular) or sodium chloride, 4 h after pneumococcal challenge. Twenty-four-hour survival (primary outcome), lung injury, bacterial burden, immune and mitochondrial dysfunction, and lung transcriptomes (secondary outcomes) were assessed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; High-pressure adverse mechanical ventilation reduced the survival of infected animals (0%; 0 of 7) compared with spontaneous breathing (100%; 7 of 7) and protective mechanical ventilation (86%; 6 of 7; both _P &amp;lt; 0.001), with higher lung pathology scores (median [interquartile ranges], 5.5 [4.5 to 7.0] vs. 12.6 [12.0 to 14.0]; &lt;em&gt;P&lt;/em&gt; = 0.046), interleukin-8 lung concentrations (106 [54 to 316] vs. 804 [753 to 868] pg/g of lung; &lt;em&gt;P&lt;/em&gt; = 0.012), and alveolar mitochondrial DNA release (0.33 [0.28 to 0.36] vs. 0.98 [0.76 to 1.21] ng/μl; &lt;em&gt;P&lt;/em&gt; &amp;lt; 0.001) compared with infected spontaneously breathing animals. Survival (0%; 0 of 7; control group) was improved by mesenchymal stem cells (57%; 4 of 7; &lt;em&gt;P&lt;/em&gt; = 0.001) or ceftaroline alone (57%; 4 of 7; &lt;em&gt;P&lt;/em&gt; &amp;lt; 0.001) and improved even more with a combination treatment (86%; 6 of 7; &lt;em&gt;P&lt;/em&gt; &amp;lt; 0.001). Mesenchymal stem cells reduced lung pathology score (8.5 [7.0 to 10.5] vs. 12.6 [12.0 to 14.0]; &lt;em&gt;P&lt;/em&gt; = 0.043) and alveolar mitochondrial DNA release (0.39 (0.34 to 0.65) vs. 0.98 (0.76 to 1.21) ng/μl; &lt;em&gt;P&lt;/em&gt; = 0.025). Mesenchymal stem cells combined with ceftaroline reduced interleukin-8 lung concentrations (665 [595 to 795] vs. 804 [753 to 868] pg/g of lung; &lt;em&gt;P&lt;/em&gt; = 0.007) compared to ceftaroline alone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; In this preclinical study, mesenchymal stem cells improved the outcome of rabbits with pneumonia and high-pressure mechanical ventilation by correcting immune and mitochondrial dysfunction and when combined with the antibiotic ceftaroline was synergistic in mitigating lung inflammation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Single-Cell RNA Sequencing-Based Characterization of Resident Lung Mesenchymal Stromal Cells in Bronchopulmonary Dysplasia</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35445270/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35445270/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Late lung development is a period of alveolar and microvascular formation, which is pivotal in ensuring sufficient and effective gas exchange. Defects in late lung development manifest in premature infants as a chronic lung disease named bronchopulmonary dysplasia (BPD). Numerous studies demonstrated the therapeutic properties of exogenous bone marrow and umbilical cord-derived mesenchymal stromal cells (MSCs) in experimental BPD. However, very little is known regarding the regenerative capacity of resident lung MSCs (L-MSCs) during normal development and in BPD. In this study we aimed to characterize the L-MSC population in homeostasis and upon injury. We used single-cell RNA sequencing (scRNA-seq) to profile in situ Ly6a+ L-MSCs in the lungs of normal and O2-exposed neonatal mice (a well-established model to mimic BPD) at 3 developmental timepoints (postnatal days 3, 7, and 14). Hyperoxia exposure increased the number and altered the expression profile of L-MSCs, particularly by increasing the expression of multiple pro-inflammatory, pro-fibrotic, and anti-angiogenic genes. In order to identify potential changes induced in the L-MSCs transcriptome by storage and culture, we profiled 15 000 Ly6a+ L-MSCs after in vitro culture. We observed great differences in expression profiles of in situ and cultured L-MSCs, particularly those derived from healthy lungs. Additionally, we have identified the location of Ly6a+/Col14a1+ L-MSCs in the developing lung and propose Serpinf1 as a novel, culture-stable marker of L-MSCs. Finally, cell communication analysis suggests inflammatory signals from immune and endothelial cells as main drivers of hyperoxia-induced changes in L-MSCs transcriptome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MICU1-dependent mitochondrial calcium uptake regulates lung alveolar type 2 cell plasticity and lung regeneration</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35050901/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35050901/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lung alveolar type 2 (AT2) cells are progenitors for alveolar type 1 (AT1) cells. Although many factors regulate AT2 cell plasticity, the role of mitochondrial calcium (&lt;sub&gt;m&lt;/sub&gt;Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt;) uptake in controlling AT2 cells remains unclear. We previously identified that the miR-302 family supports lung epithelial progenitor cell proliferation and less differentiated phenotypes during development. Here, we report that a sustained elevation of miR-302 in adult AT2 cells decreases AT2-to-AT1 cell differentiation during the Streptococcus pneumoniae-induced lung injury repair. We identified that miR-302 targets and represses the expression of mitochondrial Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt; uptake 1 (MICU1), which regulates &lt;sub&gt;m&lt;/sub&gt;Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt; uptake through the &lt;sub&gt;m&lt;/sub&gt;Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt; uniporter channel by acting as a gatekeeper at low cytosolic Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt; levels. Our results reveal a marked increase in MICU1 protein expression and decreased &lt;sub&gt;m&lt;/sub&gt;Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt; uptake during AT2-to-AT1 cell differentiation in the adult lung. Deletion of &lt;em&gt;Micu1&lt;/em&gt; in AT2 cells reduces AT2-to-AT1 cell differentiation during steady-state tissue maintenance and alveolar epithelial regeneration after bacterial pneumonia. These studies indicate that &lt;sub&gt;m&lt;/sub&gt;Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt; uptake is extensively modulated during AT2-to-AT1 cell differentiation and that MICU1-dependent &lt;sub&gt;m&lt;/sub&gt;Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt; uniporter channel gating is a prominent mechanism modulating AT2-to-AT1 cell differentiation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BMSC-Derived Exosomes Carrying lncRNA-ZFAS1 Alleviate Pulmonary Ischemia/Reperfusion Injury by UPF1-Mediated mRNA Decay of FOXD1</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36652050/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36652050/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bone marrow-derived mesenchymal stem cells (BMSCs) exert protective effects against pulmonary ischemia/reperfusion (I/R) injury; however, the potential mechanism involved in their protective ability remains unclear. Thus, this study aimed to explore the function and underlying mechanism of BMSC-derived exosomal lncRNA-ZFAS1 in pulmonary I/R injury. Pulmonary I/R injury models were established in mice and hypoxia/reoxygenation (H/R)-exposed primary mouse lung microvascular endothelial cells (LMECs). Exosomes were extracted from BMSCs. Target molecule expression was assessed by qRT-PCR and Western blotting. Pathological changes in the lungs, pulmonary edema, apoptosis, pro-inflammatory cytokine levels, SOD, MPO activities, and MDA level were measured. The proliferation, apoptosis, and migration of LMECs were detected by CCK-8, EdU staining, flow cytometry, and scratch assay. Dual-luciferase reporter assay, RNA pull-down, RIP, and ChIP assays were performed to validate the molecular interaction. In the mouse model of pulmonary I/R injury, BMSC-Exos treatment relieved lung pathological injury, reduced lung W/D weight ratio, and restrained apoptosis and inflammation, whereas exosomal ZFAS1 silencing abolished these beneficial effects. In addition, the proliferation, migration inhibition, apoptosis, and inflammation in H/R-exposed LMECs were repressed by BMSC-derived exosomal ZFAS1. Mechanistically, ZFAS1 contributed to FOXD1 mRNA decay via interaction with UPF1, thereby leading to Gal-3 inactivation. Furthermore, FOXD1 depletion strengthened the weakened protective effect of ZFAS1-silenced BMSC-Exos on pulmonary I/R injury. ZFAS1 delivered by BMSC-Exos results in FOXD1 mRNA decay and subsequent Gal-3 inactivation via direct interaction with UPF1, thereby attenuating pulmonary I/R injury.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Development of human alveolar epithelial cell models to study distal lung biology and disease</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35169685/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35169685/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Human AT2 cells grown in Y-27632 medium are immortalized by SV40 Large T antigen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Immortalized AT2 cells are SOX9&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt;/SOX2&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; in the absence of mature alveolar markers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Immortalized AT2 cells form NKX2-1&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt;/AQP5&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt;/GPRC5A&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; organoids in 3D culture&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Specific 3D culture conditions induce AT2 marker HTII280 expression in organoids&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many acute and chronic diseases affect the distal lung alveoli. Alveolar epithelial cell (AEC) lines are needed to better model these diseases. We used de-identified human remnant transplant lungs to develop a method to establish AEC lines. The lines grow well in 2-dimensional (2D) culture as epithelial monolayers expressing lung progenitor markers. In 3-dimensional (3D) culture with fibroblasts, Matrigel, and specific media conditions, the cells form alveolar-like organoids expressing mature AEC markers including aquaporin 5 (AQP5), G-protein-coupled receptor class C group 5 member A (GPRC5A), and surface marker HTII280. Single-cell RNA sequencing of an AEC line in 2D versus 3D culture revealed increased cellular heterogeneity and induction of cytokine and lipoprotein signaling in 3D organoids. Our approach yields lung progenitor lines that retain the ability to differentiate along the alveolar cell lineage despite long-term expansion and provides a valuable system to model and study the distal lung &lt;em&gt;in vitro&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Distinct transcription kinetics of pluripotent cell states</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35020268/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35020268/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mouse embryonic stem cells (mESCs) can adopt naïve, ground, and paused pluripotent states that give rise to unique transcriptomes. Here, we use transient transcriptome sequencing (TT-seq) to define both coding and non-coding transcription units (TUs) in these three pluripotent states and combine TT-seq with RNA polymerase II occupancy profiling to unravel the kinetics of RNA metabolism genome-wide. Compared to the naïve state (serum), RNA synthesis and turnover rates are globally reduced in the ground state (2i) and the paused state (mTORi). The global reduction in RNA synthesis goes along with a genome-wide decrease of polymerase elongation velocity, which is related to epigenomic features and alterations in the Pol II termination window. Our data suggest that transcription activity is the main determinant of steady state mRNA levels in the naïve state and that genome-wide changes in transcription kinetics invoke ground and paused pluripotent states.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exosomes derived from adipose-derived stem cells alleviate cigarette smoke-induced lung inflammation and injury by inhibiting alveolar macrophages pyroptosis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35016678/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35016678/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD) is a frequently encountered disease condition in clinical practice mainly caused by cigarette smoke (CS). The aim of this study was to investigate the protective roles of human adipose-derived stem cells-derived exosomes (ADSCs-Exo) in CS-induced lung inflammation and injury and explore the underlying mechanism by discovering the effects of ADSCs-Exo on alveolar macrophages (AMs) pyroptosis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; ADSCs were isolated from human adipose tissues harvested from three healthy donors, and then ADSCs-Exo were isolated. &lt;em&gt;In vivo&lt;/em&gt;, 24 age-matched male C57BL/6 mice were exposed to CS for 4 weeks, followed by intratracheal administration of ADSCs-Exo or phosphate buffered saline. &lt;em&gt;In vitro&lt;/em&gt;, MH-S cells, derived from mouse AMs, were stimulated by 2% CS extract (CSE) for 24 h, followed by the treatment of ADSCs-Exo or phosphate buffered saline. Pulmonary inflammation was analyzed by detecting pro-inflammatory cells and mediators in the bronchoalveolar lavage fluid. Lung histology was assessed by hematoxylin and eosin staining. Mucus production was determined by Alcian blue-periodic acid-Schiff staining. The profile of AMs pyroptosis was evaluated by detecting the levels of pyroptosis-indicated proteins. The inflammatory response in AMs and the phagocytic activity of AMs were also investigated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; In mice exposed to CS, the levels of pro-inflammatory cells and mediators were significantly increased, mucus production was markedly increased and lung architecture was obviously disrupted. AMs pyroptosis was elevated and AMs phagocytosis was inhibited. However, the administration of ADSCs-Exo greatly reversed these alterations caused by CS exposure. Consistently, in MH-S cells with CSE-induced properties modelling those found in COPD, the cellular inflammatory response was elevated, the pyroptotic activity was upregulated while the phagocytosis was decreased. Nonetheless, these abnormalities were remarkably alleviated by the treatment of ADSCs-Exo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; ADSCs-Exo effectively attenuate CS-induced airway mucus overproduction, lung inflammation and injury by inhibiting AMs pyroptosis. Therefore, hADSCs-Exo may be a promising cell-free therapeutic candidate for CS-induced lung inflammation and injury.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exosomes from adipose-derived mesenchymal stem cells alleviate sepsis-induced lung injury in mice by inhibiting the secretion of IL-27 in macrophages</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35013123/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35013123/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acute lung injury (ALI) represents a frequent sepsis-induced inflammatory disorder. Mesenchymal stromal cells (MSCs) elicit anti-inflammatory effects in sepsis. This study investigated the mechanism of exosomes from adipose-derived MSCs (ADMSCs) in sepsis-induced ALI. The IL-27r&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt; (WSX-1 knockout) or wild-type mouse model of sepsis was established by cecal ligation and puncture (CLP). The model mice and lipopolysaccharide (LPS)-induced macrophages were treated with ADMSC-exosomes. The content of Dil-labeled exosomes in pulmonary macrophages, macrophages CD68&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt;F4/80&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; in whole lung tissues, and IL-27 content in macrophages were detected. The mRNA expression and protein level of IL27 subunits P28 and EBI3 in lung tissue and the levels of IL-6, TNF-α, and IL-1β were measured. The pulmonary edema, tissue injury, and pulmonary vascular leakage were measured. In vitro, macrophages internalized ADMSC-exosomes, and ADMSC-exosomes inhibited IL-27 secretion in LPS-induced macrophages. In vivo, IL-27 knockout attenuated CLP-induced ALI. ADMSC-exosomes suppressed macrophage aggregation in lung tissues and inhibited IL-27 secretion. ADMSC-exosomes decreased the contents of IL-6, TNF-α, and IL-1β, reduced pulmonary edema and pulmonary vascular leakage, and improved the survival rate of mice. Injection of recombinant IL-27 reversed the protective effect of ADMSC-exosomes on sepsis mice. Collectively, ADMSC-exosomes inhibited IL-27 secretion in macrophages and alleviated sepsis-induced ALI in mice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Diverse facets of MDSC in different phases of chronic HBV infection: Impact on HBV-specific T-cell response and homing</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35000202/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35000202/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background and aims:&lt;/em&gt; Chronic HBV infection (CHI) is associated with a diverse natural history that includes immune-tolerant (IT), HBeAg-positive chronic hepatitis B (CHB) (EP-CHB), inactive carrier, and HBeAg-negative CHB (EN-CHB) phases. A hallmark of CHI is impairment of HBV-specific T-cell response. Recently, myeloid-derived suppressor cells (MDSCs) have emerged as key regulator of T cells, and their properties are sculpted by their microenvironment. Here, we investigated the distinctive features of MDSCs during CHI, identified factors responsible for their functional discrepancies, and studied their impact on HBV-specific T-cell response and homing. Influence of antiviral therapy on MDSC profile and T-cell response was also assessed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Approach and results:&lt;/em&gt; Flow cytometric analysis indicated that MDSCs in EP-CHB/EN-CHB patients had profound suppressive ability, expressing arginase 1 (Arg1)/inducible nitric oxide synthase (iNOS)/programmed death ligand 1 (PD-L1)/cytotoxic T lymphocyte-associated protein 4 (CTLA-4)/CD40 at significantly greater levels relative to healthy controls (HC). However, in IT, only Arg1&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; MDSCs and in inactive carrier, iNOS&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; and PD-L1&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; MDSCs were higher than HC. In vitro assays demonstrated that high HBsAg titer in IT/CHB induced Arg1+ MDSC. Furthermore, elevated serum TNF-α and IL-4 in CHB potentiated Arg1/PD-L1/CD40/CTLA-4 expression, whereas increased IL-1β in CHB/IC triggered the expansion of PD-L1&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; MDSCs and iNOS+ MDSCs. MDSCs, sorted from CHB/IC, greatly attenuated IL-2/interferon gamma (IFN-γ) production by HBV-specific CD8&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt;/CD4&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T cells, the effect being more pronounced in CHB. However, MDSCs of IT minimally affected the cytokine production by T cells. Adding Arg1-/iNOS-inhibitor restored only IFN-γ production, while neutralizing PD-L1 recovered both IL-2 and IFN-γ secretion by T cells. Moreover, MDSCs from IT/CHB disrupted virus-specific T-cell trafficking by down-regulating chemokine receptor type 5 on them via TGF-β signaling. One year of tenofovir therapy failed to normalize MDSC phenotype and HBV-specific T-cell response.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; Diversity of MDSCs during CHI affects HBV-specific T-cell response and homing. Hence, therapeutic targeting of MDSCs could boost anti-HBV immunity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Application of Mesenchymal Stem Cells During Machine Perfusion: An Emerging Novel Strategy for Organ Preservation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/35024039/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/35024039/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although solid organ transplantation remains the definitive management for patients with end-stage organ failure, this ultimate treatment has been limited by the number of acceptable donor organs. Therefore, efforts have been made to expand the donor pool by utilizing marginal organs from donation after circulatory death or extended criteria donors. However, marginal organs are susceptible to ischemia-reperfusion injury (IRI) and entail higher requirements for organ preservation. Recently, machine perfusion has emerged as a novel preservation strategy for marginal grafts. This technique continually perfuses the organs to mimic the physiologic condition, allows the evaluation of pretransplant graft function, and more excitingly facilitates organ reconditioning during perfusion with pharmacological, gene, and stem cell therapy. As mesenchymal stem cells (MSCs) have anti-oxidative, immunomodulatory, and regenerative properties, mounting studies have demonstrated the therapeutic effects of MSCs on organ IRI and solid organ transplantation. Therefore, MSCs are promising candidates for organ reconditioning during machine perfusion. This review provides an overview of the application of MSCs combined with machine perfusion for lung, kidney, liver, and heart preservation and reconditioning. Promising preclinical results highlight the potential clinical translation of this innovative strategy to improve the quality of marginal grafts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nanotopography Sequentially Mediates Human Mesenchymal Stem Cell-Derived Small Extracellular Vesicles for Enhancing Osteogenesis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34935354/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34935354/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Engineered small extracellular vesicles (sEVs) are used as tools to enhance therapeutic efficacy. However, such application of sEVs is associated with several issues, including high costs and a high risk of tumorigenesis. Nanotopography has a greater influence on bone-related cell behaviors. However, whether nanotopography specifically mediate sEV content to perform particular biological functions remains unclear. Here, we demonstrate that selective nanotopography may be used to sequentially mediate human bone mesenchymal stem cell (hBMSC) sEVs to enhance the therapeutic efficacy of hBMSCs-EVs for osteogenesis. We subjected sEVs harvested from hBMSCs cultured on polished titanium plates (Ti) or nanotopographical titanium plates (Ti4) after 7, 14, and 21 d for RNA sequencing, and we found that there was no significant difference in sEV-miRNA expression after 7 d. Differentially expressed osteogenic-related microRNAs were founded after 14 days, and KEGG analysis indicated that the main microRNAs were associated with osteogenesis-related pathways, such as TGF-beta, AMPK, and FoxO. A significant difference was found in sEV-miRNAs expression after 21 d. We loaded sEV secreted from hBMSCs cultured on Ti4 after 21 d on 3D-printed porous PEEK scaffolds with poly dopamine (PDA) and found that such scaffolds showed superior osteogenic ability after 6- and 12-weeks. Here, we demonstrate the alkali- and heat-treated nanotopography with the ability of stimulating osteogenic differentiation of hBMSC can induce the secretion of pro-osteogenesis sEV, and we also found that sEVs meditate osteogenesis through miRNA. Thus, whether nanotopography has the ability to regulate other contents of sEVs such as proteins for enhancing osteogenesis needs further research. These findings may help us use nanotopography to extract sEVs for other biomedical applications, including cancer therapy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Differential pre-malignant programs and microenvironment chart distinct paths to malignancy in human colorectal polyps</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34910928/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34910928/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A single-cell resolution atlas of human adenomas and serrated polyps&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Serrated polyps arise from metaplasia as opposed to stem cell expansion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cytotoxic immunity in serrated polyps occurs independently of hypermutation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Distinct immune microenvironments track tumor cell-differentiation states&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Colorectal cancers (CRCs) arise from precursor polyps whose cellular origins, molecular heterogeneity, and immunogenic potential may reveal diagnostic and therapeutic insights when analyzed at high resolution. We present a single-cell transcriptomic and imaging atlas of the two most common human colorectal polyps, conventional adenomas and serrated polyps, and their resulting CRC counterparts. Integrative analysis of 128 datasets from 62 participants reveals adenomas arise from WNT-driven expansion of stem cells, while serrated polyps derive from differentiated cells through gastric metaplasia. Metaplasia-associated damage is coupled to a cytotoxic immune microenvironment preceding hypermutation, driven partly by antigen-presentation differences associated with tumor cell-differentiation status. Microsatellite unstable CRCs contain distinct non-metaplastic regions where tumor cells acquire stem cell properties and cytotoxic immune cells are depleted. Our multi-omic atlas provides insights into malignant progression of colorectal polyps and their microenvironment, serving as a framework for precision surveillance and prevention of CRC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cartilaginous Extracellular Matrix Enriched with Human Gingival Mesenchymal Stem Cells Derived &#39;Matrix Bound Extracellular Vesicles&#39; Enabled Functional Reconstruction of Tracheal Defect</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34841733/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34841733/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stem cells derived extracellular vesicles (EVs) conceive cues essential for tissue repair. Mammalian cartilaginous extracellular matrix (cECM) may not be optimally inductive for tracheal regeneration because of the granulomatous, instead of regenerative, responses in injured adult mammalian tracheas. Given the high regenerative capacity of gingiva, it is hypothesized human gingival mesenchymal stem cells derived EVs (gEVs) can induce mammalian tracheal epithelia regeneration. Coculturing chondrocytes with GMSCs produce abundant &amp;ldquo;matrix bound gEVs (gMVs)&amp;rdquo; in forming cartilaginous ECM, which are further preserved in acellular cECM (cACM) following mild, short-period decellularization. The results show that gMVs-cACM could be well anchored on polyglycerol sebacate microporous patch thus enforce the surgical suturability and mechanical strength. In rabbit tracheal defect, the gMVs-cACM patch induces rapid regeneration of vascularized ciliated columnar epithelium, which supports long-term survival of animals. gMVs-cACM treated groups exhibit proliferation of tracheal progenitors-basal epithelial cells, as well as, activation of JAK2/STAT1 pathway in reparative cells. This study departs from conventional focuses on tissue derived ECM and introduces a new approach for tracheal tissue regeneration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mesenchymal Stem Cell-Derived Extracellular Vesicles with High PD-L1 Expression for Autoimmune Diseases Treatment</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34613627/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34613627/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Autoimmune diseases are the third most common disease influencing the quality of life of many patients. Here, a programmed cell death-ligand 1 + (PD-L1) mesenchymal stem cell (MSC) derived extracellular vesicles (MSC-sEVs-PD-L1) using lentivirus-mediated gene transfection technology is developed for reconfiguration of the local immune microenvironment of affected tissue in autoimmune diseases. MSC-sEVs-PD-L1 exhibits an impressive ability to regulate various activated immune cells to an immunosuppressed state in vitro. More importantly, in dextran sulfate sodium-induced ulcerative colitis (UC) and imiquimod-induced psoriasis mouse models, a significantly high accumulation of MSC-sEVs-PD-L1 is observed in the inflamed tissues compared to the PD-L1+ MSCs. Therapeutic efficiency in both UC and psoriasis mouse disease models is demonstrated using MSC-sEVs-PD-L1 to reshape the inflammatory ecosystem in the local immune context. A technology is developed using MSC-sEVs-PD-L1 as a natural delivery platform for autoimmune diseases treatment with high clinical potential.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spatiotemporal Immune Landscape of Colorectal Cancer Liver Metastasis at Single-Cell Level</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34417225/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34417225/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Liver metastasis, the leading cause of colorectal cancer mortality, exhibits a highly heterogeneous and suppressive immune microenvironment. Here, we sequenced 97 matched samples by using single-cell RNA sequencing and spatial transcriptomics. Strikingly, the metastatic microenvironment underwent remarkable spatial reprogramming of immunosuppressive cells such as &lt;em&gt;MRC1&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;CCL18&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; M2-like macrophages. We further developed scMetabolism, a computational pipeline for quantifying single-cell metabolism, and observed that those macrophages harbored enhanced metabolic activity. Interestingly, neoadjuvant chemotherapy could block this status and restore the antitumor immune balance in responsive patients, whereas the nonresponsive patients deteriorated into a more suppressive one. Our work described the immune evolution of metastasis and uncovered the black box of how tumors respond to neoadjuvant chemotherapy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Significance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We present a single-cell and spatial atlas of colorectal liver metastasis and found the highly metabolically activated &lt;em&gt;MRC1&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;CCL18&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; M2-like macrophages in metastatic sites. Efficient neoadjuvant chemotherapy can slow down such metabolic activation, raising the possibility to target metabolism pathways in metastasis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hypoxia adipose stem cell-derived exosomes promote high-quality healing of diabetic wound involves activation of PI3K/Akt pathways</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34233694/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34233694/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Refractory diabetic wounds can cause persistent inflammation and delayed healing due to hypoxia. Currently, no optimal solution is available. Exosomes of adipose stem cells (ADSCs-exo) may promote skin wound healing, however, molecular mechanisms remains mysterious. We found significantly enhanced survival and proliferation of adipose stem cells after hypoxia induction compared to normoxia. Here, we aimed to investigate if hypoxic adipose stem cells exosomes (HypADSCs-exo) participate in hypoxia adaptability and accelerate diabetic wound healing. Based on high-throughput sequencing, 215 microRNAs (miRNAs) were upregulated and 369 miRNAs downregulated in HypADSCs-exo compared to ADSCs-exo. Up-regulated miR-21-3p, miR-126-5p, miR-31-5p whereas down-regulated gene miR-99b and miR-146-a correlated with wound healing. According to Gene Ontology (GO) and Kyoto Encyclopedia of Genes and Genomes (KEGG), miRNAs might regulate cell metabolism, differentiation and Transforming growth factor-β (TGF-β) function. Consistently, HpyADSCs-exo could promote diabetic wounds healing and inhibit inflammation through PI3K/AKT signaling pathway. Collectively, HpyADSCs-exo can promote diabetic wound healing as an alternative strategy to improve wound healing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ac4C acetylation of RUNX2 catalyzed by NAT10 spurs osteogenesis of BMSCs and prevents ovariectomy-induced bone loss</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34513300/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34513300/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;N-acetyltransferase 10 (NAT10) is the key enzyme for N4-acetylcytidine (ac4C) modification of mRNA, which participates in various cellular processes and is related to many diseases. Here, we explore the relationships among osteoblast differentiation, NAT10, and ac4C, and we found that NAT0 expression and the ac4C level of total RNA were decreased in the bone tissues of bilateral ovariectomized (OVX) mice and osteoporosis patients. Adenoviruses overexpressing NAT10 reversed bone loss, and Remodelin, an NAT10 inhibitor, enhanced the loss of bone mass in OVX mice. Moreover, bone marrow-derived mesenchymal stem cells (BMSCs) with low-level ac4C modification formed fewer calcium nodules &lt;em&gt;in vitro&lt;/em&gt; with NAT10 silencing, whereas BMSCs with high-level ac4C modification formed more calcium nodules with NAT10 overexpression. Moreover, we demonstrated that the ac4C level of runt-related transcription factor 2 (RUNX2) mRNA was increased after BMSCs were cultured in osteogenic medium (OM) and decreased after NAT10 silencing. The RUNX2 mRNA half-life and protein expression decreased after silencing NAT10 in BMSCs. Therefore, NAT10-based ac4C modification promotes the osteogenic differentiation of BMSCs by regulating the RUNX2 ac4C level. Because abnormal levels of NAT10 are probably one of the mechanisms responsible for osteoporosis, NAT10 is a new potential therapeutic target for this disease.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Metabolic modeling of single Th17 cells reveals regulators of autoimmunity</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34216539/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34216539/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Compass enables studying cellular metabolism based on single-cell transcriptomes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Compass links the pathogenic potential of Th17 cells with their metabolic programs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Th17 pathogenicity is associated with a switch between glycolysis and beta oxidation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The polyamine pathway is required for Th17 induction and restriction of a Treg profile&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Summary&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Metabolism is a major regulator of immune cell function, but it remains difficult to study the metabolic status of individual cells. Here, we present Compass, an algorithm to characterize cellular metabolic states based on single-cell RNA sequencing and flux balance analysis. We applied Compass to associate metabolic states with T helper 17 (Th17) functional variability (pathogenic potential) and recovered a metabolic switch between glycolysis and fatty acid oxidation, akin to known Th17/regulatory T cell (Treg) differences, which we validated by metabolic assays. Compass also predicted that Th17 pathogenicity was associated with arginine and downstream polyamine metabolism. Indeed, polyamine-related enzyme expression was enhanced in pathogenic Th17 and suppressed in Treg cells. Chemical and genetic perturbation of polyamine metabolism inhibited Th17 cytokines, promoted Foxp3 expression, and remodeled the transcriptome and epigenome of Th17 cells toward a Treg-like state. In vivo perturbations of the polyamine pathway altered the phenotype of encephalitogenic T cells and attenuated tissue inflammation in CNS autoimmunity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Circular RNA AFF4 modulates osteogenic differentiation in BM-MSCs by activating SMAD1/5 pathway through miR-135a-5p/FNDC5/Irisin axis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34145212/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34145212/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bone marrow-derived mesenchymal stem cells (BM-MSCs), the common progenitor cells of adipocytes and osteoblasts, have been recognized as the key mediator during bone formation. Herein, our study aim to investigate molecular mechanisms underlying circular RNA (circRNA) AFF4 (circ_AFF4)-regulated BM-MSCs osteogenesis. BM-MSCs were characterized by FACS, ARS, and ALP staining. Expression patterns of circ_AFF4, miR-135a-5p, FNDC5/Irisin, SMAD1/5, and osteogenesis markers, including ALP, BMP4, RUNX2, Spp1, and Colla1 were detected by qRT-PCR, western blot, or immunofluorescence staining, respectively. Interactions between circ_AFF4 and miR-135a-5p, FNDC5, and miR-135a-5p were analyzed using web tools including TargetScan, miRanda, and miRDB, and further confirmed by luciferase reporter assay and RNA pull-down. Complex formation between Irisin and Integrin αV was verified by Co-immunoprecipitation. To further verify the functional role of circ_AFF4 in vivo during bone formation, we conducted animal experiments harboring circ_AFF4 knockdown, and born samples were evaluated by immunohistochemistry, hematoxylin and eosin, and Masson staining. Circ_AFF4 was upregulated upon osteogenic differentiation induction in BM-MSCs, and miR-135a-5p expression declined as differentiation proceeds. Circ_AFF4 knockdown significantly inhibited osteogenesis potential in BM-MSCs. Circ_AFF4 stimulated FNDC5/Irisin expression through complementary binding to its downstream target molecule miR-135a-5p. Irisin formed an intermolecular complex with Integrin αV and activated the SMAD1/5 pathway during osteogenic differentiation. Our work revealed that circ_AFF4, acting as a sponge of miR-135a-5p, triggers the promotion of FNDC5/Irisin via activating the SMAD1/5 pathway to induce osteogenic differentiation in BM-MSCs. These findings gained a deeper insight into the circRNA-miRNA regulatory system in the bone marrow microenvironment and may improve our understanding of bone formation-related diseases at physiological and pathological levels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extracellular vesicles from human iPSCs enhance reconstitution capacity of cord blood-derived hematopoietic stem and progenitor cells</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34140648/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34140648/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cord blood (CB) represents a source of hematopoietic stem and progenitor cells (CB-HSPCs) for bone marrow (BM) reconstitution, but clinical CB application is limited in adult patients due to the insufficient number of CB-HSCPCs and the lack of effective ex vivo approaches to increase CB-HSPC functionality. Since human-induced pluripotent stem cells (hiPSCs) have been indicated as donor cells for bioactive extracellular vesicles (EVs) modulating properties of other cells, we are the first to employ hiPSC-derived EVs (hiPSC-EVs) to enhance the hematopoietic potential of CB-derived CD45dimLin-CD34+ cell fraction enriched in CB-HSPCs. We demonstrated that hiPSC-EVs improved functional properties of CB-HSPCs critical for their hematopoietic capacity including metabolic, hematopoietic and clonogenic potential as well as survival, chemotactic response to stromal cell-derived factor 1 and adhesion to the model components of hematopoietic niche in vitro. Moreover, hiPSC-EVs enhanced homing and engraftment of CB-HSPCs in vivo. This phenomenon might be related to activation of signaling pathways in CB-HSPCs following hiPSC-EV treatment, as shown on both gene expression and the protein kinases activity levels. In conclusion, hiPSC-EVs might be used as ex vivo modulators of CB-HSPCs capacity to enhance their functional properties and augment future practical applications of CB-derived cells in BM reconstitution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mesenchymal stem cell-mediated immunomodulation of recruited mononuclear phagocytes during acute lung injury: a high-dimensional analysis study</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33500722/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33500722/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rationale:&lt;/em&gt; Acute lung injury (ALI)-recruited mononuclear phagocytes play a pivotal role in lung injury and repair. This study investigated the types of recruited mononuclear phagocytes and the immunotherapeutic effects of allograft mesenchymal stem cells (MSCs) in a mouse model of lipopolysaccharide (LPS)-induced ALI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; C57BL/6 mice were orotracheally instilled with LPS (20 mg/kg). Compact bone-derived MSCs were administered orotracheally 4 h after LPS inhalation. Mononuclear phagocytes recruited in the lung tissues were characterized at different timepoints by high-dimensional analysis including flow cytometry, mass cytometry, and single-cell RNA sequencing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; Eight mononuclear phagocyte subsets recruited to LPS-challenged lungs were precisely identified. On day 3 after LPS administration, both Ly6C&lt;sup&gt;hi&lt;/sup&gt;CD38&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; and Ly6C&lt;sup&gt;low&lt;/sup&gt;CD38&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; monocytes were recruited into acutely injured lungs, which was associated with increased secretion of neutrophil chemokines. Ly6C&lt;sup&gt;hi&lt;/sup&gt;CD38&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; monocytes differentiated into M1 macrophages on day 3, and subsequently differentiated into CD38&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; monocyte-derived dendritic cells (mo-DCs) on day 7, while Ly6C&lt;sup&gt;low&lt;/sup&gt;CD38&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; monocytes differentiated into CD11b&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt;CD38&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; DCs on day 7. When ALI mice were treated with MSCs, the mortality significantly reduced. Notably, MSCs reduced the amount of M1 macrophages and reduced the secretion of neutrophil chemokines on day 3. Furthermore, MSCs reduced the number of CD38&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; mo-DCs and CD11b&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt;CD38&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; DCs on day 7, suppressing the antigen presentation process. Recruited mononuclear phagocyte subsets with a high level of CD38 exhibited an activated phenotype and could secrete higher levels of cytokines and chemokines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; This study characterized the dynamic functions and phenotypes of recruited mononuclear phagocytes in ALI mice and MSC-treated ALI mice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mesenchymal stem cells alleviate LPS-induced acute lung injury by inhibiting the proinflammatory function of Ly6C&#43; CD8&#43; T cells</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33024074/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33024074/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Systemic inflammatory processes, including alveolar injury, cytokine induction, and neutrophil accumulation, play key roles in the pathophysiology of acute lung injury (ALI). The immunomodulatory effects of mesenchymal stem cells (MSCs) can contribute to the treatment of inflammatory disorders. In previous studies, the focus was on innate immune cells and the effects of MSCs on ALI through CD8&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T cells remain unclear. In the present study, lipopolysaccharide (LPS) was used to induce ALI in mice. ALI mice were treated with MSCs via intratracheal instillation. Survival rate, histopathological changes, protein levels, total cell count, cytokine levels, and chemokine levels in alveolar lavage fluid were used to determine the efficacy of MSCs. Mass cytometry and single-cell RNA sequencing (scRNA-seq) were used to characterize the CD8&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T cells in the lungs. Ly6C&lt;sup&gt;-&lt;/sup&gt; CD8&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T cells are prevalent in normal mice, whereas a specialized effector phenotype expressing a high level of Ly6C is predominant in advanced disease. MSCs significantly mitigated ALI and improved survival. MSCs decreased the infiltration of CD8&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T cells, especially Ly6C&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; CD8&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T cells into the lungs. Mass cytometry revealed that CD8&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T cells expressing high Ly6C and CXCR3 levels caused tissue damage in the lungs of ALI mice, which was alleviated by MSCs. The scRNA-seq showed that Ly6C&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; CD8&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T cells exhibited a more activated phenotype and decreased expression of proinflammatory factors that were enriched the most in immune chemotaxis after treatment with MSCs. We showed that CD8&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T cells play an important role in MSC-mediated ALI remission, and both infiltration quantity and proinflammatory function were inhibited by MSCs, indicating a potential mechanism for therapeutic intervention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multilineage murine stem cells generate complex organoids to model distal lung development and disease</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32985719/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32985719/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Organoids derived from mouse and human stem cells have recently emerged as a powerful tool to study organ development and disease. We here established a three-dimensional (3D) murine bronchioalveolar lung organoid (BALO) model that allows clonal expansion and self-organization of FACS-sorted bronchioalveolar stem cells (BASCs) upon co-culture with lung-resident mesenchymal cells. BALOs yield a highly branched 3D structure within 21 days of culture, mimicking the cellular composition of the bronchioalveolar compartment as defined by single-cell RNA sequencing and fluorescence as well as electron microscopic phenotyping. Additionally, BALOs support engraftment and maintenance of the cellular phenotype of injected tissue-resident macrophages. We also demonstrate that BALOs recapitulate lung developmental defects after knockdown of a critical regulatory gene, and permit modeling of viral infection. We conclude that the BALO model enables reconstruction of the epithelial-mesenchymal-myeloid unit of the distal lung, thereby opening numerous new avenues to study lung development, infection, and regenerative processes &lt;em&gt;in vitro&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Immunosuppressive effects of mesenchymal stem cells on lung B cell gene expression in LPS-induced acute lung injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32977837/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32977837/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Immune system disorders play important roles in acute lung injury (ALI), and mesenchymal stem cell (MSC) treatment can reduce inflammation during ALI. In this study, we compared the changes in lung B cells during MSC treatment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; We investigated the effects of MSCs on lung B cells in a mouse model of lipopolysaccharide (LPS)-induced ALI. MSCs were administered intratracheally 4 h after LPS. As vehicle-treated controls, mice were treated with phosphate-buffered saline (PBS) containing 2% C57BL/6 (PBS group). Histopathological changes, survival rate, inflammatory factor levels, and the number of neutrophils in bronchoalveolar lavage fluid (BALF) were determined. Single-cell RNA sequencing (scRNA-Seq) analysis was performed to evaluate the transcriptional changes in lung B cells between the PBS, LPS, and LPS/MSC groups on days 3 and 7.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; MSC treatment ameliorated LPS-induced ALI, as indicated by the reductions in mortality, the levels of chemokines and cytokines in BALF, and the severity of lung tissue histopathology in ALI mice. Lung B cells in the PBS group remained undifferentiated and had an inhibitory phenotype. Based on our scRNA-Seq results, the differentially expressed genes (DEGs) in lung B cells in both the PBS group and LPS group were involved in chemotaxis processes and some proinflammatory pathways. MSC treatment inhibited the expression of chemokine genes that were upregulated by LPS and were related to the recruitment of neutrophils into lung tissues. Immunoglobulin-related gene expression was decreased in lung B cells of mice treated with LPS/MSC for 7 days. The DEGs regulated by MSCs were enriched in biological processes, including humoral immune response and apoptotic signaling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; Lung B cells played an important role in the effects of treatment of ALI with MSCs. These observations provide new insights into the mechanisms underlying the effects of MSC treatment for ALI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Long non-coding RNA HCAR promotes endochondral bone repair by upregulating VEGF and MMP13 in hypertrophic chondrocyte through sponging miR-15b-5p</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35224160/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35224160/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Endochondral bone formation is an important route for bone repair. Although emerging evidence has revealed the functions of long non-coding RNAs (lncRNAs) in bone and cartilage development, the effect of lncRNAs in endochondral bone repair is still largely unknown. Here, we identified a lncRNA, named Hypertrophic Chondrocyte Angiogenesis-related lncRNA (HCAR), and proved it to promote the endochondral bone repair by upregulating the expression of matrix metallopeptidase 13 (Mmp13) and vascular endothelial growth factor α (Vegfa) in hypertrophic chondrocytes. Lnc-HCAR knockdown in hypertrophic chondrocytes restrained the cartilage matrix remodeling and decrease the CD31hiEmcnhi vessels number in a bone repair model. Mechanistically, we proved that lnc-HCAR was mainly enriched in the cytoplasm using fluorescence in situ hybridization (FISH) assay, and it acted as a molecular sponge for miR-15b-5p. Further, in hypertrophic chondrocytes, lnc-HCAR competitively bound to miR-15b-5p to increase Vegfa and Mmp13 expression. Our results proved that lncRNA is deeply involved in endochondral bone repair, which will provide a new theoretical basis for future strategies for promoting fracture healing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Functional reconstruction of injured corpus cavernosa using 3D-printed hydrogel scaffolds seeded with HIF-1α-expressing stem cells</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32483116/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32483116/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Injury of corpus cavernosa results in erectile dysfunction, but its treatment has been very difficult. Here we construct heparin-coated 3D-printed hydrogel scaffolds seeded with hypoxia inducible factor-1α (HIF-1α)-mutated muscle-derived stem cells (MDSCs) to develop bioengineered vascularized corpora. HIF-1α-mutated MDSCs significantly secrete various angiogenic factors in MDSCs regardless of hypoxia or normoxia. The biodegradable scaffolds, along with MDSCs, are implanted into corpus cavernosa defects in a rabbit model to show good histocompatibility with no immunological rejection, support vascularized tissue ingrowth, and promote neovascularisation to repair the defects. Evaluation of morphology, intracavernosal pressure, elasticity and shrinkage of repaired cavernous tissue prove that the bioengineered corpora scaffolds repair the defects and recover penile erectile and ejaculation function successfully. The function recovery restores the reproductive capability of the injured male rabbits. Our work demonstrates that the 3D-printed hydrogels with angiogenic cells hold great promise for penile reconstruction to restore reproductive capability of males.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Long-Term Culture Captures Injury-Repair Cycles of Colonic Stem Cells</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/31708126/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/31708126/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The colonic epithelium can undergo multiple rounds of damage and repair, often in response to excessive inflammation. The responsive stem cell that mediates this process is unclear, in part because of a lack of in vitro models that recapitulate key epithelial changes that occur in vivo during damage and repair. Here, we identify a Hopx&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; colitis-associated regenerative stem cell (CARSC) population that functionally contributes to mucosal repair in mouse models of colitis. Hopx&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; CARSCs, enriched for fetal-like markers, transiently arose from hypertrophic crypts known to facilitate regeneration. Importantly, we established a long-term, self-organizing two-dimensional (2D) epithelial monolayer system to model the regenerative properties and responses of Hopx&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; CARSCs. This system can reenact the &amp;ldquo;homeostasis-injury-regeneration&amp;rdquo; cycles of epithelial alterations that occur in vivo. Using this system, we found that hypoxia and endoplasmic reticulum stress, insults commonly present in inflammatory bowel diseases, mediated the cyclic switch of cellular status in this process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wnt/β-Catenin Signaling, Disease, and Emerging Therapeutic Modalities</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/28575679/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/28575679/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The WNT signal transduction cascade is a main regulator of development throughout the animal kingdom. Wnts are also key drivers of most types of tissue stem cells in adult mammals. Unsurprisingly, mutated Wnt pathway components are causative to multiple growth-related pathologies and to cancer. Here, we describe the core Wnt/β-catenin signaling pathway, how it controls stem cells, and contributes to disease. Finally, we discuss strategies for Wnt-based therapies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A three-dimensional model of human lung development and disease from pluripotent stem cells</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/28436965/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/28436965/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recapitulation of lung development from human pluripotent stem cells (hPSCs) in three dimensions (3D) would allow deeper insight into human development, as well as the development of innovative strategies for disease modelling, drug discovery and regenerative medicine. We report here the generation from hPSCs of lung bud organoids (LBOs) that contain mesoderm and pulmonary endoderm and develop into branching airway and early alveolar structures after xenotransplantation and in Matrigel 3D culture. Expression analysis and structural features indicated that the branching structures reached the second trimester of human gestation. Infection in vitro with respiratory syncytial virus, which causes small airway obstruction and bronchiolitis in infants, led to swelling, detachment and shedding of infected cells into the organoid lumens, similar to what has been observed in human lungs. Introduction of mutation in HPS1, which causes an early-onset form of intractable pulmonary fibrosis, led to accumulation of extracellular matrix and mesenchymal cells, suggesting the potential use of this model to recapitulate fibrotic lung disease in vitro. LBOs therefore recapitulate lung development and may provide a useful tool to model lung disease.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
