<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Trachea | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/trachea/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/trachea/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Trachea</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Trachea</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/trachea/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alpha-1 antitrypsin limits neutrophil extracellular trap disruption of airway epithelial barrier function</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36703990/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36703990/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Neutrophil extracellular traps contribute to lung injury in cystic fibrosis and asthma, but the mechanisms are poorly understood. We sought to understand the impact of human NETs on barrier function in primary human bronchial epithelial and a human airway epithelial cell line. We demonstrate that NETs disrupt airway epithelial barrier function by decreasing transepithelial electrical resistance and increasing paracellular flux, partially by NET-induced airway cell apoptosis. NETs selectively impact the expression of tight junction genes claudins 4, 8 and 11. Bronchial epithelia exposed to NETs demonstrate visible gaps in E-cadherin staining, a decrease in full-length E-cadherin protein and the appearance of cleaved E-cadherin peptides. Pretreatment of NETs with alpha-1 antitrypsin (A1AT) inhibits NET serine protease activity, limits E-cadherin cleavage, decreases bronchial cell apoptosis and preserves epithelial integrity. In conclusion, NETs disrupt human airway epithelial barrier function through bronchial cell death and degradation of E-cadherin, which are limited by exogenous A1AT.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cartilaginous Extracellular Matrix Enriched with Human Gingival Mesenchymal Stem Cells Derived &#39;Matrix Bound Extracellular Vesicles&#39; Enabled Functional Reconstruction of Tracheal Defect</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34841733/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34841733/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stem cells derived extracellular vesicles (EVs) conceive cues essential for tissue repair. Mammalian cartilaginous extracellular matrix (cECM) may not be optimally inductive for tracheal regeneration because of the granulomatous, instead of regenerative, responses in injured adult mammalian tracheas. Given the high regenerative capacity of gingiva, it is hypothesized human gingival mesenchymal stem cells derived EVs (gEVs) can induce mammalian tracheal epithelia regeneration. Coculturing chondrocytes with GMSCs produce abundant &amp;ldquo;matrix bound gEVs (gMVs)&amp;rdquo; in forming cartilaginous ECM, which are further preserved in acellular cECM (cACM) following mild, short-period decellularization. The results show that gMVs-cACM could be well anchored on polyglycerol sebacate microporous patch thus enforce the surgical suturability and mechanical strength. In rabbit tracheal defect, the gMVs-cACM patch induces rapid regeneration of vascularized ciliated columnar epithelium, which supports long-term survival of animals. gMVs-cACM treated groups exhibit proliferation of tracheal progenitors-basal epithelial cells, as well as, activation of JAK2/STAT1 pathway in reparative cells. This study departs from conventional focuses on tissue derived ECM and introduces a new approach for tracheal tissue regeneration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
