<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Acylation/Palmitoylation | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/acylation/palmitoylation/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/acylation/palmitoylation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Acylation/Palmitoylation</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Acylation/Palmitoylation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/acylation/palmitoylation/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Palmitoylation couples insulin hypersecretion with β cell failure in diabetes</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36634673/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36634673/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;APT1 shows altered expression in human pancreatic islets&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;APT1 deficiency causes insulin hypersecretion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deficiency of the APT1 substrate Scamp1 causes insulin hypersecretion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;APT1 deficiency promotes β cell failure in high-fat-fed mice and &lt;em&gt;db/db&lt;/em&gt; mice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hyperinsulinemia often precedes type 2 diabetes. Palmitoylation, implicated in exocytosis, is reversed by acyl-protein thioesterase 1 (APT1). APT1 biology was altered in pancreatic islets from humans with type 2 diabetes, and APT1 knockdown in nondiabetic islets caused insulin hypersecretion. APT1 knockout mice had islet autonomous increased glucose-stimulated insulin secretion that was associated with prolonged insulin granule fusion. Using palmitoylation proteomics, we identified Scamp1 as an APT1 substrate that localized to insulin secretory granules. Scamp1 knockdown caused insulin hypersecretion. Expression of a mutated Scamp1 incapable of being palmitoylated in APT1-deficient cells rescued insulin hypersecretion and nutrient-induced apoptosis. High-fat-fed islet-specific APT1-knockout mice and global APT1-deficient &lt;em&gt;db/db&lt;/em&gt; mice showed increased β cell failure. These findings suggest that APT1 is regulated in human islets and that APT1 deficiency causes insulin hypersecretion leading to β cell failure, modeling the evolution of some forms of human type 2 diabetes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Palmitoylation prevents sustained inflammation by limiting NLRP3 inflammasome activation through chaperone-mediated autophagy</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36586411/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36586411/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Palmitoylation of NLRP3 at C844 is critical for preventing inflammasome activation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;zDHHC12 directly palmitoylates NLRP3&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;zDHHC12 enhances NLRP3 degradation through CMA pathway&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Defective NLRP3 palmitoylation is associated with inflammatory diseases&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Summary&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a key component of the inflammasome, NLRP3 is a critical intracellular danger sensor emerging as an important clinical target in inflammatory diseases. However, little is known about the mechanisms that determine the kinetics of NLRP3 inflammasome stability and activity to ensure effective and controllable inflammatory responses. Here, we show that S-palmitoylation acts as a brake to turn NLRP3 inflammasome off. zDHHC12 is identified as the S-acyltransferase for NLRP3 palmitoylation, which promotes its degradation through the chaperone-mediated autophagy pathway. Zdhhc12 deficiency in mice enhances inflammatory symptoms and lethality following alum-induced peritonitis and LPS-induced endotoxic shock. Notably, several disease-associated mutations in NLRP3 are associated with defective palmitoylation, resulting in overt NLRP3 inflammasome activation. Thus, our findings identify zDHHC12 as a repressor of NLRP3 inflammasome activation and uncover a previously unknown regulatory mechanism by which the inflammasome pathway is tightly controlled by the dynamic palmitoylation of NLRP3.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Protein acylation: mechanisms, biological functions and therapeutic targets</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/36577755/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/36577755/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Metabolic reprogramming is involved in the pathogenesis of not only cancers but also neurodegenerative diseases, cardiovascular diseases, and infectious diseases. With the progress of metabonomics and proteomics, metabolites have been found to affect protein acylations through providing acyl groups or changing the activities of acyltransferases or deacylases. Reciprocally, protein acylation is involved in key cellular processes relevant to physiology and diseases, such as protein stability, protein subcellular localization, enzyme activity, transcriptional activity, protein-protein interactions and protein-DNA interactions. Herein, we summarize the functional diversity and mechanisms of eight kinds of nonhistone protein acylations in the physiological processes and progression of several diseases. We also highlight the recent progress in the development of inhibitors for acyltransferase, deacylase, and acylation reader proteins for their potential applications in drug discovery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Targeting EGFR-dependent tumors by disrupting an ARF6-mediated sorting system</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36224181/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36224181/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aberrant activation of EGFR due to overexpression or mutation is associated with poor prognosis in many types of tumors. Here we show that blocking the sorting system that directs EGFR to plasma membrane is a potent strategy to treat EGFR-dependent tumors. We find that EGFR palmitoylation by DHHC13 is critical for its plasma membrane localization and identify ARF6 as a key factor in this process. N-myristoylated ARF6 recognizes palmitoylated EGFR via lipid-lipid interaction, recruits the exocyst complex to promote EGFR budding from Golgi, and facilitates EGFR transporting to plasma membrane in a GTP-bound form. To evaluate the therapeutic potential of this sorting system, we design a cell-permeable peptide, N-myristoylated GKVL-TAT, and find it effectively disrupts plasma membrane localization of EGFR and significantly inhibits progression of EGFR-dependent tumors. Our findings shed lights on the underlying mechanism of how palmitoylation directs protein sorting and provide an potential strategy to manage EGFR-dependent tumors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ZDHHC18 negatively regulates cGAS-mediated innate immunity through palmitoylation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35438208/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35438208/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Double-stranded DNA is recognized as a danger signal by cyclic guanosine monophosphate-adenosine monophosphate synthase (cGAS), triggering innate immune responses. Palmitoylation is an important post-translational modification (PTM) catalyzed by DHHC-palmitoyl transferases, which participate in the regulation of diverse biological processes. However, whether palmitoylation regulates cGAS function has not yet been explored. Here, we found that palmitoylation of cGAS at C474 restricted its enzymatic activity in the presence of double-stranded DNA. cGAS palmitoylation was catalyzed mainly by the palmitoyltransferase ZDHHC18 and double-stranded DNA promoted this modification. Mechanistically, palmitoylation of cGAS reduced the interaction between cGAS and double-stranded DNA, further inhibiting cGAS dimerization. Consistently, ZDHHC18 negatively regulated cGAS activation in human and mouse cell lines. In a more biologically relevant model system, Zdhhc18-deficient mice were found to be resistant to infection by DNA viruses, in agreement with the observation that ZDHHC18 negatively regulated cGAS mediated innate immune responses in human and mouse primary cells. In summary, the negative role of ZDHHC18-mediated cGAS palmitoylation may be a novel regulatory mechanism in the fine-tuning of innate immunity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Methylene-bridge tryptophan fatty acylation regulates PI3K-AKT signaling and glucose uptake</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35294873/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35294873/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The methylene-bridge-containing polyunsaturated fatty acids EPA and DHA modify proteins&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tryptophan is a site of posttranslational modifications by polyunsaturated fatty acids&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;EPA and DHA activate AKT signaling by modifying PDK1 and AKT2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;EPA and DHA promote glucose uptake but induce insulin resistance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Summary&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Protein fatty acylation regulates numerous cell signaling pathways. Polyunsaturated fatty acids (PUFAs) exert a plethora of physiological effects, including cell signaling regulation, with underlying mechanisms to be fully understood. Herein, we report that docosahexaenoic acid (DHA) and eicosapentaenoic acid (EPA) regulate PI3K-AKT signaling by modifying PDK1 and AKT2. DHA-administered mice exhibit altered phosphorylation of proteins in signaling pathways. Methylene bridge-containing DHA/EPA acylate δ1 carbon of tryptophan 448/543 in PDK1 and tryptophan 414 in AKT2 via free radical pathway, recruit both the proteins to the cytoplasmic membrane, and activate PI3K signaling and glucose uptake in a tryptophan acylation-dependent but insulin-independent manner in cultured cells and in mice. DHA/EPA deplete cytosolic PDK1 and AKT2 and induce insulin resistance. Akt2 knockout in mice abrogates DHA/EPA-induced PI3K-AKT signaling. Our results identify PUFA’s methylene bridge tryptophan acylation, a protein fatty acylation that regulates cell signaling and may underlie multifaceted effects of methylene-bridge-containing PUFAs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A STAT3 palmitoylation cycle promotes TH17 differentiation and colitis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33029007/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33029007/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cysteine palmitoylation (S-palmitoylation) is a reversible post-translational modification that is installed by the DHHC family of palmitoyltransferases and is reversed by several acyl protein thioesterases. Although thousands of human proteins are known to undergo S-palmitoylation, how this modification is regulated to modulate specific biological functions is poorly understood. Here we report that the key T helper 17 (T&lt;sub&gt;H&lt;/sub&gt;17) cell differentiation stimulator, STAT3, is subject to reversible S-palmitoylation on cysteine 108. DHHC7 palmitoylates STAT3 and promotes its membrane recruitment and phosphorylation. Acyl protein thioesterase 2 (APT2, also known as LYPLA2) depalmitoylates phosphorylated STAT3 (p-STAT3) and enables it to translocate to the nucleus. This palmitoylation-depalmitoylation cycle enhances STAT3 activation and promotes T&lt;sub&gt;H&lt;/sub&gt;17 cell differentiation; perturbation of either palmitoylation or depalmitoylation negatively affects T&lt;sub&gt;H&lt;/sub&gt;17 cell differentiation. Overactivation of T&lt;sub&gt;H&lt;/sub&gt;17 cells is associated with several inflammatory diseases, including inflammatory bowel disease (IBD). In a mouse model, pharmacological inhibition of APT2 or knockout of Zdhhc7-which encodes DHHC7-relieves the symptoms of IBD. Our study reveals not only a potential therapeutic strategy for the treatment of IBD but also a model through which S-palmitoylation regulates cell signalling, which might be broadly applicable for understanding the signalling functions of numerous S-palmitoylation events.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ABHD10 is an S-depalmitoylase affecting redox homeostasis through peroxiredoxin-5</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/31740833/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/31740833/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;S-Palmitoylation is a reversible lipid post-translational modification that has been observed on mitochondrial proteins, but both the regulation and functional consequences of mitochondrial S-palmitoylation are poorly understood. Here, we show that perturbing the &amp;rsquo;erasers&amp;rsquo; of S-palmitoylation, acyl protein thioesterases (APTs), with either pan-active inhibitors or a mitochondrial-targeted APT inhibitor, diminishes the antioxidant buffering capacity of mitochondria. Surprisingly, this effect was not mediated by the only known mitochondrial APT, but rather by a resident mitochondrial protein with no known endogenous function, ABHD10. We show that ABHD10 is a member of the APT family of regulatory proteins and identify peroxiredoxin-5 (PRDX5), a key antioxidant protein, as a target of ABHD10 S-depalmitoylase activity. We then find that ABHD10 regulates the S-palmitoylation status of the nucleophilic active site residue of PRDX5, providing a direct mechanistic connection between ABHD10-mediated S-depalmitoylation of PRDX5 and its antioxidant capacity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Toll-like receptor mediated inflammation requires FASN-dependent MYD88 palmitoylation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/31427815/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/31427815/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Toll-like receptor (TLR)/myeloid differentiation primary response protein (MYD88) signaling aggravates sepsis by impairing neutrophil migration to infection sites. However, the role of intracellular fatty acids in TLR/MYD88 signaling is unclear. Here, inhibition of fatty acid synthase by C75 improved neutrophil chemotaxis and increased the survival of mice with sepsis in cecal ligation puncture and lipopolysaccharide-induced septic shock models. C75 specifically blocked TLR/MYD88 signaling in neutrophils. Treatment with GSK2194069 that targets a different domain of fatty acid synthase, did not block TLR signaling or MYD88 palmitoylation. De novo fatty acid synthesis and CD36-mediated exogenous fatty acid incorporation contributed to MYD88 palmitoylation. The binding of IRAK4 to the MYD88 intermediate domain and downstream signal activation required MYD88 palmitoylation at cysteine 113. MYD88 was palmitoylated by ZDHHC6, and ZDHHC6 knockdown decreased MYD88 palmitoylation and TLR/MYD88 activation upon lipopolysaccharide stimulus. Thus, intracellular saturated fatty acid-dependent palmitoylation of MYD88 by ZDHHC6 is a therapeutic target of sepsis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
