<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Microbiome | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/microbiome/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/microbiome/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Microbiome</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Microbiome</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/microbiome/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Summary of microbiome databases</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tool/2022-07-10-db-microbiome/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/tool/2022-07-10-db-microbiome/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.dsmz.de/collection/catalogue/microorganisms/special-groups-of-organisms/dzif-sammlung/maus-mikrobiomliste&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;mouse intestinal Bacterial Collection (miBC)&lt;/a&gt;  is an initiative from the RTWH Aachen (Prof. Thomas Clavel) and the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.dsmz.de/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Leibniz-Institute DSMZ-German Collection of Microorganisms and Cell Cultures&lt;/a&gt;. It is supported by Collaborative Research Centre (CRC) 1371 and CRC1382 and by the German Federal Ministry of Science and Education through the German Center of Infection Research (DZIF). This collection includes bacterial strains isolated from the intestine of mice. They have been taxonomically described and are all publicly available. This well-curated resource was built to increase our knowledge of cultured diversity within the mouse gut microbiota and to support scientists with their own research by providing multiple strains representing a broad phylogenetic diversity to be used for functional experiments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://bio-annotation.cn/gutMDisorder/home.dhtml&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;gutMDisorder&lt;/a&gt; is a comprehensive resource for associations between gut microbes and phenotypes or interventions in Human and Mouse, derived from manual literature extraction and raw data reprocessing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Microbiome and its metabolites are closely associated with human health and diseases. However, it is challenging to understand the complex interplay between microbiome and metabolites. &lt;a href=&#34;http://metorigin.met-bioinformatics.cn/home/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;MetOrigin&lt;/a&gt; is a bioinformatics tool, aiming to identify which bacteria and how they participate in certain metabolic reactions, helping us to understand where metabolites come from: host, bacteria, or both?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://gmrepo.humangut.info/home&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;GMrepo&lt;/a&gt; is a curated database of consistently annotated human gut metagenomes. So far &lt;a href=&#34;https://gmrepo.humangut.info/home&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;GMrepo&lt;/a&gt; contains 71,642 human gut runs/samples from 353 projects; they are associated with 132 human phenotypes. Its main features include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;extensive manual curation of meta-data of gut samples/runs,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;grouping samples/runs according to their associated human phenotypes (i.e. health and diseases),&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;graphical selectors enabling easy and efficient access to all our collected data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently numerous studies have identified that the perturbations in the gut microbiome were associated with human health, including diseases and cancers, even mental health. The recent development of high-throughput sequencing based metagenomics technologies such as 16S ribosomal RNA gene amplicon-based and genome-centric approaches have burst the profiling of the landscape for gut microbiome and the identification of human health related microbes. Here, we presented the &lt;a href=&#34;http://gutmega.omicsbio.info/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;gutMEGA&lt;/a&gt; database, which hosted the results of metagenomics studies. In total, 59,132 quantification events for 6,457 taxa at 7 different levels (kingdom, phylum, class, order, family, genus and species) under 776 conditions were collected and integrated in the database, and the details about the samples and experiments were also curated. Various browse and search options were provided in the database, and the detailed information was organized and visualized for queries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://bio-annotation.cn/gutmgene/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;gutMGene&lt;/a&gt; is a comprehensive database for target genes of gut microbes and microbial metabolites. Metagenomic sequencing of fecal samples has identified 3.3×10&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt; non-redundant microbial genes from up to 1,500 different species. One of the contributions of gut microbiota to host biology is the circulating pool of bacterially derived small-molecule metabolites. It has been estimated that 10% of metabolites found in mammalian blood are derived from the gut microbiota, where they can produce systemic effects on the host through activating or inhibiting gene expression. Currently, detailed information on target genes of gut microbes and microbial metabolites is scattered in literatures and no online repository is available for collecting these data. Here, we manually extracted microbe-metabolite, microbe-target, and metabolite-target relationships in Human and Mouse from almost 400 publications. All of these relationships were experimentally validated in vivo or in vitro and measured by RT-qPCR, high performance liquid chromatography, 16S rRNA sequence, and so on. Currently, users can:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://bio-annotation.cn/gutmgene/resource.dhtml&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Download&lt;/a&gt; all manually curated relationships.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Achieve relationships by &lt;em&gt;browsing&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;searching&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Submit&lt;/em&gt; novel relationships to the &lt;a href=&#34;http://bio-annotation.cn/gutmgene/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;gutMGene&lt;/a&gt; database.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Taxonomic and functional research of microorganisms has increasingly relied upon genome-based data and methods. As the depository of the Global Catalogue of Microorganisms (GCM) 10K prokaryotic type strain sequencing project, &lt;a href=&#34;http://gctype.wdcm.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Global Catalogue of Type Strain (gcType)&lt;/a&gt; has published 1049 type strain genomes sequenced by the GCM 10K project which are preserved in global culture collections with a valid published status. Additionally, the information provided through &lt;a href=&#34;http://gctype.wdcm.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;gcType&lt;/a&gt; includes &amp;gt;12 000 publicly available type strain genome sequences from GenBank incorporated using quality control criteria and standard data annotation pipelines to form a high-quality reference database. This database integrates type strain sequences with their phenotypic information to facilitate phenotypic and genotypic analyses. Multiple formats of cross-genome searches and interactive interfaces have allowed extensive exploration of the database&amp;rsquo;s resources. In this study, we describe web-based data analysis pipelines for genomic analyses and genome-based taxonomy, which could serve as a one-stop platform for the identification of prokaryotic species. The number of type strain genomes that are published will continue to increase as the GCM 10K project increases its collaboration with culture collections worldwide. Data of this project is shared with the International Nucleotide Sequence Database Collaboration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://disbiome.ugent.be/home&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Disbiome&lt;/a&gt; is a database covering microbial composition changes in different kinds of diseases, managed by Ghent University. Disease names, detection methods or organism names can be used as search queries giving you all information related to the experiment (related disease/bacteria, abundancy subject/control, control type, detection method and related literature).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.vmh.life/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Virtual Metabolic Human (VMH)&lt;/a&gt; database captures information on human and gut microbial metabolism and links this information to hundreds of diseases and nutritional data. At its core, there are hundreds of manually curated genome-scale metabolic reconstructions, which have been assembled based on genomic, biochemical, and physiological data. The &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.vmh.life/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;VMH&lt;/a&gt; facilitates rapid analyses and interpretations of complex data arising from large-scale biomedical studies by enabling complex queries of its content, by providing a detailed graphical representation of human metabolism, and by distributing computational models for simulating human and microbial metabolism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dianalab.e-ce.uth.gr/peryton/#/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Peryton&lt;/a&gt; constitutes a novel resource of experimentally supported microbe-disease associations, currently hosting more than 7,900 entries linking 43 diseases and 1,396 microorganisms. &lt;a href=&#34;https://dianalab.e-ce.uth.gr/peryton/#/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Peryton&lt;/a&gt;’s content is exclusively sustained by manual curation of biomedical articles. Importantly, diseases and microorganisms are provided in a systematic, standardized manner using reference resources to create database dictionaries. Information about the experimental design, study cohorts and the applied high- or low-throughput techniques are meticulously annotated and catered to users. Extensive details regarding bacterial abundance, the groups under study (including their sex ratio and their size) and article metadata are available for each entry. A number of functionalities are provided to enhance user experience and enable ingenious use of &lt;a href=&#34;https://dianalab.e-ce.uth.gr/peryton/#/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Peryton&lt;/a&gt;. One or more microorganisms and/or diseases can be queried at the same time. Advanced filtering options and direct text-based filtering of results enable refinement of returned information and the conducting of tailored queries suitable to different research questions. Results can be directly downloaded as tab-separated files for local storage and downstream analyses. &lt;a href=&#34;https://dianalab.e-ce.uth.gr/peryton/#/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Peryton&lt;/a&gt; also provides to users’ interactive visualizations to effectively capture different aspects of its content. Via Network graphs, Chord diagrams and Hierarchy Diagrams users can browse into the available content and perform observations about microbe-disease relationships using information from the latest relevant literature. &lt;a href=&#34;https://dianalab.e-ce.uth.gr/peryton/#/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Peryton&lt;/a&gt;’s content in numbers:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2,918 gastrointestinal disease associations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4,065 cancer-related associations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;869 neurodegenerative disorder associations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;125 cardiovascular disease associations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1,718 entries providing information at species level or below&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3,777 entries comparing a disease group against healthy individuals and 4,200 comparing disease states&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Accumulating evidence about the interaction between human microbiota and therapeutic-related substances, especially for clinical used drugs, deepens and broadens our understanding in the role of &amp;ldquo;our second genome&amp;rdquo; in human health and diseases, and opens a new window for managing/treating human healthy problems/diseases by manipulating microbiota-human interactions. A centralized and standardized database to catalog Microbiota-Active Substances Interactions (MASIs) will be very useful for related research fields, including microbiota-related pharmaceutical research, food and nutrition research, clinical pharmacy, health management studies. Here, the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.aiddlab.com/MASI/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;MASI&lt;/a&gt; database is developed to cater this urgent need by providing manually curated MASIs data from scientific literature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://leb.snu.ac.kr/amdb&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Animal Microbiome Database (AMDB)&lt;/a&gt; is a database covering bacterial 16S rRNA gene profiles from various animal species to assess the relationship between the gut microbiota and animal hosts. We collected 2,530 samples from 34 public projects with manually curated metadata. Currently, &lt;a href=&#34;http://leb.snu.ac.kr/amdb&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;AMDB&lt;/a&gt; contains 10,478 bacterial taxa from 467 animal species. Please refer to our paper for detailed analysis methods. &lt;a href=&#34;http://leb.snu.ac.kr/amdb&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;AMDB&lt;/a&gt; provides four main functions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Taxa: It shows samples enriched with the bacterial taxon of interest.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Samples: It provides the gut microbiota composition of the sample of interest.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Projects/Hosts: It gives you summary information for the project or the host.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Visualization: It visually presents valuable information about the relationships between the samples and the gut microbiota.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/tag/databases/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Databases&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/tool/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Tools &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Berberine Relieves Metabolic Syndrome in Mice by Inhibiting Liver Inflammation Caused by a High-Fat Diet and Potential Association With Gut Microbiota</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35095784/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35095784/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whether berberine mediates its anti-inflammatory and blood sugar and lipid-lowering effects solely by adjusting the structure of the gut microbiota or by first directly regulating the expression of host pro-inflammatory proteins and activation of macrophages and subsequently acting on gut microbiota, is currently unclear. To clarify the mechanism of berberine-mediated regulation of metabolism, we constructed an obese mouse model using SPF-grade C57BL/6J male mice and conducted a systematic study of liver tissue pathology, inflammatory factor expression, and gut microbiota structure. We screened the gut microbiota targets of berberine and showed that the molecular mechanism of berberine-mediated treatment of metabolic syndrome involves the regulation of gut microbiota structure and the expression of inflammatory factors. Our results revealed that a high-fat diet (HFD) significantly changed mice gut microbiota, thereby probably increasing the level of toxins in the intestine, and triggered the host inflammatory response. The HFD also reduced the proportion of short-chain fatty acid (SCFA)-producing genes, thereby hindering mucosal immunity and cell nutrition, and increased the host inflammatory response and liver fat metabolism disorders. Further, berberine could improve the chronic HFD-induced inflammatory metabolic syndrome to some extent and effectively improved the metabolism of high-fat foods in mice, which correlated with the gut microbiota composition. Taken together, our study may improve our understanding of host-microbe interactions during the treatment of metabolic diseases and provide useful insights into the action mechanism of berberine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AMDB: a database of animal gut microbial communities with manually curated metadata</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34747470/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34747470/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Variations in gut microbiota can be explained by animal host characteristics, including host phylogeny and diet. However, there are currently no databases that allow for easy exploration of the relationship between gut microbiota and diverse animal hosts. The &lt;a href=&#34;http://leb.snu.ac.kr/amdb&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Animal Microbiome Database (AMDB)&lt;/a&gt; is the first database to provide taxonomic profiles of the gut microbiota in various animal species. &lt;a href=&#34;http://leb.snu.ac.kr/amdb&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;AMDB&lt;/a&gt; contains 2530 amplicon data from 34 projects with manually curated metadata. The total data represent 467 animal species and contain 10 478 bacterial taxa. This novel database provides information regarding gut microbiota structures and the distribution of gut bacteria in animals, with an easy-to-use interface. Interactive visualizations are also available, enabling effective investigation of the relationship between the gut microbiota and animal hosts. &lt;a href=&#34;http://leb.snu.ac.kr/amdb&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;AMDB&lt;/a&gt; will contribute to a better understanding of the gut microbiota of animals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>gutMGene: a comprehensive database for target genes of gut microbes and microbial metabolites</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34500458/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34500458/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://bio-annotation.cn/gutmgene&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;gutMGene&lt;/a&gt;, a manually curated database, aims at providing a comprehensive resource of target genes of gut microbes and microbial metabolites in humans and mice. Metagenomic sequencing of fecal samples has identified 3.3 × 106 non-redundant microbial genes from up to 1500 different species. One of the contributions of gut microbiota to host biology is the circulating pool of bacterially derived small-molecule metabolites. It has been estimated that 10% of metabolites found in mammalian blood are derived from the gut microbiota, where they can produce systemic effects on the host through activating or inhibiting gene expression. The current version of &lt;a href=&#34;http://bio-annotation.cn/gutmgene&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;gutMGene&lt;/a&gt; documents 1331 curated relationships between 332 gut microbes, 207 microbial metabolites and 223 genes in humans, and 2349 curated relationships between 209 gut microbes, 149 microbial metabolites and 544 genes in mice. Each entry in the &lt;a href=&#34;http://bio-annotation.cn/gutmgene&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;gutMGene&lt;/a&gt; contains detailed information on a relationship between gut microbe, microbial metabolite and target gene, a brief description of the relationship, experiment technology and platform, literature reference and so on. &lt;a href=&#34;http://bio-annotation.cn/gutmgene&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;gutMGene&lt;/a&gt; provides a user-friendly interface to browse and retrieve each entry using gut microbes, disorders and intervention measures. It also offers the option to download all the entries and submit new experimentally validated associations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Metagenomic compendium of 189,680 DNA viruses from the human gut microbiome</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34168315/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34168315/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bacteriophages have important roles in the ecology of the human gut microbiome but are under-represented in reference databases. To address this problem, we assembled the Metagenomic Gut Virus catalogue that comprises 189,680 viral genomes from 11,810 publicly available human stool metagenomes. Over 75% of genomes represent double-stranded DNA phages that infect members of the Bacteroidia and Clostridia classes. Based on sequence clustering we identified 54,118 candidate viral species, 92% of which were not found in existing databases. The Metagenomic Gut Virus catalogue improves detection of viruses in stool metagenomes and accounts for nearly 40% of CRISPR spacers found in human gut Bacteria and Archaea. We also produced a catalogue of 459,375 viral protein clusters to explore the functional potential of the gut virome. This revealed tens of thousands of diversity-generating retroelements, which use error-prone reverse transcription to mutate target genes and may be involved in the molecular arms race between phages and their bacterial hosts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Endogenous retroviruses promote homeostatic and inflammatory responses to the microbiota</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34166614/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34166614/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The microbiota plays a fundamental role in regulating host immunity. However, the processes involved in the initiation and regulation of immunity to the microbiota remain largely unknown. Here, we show that the skin microbiota promotes the discrete expression of defined endogenous retroviruses (ERVs). Keratinocyte-intrinsic responses to ERVs depended on cyclic GMP-AMP synthase (cGAS)/stimulator of interferon genes protein (STING) signaling and promoted the induction of commensal-specific T cells. Inhibition of ERV reverse transcription significantly impacted these responses, resulting in impaired immunity to the microbiota and its associated tissue repair function. Conversely, a lipid-enriched diet primed the skin for heightened ERV- expression in response to commensal colonization, leading to increased immune responses and tissue inflammation. Together, our results support the idea that the host may have co-opted its endogenous virome as a means to communicate with the exogenous microbiota, resulting in a multi-kingdom dialog that controls both tissue homeostasis and inflammation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A catalog of tens of thousands of viruses from human metagenomes reveals hidden associations with chronic diseases</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34083435/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34083435/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite remarkable strides in microbiome research, the viral component of the microbiome has generally presented a more challenging target than the bacteriome. This gap persists, even though many thousands of shotgun sequencing runs from human metagenomic samples exist in public databases, and all of them encompass large amounts of viral sequence data. The lack of a comprehensive database for human-associated viruses has historically stymied efforts to interrogate the impact of the virome on human health. This study probes thousands of datasets to uncover sequences from over 45,000 unique virus taxa, with historically high per-genome completeness. Large publicly available case-control studies are reanalyzed, and over 2,200 strong virus-disease associations are found.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>gutMEGA: a database of the human gut MEtaGenome Atlas</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32496513/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32496513/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The gut microbiota plays important roles in human health through regulating both physiological homeostasis and disease emergence. The accumulation of metagenomic sequencing studies enables us to better understand the temporal and spatial variations of the gut microbiota under different physiological and pathological conditions. However, it is inconvenient for scientists to query and retrieve published data; thus, a comprehensive resource for the quantitative gut metagenome is urgently needed. In this study, we developed &lt;a href=&#34;http://gutmega.omicsbio.info/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;gut MEtaGenome Atlas (gutMEGA)&lt;/a&gt;, a well-annotated comprehensive database, to curate and host published quantitative gut microbiota datasets from Homo sapiens. By carefully curating the gut microbiota composition, phenotypes and experimental information, &lt;a href=&#34;http://gutmega.omicsbio.info/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;gutMEGA&lt;/a&gt; finally integrated 59 132 quantification events for 6457 taxa at seven different levels (kingdom, phylum, class, order, family, genus and species) under 776 conditions. Moreover, with various browsing and search functions, &lt;a href=&#34;http://gutmega.omicsbio.info/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;gutMEGA&lt;/a&gt; provides a fast and simple way for users to obtain the relative abundances of intestinal microbes among phenotypes. Overall, &lt;a href=&#34;http://gutmega.omicsbio.info/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;gutMEGA&lt;/a&gt; is a convenient and comprehensive resource for gut metagenome research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Temporal landscape of human gut RNA and DNA virome in SARS-CoV-2 infection and severity</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33853691/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33853691/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) caused by the enveloped RNA virus SARS-CoV-2 primarily affects the respiratory and gastrointestinal tracts. SARS-CoV-2 was isolated from fecal samples, and active viral replication was reported in human intestinal cells. The human gut also harbors an enormous amount of resident viruses (collectively known as the virome) that play a role in regulating host immunity and disease pathophysiology. Understanding gut virome perturbation that underlies SARS-CoV-2 infection and severity is an unmet need.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; We enrolled 98 COVID-19 patients with varying disease severity (3 asymptomatic, 53 mild, 34 moderate, 5 severe, 3 critical) and 78 non-COVID-19 controls matched for gender and co-morbidities. All subjects had fecal specimens sampled at inclusion. Blood specimens were collected for COVID-19 patients at admission to test for inflammatory markers and white cell counts. Among COVID-19 cases, 37 (38%) patients had serial fecal samples collected 2 to 3 times per week from time of hospitalization until after discharge. Using shotgun metagenomics sequencing, we sequenced and profiled the fecal RNA and DNA virome. We investigated alterations and longitudinal dynamics of the gut virome in association with disease severity and blood parameters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; Patients with COVID-19 showed underrepresentation of Pepper mild mottle virus (RNA virus) and multiple bacteriophage lineages (DNA viruses) and enrichment of environment-derived eukaryotic DNA viruses in fecal samples, compared to non-COVID-19 subjects. Such gut virome alterations persisted up to 30 days after disease resolution. Fecal virome in SARS-CoV-2 infection harbored more stress-, inflammation-, and virulence-associated gene encoding capacities including those pertaining to bacteriophage integration, DNA repair, and metabolism and virulence associated with their bacterial host. Baseline fecal abundance of 10 virus species (1 RNA virus, pepper chlorotic spot virus, and 9 DNA virus species) inversely correlated with disease COVID-19 severity. These viruses inversely correlated with blood levels of pro-inflammatory proteins, white cells, and neutrophils. Among the 10 COVID-19 severity-associated DNA virus species, 4 showed inverse correlation with age; 5 showed persistent lower abundance both during disease course and after disease resolution relative to non-COVID-19 subjects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; Both enteric RNA and DNA virome in COVID-19 patients were different from non-COVID-19 subjects, which persisted after disease resolution of COVID-19. Gut virome may calibrate host immunity and regulate severity to SARS-CoV-2 infection. Our observation that gut viruses inversely correlated with both severity of COVID-19 and host age may partly explain that older subjects are prone to severe and worse COVID-19 outcomes. Altogether, our data highlight the importance of human gut virome in severity and potentially therapeutics of COVID-19.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lung virome: New potential biomarkers for asthma severity and exacerbation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33757721/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33757721/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Although some respiratory virus infections are known to contribute to the development and exacerbation of asthma, commensal viromes in airway have not been extensively studied due to technical challenges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Objectives:&lt;/em&gt; This study investigated the characteristics of the virome in asthmatic airways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; Both the bacteriome and virome profiles in sputum from 12 healthy individuals, 15 patients with nonsevere asthma, and 15 patients with severe asthma were analyzed and assessed for the association with clinical characteristics such as severity, exacerbation, Asthma Control Test (ACT), and lung function.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; While analysis of the 16S ribosomal RNA bacteriome in the airway showed no differences, clear contrasts in the diversity and composition of airway viromes were observed between healthy controls and patients with asthma. Herpesviruses were the most abundant type of virus in the asthma group (44.6 ± 4.6%), mainly with cytomegalovirus (CMV) and EBV accounting for 24.5 ± 3.3% and 16.9 ± 3.5%, respectively, in contrast to those in the healthy controls (5.4 ± 2.5% and 7.1 ± 3.0%, respectively). CMV and EBV were more abundant in patients with asthma who experienced exacerbation, and their abundance showed correlation with more severe asthma, lower ACT score, and lower lung function. On the contrary, bacteriophage that is abundant in healthy controls was severely reduced in patients with asthma in the order of nonsevere and severe asthma and presented significant positive correlation with ACT and FEV1/forced vital capacity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; Lung viromes, especially, CMV, EBV, and bacteriophage may be potential biomarkers of asthma severity and exacerbation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integrated gut virome and bacteriome dynamics in COVID-19 patients</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33678150/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33678150/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SARS-CoV-2 is the cause of the current global pandemic of COVID-19; this virus infects multiple organs, such as the lungs and gastrointestinal tract. The microbiome in these organs, including the bacteriome and virome, responds to infection and might also influence disease progression and treatment outcome. In a cohort of 13 COVID-19 patients in Beijing, China, we observed that the gut virome and bacteriome in the COVID-19 patients were notably different from those of five healthy controls. We identified a bacterial dysbiosis signature by observing reduced diversity and viral shifts in patients, and among the patients, the bacterial/viral compositions were different between patients of different severities, although these differences are not entirely distinguishable from the effect of antibiotics. Severe cases of COVID-19 exhibited a greater abundance of opportunistic pathogens but were depleted for butyrate-producing groups of bacteria compared with mild to moderate cases. We replicated our findings in a mouse COVID-19 model, confirmed virome differences and bacteriome dysbiosis due to SARS-CoV-2 infection, and observed that immune/infection-related genes were differentially expressed in gut epithelial cells during infection, possibly explaining the virome and bacteriome dynamics. Our results suggest that the components of the microbiome, including the bacteriome and virome, are affected by SARS-CoV-2 infections, while their compositional signatures could reflect or even contribute to disease severity and recovery processes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Massive expansion of human gut bacteriophage diversity</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33606979/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33606979/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bacteriophages drive evolutionary change in bacterial communities by creating gene flow networks that fuel ecological adaptions. However, the extent of viral diversity and its prevalence in the human gut remains largely unknown. Here, we introduce the Gut Phage Database, a collection of ∼142,000 non-redundant viral genomes (&amp;gt;10 kb) obtained by mining a dataset of 28,060 globally distributed human gut metagenomes and 2,898 reference genomes of cultured gut bacteria. Host assignment revealed that viral diversity is highest in the Firmicutes phyla and that ∼36% of viral clusters (VCs) are not restricted to a single species, creating gene flow networks across phylogenetically distinct bacterial species. Epidemiological analysis uncovered 280 globally distributed VCs found in at least 5 continents and a highly prevalent phage clade with features reminiscent of p-crAssphage. This high-quality, large-scale catalog of phage genomes will improve future virome studies and enable ecological and evolutionary analysis of human gut bacteriophages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>gcType: a high-quality type strain genome database for microbial phylogenetic and functional research</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33119759/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33119759/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Taxonomic and functional research of microorganisms has increasingly relied upon genome-based data and methods. As the depository of the Global Catalogue of Microorganisms (GCM) 10K prokaryotic type strain sequencing project, &lt;a href=&#34;http://gctype.wdcm.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Global Catalogue of Type Strain (gcType)&lt;/a&gt; has published 1049 type strain genomes sequenced by the GCM 10K project which are preserved in global culture collections with a valid published status. Additionally, the information provided through &lt;a href=&#34;http://gctype.wdcm.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;gcType&lt;/a&gt; includes &amp;gt;12 000 publicly available type strain genome sequences from GenBank incorporated using quality control criteria and standard data annotation pipelines to form a high-quality reference database. This database integrates type strain sequences with their phenotypic information to facilitate phenotypic and genotypic analyses. Multiple formats of cross-genome searches and interactive interfaces have allowed extensive exploration of the database&amp;rsquo;s resources. In this study, we describe web-based data analysis pipelines for genomic analyses and genome-based taxonomy, which could serve as a one-stop platform for the identification of prokaryotic species. The number of type strain genomes that are published will continue to increase as the GCM 10K project increases its collaboration with culture collections worldwide. Data of this project is shared with the International Nucleotide Sequence Database Collaboration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MASI: microbiota-active substance interactions database</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33125077/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33125077/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Xenobiotic and host active substances interact with gut microbiota to influence human health and therapeutics. Dietary, pharmaceutical, herbal and environmental substances are modified by microbiota with altered bioavailabilities, bioactivities and toxic effects. Xenobiotics also affect microbiota with health implications. Knowledge of these microbiota and active substance interactions is important for understanding microbiota-regulated functions and therapeutics. Established microbiota databases provide useful information about the microbiota-disease associations, diet and drug interventions, and microbiota modulation of drugs. However, there is insufficient information on the active substances modified by microbiota and the abundance of gut bacteria in humans. Only ∼7% drugs are covered by the established databases. To complement these databases, we developed &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.aiddlab.com/MASI/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;MASI&lt;/a&gt;, Microbiota-Active Substance Interactions database, for providing the information about the microbiota alteration of various substances, substance alteration of microbiota, and the abundance of gut bacteria in humans. These include 1,051 pharmaceutical, 103 dietary, 119 herbal, 46 probiotic, 142 environmental substances interacting with 806 microbiota species linked to 56 diseases and 784 microbiota-disease associations. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.aiddlab.com/MASI/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;MASI&lt;/a&gt; covers 11 215 bacteria-pharmaceutical, 914 bacteria-herbal, 309 bacteria-dietary, 753 bacteria-environmental substance interactions and the abundance profiles of 259 bacteria species in 3465 patients and 5334 healthy individuals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Peryton: a manual collection of experimentally supported microbe-disease associations</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33080028/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33080028/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We present &lt;a href=&#34;https://dianalab.e-ce.uth.gr/peryton/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Peryton&lt;/a&gt;, a database of experimentally supported microbe-disease associations. Its first version constitutes a novel resource hosting more than 7900 entries linking 43 diseases with 1396 microorganisms. &lt;a href=&#34;https://dianalab.e-ce.uth.gr/peryton/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Peryton&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s content is exclusively sustained by manual curation of biomedical articles. Diseases and microorganisms are provided in a systematic, standardized manner using reference resources to create database dictionaries. Information about the experimental design, study cohorts and the applied high- or low-throughput techniques is meticulously annotated and catered to users. Several functionalities are provided to enhance user experience and enable ingenious use of &lt;a href=&#34;https://dianalab.e-ce.uth.gr/peryton/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Peryton&lt;/a&gt;. One or more microorganisms and/or diseases can be queried at the same time. Advanced filtering options and direct text-based filtering of results enable refinement of returned information and the conducting of tailored queries suitable to different research questions. &lt;a href=&#34;https://dianalab.e-ce.uth.gr/peryton/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Peryton&lt;/a&gt; also provides interactive visualizations to effectively capture different aspects of its content and results can be directly downloaded for local storage and downstream analyses. &lt;a href=&#34;https://dianalab.e-ce.uth.gr/peryton/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Peryton&lt;/a&gt; will serve as a valuable source, enabling scientists of microbe-related disease fields to form novel hypotheses but, equally importantly, to assist in cross-validation of findings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Longitudinal Multi-omics Reveals Subset-Specific Mechanisms Underlying Irritable Bowel Syndrome</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32916129/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32916129/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Erratum in:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674%2820%2931447-1&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Longitudinal Multi-omics Reveals Subset-Specific Mechanisms Underlying Irritable Bowel Syndrome&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The gut microbiome has been implicated in multiple human chronic gastrointestinal (GI) disorders. Determining its mechanistic role in disease has been difficult due to apparent disconnects between animal and human studies and lack of an integrated multi-omics view of disease-specific physiological changes. We integrated longitudinal multi-omics data from the gut microbiome, metabolome, host epigenome, and transcriptome in the context of irritable bowel syndrome (IBS) host physiology. We identified IBS subtype-specific and symptom-related variation in microbial composition and function. A subset of identified changes in microbial metabolites correspond to host physiological mechanisms that are relevant to IBS. By integrating multiple data layers, we identified purine metabolism as a novel host-microbial metabolic pathway in IBS with translational potential. Our study highlights the importance of longitudinal sampling and integrating complementary multi-omics data to identify functional mechanisms that can serve as therapeutic targets in a comprehensive treatment strategy for chronic GI diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Virome of Acute Respiratory Diseases in Individuals at Risk of Zoonotic Infections</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32872469/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32872469/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ongoing coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) pandemic emphasizes the need to actively study the virome of unexplained respiratory diseases. We performed viral metagenomic next-generation sequencing (mNGS) analysis of 91 nasal-throat swabs from individuals working with animals and with acute respiratory diseases. Fifteen virus RT-PCR-positive samples were included as controls, while the other 76 samples were RT-PCR negative for a wide panel of respiratory pathogens. Eukaryotic viruses detected by mNGS were then screened by PCR (using primers based on mNGS-derived contigs) in all samples to compare viral detection by mNGS versus PCR and assess the utility of mNGS in routine diagnostics. mNGS identified expected human rhinoviruses, enteroviruses, influenza A virus, coronavirus OC43, and respiratory syncytial virus (RSV) A in 13 of 15 (86.7%) positive control samples. Additionally, rotavirus, torque teno virus, human papillomavirus, human betaherpesvirus 7, cyclovirus, vientovirus, gemycircularvirus, and statovirus were identified through mNGS. Notably, complete genomes of novel cyclovirus, gemycircularvirus, and statovirus were genetically characterized. Using PCR screening, the novel cyclovirus was additionally detected in 5 and the novel gemycircularvirus in 12 of the remaining samples included for mNGS analysis. Our studies therefore provide pioneering data of the virome of acute-respiratory diseases from individuals at risk of zoonotic infections. The mNGS protocol/pipeline applied here is sensitive for the detection of a variety of viruses, including novel ones. More frequent detections of the novel viruses by PCR than by mNGS on the same samples suggests that PCR remains the most sensitive diagnostic test for viruses whose genomes are known. The detection of novel viruses expands our understanding of the respiratory virome of animal-exposed humans and warrant further studies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Gut Virome Database Reveals Age-Dependent Patterns of Virome Diversity in the Human Gut</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32841606/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32841606/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The gut microbiome profoundly affects human health and disease, and their infecting viruses are likely as important, but often missed because of reference database limitations. Here, we (1) built a human Gut Virome Database (GVD) from 2,697 viral particle or microbial metagenomes from 1,986 individuals representing 16 countries, (2) assess its effectiveness, and (3) report a meta-analysis that reveals age-dependent patterns across healthy Westerners. The GVD contains 33,242 unique viral populations (approximately species-level taxa) and improves average viral detection rates over viral RefSeq and IMG/VR nearly 182-fold and 2.6-fold, respectively. GVD meta-analyses show highly personalized viromes, reveal that inter-study variability from technical artifacts is larger than any &amp;ldquo;disease&amp;rdquo; effect at the population level, and document how viral diversity changes from human infancy into senescence. Together, this compact foundational resource, these standardization guidelines, and these meta-analysis findings provide a systematic toolkit to help maximize our understanding of viral roles in health and disease.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Influenza infection elicits an expansion of gut population of endogenous Bifidobacterium animalis which protects mice against infection</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32345342/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32345342/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Influenza is a severe respiratory illness that continually threatens global health. It has been widely known that gut microbiota modulates the host response to protect against influenza infection, but mechanistic details remain largely unknown. Here, we took advantage of the phenomenon of lethal dose 50 (LD&lt;sub&gt;50&lt;/sub&gt;) and metagenomic sequencing analysis to identify specific anti-influenza gut microbes and analyze the underlying mechanism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; Transferring fecal microbes from mice that survive virulent influenza H7N9 infection into antibiotic-treated mice confers resistance to infection. Some gut microbes exhibit differential features to lethal influenza infection depending on the infection outcome. Bifidobacterium pseudolongum and Bifidobacterium animalis levels are significantly elevated in surviving mice when compared to dead or mock-infected mice. Oral administration of B. animalis alone or the combination of both significantly reduces the severity of H7N9 infection in both antibiotic-treated and germ-free mice. Functional metagenomic analysis suggests that B. animalis mediates the anti-influenza effect via several specific metabolic molecules. In vivo tests confirm valine and coenzyme A produce an anti-influenza effect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; These findings show that the severity of influenza infection is closely related to the heterogeneous responses of the gut microbiota. We demonstrate the anti-influenza effect of B. animalis, and also find that the gut population of endogenous B. animalis can expand to enhance host influenza resistance when lethal influenza infection occurs, representing a novel interaction between host and gut microbiota. Further, our data suggest the potential utility of Bifidobacterium in the prevention and as a prognostic predictor of influenza.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Altered Gut Microbiome Profile in Patients With Pulmonary Arterial Hypertension</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32088998/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32088998/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pulmonary arterial hypertension (PAH) is considered a disease of the pulmonary vasculature. Limited progress has been made in preventing or arresting progression of PAH despite extensive efforts. Our previous studies indicated that PAH could be considered a systemic disease since its pathology involves interplay of multiple organs. This, coupled with increasing implication of the gut and its microbiome in chronic diseases, led us to hypothesize that patients with PAH exhibit a distinct gut microbiome that contributes to, and predicts, the disease. Fecal microbiome of 18 type 1 PAH patients (mean pulmonary arterial pressure, 57.4, SD 16.7 mm Hg) and 13 reference subjects were compared by shotgun metagenomics to evaluate this hypothesis. Significant taxonomic and functional changes in microbial communities in the PAH cohort were observed. Pathways for the synthesis of arginine, proline, and ornithine were increased in PAH cohort compared with reference cohort. Additionally, groups of bacterial communities associated with trimethylamine/ trimethylamine N-oxide and purine metabolism were increased in PAH cohort. In contrast, butyrate-and propionate-producing bacteria such as Coprococcus, Butyrivibrio, Lachnospiraceae, Eubacterium, Akkermansia, and Bacteroides were increased in reference cohort. A random forest model predicted PAH from the composition of the gut microbiome with 83% accuracy. Finally, virome analysis showed enrichment of Enterococcal and relative depletion of Lactococcal phages in the PAH cohort. In conclusion, patients with PAH exhibit a unique microbiome profile that has the high predictive potential for PAH. This highlights previously unknown roles of gut bacteria in this disease and could lead to new therapeutic, diagnostic, or management paradigms for PAH.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using MicrobiomeAnalyst for comprehensive statistical, functional, and meta-analysis of microbiome data</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/31942082/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/31942082/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.microbiomeanalyst.ca/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;MicrobiomeAnalyst&lt;/a&gt; is an easy-to-use, web-based platform for comprehensive analysis of common data outputs generated from current microbiome studies. It enables researchers and clinicians with little or no bioinformatics training to explore a wide variety of well-established methods for microbiome data processing, statistical analysis, functional profiling and comparison with public datasets or known microbial signatures. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.microbiomeanalyst.ca/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;MicrobiomeAnalyst&lt;/a&gt; currently contains four modules: Marker-gene Data Profiling (MDP), Shotgun Data Profiling (SDP), Projection with Public Data (PPD), and Taxon Set Enrichment Analysis (TSEA). This protocol will first introduce the MDP module by providing a step-wise description of how to prepare, process and normalize data; perform community profiling; identify important features; and conduct correlation and classification analysis. We will then demonstrate how to perform predictive functional profiling and introduce several unique features of the SDP module for functional analysis. The last two sections will describe the key steps involved in using the PPD and TSEA modules for meta-analysis and visual exploration of the results. In summary, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.microbiomeanalyst.ca/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;MicrobiomeAnalyst&lt;/a&gt; offers a one-stop shop that enables microbiome researchers to thoroughly explore their preprocessed microbiome data via intuitive web interfaces. The complete protocol can be executed in ~70 min.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GMrepo: a database of curated and consistently annotated human gut metagenomes</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/31504765/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/31504765/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://gmrepo.humangut.info/home&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;GMrepo&lt;/a&gt; (data repository for Gut Microbiota) is a database of curated and consistently annotated human gut metagenomes. Its main purpose is to facilitate the reusability and accessibility of the rapidly growing human metagenomic data. This is achieved by consistently annotating the microbial contents of collected samples using state-of-art toolsets and by manual curation of the meta-data of the corresponding human hosts. &lt;a href=&#34;https://gmrepo.humangut.info/home&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;GMrepo&lt;/a&gt; organizes the collected samples according to their associated phenotypes and includes all possible related meta-data such as age, sex, country, body-mass-index (BMI) and recent antibiotics usage. To make relevant information easier to access, &lt;a href=&#34;https://gmrepo.humangut.info/home&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;GMrepo&lt;/a&gt; is equipped with a graphical query builder, enabling users to make customized, complex and biologically relevant queries. For example, to find (1) samples from healthy individuals of 18 to 25 years old with BMIs between 18.5 and 24.9, or (2) projects that are related to colorectal neoplasms, with each containing &amp;gt;100 samples and both patients and healthy controls. Precomputed species/genus relative abundances, prevalence within and across phenotypes, and pairwise co-occurrence information are all available at the website and accessible through programmable interfaces. So far, &lt;a href=&#34;https://gmrepo.humangut.info/home&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;GMrepo&lt;/a&gt; contains 58 903 human gut samples/runs (including 17 618 metagenomes and 41 285 amplicons) from 253 projects concerning 92 phenotypes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commensal viruses maintain intestinal intraepithelial lymphocytes via noncanonical RIG-I signaling</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/31636462/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/31636462/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Much attention has focused on commensal bacteria in health and disease, but the role of commensal viruses is understudied. Although metagenomic analysis shows that the intestine of healthy humans and animals harbors various commensal viruses and the dysbiosis of these viruses can be associated with inflammatory diseases, there is still a lack of causal data and underlying mechanisms to understand the physiological role of commensal viruses in intestinal homeostasis. In the present study, we show that commensal viruses are essential for the homeostasis of intestinal intraepithelial lymphocytes (IELs). Mechanistically, the cytosolic viral RNA-sensing receptor RIG-I in antigen-presenting cells can recognize commensal viruses and maintain IELs via a type I interferon-independent, but MAVS-IRF1-IL-15 axis-dependent, manner. The recovery of IELs by interleukin-15 administration reverses the susceptibility of commensal virus-depleted mice to dextran sulfate sodium-induced colitis. Collectively, our results indicate that commensal viruses maintain the IELs and consequently sustain intestinal homeostasis via noncanonical RIG-I signaling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Statistical Analysis of Microbiome Data with R</title>
      <link>https://example.com/books/2019-02-02-stat-analy-microbiome-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/books/2019-02-02-stat-analy-microbiome-r/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This unique book addresses the statistical modelling and analysis of microbiome data using cutting-edge R software. It includes real-world data from the authors’ research and from the public domain, and discusses the implementation of R for data analysis step by step. The data and R computer programs are publicly available, allowing readers to replicate the model development and data analysis presented in each chapter, so that these new methods can be readily applied in their own research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The book also discusses recent developments in statistical modelling and data analysis in microbiome research, as well as the latest advances in next-generation sequencing and big data in methodological development and applications. This timely book will greatly benefit all readers involved in microbiome, ecology and microarray data analyses, as well as other fields of research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/books/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Books &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Virtual Metabolic Human database: integrating human and gut microbiome metabolism with nutrition and disease</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/30371894/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/30371894/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A multitude of factors contribute to complex diseases and can be measured with &amp;lsquo;omics&amp;rsquo; methods. Databases facilitate data interpretation for underlying mechanisms. Here, we describe the &lt;a href=&#34;www.vmh.life&#34;&gt;Virtual Metabolic Human (VMH)&lt;/a&gt; database encapsulating current knowledge of human metabolism within five interlinked resources &amp;lsquo;Human metabolism&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;Gut microbiome&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;Disease&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;Nutrition&amp;rsquo;, and &amp;lsquo;ReconMaps&amp;rsquo;. The &lt;a href=&#34;www.vmh.life&#34;&gt;VMH&lt;/a&gt; captures 5180 unique metabolites, 17 730 unique reactions, 3695 human genes, 255 Mendelian diseases, 818 microbes, 632 685 microbial genes and 8790 food items. The &lt;a href=&#34;www.vmh.life&#34;&gt;VMH&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s unique features are (i) the hosting of the metabolic reconstructions of human and gut microbes amenable for metabolic modeling; (ii) seven human metabolic maps for data visualization; (iii) a nutrition designer; (iv) a user-friendly webpage and application-programming interface to access its content; (v) user feedback option for community engagement and (vi) the connection of its entities to 57 other web resources. The &lt;a href=&#34;www.vmh.life&#34;&gt;VMH&lt;/a&gt; represents a novel, interdisciplinary database for data interpretation and hypothesis generation to the biomedical community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Disbiome database: linking the microbiome to disease</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/29866037/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/29866037/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Recent research has provided fascinating indications and evidence that the host health is linked to its microbial inhabitants. Due to the development of high-throughput sequencing technologies, more and more data covering microbial composition changes in different disease types are emerging. However, this information is dispersed over a wide variety of medical and biomedical disciplines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Description:&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://disbiome.ugent.be/home&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Disbiome&lt;/a&gt; is a database which collects and presents published microbiota-disease information in a standardized way. The diseases are classified using the MedDRA classification system and the micro-organisms are linked to their NCBI and SILVA taxonomy. Finally, each study included in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://disbiome.ugent.be/home&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Disbiome&lt;/a&gt; database is assessed for its reporting quality using a standardized questionnaire.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://disbiome.ugent.be/home&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Disbiome&lt;/a&gt; is the first database giving a clear, concise and up-to-date overview of microbial composition differences in diseases, together with the relevant information of the studies published. The strength of this database lies within the combination of the presence of references to other databases, which enables both specific and diverse search strategies within the &lt;a href=&#34;https://disbiome.ugent.be/home&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Disbiome&lt;/a&gt; database, and the human annotation which ensures a simple and structured presentation of the available data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rethinking Diet to Aid Human-Microbe Symbiosis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/27916707/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/27916707/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The spread of the Western lifestyle has been accompanied by microbial changes thought to underlie the emergence of chronic, nontransmissible, immune-related diseases. The past decade has seen the unprecedented development of therapies for &amp;lsquo;replenishing&amp;rsquo; the microbiota of sick individuals. However, functional and ecological solutions helping the host and the gut microbiota to cope with the ecological stressors of modern life are still lacking. In this review, we discuss how recent advances in gut microbiome science are leading to the identification of microbe-derived and health-relevant metabolites. These molecules will guide the selection of the next-generation of probiotics and dietary recommendations, which should also take the resident gut microbiota into account, to optimise efficacy. These solutions for maintaining a well-functioning gut ecosystem and promoting good health should be customised, palatable, and as widely accessible as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Mouse Intestinal Bacterial Collection (miBC) provides host-specific insight into cultured diversity and functional potential of the gut microbiota</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/27670113/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/27670113/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Erratum in:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Corrigendum: &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nature.com/articles/nmicrobiol2016219&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;The Mouse Intestinal Bacterial Collection (miBC) provides host-specific insight into cultured diversity and functional potential of the gut microbiota&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Intestinal bacteria influence mammalian physiology, but many types of bacteria are still uncharacterized. Moreover, reference strains of mouse gut bacteria are not easily available, although mouse models are extensively used in medical research. These are major limitations for the investigation of intestinal microbiomes and their interactions with diet and host. It is thus important to study in detail the diversity and functions of gut microbiota members, including those colonizing the mouse intestine. To address these issues, we aimed at establishing the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.dsmz.de/collection/catalogue/microorganisms/special-groups-of-organisms/dzif-sammlung/maus-mikrobiomliste&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Mouse Intestinal Bacterial Collection (miBC)&lt;/a&gt;, a public repository of bacterial strains and associated genomes from the mouse gut, and studied host-specificity of colonization and sequence-based relevance of the resource. The collection includes several strains representing novel species, genera and even one family. Genomic analyses showed that certain species are specific to the mouse intestine and that a minimal consortium of 18 strains covered 50-75% of the known functional potential of metagenomes. The present work will sustain future research on microbiota-host interactions in health and disease, as it will facilitate targeted colonization and molecular studies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
