<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Microbiome | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/microbiome/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/microbiome/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Microbiome</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Microbiome</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/microbiome/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sesamolin Attenuates Kidney Injury, Intestinal Barrier Dysfunction, and Gut Microbiota Imbalance in High-Fat and High-Fructose Diet-Fed Mice</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36630317/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36630317/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This study investigated the effects of sesamolin on kidney injury, intestinal barrier dysfunction, and gut microbiota imbalance in high-fat and high-fructose (HF-HF) diet-fed mice and explored the underlying correlations among them. The results indicated that sesamolin suppressed metabolic disorders and increased renal function parameters. Histological evaluation showed that sesamolin mitigated renal epithelial cell degeneration and brush border damage. Meanwhile, sesamolin inhibited the endotoxin-mediated induction of the Toll-like receptor 4-related IKKα/NF-κB p65 pathway activation. Additionally, sesamolin mitigated intestinal barrier dysfunction and improved the composition of gut microbiota. The correlation results further indicated that changes in the dominant phyla, including &lt;em&gt;Firmicutes&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Deferribacterota&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Desulfobacterota&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Bacteroidota&lt;/em&gt;, were more highly correlated with a reduction in endotoxemia and metabolic disorders, as well as decreases in intestinal proinflammatory response and related renal risk biomarkers. The results of this study suggest that sesamolin attenuates kidney injuries, which might be associated with its effects on the reduction of endotoxemia and related metabolic disorders through the restoration of the intestinal barrier and the modulation of gut microbiota. Thus, sesamolin may be a potential dietary supplement for protection against obesity-associated kidney injury.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A high-quality genome compendium of the human gut microbiome of Inner Mongolians</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36604505/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36604505/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Metagenome-based resources have revealed the diversity and function of the human gut microbiome, but further understanding is limited by insufficient genome quality and a lack of samples from typically understudied populations. Here we used hybrid long-read PromethION and short-read HiSeq sequencing to characterize the faecal microbiota of 60 Inner Mongolian individuals (n = 180 samples over three time points) who were part of a probiotic yogurt intervention trial. We present the Inner Mongolian Gut Genome catalogue, comprising 802 closed and 5,927 high-quality metagenome-assembled genomes. This approach achieved high genome continuity and substantially increased the resolution of genomic elements, including ribosomal RNA operons, metabolic gene clusters, prophages and insertion sequences. Particularly, we report the ribosomal RNA operon copy numbers for uncultured species, over 12,000 previously undescribed gut prophages and the distribution of insertion sequence elements across gut bacteria. Overall, these data provide a high-quality, large-scale resource for studying the human gut microbiota.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gut commensal Parabacteroides distasonis alleviates inflammatory arthritis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36604114/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36604114/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Objective:&lt;/em&gt; Gut microbiota dysbiosis is closely linked to the pathogenesis of rheumatoid arthritis (RA). We aimed to identify potential probiotic gut microbes that can ameliorate the development of RA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Design:&lt;/em&gt; Microbiota profiling in patients with RA and healthy individuals was investigated via 16S rDNA bacterial gene sequencing and shotgun metagenomics. Collagen-induced arthritic mice and TNF-α transgenic mice were used to evaluate the roles of the gut commensal &lt;em&gt;Parabacteroides distasonis&lt;/em&gt; in RA. The effects of &lt;em&gt;P. distasonis&lt;/em&gt;-derived microbial metabolites on the differentiation of CD4&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T cells and macrophage polarisation were also investigated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; The relative abundance of &lt;em&gt;P. distasonis&lt;/em&gt; in new-onset patients with RA and patients with RA with history of the disease was downregulated and this decrease was negatively correlated with Disease Activity Score-28 (DAS28). Oral treatment of arthritic mice with live &lt;em&gt;P. distasonis&lt;/em&gt; (LPD) considerably ameliorated RA pathogenesis. LPD-derived lithocholic acid (LCA), deoxycholic acid (DCA), isolithocholic acid (isoLCA) and 3-oxolithocholic acid (3-oxoLCA) had similar and synergistic effects on the treatment of RA. In addition to directly inhibiting the differentiation of Th17 cells, 3-oxoLCA and isoLCA were identified as TGR5 agonists that promoted the M2 polarisation of macrophages. A specific synthetic inhibitor of bile salt hydrolase attenuated the antiarthritic effects of LPD by reducing the production of these four bile acids. The natural product ginsenoside Rg2 exhibited its anti-RA effects by promoting the growth of &lt;em&gt;P. distasonis&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;P. distasonis&lt;/em&gt; and ginsenoside Rg2 might represent probiotic and prebiotic agents in the treatment of RA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commensal microbiome promotes hair follicle regeneration by inducing keratinocyte HIF-1α signaling and glutamine metabolism</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36598999/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36598999/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tissue injury induces metabolic changes in stem cells, which likely modulate regeneration. Using a model of organ regeneration called wound-induced hair follicle neogenesis (WIHN), we identified skin-resident bacteria as key modulators of keratinocyte metabolism, demonstrating a positive correlation between bacterial load, glutamine metabolism, and regeneration. Specifically, through comprehensive multiomic analysis and single-cell RNA sequencing in murine skin, we show that bacterially induced hypoxia drives increased glutamine metabolism in keratinocytes with attendant enhancement of skin and hair follicle regeneration. In human skin wounds, topical broad-spectrum antibiotics inhibit glutamine production and are partially responsible for reduced healing. These findings reveal a conserved and coherent physiologic context in which bacterially induced metabolic changes improve the tolerance of stem cells to damage and enhance regenerative capacity. This unexpected proregenerative modulation of metabolism by the skin microbiome in both mice and humans suggests important methods for enhancing regeneration after injury.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gut microbiome dysregulation drives bone damage in broiler tibial dyschondroplasia by disrupting glucose homeostasis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36596826/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36596826/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tibial dyschondroplasia (TD) with multiple incentives is a metabolic skeletal disease that occurs in fast-growing broilers. Perturbations in the gut microbiota (GM) have been shown to affect bone homoeostasis, but the mechanisms by which GM modulates bone metabolism in TD broilers remain unknown. Here, using a broiler model of TD, we noted elevated blood glucose (GLU) levels in TD broilers, accompanied by alterations in the pancreatic structure and secretory function and damaged intestinal barrier function. Importantly, faecal microbiota transplantation (FMT) of gut microbes from normal donors rehabilitated the GM and decreased the elevated GLU levels in TD broilers. A high GLU level is a predisposing factor to bone disease, suggesting that GM dysbiosis-mediated hyperglycaemia might be involved in bone regulation. 16S rRNA gene sequencing and short-chain fatty acid analysis revealed that the significantly increased level of the metabolite butyric acid derived from the genera &lt;em&gt;Blautia&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Coprococcus&lt;/em&gt; regulated GLU levels in TD broilers by binding to GPR109A in the pancreas. Tibial studies showed reduced expression of vascular regulatory factors (including PI3K, AKT and VEFGA) based on transcriptomics analysis and reduced vascular distribution, contributing to nonvascularization of cartilage in the proximal tibial growth plate of TD broilers with elevated GLU levels. Additionally, treatment with the total flavonoids from Rhizoma drynariae further validated the improvement in bone homoeostasis in TD broilers by regulating GLU levels through the regulation of GM to subsequently improve intestinal and pancreatic function. These findings clarify the critical role of GM-mediated changes in GLU levels via the gut–pancreas axis in bone homoeostasis in TD chickens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gut microbiota modulates lung fibrosis severity following acute lung injury in mice</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36543914/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36543914/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Independent studies demonstrate the significance of gut microbiota on the pathogenesis of chronic lung diseases; yet little is known regarding the role of the gut microbiota in lung fibrosis progression. Here we show, using the bleomycin murine model to quantify lung fibrosis in C57BL/6 J mice housed in germ-free, animal biosafety level 1 (ABSL-1), or animal biosafety level 2 (ABSL-2) environments, that germ-free mice are protected from lung fibrosis, while ABSL-1 and ABSL-2 mice develop mild and severe lung fibrosis, respectively. Metagenomic analysis reveals no notable distinctions between ABSL-1 and ABSL-2 lung microbiota, whereas greater microbial diversity, with increased Bifidobacterium and Lactobacilli, is present in ABSL-1 compared to ABSL-2 gut microbiota. Flow cytometric analysis reveals enhanced IL-6/STAT3/IL-17A signaling in pulmonary CD4 + T cells of ABSL-2 mice. Fecal transplantation of ABSL-2 stool into germ-free mice recapitulated more severe fibrosis than transplantation of ABSL-1 stool. Lactobacilli supernatant reduces collagen 1 A production in IL-17A- and TGFβ1-stimulated human lung fibroblasts. These findings support a functional role of the gut microbiota in augmenting lung fibrosis severity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Study on the protective effect of berberine treatment on sepsis based on gut microbiota and metabolomic analysis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36601077/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36601077/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Introduction:&lt;/em&gt; Sepsis, an infection with multiorgan dysfunction, is a serious burden on human health. Berberine (BBR), a bioactive component, has a protective effect on sepsis and the effect may be related to gut microbiota. However, studies on the role of BBR with gut microbiota in sepsis are lacking. Therefore, this study investigated the ameliorative effects and the underlying mechanisms of BBR on cecal ligature and puncture (CLP) rats.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; This study has observed the effect of BBR on pathological injury, Inflammation, intestinal barrier function, gut microbiota, and metabolite change in CLP rats by Hematoxylin-eosin staining, enzyme-linked immunosorbent assays, flow cytometry, 16S rDNA, and metabolomics analyses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; The inhibition effects of BBR treatment on the histological damage of the lung, kidney, and ileum, the interleukin (IL)-1b, IL-6, IL-17A, and monocyte chemokine-1 levels in serum in CLP rats were proved. Also, the BBR inhibited the diamine-oxidase and fluorescein isothiocyanate-dextran 40 levels, suggesting it can improve intestinal barrier function disorders. The cluster of differentiation (CD) 4&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt;, CD8&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt;, and CD25&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; Forkhead box protein P3 (Foxp3) &lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T lymphocytes in splenocytes were up-regulated by BBR, while the IL-17A&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt;CD4&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; cell level was decreased. The abundance of gut microbiota in CLP rats was significantly different from that of the sham and BBR treatment rats. The significantly changed metabolites in the serum mainly included carbohydrates, phenols, benzoic acids, alcohols, vitamins et al. Additionally, this study predicted that the biological mechanism of BBR to ameliorate sepsis involves glycolysis-, nucleotide-, and amino acid-related metabolic pathways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Discussion: This study proved the strong correlation between the improvement effect of BBR on sepsis and gut microbiota and analyzed by metabolomics that gut microbiota may improve CLP rats through metabolites, providing a scientific basis for BBR to improve sepsis and a new direction for the study of the biological mechanism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A microbiome-dependent gut–brain pathway regulates motivation for exercise</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36517598/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36517598/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Exercise exerts a wide range of beneficial effects for healthy physiology. However, the mechanisms regulating an individual’s motivation to engage in physical activity remain incompletely understood. An important factor stimulating the engagement in both competitive and recreational exercise is the motivating pleasure derived from prolonged physical activity, which is triggered by exercise-induced neurochemical changes in the brain. Here, we report on the discovery of a gut–brain connection in mice that enhances exercise performance by augmenting dopamine signalling during physical activity. We find that microbiome-dependent production of endocannabinoid metabolites in the gut stimulates the activity of TRPV1-expressing sensory neurons and thereby elevates dopamine levels in the ventral striatum during exercise. Stimulation of this pathway improves running performance, whereas microbiome depletion, peripheral endocannabinoid receptor inhibition, ablation of spinal afferent neurons or dopamine blockade abrogate exercise capacity. These findings indicate that the rewarding properties of exercise are influenced by gut-derived interoceptive circuits and provide a microbiome-dependent explanation for interindividual variability in exercise performance. Our study also suggests that interoceptomimetic molecules that stimulate the transmission of gut-derived signals to the brain may enhance the motivation for exercise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gut dysbiosis induces the development of mastitis through a reduction in host anti-inflammatory enzyme activity by endotoxemia</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36451232/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36451232/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Mounting experimental evidence has shown that the gut microbiota plays a significant role in the pathogenesis of mastitis, and clinical investigations have found that the occurrence of mastitis is correlated with ruminal dysbiosis. However, the underlying mechanism by which the ruminal microbiota participates in the development of mastitis remains unknown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; In the present study, we found that cows with clinical mastitis had marked systemic inflammation, which was associated with significant ruminal dysbiosis, especially enriched Proteobacteria in the rumen. Ruminal microbiota transplantation from mastitis cows (M-RMT) to mice induced mastitis symptoms in recipient mice along with increased mammary proinflammatory signature activation of the TLR4-cGAS-STING-NF-κB/NLRP3 pathways. M-RMT also induced mucosal inflammation and impaired intestinal barrier integrity, leading to increased endotoxemia and systemic inflammation. Moreover, we showed that M-RMT mirrored ruminal microbiota disruption in the gut of recipient mice, as evidenced by enriched Proteobacteria and similar bacterial functions, which were correlated with most proinflammatory parameters and serum lipopolysaccharide (LPS) levels in mice. Recurrent low-grade LPS treatment mirrored gut dysbiosis-induced endotoxemia and caused severe mastitis in mice. Furthermore, we found that gut dysbiosis-derived LPS reduced host alkaline phosphatase activity by activating neuraminidase (Neu), which facilitates low-grade LPS exposure and E. coli-induced mastitis in mice. Conversely, treatment with calf intestinal alkaline phosphatase or the Neu inhibitor zanamivir alleviated low-grade LPS exposure and E. coli-induced mastitis in mice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; Our results suggest that ruminal dysbiosis-derived low-grade endotoxemia can cause mastitis and aggravate pathogen-induced mastitis by impairing host anti-inflammatory enzymes, which implies that regulating the ruminal or gut microbiota to prevent low-grade systemic inflammation is a potential strategy for mastitis intervention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The microbiota and the gut-liver axis in primary sclerosing cholangitis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/36352157/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/36352157/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Primary sclerosing cholangitis (PSC) offers unique opportunities to explore the gut-liver axis owing to the close association between liver disease and colonic inflammation. It is well established that the gut microbiota in people with PSC differs from that of healthy individuals, but details of the microbial factors that demarcate PSC from inflammatory bowel disease (IBD) without PSC are poorly understood. In this Review, we aim to provide an overview of the latest literature on the gut microbiome in PSC and PSC with IBD, critically examining hypotheses on how microorganisms could contribute to the pathogenesis of PSC. A particular emphasis will be put on pathogenic features of the gut microbiota that might explain the occurrence of bile duct inflammation and liver disease in the context of IBD, and we postulate the potential existence of a specific yet unknown factor related to the gut-liver axis as causative in PSC. Available data are scrutinized in the perspective of therapeutic approaches related to the gut-liver axis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gut bacteria alleviate smoking-related NASH by degrading gut nicotine</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36261549/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36261549/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tobacco smoking is positively correlated with non-alcoholic fatty liver disease (NAFLD), but the underlying mechanism for this association is unclear. Here we report that nicotine accumulates in the intestine during tobacco smoking and activates intestinal AMPKα. We identify the gut bacterium Bacteroides xylanisolvens as an effective nicotine degrader. Colonization of B.xylanisolvens reduces intestinal nicotine concentrations in nicotine-exposed mice, and it improves nicotine-exacerbated NAFLD progression. Mechanistically, AMPKα promotes the phosphorylation of sphingomyelin phosphodiesterase 3 (SMPD3), stabilizing the latter and therefore increasing intestinal ceramide formation, which contributes to NAFLD progression to non-alcoholic steatohepatitis (NASH). Our results establish a role for intestinal nicotine accumulation in NAFLD progression and reveal an endogenous bacterium in the human intestine with the ability to metabolize nicotine. These findings suggest a possible route to reduce tobacco smoking-exacerbated NAFLD progression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gut microbiota-derived succinate aggravates acute lung injury after intestinal ischemia/reperfusion in mice</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36229053/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36229053/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Introduction:&lt;/em&gt; Acute lung injury (ALI) is a major cause of morbidity and mortality after intestinal ischemia/reperfusion (I/R). Gut microbiota and their metabolic byproducts act as important modulators of the gut-lung axis. This study aimed to define the role of succinate, a key microbiota metabolite, in intestinal I/R-induced ALI progression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; Gut and lung microbiota of mice subjected to intestinal I/R were analysed using 16S rRNA gene sequencing. Succinate level alterations were measured in Germ-free (GF) mice or conventional mice treated with antibiotics. Succinate-induced alveolar macrophage polarisation and its effects on alveolar epithelial apoptosis were evaluated in succinate receptor1 (&lt;em&gt;Sucnr1&lt;/em&gt;)-deficient mice and in murine alveolar macrophages transfected with &lt;em&gt;Sucnr1&lt;/em&gt;-siRNA. Succinate levels were measured in patients undergoing cardiopulmonary bypass, including intestinal I/R.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; Succinate accumulated in lungs after intestinal I/R, and this was associated with an imbalance of succinate-producing and succinate-consuming bacteria in the gut, but not the lungs. Succinate accumulation was absent in GF mice and was reversed by gut microbiota depletion with antibiotics, indicating that gut microbiota are a source of lung succinate. Moreover, succinate promoted alveolar macrophage polarisation, alveolar epithelial apoptosis, and lung injury during intestinal I/R. Conversely, knockdown of &lt;em&gt;Sucnr1&lt;/em&gt; or blockage of SUCNR1 &lt;em&gt;in vitro&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt; reversed the effects of succinate by modulating PI3K-AKT/HIF-1α pathway. Plasma succinate levels significantly correlated with intestinal I/R-related lung injury after cardiopulmonary bypass.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/em&gt; Gut microbiota-derived succinate exacerbates intestinal I/R-induced ALI through SUCNR1-dependent alveolar macrophage polarisation, identifying succinate as a novel target for gut-derived ALI in critically ill patients.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>gutMDisorder v2.0: a comprehensive database for dysbiosis of gut microbiota in phenotypes and interventions</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36215029/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36215029/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gut microbiota plays a significant role in maintaining host health, and conversely, disorders potentially lead to dysbiosis, an imbalance in the composition of the gut microbial community. Intervention approaches, such as medications, diets, and several others, also alter the gut microbiota in either a beneficial or harmful direction. In 2020, the &lt;a href=&#34;http://bio-annotation.cn/gutMDisorder/home.dhtml&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;gutMDisorder&lt;/a&gt; was developed to facilitate researchers in the investigation of dysbiosis of gut microbes as occurs in various disorders as well as with therapeutic interventions. The database has been updated this year, following revision of previous publications and newly published reports to manually integrate confirmed associations under multitudinous conditions. Additionally, the microbial contents of downloaded gut microbial raw sequencing data were annotated, the metadata of the corresponding hosts were manually curated, and the interactive charts were developed to enhance visualization. The improvements have assembled into &lt;a href=&#34;http://bio-annotation.cn/gutMDisorder/home.dhtml&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;gutMDisorder&lt;/a&gt; v2.0, a more advanced search engine and an upgraded web interface.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emergent phases of ecological diversity and dynamics mapped in microcosms</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36201585/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36201585/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Predicting microbial community dynamics&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ecological communities are complex, and their dynamics are difficult to predict. Hu et al. used experimental bacteria communities to show that species richness and the strength of species interactions drive community dynamics (see the Perspective by Huelsmann and Ackermann), as predicted by theory. By manipulating species pool size and nutrient availability (which affects species interactions), the authors found that more complex communities were less stable over time. Furthermore, communities showed distinct phases, shifting from full species coexistence to partial coexistence to dynamic fluctuations as species pool size or interaction strength increased. Communities that fluctuated maintained higher species richness, suggesting that diversity and stability promote one another.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From tropical forests to gut microbiomes, ecological communities host notably high numbers of coexisting species. Beyond high biodiversity, communities exhibit a range of complex dynamics that are difficult to explain under a unified framework. Using bacterial microcosms, we performed a direct test of theory predicting that simple community-level features dictate emergent behaviors of communities. As either the number of species or the strength of interactions increases, we show that microbial ecosystems transition between three distinct dynamical phases, from a stable equilibrium in which all species coexist to partial coexistence to emergence of persistent fluctuations in species abundances, in the order predicted by theory. Under fixed conditions, high biodiversity and fluctuations reinforce each other. Our results demonstrate predictable emergent patterns of diversity and dynamics in ecological communities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alterations in the respiratory tract microbiome in COVID-19: current observations and potential significance</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36195943/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36195943/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SARS-CoV-2 infection causes COVID-19 disease, which can result in consequences ranging from undetectable to fatal, focusing attention on the modulators of outcomes. The respiratory tract microbiome is thought to modulate the outcomes of infections such as influenza as well as acute lung injury, raising the question to what degree does the airway microbiome influence COVID-19? Here, we review the results of 56 studies examining COVID-19 and the respiratory tract microbiome, summarize the main generalizations, and point to useful avenues for further research. Although the results vary among studies, a few consistent findings stand out. The diversity of bacterial communities in the oropharynx typically declined with increasing disease severity. The relative abundance of Haemophilus and Neisseria also declined with severity. Multiple microbiome measures tracked with measures of systemic immune responses and COVID outcomes. For many of the conclusions drawn in these studies, the direction of causality is unknown-did an alteration in the microbiome result in increased COVID severity, did COVID severity alter the microbiome, or was some third factor the primary driver, such as medication use. Follow-up mechanistic studies can help answer these questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gut microbiota-stem cell niche crosstalk: A new territory for maintaining intestinal homeostasis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/imt2.54/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/imt2.54/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Intestinal stem cells (ISCs) are protected by their niche and are regulated by Wnt, bone morphogenetic protein, and Notch.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ISCs and their relationship with intestinal microbiota provide a feasible pathway to alleviate intestinal diseases.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Diverse bacteria-related postbiotics regulate ISCs and maintain their homeostasis.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Intestinal epithelium undergoes rapid cellular turnover, relying on the local niche, to support intestinal stem cells (ISCs) function and self-renewal. Research into the association between ISCs and disease continues to expand at a rapid rate. However, the detailed interaction of ISCs and gut microbes remains to be elucidated. Thus, this review witnessed major advances in the crosstalk between ISCs and gut microbes, delivering key insights into (1) construction of ISC niche and molecular mechanism of how to jointly govern epithelial homeostasis and protect against intestinal diseases with the participation of Wnt, bone morphogenetic protein, and Notch; (2) differentiation fate of ISCs affect the gut microbiota. Meanwhile, the presence of intestinal microbes also regulates ISC function; (3) microbiota regulation on ISCs by Wnt and Notch signals through pattern recognition receptors; (4) how do specific microbiota-related postbiotics influence ISCs to maintain intestinal epithelial regeneration and homeostasis that provide insights into a promising alternative therapeutic method for intestinal diseases. Considering the detailed interaction is still unclear, it is necessary to further explore the regulatory role of gut microbiota on ISCs to utilize microbes to alleviate gut disorders. Furthermore, these major advances collectively drive us ever closer to breakthroughs in regenerative medicine and cancer treatment by microbial transplantation in the clinic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intestinal Microbiota-derived Propionic Acid Protects against Zinc Oxide Nanoparticle-induced Lung Injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36150095/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36150095/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the rapid development of nanotechnology, the risks of accidental and/or occupational exposure to zinc oxide nanoparticles (ZnONPs) are increasing. Inhalation of ZnONPs induces metal fume fever in humans and acute lung injury (ALI) in animal models. Although the intestinal microbiota is considered an important modulator of various diseases, the role and mechanism of intestinal microbiota in the pathology of ZnONP-induced ALI are unclear. Herein, we established an intratracheal instillation of a ZnONP-induced ALI mouse model and found that the inhalation of ZnONPs caused ALI along with a perturbation of intestinal flora. Antibiotic cocktail treatment-mediated depletion of intestinal microbiota aggravated ZnONP-induced ALI, and in contrast, fecal microbiota transplantation-mediated restoration of intestinal microbiota exerted the opposite effects. A decrease in short-chain fatty acids, the intestinal microbiota-derived metabolites in the plasma-in particular, acetic acid and propionic acid-occurred after exposure to ZnONPs. It is important to note that supplementation with propionic acid, but not acetic acid, ameliorated ZnONP-induced ALI. We also showed that the source of inflammatory cytokines might partially be the infiltration of macrophages. Supplementation with propionic acid was found to act on macrophages through the receptor GPR43, because knockdown of GPR43 sharply reversed the protective effects of propionic acid during the ZnONP-induced inflammatory response and oxidative stress in both primary alveolar macrophages and RAW 264.7 macrophage cell lines. Altogether, a novel gut-lung axis mechanism is revealed in which intestinal microbiota and their derived metabolite propionic acid play protective roles against ZnONP-induced ALI and suggest that fecal microbiota transplantation and supplementation with propionic acid are potential remedy strategies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Probiotics ameliorates pulmonary inflammation via modulating gut microbiota and rectifying Th17/Treg imbalance in a rat model of PM2.5 induced lung injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36115151/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36115151/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PM2.5 exposure altered gut microbiome and influences the balance of Th17/Treg cell.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The changes of gut microbiome and the imbalance of Th17/Treg cell are critical mechanism of PM2.5-induced lung injury in rats.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The administration of Probiotics regulating Th17/Treg cell balance and gut microbiome attenuates PM2.5-induced lung injury in rats.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The imbalance of intestinal microbiota and inflammatory response is crucial in the development of lung injury induced by PM2.5. In recent years, probiotics have attracted great attention for their health benefits in inflammatory diseases and regulating intestinal balance, but their intricate mechanisms need further experiments to elucidate. In our research, a rat lung damage model induced by PM2.5 exposure in real environment was established to explore the protective properties of probiotics on PM2.5 exposure injury and its related mechanism. The results indicated that compared with the AF control group, rats in the PM2.5 group gained weight slowly, ate less and had yellow hair. The results of pathological and immunohistochemical examinations showed that the inflammatory infiltration of lung tissue was alleviated after probiotic treatment. The Lung function results also showed the improvement effects of probiotics administration. In addition, probiotics could promote the balance of Th17 and Treg cells, inhibit cytokines expression (TNF-α, IL-6, IL-1β, IL-17A), and increase the concentration of anti-inflammatory factors (IL-10, TGF-β). In addition, 16 S rRNA sequence analysis showed that probiotic treatment could reduce microbiota abundance and diversity, increase the abundance of possible beneficial bacteria, and decrease the abundance of bacteria associated with inflammation. In general, probiotic intervention was found to have preventive effects on the occurrence of PM2.5 induced pathological injury, and the mechanism was associate with to the inhibition of inflammatory response, regulation of Th17/Treg balance and maintenance of intestinal internal environment stability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intestinal microbiota metabolizing Houttuynia cordata polysaccharides in H1N1 induced pneumonia mice contributed to Th17/Treg rebalance in gut-lung axis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36084869/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36084869/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Influenza A virus is intricately linked to dysregulation of gut microbiota and host immunity. Previous study revealed that Houttuynia cordata polysaccharides (HCP) exert the therapeutic effect on influenza A virus inducing lung and intestine damage via regulating pulmonary and intestinal mucosal immunity. However, whether this result was due to the regulation of gut microbiota in the gut-lung axis remains unclear. Here, we firstly found that the elimination of gut microbiota using antibiotic cocktails led to both loss of the protective effect of HCP on intestine and lung injury, and reduction of the efficacy on regulating Th17/Treg balance in gut-lung axis. Fecal microbiota transplantation study confirmed that the gut microbiota fermented with HCP under pathological conditions (H1N1 infection) was responsible for reducing pulmonary and intestinal injury. Moreover, the interaction of HCP and gut microbiota under pathological conditions exhibited not only much more abundant gut microbial diversity, but also higher content of the acetate. Our results demonstrated that the underlying mechanism to ameliorate viral pneumonia in mice involving Th17/Treg rebalance via the gut microbiota and HCP metabolite (acetate) metabolized in pneumonia mice. Our results provided a new insight for macromolecular polysaccharides through targeting intestinal microenvironment reducing distant pulmonary infection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microbiota manipulation to increase macrophage IL-10 improves colitis and limits colitis-associated colorectal cancer</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36062329/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36062329/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inflammatory bowel disease (IBD) is a chronic life-long inflammatory disease affecting almost 2 million Americans. Although new biologic therapies have been developed, the standard medical treatment fails to selectively control the dysregulated immune pathways involved in chronic colonic inflammation. Further, IBD patients with uncontrolled colonic inflammation are at a higher risk for developing colorectal cancer (CRC). Intestinal microbes can impact many immune functions, and here we asked if they could be used to improve intestinal inflammation. By utilizing an intestinal adherent &lt;em&gt;E. coli&lt;/em&gt; that we find increases IL-10 producing macrophages, we were able to limit intestinal inflammation and restrict tumor formation. Macrophage IL-10 along with IL-10 signaling to the intestinal epithelium were required for protection in both inflammation and tumor development. Our work highlights that administration of immune modulating microbes can improve intestinal outcomes by altering tissue inflammation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tonsillar Microbiome-Derived Lantibiotics Induce Structural Changes of IL-6 and IL-21 Receptors and Modulate Host Immunity</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36031409/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36031409/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Emerging evidence emphasizes the functional impacts of host microbiome on the etiopathogenesis of autoimmune diseases, including rheumatoid arthritis (RA). However, there are limited mechanistic insights into the contribution of microbial biomolecules especially microbial peptides toward modulating immune homeostasis. Here, by mining the metagenomics data of tonsillar microbiome, a deficiency of the encoding genes of lantibiotic peptides salivaricins in RA patients is identified, which shows strong correlation with circulating immune cells. Evidence is provided that the salivaricins exert immunomodulatory effects in inhibiting T follicular helper (Tfh) cell differentiation and interleukin-21 (IL-21) production. Mechanically, salivaricins directly bind to and induce conformational changes of IL-6 and IL-21 receptors, thereby inhibiting the bindings of IL-6 and IL-21 to their receptors and suppressing the downstream signaling pathway. Finally, salivaricin administration exerts both prophylactic and therapeutic effects against experimental arthritis in a murine model of RA. Together, these results provide a mechanism link of microbial peptides-mediated immunomodulation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Effect of invasive mechanical ventilation on the diversity of the pulmonary microbiota</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/35996150/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/35996150/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pulmonary microbial diversity may be influenced by biotic or abiotic conditions (e.g., disease, smoking, invasive mechanical ventilation (MV), etc.). Specially, invasive MV may trigger structural and physiological changes in both tissue and microbiota of lung, due to gastric and oral microaspiration, altered body posture, high O&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; inhalation-induced O&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; toxicity in hypoxemic patients, impaired airway clearance and ventilator-induced lung injury (VILI), which in turn reduce the diversity of the pulmonary microbiota and may ultimately lead to poor prognosis. Furthermore, changes in (local) O&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; concentration can reduce the diversity of the pulmonary microbiota by affecting the local immune microenvironment of lung. In conclusion, systematic literature studies have found that invasive MV reduces pulmonary microbiota diversity, and future rational regulation of pulmonary microbiota diversity by existing or novel clinical tools (e.g., lung probiotics, drugs) may improve the prognosis of invasive MV treatment and lead to more effective treatment of lung diseases with precision.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Antibiotic-induced microbiome depletion improves LPS-induced acute lung injury via gut-lung axis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35981631/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35981631/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Aims:&lt;/em&gt; Acute lung injury (ALI) is an acute inflammatory disorder. However, the precise mechanisms underlying the pathology of ALI remain elusive. An increasing evidence suggests the role of the gut-microbiota axis in the pathology of lung injury. This study aimed to investigate whether antibiotic-induced microbiome depletion could affect ALI in mice after lipopolysaccharide (LPS) administration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Main methods:&lt;/em&gt; The effects of antibiotic cocktail (ABX) on ALI in the mice after intratracheally administration of LPS (5 mg/kg) were examined. Furthermore, 16s rRNA analysis and measurement of short-chain fatty acids in feces samples and metabolomics analysis of blood samples were performed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Key findings:&lt;/em&gt; LPS significantly increased the interleukin-6 (IL-6) levels in the bronchoalveolar lavage fluid (BALF) of water-treated mice. Interestingly, an ABX significantly attenuated the LPS-induced increase in IL-6 in BALF and lung injury scores. Furthermore, ABX and/or LPS treatment markedly altered the α- and β-diversity of the gut microbiota. There were significant differences in the α- and β-diversity of the water + LPS group and ABX + LPS group. LEfSe analysis identified &lt;em&gt;Enterococusfaecalis&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Clostriumtertium&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Bacteroidescaecimyris&lt;/em&gt; as potential microbial markers for ABX + LPS group. Untargeted metabolomics analysis identified several plasma metabolites responsible for discriminating water + LPS group from ABX + LPS group. There were correlations between the relative abundance of the microbiome and plasma metabolites. Integrative network analysis showed correlations between IL-6 levels in BALF and several gut microbes (or plasma metabolites).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Significance:&lt;/em&gt; These data suggest that ABX-induced microbiome depletion could protect against LPS-induced ALI via the gut-microbiota-lung axis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chlorogenic Acid Prevents Hyperuricemia Nephropathy via Regulating TMAO-Related Gut Microbes and Inhibiting the PI3K/AKT/mTOR Pathway</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35950815/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35950815/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hyperuricemia is an independent hazard factor of renal injury and can induce renal fibrosis, promoting the development of chronic kidney disease (CKD). This study aimed to explore the probability of chlorogenic acid (CGA) as a potential substance for preventing hyperuricemia nephropathy (HN). Pretreatment with CGA downregulated SUA, BUN, and CR levels, relieved oxidative stress and inflammatory response, alleviated kidney fibrosis, and contributed to the prevention of HN. In the gut microbiota, &lt;em&gt;Blautia&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Enterococcus&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Faecalibaculum&lt;/em&gt; related to trimethylamine N-oxide (TMAO) synthesis were significantly increased in HN rats. In addition, it showed a significant increase in serum TMAO content in HN rats. However, CGA regulated the cascade response of the microbiota-TMAO signaling to reverse the increase of serum TMAO. CGA also decreased the protein expression of protein kinase B (AKT) phosphorylation, phosphatidylinositide 3-kinase (PI3K), and mammalian target of rapamycin (mTOR) by reducing the production of TMAO. CGA delayed kidney fibrosis in HN rats as evidenced by regulating the cascade response of the microbiota-TMAO-PI3K/AKT/mTOR signaling pathway. In summary, CGA can be an excellent candidate for HN prevention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integrated metagenomic and metabolomic analysis reveals distinct gut-microbiome-derived phenotypes in early-onset colorectal cancer</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35953094/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35953094/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Objective:&lt;/em&gt; The incidence of early-onset colorectal cancer (EO-CRC) is steadily increasing. Here, we aimed to characterise the interactions between gut microbiome, metabolites and microbial enzymes in EO-CRC patients and evaluate their potential as non-invasive biomarkers for EO-CRC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Design:&lt;/em&gt; We performed metagenomic and metabolomic analyses, identified multiomics markers and constructed CRC classifiers for the discovery cohort with 130 late-onset CRC (LO-CRC), 114 EO-CRC subjects and age-matched healthy controls (97 LO-Control and 100 EO-Control). An independent cohort of 38 LO-CRC, 24 EO-CRC, 22 LO-Controls and 24 EO-Controls was analysed to validate the results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; Compared with controls, reduced alpha-diversity was apparent in both, LO-CRC and EO-CRC subjects. Although common variations existed, integrative analyses identified distinct microbiome-metabolome associations in LO-CRC and EO-CRC. &lt;em&gt;Fusobacterium nucleatum&lt;/em&gt; enrichment and short-chain fatty acid depletion, including reduced microbial GABA biosynthesis and a shift in acetate/acetaldehyde metabolism towards acetyl-CoA production characterises LO-CRC. In comparison, multiomics signatures of EO-CRC tended to be associated with enriched &lt;em&gt;Flavonifractor plauti&lt;/em&gt; and increased tryptophan, bile acid and choline metabolism. Notably, elevated red meat intake-related species, choline metabolites and KEGG orthology (KO) pldB and cbh gene axis may be potential tumour stimulators in EO-CRC. The predictive model based on metagenomic, metabolomic and KO gene markers achieved a powerful classification performance for distinguishing EO-CRC from controls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/em&gt; Our large-sample multiomics data suggest that altered microbiome-metabolome interplay helps explain the pathogenesis of EO-CRC and LO-CRC. The potential of microbiome-derived biomarkers as promising non-invasive tools could be used for the accurate detection and distinction of individuals with EO-CRC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cangma Huadu granules attenuate H1N1 virus-induced severe lung injury correlated with repressed apoptosis and altered gut microbiome</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36090063/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36090063/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Severe influenza A virus infection leads to overwhelming inflammatory responses and cellular apoptosis, which causes lung injury and contributes to high mortality and morbidity. The gut microbiome altered in response to the infection might influence the disease progression and the treatment outcome. Cangma Huadu (CMHD) granules, an in-hospital preparation of traditional Chinese medicine, have been shown to be favorable in the clinical treatment of influenza. However, the effects and mechanisms of CMHD granules on severe influenza pneumonia and its mechanisms are not well-known. In this study, a lethal influenza A (H1N1) A/Puerto Rico/8/34 virus (PR8)-infected mice model was established, and the 16S ribosomal RNA (16S rRNA) V3-V4 region sequencing of the intestinal microbiome was conducted. We revealed that the oral administration of CMHD granules protects mice against higher mortality, enhanced weight loss, overwhelmed interferon-γ concentration, lung viral titers, and severe lung pathological injury in PR8-infected mice. CMHD granules&amp;rsquo; administration downregulated the levels of interleukin (IL)-1β, tumor necrosis factor-α, and malondialdehyde, while it upregulated the levels of IL-10, superoxide dismutase, and glutathione peroxidase. Subsequently, it decreased the protein ratio of B-cell lymphoma-2/Bcl-2-associated X and the expression of cleaved caspase-3. The diversity and compositions of the gut microbes were altered profoundly after the administration of CMHD granules in PR8-infected mice. A higher abundance of &lt;em&gt;Bifidobacterium&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Parasutterella&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Bacteroides&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Faecalibaculum&lt;/em&gt; was observed in the CMHD group, and a higher abundance of &lt;em&gt;Lactobacillus&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Turicibacter&lt;/em&gt; was observed in the positive drug Ribavirin group. The linear discriminant analysis effect size also revealed a higher proportion of &lt;em&gt;Bacteroides&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Bifidobacterium_pseudolongum&lt;/em&gt; characterized in the CMHD group. These results demonstrated that CMHD granules are a promising strategy for managing severe influenza and attenuating severe lung damage via reducing viral titer, inflammatory responses, and oxidative stress. The mechanisms are involved in repressed Bcl-2-regulated apoptosis and altered composition and diversity of the gut microbiome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microbiota succession throughout life from the cradle to the grave</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/35906422/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/35906422/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Associations between age and the human microbiota are robust and reproducible. The microbial composition at several body sites can predict human chronological age relatively accurately. Although it is largely unknown why specific microorganisms are more abundant at certain ages, human microbiota research has elucidated a series of microbial community transformations that occur between birth and death. In this Review, we explore microbial succession in the healthy human microbiota from the cradle to the grave. We discuss the stages from primary succession at birth, to disruptions by disease or antibiotic use, to microbial expansion at death. We address how these successions differ by body site and by domain (bacteria, fungi or viruses). We also review experimental tools that microbiota researchers use to conduct this work. Finally, we discuss future directions for studying the microbiota&amp;rsquo;s relationship with age, including designing consistent, well-powered, longitudinal studies, performing robust statistical analyses and improving characterization of non-bacterial microorganisms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advances and challenges in cataloging the human gut virome</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/35834962/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/35834962/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The human gut virome, which is often referred to as the &amp;ldquo;dark matter&amp;rdquo; of the gut microbiome, remains understudied. A better understanding of the composition and variations of the gut virome across populations is critical for exploring its impact on diseases and health. A series of advances in the characterization of human gut virome have unveiled high genetic diversity and various functional potentials of gut viruses. Here, we summarize the recently available human gut virome databases and discuss their features, procedures, and challenges with the intention to provide a reference to researchers to use while choosing a profiling database. We also propose a &amp;ldquo;best practice&amp;rdquo; for cataloging the viral population.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Summary of microbiome databases</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tool/2022-07-10-db-microbiome/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/tool/2022-07-10-db-microbiome/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.dsmz.de/collection/catalogue/microorganisms/special-groups-of-organisms/dzif-sammlung/maus-mikrobiomliste&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;mouse intestinal Bacterial Collection (miBC)&lt;/a&gt;  is an initiative from the RTWH Aachen (Prof. Thomas Clavel) and the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.dsmz.de/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Leibniz-Institute DSMZ-German Collection of Microorganisms and Cell Cultures&lt;/a&gt;. It is supported by Collaborative Research Centre (CRC) 1371 and CRC1382 and by the German Federal Ministry of Science and Education through the German Center of Infection Research (DZIF). This collection includes bacterial strains isolated from the intestine of mice. They have been taxonomically described and are all publicly available. This well-curated resource was built to increase our knowledge of cultured diversity within the mouse gut microbiota and to support scientists with their own research by providing multiple strains representing a broad phylogenetic diversity to be used for functional experiments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://bio-annotation.cn/gutMDisorder/home.dhtml&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;gutMDisorder&lt;/a&gt; is a comprehensive resource for associations between gut microbes and phenotypes or interventions in Human and Mouse, derived from manual literature extraction and raw data reprocessing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Microbiome and its metabolites are closely associated with human health and diseases. However, it is challenging to understand the complex interplay between microbiome and metabolites. &lt;a href=&#34;http://metorigin.met-bioinformatics.cn/home/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;MetOrigin&lt;/a&gt; is a bioinformatics tool, aiming to identify which bacteria and how they participate in certain metabolic reactions, helping us to understand where metabolites come from: host, bacteria, or both?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://gmrepo.humangut.info/home&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;GMrepo&lt;/a&gt; is a curated database of consistently annotated human gut metagenomes. So far &lt;a href=&#34;https://gmrepo.humangut.info/home&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;GMrepo&lt;/a&gt; contains 71,642 human gut runs/samples from 353 projects; they are associated with 132 human phenotypes. Its main features include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;extensive manual curation of meta-data of gut samples/runs,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;grouping samples/runs according to their associated human phenotypes (i.e. health and diseases),&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;graphical selectors enabling easy and efficient access to all our collected data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently numerous studies have identified that the perturbations in the gut microbiome were associated with human health, including diseases and cancers, even mental health. The recent development of high-throughput sequencing based metagenomics technologies such as 16S ribosomal RNA gene amplicon-based and genome-centric approaches have burst the profiling of the landscape for gut microbiome and the identification of human health related microbes. Here, we presented the &lt;a href=&#34;http://gutmega.omicsbio.info/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;gutMEGA&lt;/a&gt; database, which hosted the results of metagenomics studies. In total, 59,132 quantification events for 6,457 taxa at 7 different levels (kingdom, phylum, class, order, family, genus and species) under 776 conditions were collected and integrated in the database, and the details about the samples and experiments were also curated. Various browse and search options were provided in the database, and the detailed information was organized and visualized for queries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://bio-annotation.cn/gutmgene/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;gutMGene&lt;/a&gt; is a comprehensive database for target genes of gut microbes and microbial metabolites. Metagenomic sequencing of fecal samples has identified 3.3×10&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt; non-redundant microbial genes from up to 1,500 different species. One of the contributions of gut microbiota to host biology is the circulating pool of bacterially derived small-molecule metabolites. It has been estimated that 10% of metabolites found in mammalian blood are derived from the gut microbiota, where they can produce systemic effects on the host through activating or inhibiting gene expression. Currently, detailed information on target genes of gut microbes and microbial metabolites is scattered in literatures and no online repository is available for collecting these data. Here, we manually extracted microbe-metabolite, microbe-target, and metabolite-target relationships in Human and Mouse from almost 400 publications. All of these relationships were experimentally validated in vivo or in vitro and measured by RT-qPCR, high performance liquid chromatography, 16S rRNA sequence, and so on. Currently, users can:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://bio-annotation.cn/gutmgene/resource.dhtml&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Download&lt;/a&gt; all manually curated relationships.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Achieve relationships by &lt;em&gt;browsing&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;searching&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Submit&lt;/em&gt; novel relationships to the &lt;a href=&#34;http://bio-annotation.cn/gutmgene/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;gutMGene&lt;/a&gt; database.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Taxonomic and functional research of microorganisms has increasingly relied upon genome-based data and methods. As the depository of the Global Catalogue of Microorganisms (GCM) 10K prokaryotic type strain sequencing project, &lt;a href=&#34;http://gctype.wdcm.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Global Catalogue of Type Strain (gcType)&lt;/a&gt; has published 1049 type strain genomes sequenced by the GCM 10K project which are preserved in global culture collections with a valid published status. Additionally, the information provided through &lt;a href=&#34;http://gctype.wdcm.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;gcType&lt;/a&gt; includes &amp;gt;12 000 publicly available type strain genome sequences from GenBank incorporated using quality control criteria and standard data annotation pipelines to form a high-quality reference database. This database integrates type strain sequences with their phenotypic information to facilitate phenotypic and genotypic analyses. Multiple formats of cross-genome searches and interactive interfaces have allowed extensive exploration of the database&amp;rsquo;s resources. In this study, we describe web-based data analysis pipelines for genomic analyses and genome-based taxonomy, which could serve as a one-stop platform for the identification of prokaryotic species. The number of type strain genomes that are published will continue to increase as the GCM 10K project increases its collaboration with culture collections worldwide. Data of this project is shared with the International Nucleotide Sequence Database Collaboration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://disbiome.ugent.be/home&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Disbiome&lt;/a&gt; is a database covering microbial composition changes in different kinds of diseases, managed by Ghent University. Disease names, detection methods or organism names can be used as search queries giving you all information related to the experiment (related disease/bacteria, abundancy subject/control, control type, detection method and related literature).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.vmh.life/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Virtual Metabolic Human (VMH)&lt;/a&gt; database captures information on human and gut microbial metabolism and links this information to hundreds of diseases and nutritional data. At its core, there are hundreds of manually curated genome-scale metabolic reconstructions, which have been assembled based on genomic, biochemical, and physiological data. The &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.vmh.life/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;VMH&lt;/a&gt; facilitates rapid analyses and interpretations of complex data arising from large-scale biomedical studies by enabling complex queries of its content, by providing a detailed graphical representation of human metabolism, and by distributing computational models for simulating human and microbial metabolism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dianalab.e-ce.uth.gr/peryton/#/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Peryton&lt;/a&gt; constitutes a novel resource of experimentally supported microbe-disease associations, currently hosting more than 7,900 entries linking 43 diseases and 1,396 microorganisms. &lt;a href=&#34;https://dianalab.e-ce.uth.gr/peryton/#/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Peryton&lt;/a&gt;’s content is exclusively sustained by manual curation of biomedical articles. Importantly, diseases and microorganisms are provided in a systematic, standardized manner using reference resources to create database dictionaries. Information about the experimental design, study cohorts and the applied high- or low-throughput techniques are meticulously annotated and catered to users. Extensive details regarding bacterial abundance, the groups under study (including their sex ratio and their size) and article metadata are available for each entry. A number of functionalities are provided to enhance user experience and enable ingenious use of &lt;a href=&#34;https://dianalab.e-ce.uth.gr/peryton/#/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Peryton&lt;/a&gt;. One or more microorganisms and/or diseases can be queried at the same time. Advanced filtering options and direct text-based filtering of results enable refinement of returned information and the conducting of tailored queries suitable to different research questions. Results can be directly downloaded as tab-separated files for local storage and downstream analyses. &lt;a href=&#34;https://dianalab.e-ce.uth.gr/peryton/#/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Peryton&lt;/a&gt; also provides to users’ interactive visualizations to effectively capture different aspects of its content. Via Network graphs, Chord diagrams and Hierarchy Diagrams users can browse into the available content and perform observations about microbe-disease relationships using information from the latest relevant literature. &lt;a href=&#34;https://dianalab.e-ce.uth.gr/peryton/#/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Peryton&lt;/a&gt;’s content in numbers:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2,918 gastrointestinal disease associations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4,065 cancer-related associations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;869 neurodegenerative disorder associations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;125 cardiovascular disease associations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1,718 entries providing information at species level or below&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3,777 entries comparing a disease group against healthy individuals and 4,200 comparing disease states&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Accumulating evidence about the interaction between human microbiota and therapeutic-related substances, especially for clinical used drugs, deepens and broadens our understanding in the role of &amp;ldquo;our second genome&amp;rdquo; in human health and diseases, and opens a new window for managing/treating human healthy problems/diseases by manipulating microbiota-human interactions. A centralized and standardized database to catalog Microbiota-Active Substances Interactions (MASIs) will be very useful for related research fields, including microbiota-related pharmaceutical research, food and nutrition research, clinical pharmacy, health management studies. Here, the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.aiddlab.com/MASI/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;MASI&lt;/a&gt; database is developed to cater this urgent need by providing manually curated MASIs data from scientific literature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://leb.snu.ac.kr/amdb&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Animal Microbiome Database (AMDB)&lt;/a&gt; is a database covering bacterial 16S rRNA gene profiles from various animal species to assess the relationship between the gut microbiota and animal hosts. We collected 2,530 samples from 34 public projects with manually curated metadata. Currently, &lt;a href=&#34;http://leb.snu.ac.kr/amdb&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;AMDB&lt;/a&gt; contains 10,478 bacterial taxa from 467 animal species. Please refer to our paper for detailed analysis methods. &lt;a href=&#34;http://leb.snu.ac.kr/amdb&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;AMDB&lt;/a&gt; provides four main functions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Taxa: It shows samples enriched with the bacterial taxon of interest.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Samples: It provides the gut microbiota composition of the sample of interest.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Projects/Hosts: It gives you summary information for the project or the host.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Visualization: It visually presents valuable information about the relationships between the samples and the gut microbiota.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/tag/databases/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Databases&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/tool/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Tools &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lactiplantibacillus plantarum 0111 Protects Against Influenza Virus by Modulating Intestinal Microbial-Mediated Immune Responses</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35847111/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35847111/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are some limitations of traditional influenza vaccines concerning novel mutant strains. Therefore, it is particularly important to develop preventive means for antigen-unrelated types of influenza viruses. Recent studies have shown that probiotics can modulate the immune system and reduce the severity of viral infections. In this study, we investigated the potential of &lt;em&gt;Lactiplantibacillus plantarum&lt;/em&gt; 0111 against influenza virus H9N2. Challenge experiments showed that &lt;em&gt;L. plantarum&lt;/em&gt; 0111 pretreatments could effectively improve mice&amp;rsquo;s survival rate and weight loss and reduce the inflammatory cytokines IL-6 and TNF-α in the lungs and bronchoalveolar lavage fluid (BALF) along with the degree of lung and intestinal injury. FMT experiment demonstrates that the protective effect produced by &lt;em&gt;L. plantarum&lt;/em&gt; 0111 is associated with gut microorganisms. In addition, 16S high-throughput sequencing of the mouse intestinal microbiota showed that &lt;em&gt;L. plantarum&lt;/em&gt; 0111 remodeled the intestinal microbiota after H9N2 infection and maintained the gut microbiota balance. In a mouse model, the oral administration of &lt;em&gt;L. plantarum&lt;/em&gt; 0111 increased IFN-β expression in the serum and BALF. At the same time, the transcript levels of IFN-β and related ISGs in the intestine and lungs of mice were also increased. In addition, the activation and polarization of T cells in mesenteric lymph nodes (MLNs) and the spleen were detected by flow cytometry, and the results showed that &lt;em&gt;L. plantarum&lt;/em&gt; 0111 modulated cytokines in T cells and increased IgA expression in B cells in the MLNs and spleen. Thus, &lt;em&gt;L. plantarum&lt;/em&gt; 0111 may improve gut microbiota-mediated immune responses and thus, resist infection by the influenza virus, and it could be used as an effective preventive measure against the influenza virus.
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The gut-lung axis in severe acute Pancreatitis-associated lung injury: The protection by the gut microbiota through short-chain fatty acids</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/35752356/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/35752356/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The role of gut microbiota in regulating the intestinal homeostasis, as well as the pathogenesis of severe acute pancreatitis-associated lung injury (PALI) is widely recognized. The bioactive functions of metabolites with small molecule weight and the detail molecular mechanisms of PALI mediated by &amp;ldquo;gut-lung axis&amp;rdquo; have gradually raised the attentions of researchers. Several studies have proved that short-chain fatty acids (SCFAs) produced by gut microbiome play crucial roles and varied activities in the process of PALI. However, relevant reviews reporting SCFAs in the involvement of PALI is lacking. In this review, we firstly introduced the synthetic and metabolic pathways of SCFAs, as well as the transport and signal transduction routes in brief. Afterwards, we focused on the possible mechanisms and clues of SCFAs to participate in the fight against PALI which referred to the inhibition of pathogen proliferation, anti-inflammatory effects, enhancement of intestinal barrier functions, and the maintenance and regulation of immune homeostasis via pathogen-associated molecular patterns (PAMPs) and damage-associated molecular patterns (DAMPs). In addition, the latest reported pathological and physiological mechanisms of the gut-lung axis involved in PALI were reviewed. Finally, we summarized the potential therapeutic interventions of PALI by targeting SCFAs, including dietary fiber supplementation, direct supplementation of SCFAs/prebiotics/probiotics, and drugs administration, which is expected to provide new sights for clinical use in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The human lung microbiome—A hidden link between microbes and human health and diseases</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/imt2.33/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/imt2.33/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once thought to be sterile, the human lung is now well recognized to harbor a consortium of microorganisms collectively known as the lung microbiome. The lung microbiome is altered in an array of lung diseases, including chronic lung diseases such as chronic obstructive pulmonary disease, asthma, and bronchiectasis, acute lung diseases caused by pneumonia, sepsis, and COVID-19, and other lung complications such as those related to lung transplantation, lung cancer, and human immunodeficiency virus. The effects of lung microbiome in modulating host immunity and inflammation in the lung and distal organs are being elucidated. However, the precise mechanism by which members of microbiota produce structural ligands that interact with host genes and pathways remains largely uncharacterized. Multiple unique challenges, both technically and biologically, exist in the field of lung microbiome, necessitating the development of tailored experimental and analytical approaches to overcome the bottlenecks. In this review, we first provide an overview of the principles and methodologies in studying the lung microbiome. We next review current knowledge of the roles of lung microbiome in human diseases, highlighting mechanistic insights. We finally discuss critical challenges in the field and share our thoughts on broad topics for future investigation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intestinal Microbiota - An Unmissable Bridge to Severe Acute Pancreatitis-Associated Acute Lung Injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/35774796/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/35774796/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Severe acute pancreatitis (SAP), one of the most serious abdominal emergencies in general surgery, is characterized by acute and rapid onset as well as high mortality, which often leads to multiple organ failure (MOF). Acute lung injury (ALI), the earliest accompanied organ dysfunction, is the most common cause of death in patients following the SAP onset. The exact pathogenesis of ALI during SAP, however, remains unclear. In recent years, advances in the microbiota-gut-lung axis have led to a better understanding of SAP-associated lung injury (PALI). In addition, the bidirectional communications between intestinal microbes and the lung are becoming more apparent. This paper aims to review the mechanisms of an imbalanced intestinal microbiota contributing to the development of PALI, which is mediated by the disruption of physical, chemical, and immune barriers in the intestine, promotes bacterial translocation, and results in the activation of abnormal immune responses in severe pancreatitis. The pathogen-associated molecular patterns (PAMPs) mediated immunol mechanisms in the occurrence of PALI via binding with pattern recognition receptors (PRRs) through the microbiota-gut-lung axis are focused in this study. Moreover, the potential therapeutic strategies for alleviating PALI by regulating the composition or the function of the intestinal microbiota are discussed in this review. The aim of this study is to provide new ideas and therapeutic tools for PALI patients.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ggClusterNet: An R package for microbiome network analysis and modularity-based multiple network layouts</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/imt2.32/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/imt2.32/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ggClusterNet is an R package for microbial networks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Analysis functions could help the user to easily complete network analysis and interpretation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ten network layout algorithms allow users more alternatives to plot the network and generate published-ready figures.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It is free to access on GitHub and Gitee.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The network analysis has attracted increasing attention and interest from ecological academics, thus it is of great necessity to develop more convenient and powerful tools. For that reason, we have developed an R package, named “ggClusterNet,” to complete and display the network analysis in an easier manner. In that package, ten network layout algorithms are designed to better display the modules of microbiome network (randomClusterG, PolygonClusterG, PolygonRrClusterG, ArtifCluster, randSNEClusterG, PolygonModsquareG, PolyRdmNotdCirG, model_Gephi.2, model_igraph, and model_maptree). For the convenience of the users, many functions related to microbial network analysis, such as corMicor(), net_properties(), node_properties(), ZiPiPlot(), random_Net_compate(), are integrated to complete the network mining. Furthermore, the pipeline function named network.2() and corBionetwork() are also added for the quick achievement of the network or bipartite network analysis as well as their in-depth mining. The ggClusterNet is publicly available via &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/taowenmicro/ggClusterNet/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://gitee.com/wentaomicro/ggClusterNet&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Gitee&lt;/a&gt; for users&amp;rsquo; access. A complete description of the usages can be found on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/taowenmicro/ggClusterNet/wiki&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;manuscript&amp;rsquo;s GitHub page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The regulatory effect of fermented black barley on the gut microbiota and metabolic dysbiosis in mice exposed to cigarette smoke</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35761699/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35761699/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Lactobacillus&lt;/em&gt; kisonensisfermented black barley could alleviate the harmful effects of cigarette smoking in mice.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The beneficial effect of fermented black barley may attribute to its regulation on gut microbiota dysbiosis. 3.Fermented black barley could also regulate the metabolic dysbiosis of lipids, amino acids, vitamin, and steroid hormones.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Smoking is a global public health event that can cause oxidative stress and gut microbiota dysbiosis and is related to the occurrence of diseases such as cancer and respiratory system disease. We previously found that fermented black barley was rich in antioxidative components such as polyphenols and flavonoids and regulated gut microbiota dysbiosis. In the present study, the protective effects of fermented black barley on cigarette smoke-induced damage, such as lung, reproduction organ injury, gut microbiota and metabolic dysbiosis, were investigated. Fermented black barley (100 μL/10 g·BW per day, containing 1 × 10&lt;sup&gt;8&lt;/sup&gt; CFU/mL &lt;em&gt;Lactobacillus&lt;/em&gt;) was administered orally to male ICR mice that were regularly exposed to cigarette smoke (one time a day, 15 cigarettes each time, 30 min/time). The intervention lasted continuously for 12 weeks. The results showed that compared to the group exposed only to cigarette smoke, fermented black barley treatment alleviated the pathological damage to lung and testis tissues and significantly increased the total sperm motility and antioxidative capacity of the lung. Fermented black barley also regulated the intestinal microbiome diversity; reduced the relative abundances of &lt;em&gt;Lactobacillus&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Turicibacter&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Bifidobacterium&lt;/em&gt;; and increased the relative abundances of &lt;em&gt;Oscillospira&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Ruminococcus&lt;/em&gt; at the genus level. Furthermore, the metabolic profile was investigated via analysis of the abundances of fecal and hepatic metabolites, and it was shown that fermented black barley treatment alleviated the metabolic dysbiosis of lipids, amino acids, and the biosynthesis of steroid hormones (such as dehydroepiandrosterone sulfate, etc.) induced by cigarette smoking, which approached normal conditions. These regulatory effects may partially elucidate the beneficial role of fermented black barley in alleviating the harmful effects of cigarette smoking. In summary, supplementation with fermented cereal food may be a helpful way to ameliorate cigarette smoking-induced damage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MIntO: A Modular and Scalable Pipeline For Microbiome Metagenomic and Metatranscriptomic Data Integration</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36304282/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36304282/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Omics technologies have revolutionized microbiome research allowing the characterization of complex microbial communities in different biomes without requiring their cultivation. As a consequence, there has been a great increase in the generation of omics data from metagenomes and metatranscriptomes. However, pre-processing and analysis of these data have been limited by the availability of computational resources, bioinformatics expertise and standardized computational workflows to obtain consistent results that are comparable across different studies. Here, we introduce MIntO (Microbiome Integrated meta-Omics), a highly versatile pipeline that integrates metagenomic and metatranscriptomic data in a scalable way. The distinctive feature of this pipeline is the computation of gene expression profile through integrating metagenomic and metatranscriptomic data taking into account the community turnover and gene expression variations to disentangle the mechanisms that shape the metatranscriptome across time and between conditions. The modular design of MIntO enables users to run the pipeline using three available modes based on the input data and the experimental design, including de novo assembly leading to metagenome-assembled genomes. The integrated pipeline will be relevant to provide unique biochemical insights into microbial ecology by linking functions to retrieved genomes and to examine gene expression variation. Functional characterization of community members will be crucial to increase our knowledge of the microbiome&amp;rsquo;s contribution to human health and environment. MIntO v1.0.1 is available at &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/arumugamlab/MIntO&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MetOrigin: Discriminating the origins of microbial metabolites for integrative analysis of the gut microbiome and metabolome</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/imt2.10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/imt2.10/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The interactions between the gut microbiome and metabolome play an important role in human health and diseases. Current studies mainly apply statistical correlation analysis between the gut microbiome and all the identified metabolites to explore their relationship. However, it remains challenging to identify the specific metabolic functions of microbes without in vitro culture experiments for validation. Discriminating the microbial metabolites from others (e.g., host, food, or environment) and exploring their metabolic functions and correlations with microbiome specifically may improve the efficiency and accuracy of biomarker discovery. So far, there have been no such bioinformatics tools available. Herein, we developed &lt;a href=&#34;http://metorigin.met-bioinformatics.cn/home/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;MetOrigin&lt;/a&gt;, an interactive web server that discriminates metabolites originating from the microbiome, performs the origin-based metabolic pathway enrichment analysis, and integrates the statistical correlations and biological relationships in the database using Sankey network visualization. &lt;a href=&#34;http://metorigin.met-bioinformatics.cn/home/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;MetOrigin&lt;/a&gt; not only enables the quick identification of microbial metabolites and their metabolic functions but also facilitates the discovery of specific bacterial species that are closely associated with metabolites statistically and biologically.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intestinal butyrate-metabolizing species contribute to autoantibody production and bone erosion in rheumatoid arthritis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35148177/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35148177/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The imbalance between pathogenic and beneficial species of the intestinal microbiome and metabolism in rheumatoid arthritis (RA) remains unclarified. Here, using shotgun-based metagenome sequencing for a treatment-naïve patient cohort and a &amp;ldquo;quasi-paired cohort&amp;rdquo; method, we observed a deficiency of butyrate-producing species and an overwhelming number of butyrate consumers in RA patients. These outcomes mainly occurred in patients with positive ACPA, with a mean AUC of 0.94. This panel was also validated in established RA with an AUC of 0.986 in those with joint deformity. In addition, we showed that butyrate promoted T&lt;sub&gt;regs&lt;/sub&gt;, while suppressing T&lt;sub&gt;convs&lt;/sub&gt; and osteoclasts, due to potentiation of the reduction in HDAC expression and down-regulation of proinflammatory cytokine genes. Dietary butyrate supplementation conferred anti-inflammatory benefits in a mouse model by rebalancing T&lt;sub&gt;FH&lt;/sub&gt; cells and T&lt;sub&gt;regs&lt;/sub&gt;, as well as reducing antibody production. These findings reveal the critical role of butyrate-metabolizing species and suggest the potential of butyrate-based therapies for RA patients.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Berberine Relieves Metabolic Syndrome in Mice by Inhibiting Liver Inflammation Caused by a High-Fat Diet and Potential Association With Gut Microbiota</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35095784/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35095784/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whether berberine mediates its anti-inflammatory and blood sugar and lipid-lowering effects solely by adjusting the structure of the gut microbiota or by first directly regulating the expression of host pro-inflammatory proteins and activation of macrophages and subsequently acting on gut microbiota, is currently unclear. To clarify the mechanism of berberine-mediated regulation of metabolism, we constructed an obese mouse model using SPF-grade C57BL/6J male mice and conducted a systematic study of liver tissue pathology, inflammatory factor expression, and gut microbiota structure. We screened the gut microbiota targets of berberine and showed that the molecular mechanism of berberine-mediated treatment of metabolic syndrome involves the regulation of gut microbiota structure and the expression of inflammatory factors. Our results revealed that a high-fat diet (HFD) significantly changed mice gut microbiota, thereby probably increasing the level of toxins in the intestine, and triggered the host inflammatory response. The HFD also reduced the proportion of short-chain fatty acid (SCFA)-producing genes, thereby hindering mucosal immunity and cell nutrition, and increased the host inflammatory response and liver fat metabolism disorders. Further, berberine could improve the chronic HFD-induced inflammatory metabolic syndrome to some extent and effectively improved the metabolism of high-fat foods in mice, which correlated with the gut microbiota composition. Taken together, our study may improve our understanding of host-microbe interactions during the treatment of metabolic diseases and provide useful insights into the action mechanism of berberine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AMDB: a database of animal gut microbial communities with manually curated metadata</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34747470/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34747470/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Variations in gut microbiota can be explained by animal host characteristics, including host phylogeny and diet. However, there are currently no databases that allow for easy exploration of the relationship between gut microbiota and diverse animal hosts. The &lt;a href=&#34;http://leb.snu.ac.kr/amdb&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Animal Microbiome Database (AMDB)&lt;/a&gt; is the first database to provide taxonomic profiles of the gut microbiota in various animal species. &lt;a href=&#34;http://leb.snu.ac.kr/amdb&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;AMDB&lt;/a&gt; contains 2530 amplicon data from 34 projects with manually curated metadata. The total data represent 467 animal species and contain 10 478 bacterial taxa. This novel database provides information regarding gut microbiota structures and the distribution of gut bacteria in animals, with an easy-to-use interface. Interactive visualizations are also available, enabling effective investigation of the relationship between the gut microbiota and animal hosts. &lt;a href=&#34;http://leb.snu.ac.kr/amdb&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;AMDB&lt;/a&gt; will contribute to a better understanding of the gut microbiota of animals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>gutMGene: a comprehensive database for target genes of gut microbes and microbial metabolites</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34500458/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34500458/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://bio-annotation.cn/gutmgene&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;gutMGene&lt;/a&gt;, a manually curated database, aims at providing a comprehensive resource of target genes of gut microbes and microbial metabolites in humans and mice. Metagenomic sequencing of fecal samples has identified 3.3 × 106 non-redundant microbial genes from up to 1500 different species. One of the contributions of gut microbiota to host biology is the circulating pool of bacterially derived small-molecule metabolites. It has been estimated that 10% of metabolites found in mammalian blood are derived from the gut microbiota, where they can produce systemic effects on the host through activating or inhibiting gene expression. The current version of &lt;a href=&#34;http://bio-annotation.cn/gutmgene&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;gutMGene&lt;/a&gt; documents 1331 curated relationships between 332 gut microbes, 207 microbial metabolites and 223 genes in humans, and 2349 curated relationships between 209 gut microbes, 149 microbial metabolites and 544 genes in mice. Each entry in the &lt;a href=&#34;http://bio-annotation.cn/gutmgene&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;gutMGene&lt;/a&gt; contains detailed information on a relationship between gut microbe, microbial metabolite and target gene, a brief description of the relationship, experiment technology and platform, literature reference and so on. &lt;a href=&#34;http://bio-annotation.cn/gutmgene&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;gutMGene&lt;/a&gt; provides a user-friendly interface to browse and retrieve each entry using gut microbes, disorders and intervention measures. It also offers the option to download all the entries and submit new experimentally validated associations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microbiome and cancer</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/34506740/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/34506740/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The human microbiome constitutes a complex multikingdom community that symbiotically interacts with the host across multiple body sites. Host-microbiome interactions impact multiple physiological processes and a variety of multifactorial disease conditions. In the past decade, microbiome communities have been suggested to influence the development, progression, metastasis formation, and treatment response of multiple cancer types. While causal evidence of microbial impacts on cancer biology is only beginning to be unraveled, enhanced molecular understanding of such cancer-modulating interactions and impacts on cancer treatment are considered of major scientific importance and clinical relevance. In this review, we describe the molecular pathogenic mechanisms shared throughout microbial niches that contribute to the initiation and progression of cancer. We highlight advances, limitations, challenges, and prospects in understanding how the microbiome may causally impact cancer and its treatment responsiveness, and how microorganisms or their secreted bioactive metabolites may be potentially harnessed and targeted as precision cancer therapeutics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Metagenomic compendium of 189,680 DNA viruses from the human gut microbiome</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34168315/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34168315/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bacteriophages have important roles in the ecology of the human gut microbiome but are under-represented in reference databases. To address this problem, we assembled the Metagenomic Gut Virus catalogue that comprises 189,680 viral genomes from 11,810 publicly available human stool metagenomes. Over 75% of genomes represent double-stranded DNA phages that infect members of the Bacteroidia and Clostridia classes. Based on sequence clustering we identified 54,118 candidate viral species, 92% of which were not found in existing databases. The Metagenomic Gut Virus catalogue improves detection of viruses in stool metagenomes and accounts for nearly 40% of CRISPR spacers found in human gut Bacteria and Archaea. We also produced a catalogue of 459,375 viral protein clusters to explore the functional potential of the gut virome. This revealed tens of thousands of diversity-generating retroelements, which use error-prone reverse transcription to mutate target genes and may be involved in the molecular arms race between phages and their bacterial hosts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Endogenous retroviruses promote homeostatic and inflammatory responses to the microbiota</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34166614/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34166614/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The microbiota plays a fundamental role in regulating host immunity. However, the processes involved in the initiation and regulation of immunity to the microbiota remain largely unknown. Here, we show that the skin microbiota promotes the discrete expression of defined endogenous retroviruses (ERVs). Keratinocyte-intrinsic responses to ERVs depended on cyclic GMP-AMP synthase (cGAS)/stimulator of interferon genes protein (STING) signaling and promoted the induction of commensal-specific T cells. Inhibition of ERV reverse transcription significantly impacted these responses, resulting in impaired immunity to the microbiota and its associated tissue repair function. Conversely, a lipid-enriched diet primed the skin for heightened ERV- expression in response to commensal colonization, leading to increased immune responses and tissue inflammation. Together, our results support the idea that the host may have co-opted its endogenous virome as a means to communicate with the exogenous microbiota, resulting in a multi-kingdom dialog that controls both tissue homeostasis and inflammation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A catalog of tens of thousands of viruses from human metagenomes reveals hidden associations with chronic diseases</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34083435/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34083435/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite remarkable strides in microbiome research, the viral component of the microbiome has generally presented a more challenging target than the bacteriome. This gap persists, even though many thousands of shotgun sequencing runs from human metagenomic samples exist in public databases, and all of them encompass large amounts of viral sequence data. The lack of a comprehensive database for human-associated viruses has historically stymied efforts to interrogate the impact of the virome on human health. This study probes thousands of datasets to uncover sequences from over 45,000 unique virus taxa, with historically high per-genome completeness. Large publicly available case-control studies are reanalyzed, and over 2,200 strong virus-disease associations are found.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>gutMEGA: a database of the human gut MEtaGenome Atlas</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32496513/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32496513/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The gut microbiota plays important roles in human health through regulating both physiological homeostasis and disease emergence. The accumulation of metagenomic sequencing studies enables us to better understand the temporal and spatial variations of the gut microbiota under different physiological and pathological conditions. However, it is inconvenient for scientists to query and retrieve published data; thus, a comprehensive resource for the quantitative gut metagenome is urgently needed. In this study, we developed &lt;a href=&#34;http://gutmega.omicsbio.info/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;gut MEtaGenome Atlas (gutMEGA)&lt;/a&gt;, a well-annotated comprehensive database, to curate and host published quantitative gut microbiota datasets from Homo sapiens. By carefully curating the gut microbiota composition, phenotypes and experimental information, &lt;a href=&#34;http://gutmega.omicsbio.info/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;gutMEGA&lt;/a&gt; finally integrated 59 132 quantification events for 6457 taxa at seven different levels (kingdom, phylum, class, order, family, genus and species) under 776 conditions. Moreover, with various browsing and search functions, &lt;a href=&#34;http://gutmega.omicsbio.info/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;gutMEGA&lt;/a&gt; provides a fast and simple way for users to obtain the relative abundances of intestinal microbes among phenotypes. Overall, &lt;a href=&#34;http://gutmega.omicsbio.info/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;gutMEGA&lt;/a&gt; is a convenient and comprehensive resource for gut metagenome research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Temporal landscape of human gut RNA and DNA virome in SARS-CoV-2 infection and severity</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33853691/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33853691/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) caused by the enveloped RNA virus SARS-CoV-2 primarily affects the respiratory and gastrointestinal tracts. SARS-CoV-2 was isolated from fecal samples, and active viral replication was reported in human intestinal cells. The human gut also harbors an enormous amount of resident viruses (collectively known as the virome) that play a role in regulating host immunity and disease pathophysiology. Understanding gut virome perturbation that underlies SARS-CoV-2 infection and severity is an unmet need.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; We enrolled 98 COVID-19 patients with varying disease severity (3 asymptomatic, 53 mild, 34 moderate, 5 severe, 3 critical) and 78 non-COVID-19 controls matched for gender and co-morbidities. All subjects had fecal specimens sampled at inclusion. Blood specimens were collected for COVID-19 patients at admission to test for inflammatory markers and white cell counts. Among COVID-19 cases, 37 (38%) patients had serial fecal samples collected 2 to 3 times per week from time of hospitalization until after discharge. Using shotgun metagenomics sequencing, we sequenced and profiled the fecal RNA and DNA virome. We investigated alterations and longitudinal dynamics of the gut virome in association with disease severity and blood parameters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; Patients with COVID-19 showed underrepresentation of Pepper mild mottle virus (RNA virus) and multiple bacteriophage lineages (DNA viruses) and enrichment of environment-derived eukaryotic DNA viruses in fecal samples, compared to non-COVID-19 subjects. Such gut virome alterations persisted up to 30 days after disease resolution. Fecal virome in SARS-CoV-2 infection harbored more stress-, inflammation-, and virulence-associated gene encoding capacities including those pertaining to bacteriophage integration, DNA repair, and metabolism and virulence associated with their bacterial host. Baseline fecal abundance of 10 virus species (1 RNA virus, pepper chlorotic spot virus, and 9 DNA virus species) inversely correlated with disease COVID-19 severity. These viruses inversely correlated with blood levels of pro-inflammatory proteins, white cells, and neutrophils. Among the 10 COVID-19 severity-associated DNA virus species, 4 showed inverse correlation with age; 5 showed persistent lower abundance both during disease course and after disease resolution relative to non-COVID-19 subjects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; Both enteric RNA and DNA virome in COVID-19 patients were different from non-COVID-19 subjects, which persisted after disease resolution of COVID-19. Gut virome may calibrate host immunity and regulate severity to SARS-CoV-2 infection. Our observation that gut viruses inversely correlated with both severity of COVID-19 and host age may partly explain that older subjects are prone to severe and worse COVID-19 outcomes. Altogether, our data highlight the importance of human gut virome in severity and potentially therapeutics of COVID-19.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lung virome: New potential biomarkers for asthma severity and exacerbation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33757721/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33757721/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Although some respiratory virus infections are known to contribute to the development and exacerbation of asthma, commensal viromes in airway have not been extensively studied due to technical challenges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Objectives:&lt;/em&gt; This study investigated the characteristics of the virome in asthmatic airways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; Both the bacteriome and virome profiles in sputum from 12 healthy individuals, 15 patients with nonsevere asthma, and 15 patients with severe asthma were analyzed and assessed for the association with clinical characteristics such as severity, exacerbation, Asthma Control Test (ACT), and lung function.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; While analysis of the 16S ribosomal RNA bacteriome in the airway showed no differences, clear contrasts in the diversity and composition of airway viromes were observed between healthy controls and patients with asthma. Herpesviruses were the most abundant type of virus in the asthma group (44.6 ± 4.6%), mainly with cytomegalovirus (CMV) and EBV accounting for 24.5 ± 3.3% and 16.9 ± 3.5%, respectively, in contrast to those in the healthy controls (5.4 ± 2.5% and 7.1 ± 3.0%, respectively). CMV and EBV were more abundant in patients with asthma who experienced exacerbation, and their abundance showed correlation with more severe asthma, lower ACT score, and lower lung function. On the contrary, bacteriophage that is abundant in healthy controls was severely reduced in patients with asthma in the order of nonsevere and severe asthma and presented significant positive correlation with ACT and FEV1/forced vital capacity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; Lung viromes, especially, CMV, EBV, and bacteriophage may be potential biomarkers of asthma severity and exacerbation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integrated gut virome and bacteriome dynamics in COVID-19 patients</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33678150/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33678150/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SARS-CoV-2 is the cause of the current global pandemic of COVID-19; this virus infects multiple organs, such as the lungs and gastrointestinal tract. The microbiome in these organs, including the bacteriome and virome, responds to infection and might also influence disease progression and treatment outcome. In a cohort of 13 COVID-19 patients in Beijing, China, we observed that the gut virome and bacteriome in the COVID-19 patients were notably different from those of five healthy controls. We identified a bacterial dysbiosis signature by observing reduced diversity and viral shifts in patients, and among the patients, the bacterial/viral compositions were different between patients of different severities, although these differences are not entirely distinguishable from the effect of antibiotics. Severe cases of COVID-19 exhibited a greater abundance of opportunistic pathogens but were depleted for butyrate-producing groups of bacteria compared with mild to moderate cases. We replicated our findings in a mouse COVID-19 model, confirmed virome differences and bacteriome dysbiosis due to SARS-CoV-2 infection, and observed that immune/infection-related genes were differentially expressed in gut epithelial cells during infection, possibly explaining the virome and bacteriome dynamics. Our results suggest that the components of the microbiome, including the bacteriome and virome, are affected by SARS-CoV-2 infections, while their compositional signatures could reflect or even contribute to disease severity and recovery processes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Massive expansion of human gut bacteriophage diversity</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33606979/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33606979/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bacteriophages drive evolutionary change in bacterial communities by creating gene flow networks that fuel ecological adaptions. However, the extent of viral diversity and its prevalence in the human gut remains largely unknown. Here, we introduce the Gut Phage Database, a collection of ∼142,000 non-redundant viral genomes (&amp;gt;10 kb) obtained by mining a dataset of 28,060 globally distributed human gut metagenomes and 2,898 reference genomes of cultured gut bacteria. Host assignment revealed that viral diversity is highest in the Firmicutes phyla and that ∼36% of viral clusters (VCs) are not restricted to a single species, creating gene flow networks across phylogenetically distinct bacterial species. Epidemiological analysis uncovered 280 globally distributed VCs found in at least 5 continents and a highly prevalent phage clade with features reminiscent of p-crAssphage. This high-quality, large-scale catalog of phage genomes will improve future virome studies and enable ecological and evolutionary analysis of human gut bacteriophages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>gcType: a high-quality type strain genome database for microbial phylogenetic and functional research</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33119759/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33119759/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Taxonomic and functional research of microorganisms has increasingly relied upon genome-based data and methods. As the depository of the Global Catalogue of Microorganisms (GCM) 10K prokaryotic type strain sequencing project, &lt;a href=&#34;http://gctype.wdcm.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Global Catalogue of Type Strain (gcType)&lt;/a&gt; has published 1049 type strain genomes sequenced by the GCM 10K project which are preserved in global culture collections with a valid published status. Additionally, the information provided through &lt;a href=&#34;http://gctype.wdcm.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;gcType&lt;/a&gt; includes &amp;gt;12 000 publicly available type strain genome sequences from GenBank incorporated using quality control criteria and standard data annotation pipelines to form a high-quality reference database. This database integrates type strain sequences with their phenotypic information to facilitate phenotypic and genotypic analyses. Multiple formats of cross-genome searches and interactive interfaces have allowed extensive exploration of the database&amp;rsquo;s resources. In this study, we describe web-based data analysis pipelines for genomic analyses and genome-based taxonomy, which could serve as a one-stop platform for the identification of prokaryotic species. The number of type strain genomes that are published will continue to increase as the GCM 10K project increases its collaboration with culture collections worldwide. Data of this project is shared with the International Nucleotide Sequence Database Collaboration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MASI: microbiota-active substance interactions database</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33125077/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33125077/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Xenobiotic and host active substances interact with gut microbiota to influence human health and therapeutics. Dietary, pharmaceutical, herbal and environmental substances are modified by microbiota with altered bioavailabilities, bioactivities and toxic effects. Xenobiotics also affect microbiota with health implications. Knowledge of these microbiota and active substance interactions is important for understanding microbiota-regulated functions and therapeutics. Established microbiota databases provide useful information about the microbiota-disease associations, diet and drug interventions, and microbiota modulation of drugs. However, there is insufficient information on the active substances modified by microbiota and the abundance of gut bacteria in humans. Only ∼7% drugs are covered by the established databases. To complement these databases, we developed &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.aiddlab.com/MASI/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;MASI&lt;/a&gt;, Microbiota-Active Substance Interactions database, for providing the information about the microbiota alteration of various substances, substance alteration of microbiota, and the abundance of gut bacteria in humans. These include 1,051 pharmaceutical, 103 dietary, 119 herbal, 46 probiotic, 142 environmental substances interacting with 806 microbiota species linked to 56 diseases and 784 microbiota-disease associations. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.aiddlab.com/MASI/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;MASI&lt;/a&gt; covers 11 215 bacteria-pharmaceutical, 914 bacteria-herbal, 309 bacteria-dietary, 753 bacteria-environmental substance interactions and the abundance profiles of 259 bacteria species in 3465 patients and 5334 healthy individuals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Peryton: a manual collection of experimentally supported microbe-disease associations</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33080028/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33080028/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We present &lt;a href=&#34;https://dianalab.e-ce.uth.gr/peryton/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Peryton&lt;/a&gt;, a database of experimentally supported microbe-disease associations. Its first version constitutes a novel resource hosting more than 7900 entries linking 43 diseases with 1396 microorganisms. &lt;a href=&#34;https://dianalab.e-ce.uth.gr/peryton/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Peryton&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s content is exclusively sustained by manual curation of biomedical articles. Diseases and microorganisms are provided in a systematic, standardized manner using reference resources to create database dictionaries. Information about the experimental design, study cohorts and the applied high- or low-throughput techniques is meticulously annotated and catered to users. Several functionalities are provided to enhance user experience and enable ingenious use of &lt;a href=&#34;https://dianalab.e-ce.uth.gr/peryton/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Peryton&lt;/a&gt;. One or more microorganisms and/or diseases can be queried at the same time. Advanced filtering options and direct text-based filtering of results enable refinement of returned information and the conducting of tailored queries suitable to different research questions. &lt;a href=&#34;https://dianalab.e-ce.uth.gr/peryton/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Peryton&lt;/a&gt; also provides interactive visualizations to effectively capture different aspects of its content and results can be directly downloaded for local storage and downstream analyses. &lt;a href=&#34;https://dianalab.e-ce.uth.gr/peryton/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Peryton&lt;/a&gt; will serve as a valuable source, enabling scientists of microbe-related disease fields to form novel hypotheses but, equally importantly, to assist in cross-validation of findings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Longitudinal Multi-omics Reveals Subset-Specific Mechanisms Underlying Irritable Bowel Syndrome</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32916129/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32916129/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Erratum in:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674%2820%2931447-1&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Longitudinal Multi-omics Reveals Subset-Specific Mechanisms Underlying Irritable Bowel Syndrome&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The gut microbiome has been implicated in multiple human chronic gastrointestinal (GI) disorders. Determining its mechanistic role in disease has been difficult due to apparent disconnects between animal and human studies and lack of an integrated multi-omics view of disease-specific physiological changes. We integrated longitudinal multi-omics data from the gut microbiome, metabolome, host epigenome, and transcriptome in the context of irritable bowel syndrome (IBS) host physiology. We identified IBS subtype-specific and symptom-related variation in microbial composition and function. A subset of identified changes in microbial metabolites correspond to host physiological mechanisms that are relevant to IBS. By integrating multiple data layers, we identified purine metabolism as a novel host-microbial metabolic pathway in IBS with translational potential. Our study highlights the importance of longitudinal sampling and integrating complementary multi-omics data to identify functional mechanisms that can serve as therapeutic targets in a comprehensive treatment strategy for chronic GI diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Virome of Acute Respiratory Diseases in Individuals at Risk of Zoonotic Infections</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32872469/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32872469/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ongoing coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) pandemic emphasizes the need to actively study the virome of unexplained respiratory diseases. We performed viral metagenomic next-generation sequencing (mNGS) analysis of 91 nasal-throat swabs from individuals working with animals and with acute respiratory diseases. Fifteen virus RT-PCR-positive samples were included as controls, while the other 76 samples were RT-PCR negative for a wide panel of respiratory pathogens. Eukaryotic viruses detected by mNGS were then screened by PCR (using primers based on mNGS-derived contigs) in all samples to compare viral detection by mNGS versus PCR and assess the utility of mNGS in routine diagnostics. mNGS identified expected human rhinoviruses, enteroviruses, influenza A virus, coronavirus OC43, and respiratory syncytial virus (RSV) A in 13 of 15 (86.7%) positive control samples. Additionally, rotavirus, torque teno virus, human papillomavirus, human betaherpesvirus 7, cyclovirus, vientovirus, gemycircularvirus, and statovirus were identified through mNGS. Notably, complete genomes of novel cyclovirus, gemycircularvirus, and statovirus were genetically characterized. Using PCR screening, the novel cyclovirus was additionally detected in 5 and the novel gemycircularvirus in 12 of the remaining samples included for mNGS analysis. Our studies therefore provide pioneering data of the virome of acute-respiratory diseases from individuals at risk of zoonotic infections. The mNGS protocol/pipeline applied here is sensitive for the detection of a variety of viruses, including novel ones. More frequent detections of the novel viruses by PCR than by mNGS on the same samples suggests that PCR remains the most sensitive diagnostic test for viruses whose genomes are known. The detection of novel viruses expands our understanding of the respiratory virome of animal-exposed humans and warrant further studies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Gut Virome Database Reveals Age-Dependent Patterns of Virome Diversity in the Human Gut</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32841606/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32841606/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The gut microbiome profoundly affects human health and disease, and their infecting viruses are likely as important, but often missed because of reference database limitations. Here, we (1) built a human Gut Virome Database (GVD) from 2,697 viral particle or microbial metagenomes from 1,986 individuals representing 16 countries, (2) assess its effectiveness, and (3) report a meta-analysis that reveals age-dependent patterns across healthy Westerners. The GVD contains 33,242 unique viral populations (approximately species-level taxa) and improves average viral detection rates over viral RefSeq and IMG/VR nearly 182-fold and 2.6-fold, respectively. GVD meta-analyses show highly personalized viromes, reveal that inter-study variability from technical artifacts is larger than any &amp;ldquo;disease&amp;rdquo; effect at the population level, and document how viral diversity changes from human infancy into senescence. Together, this compact foundational resource, these standardization guidelines, and these meta-analysis findings provide a systematic toolkit to help maximize our understanding of viral roles in health and disease.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Influenza infection elicits an expansion of gut population of endogenous Bifidobacterium animalis which protects mice against infection</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32345342/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32345342/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Influenza is a severe respiratory illness that continually threatens global health. It has been widely known that gut microbiota modulates the host response to protect against influenza infection, but mechanistic details remain largely unknown. Here, we took advantage of the phenomenon of lethal dose 50 (LD&lt;sub&gt;50&lt;/sub&gt;) and metagenomic sequencing analysis to identify specific anti-influenza gut microbes and analyze the underlying mechanism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; Transferring fecal microbes from mice that survive virulent influenza H7N9 infection into antibiotic-treated mice confers resistance to infection. Some gut microbes exhibit differential features to lethal influenza infection depending on the infection outcome. Bifidobacterium pseudolongum and Bifidobacterium animalis levels are significantly elevated in surviving mice when compared to dead or mock-infected mice. Oral administration of B. animalis alone or the combination of both significantly reduces the severity of H7N9 infection in both antibiotic-treated and germ-free mice. Functional metagenomic analysis suggests that B. animalis mediates the anti-influenza effect via several specific metabolic molecules. In vivo tests confirm valine and coenzyme A produce an anti-influenza effect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; These findings show that the severity of influenza infection is closely related to the heterogeneous responses of the gut microbiota. We demonstrate the anti-influenza effect of B. animalis, and also find that the gut population of endogenous B. animalis can expand to enhance host influenza resistance when lethal influenza infection occurs, representing a novel interaction between host and gut microbiota. Further, our data suggest the potential utility of Bifidobacterium in the prevention and as a prognostic predictor of influenza.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interaction Between the Microbiota, Epithelia, and Immune Cells in the Intestine</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/32340570/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/32340570/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The gastrointestinal tract harbors numerous commensal bacteria, referred to as the microbiota, that benefit host health by digesting dietary components and eliminating pathogens. The intestinal microbiota maintains epithelial barrier integrity and shapes the mucosal immune system, balancing host defense and oral tolerance with microbial metabolites, components, and attachment to host cells. To avoid aberrant immune responses, epithelial cells segregate the intestinal microbiota from immune cells by constructing chemical and physical barriers, leading to the establishment of host-commensal mutualism. Furthermore, intestinal immune cells participate in the maintenance of a healthy microbiota community and reinforce epithelial barrier functions. Perturbations of the microbiota composition are commonly observed in patients with autoimmune diseases and chronic inflammatory disorders. An understanding of the intimate interactions between the intestinal microbiota, epithelial cells, and immune cells that are crucial for the maintenance of intestinal homeostasis might promote advances in diagnostic and therapeutic approaches for various diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Association to Causality: the Role of the Gut Microbiota and Its Functional Products on Host Metabolism</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/32234490/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/32234490/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many genomic studies have revealed associations between the gut microbiota composition and host metabolism. These observations led to the idea that a causal relationship could exist between the microbiota and metabolic diseases, a concept supported by studies showing compositional changes in the microbial community in metabolic diseases and transmissibility of host phenotype via microbiota transfer. Accumulating data suggest that the microbiota may affect host metabolic phenotypes through the production of metabolites. These bioactive microbial metabolites, sensitive fingerprints of microbial function, can act as inter-kingdom signaling messengers via penetration into host blood circulation and tissues. These fingerprints may be used for diagnostic purposes, and increased understanding of strain specificity in producing microbial metabolites can identify bacterial strains or specific metabolites that can be used for therapeutic purposes. Here, we will review data supporting the causal role of the gut microbiota in metabolism and discuss mechanisms and potential clinical implications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Altered Gut Microbiome Profile in Patients With Pulmonary Arterial Hypertension</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32088998/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32088998/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pulmonary arterial hypertension (PAH) is considered a disease of the pulmonary vasculature. Limited progress has been made in preventing or arresting progression of PAH despite extensive efforts. Our previous studies indicated that PAH could be considered a systemic disease since its pathology involves interplay of multiple organs. This, coupled with increasing implication of the gut and its microbiome in chronic diseases, led us to hypothesize that patients with PAH exhibit a distinct gut microbiome that contributes to, and predicts, the disease. Fecal microbiome of 18 type 1 PAH patients (mean pulmonary arterial pressure, 57.4, SD 16.7 mm Hg) and 13 reference subjects were compared by shotgun metagenomics to evaluate this hypothesis. Significant taxonomic and functional changes in microbial communities in the PAH cohort were observed. Pathways for the synthesis of arginine, proline, and ornithine were increased in PAH cohort compared with reference cohort. Additionally, groups of bacterial communities associated with trimethylamine/ trimethylamine N-oxide and purine metabolism were increased in PAH cohort. In contrast, butyrate-and propionate-producing bacteria such as Coprococcus, Butyrivibrio, Lachnospiraceae, Eubacterium, Akkermansia, and Bacteroides were increased in reference cohort. A random forest model predicted PAH from the composition of the gut microbiome with 83% accuracy. Finally, virome analysis showed enrichment of Enterococcal and relative depletion of Lactococcal phages in the PAH cohort. In conclusion, patients with PAH exhibit a unique microbiome profile that has the high predictive potential for PAH. This highlights previously unknown roles of gut bacteria in this disease and could lead to new therapeutic, diagnostic, or management paradigms for PAH.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using MicrobiomeAnalyst for comprehensive statistical, functional, and meta-analysis of microbiome data</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/31942082/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/31942082/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.microbiomeanalyst.ca/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;MicrobiomeAnalyst&lt;/a&gt; is an easy-to-use, web-based platform for comprehensive analysis of common data outputs generated from current microbiome studies. It enables researchers and clinicians with little or no bioinformatics training to explore a wide variety of well-established methods for microbiome data processing, statistical analysis, functional profiling and comparison with public datasets or known microbial signatures. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.microbiomeanalyst.ca/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;MicrobiomeAnalyst&lt;/a&gt; currently contains four modules: Marker-gene Data Profiling (MDP), Shotgun Data Profiling (SDP), Projection with Public Data (PPD), and Taxon Set Enrichment Analysis (TSEA). This protocol will first introduce the MDP module by providing a step-wise description of how to prepare, process and normalize data; perform community profiling; identify important features; and conduct correlation and classification analysis. We will then demonstrate how to perform predictive functional profiling and introduce several unique features of the SDP module for functional analysis. The last two sections will describe the key steps involved in using the PPD and TSEA modules for meta-analysis and visual exploration of the results. In summary, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.microbiomeanalyst.ca/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;MicrobiomeAnalyst&lt;/a&gt; offers a one-stop shop that enables microbiome researchers to thoroughly explore their preprocessed microbiome data via intuitive web interfaces. The complete protocol can be executed in ~70 min.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GMrepo: a database of curated and consistently annotated human gut metagenomes</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/31504765/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/31504765/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://gmrepo.humangut.info/home&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;GMrepo&lt;/a&gt; (data repository for Gut Microbiota) is a database of curated and consistently annotated human gut metagenomes. Its main purpose is to facilitate the reusability and accessibility of the rapidly growing human metagenomic data. This is achieved by consistently annotating the microbial contents of collected samples using state-of-art toolsets and by manual curation of the meta-data of the corresponding human hosts. &lt;a href=&#34;https://gmrepo.humangut.info/home&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;GMrepo&lt;/a&gt; organizes the collected samples according to their associated phenotypes and includes all possible related meta-data such as age, sex, country, body-mass-index (BMI) and recent antibiotics usage. To make relevant information easier to access, &lt;a href=&#34;https://gmrepo.humangut.info/home&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;GMrepo&lt;/a&gt; is equipped with a graphical query builder, enabling users to make customized, complex and biologically relevant queries. For example, to find (1) samples from healthy individuals of 18 to 25 years old with BMIs between 18.5 and 24.9, or (2) projects that are related to colorectal neoplasms, with each containing &amp;gt;100 samples and both patients and healthy controls. Precomputed species/genus relative abundances, prevalence within and across phenotypes, and pairwise co-occurrence information are all available at the website and accessible through programmable interfaces. So far, &lt;a href=&#34;https://gmrepo.humangut.info/home&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;GMrepo&lt;/a&gt; contains 58 903 human gut samples/runs (including 17 618 metagenomes and 41 285 amplicons) from 253 projects concerning 92 phenotypes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commensal viruses maintain intestinal intraepithelial lymphocytes via noncanonical RIG-I signaling</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/31636462/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/31636462/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Much attention has focused on commensal bacteria in health and disease, but the role of commensal viruses is understudied. Although metagenomic analysis shows that the intestine of healthy humans and animals harbors various commensal viruses and the dysbiosis of these viruses can be associated with inflammatory diseases, there is still a lack of causal data and underlying mechanisms to understand the physiological role of commensal viruses in intestinal homeostasis. In the present study, we show that commensal viruses are essential for the homeostasis of intestinal intraepithelial lymphocytes (IELs). Mechanistically, the cytosolic viral RNA-sensing receptor RIG-I in antigen-presenting cells can recognize commensal viruses and maintain IELs via a type I interferon-independent, but MAVS-IRF1-IL-15 axis-dependent, manner. The recovery of IELs by interleukin-15 administration reverses the susceptibility of commensal virus-depleted mice to dextran sulfate sodium-induced colitis. Collectively, our results indicate that commensal viruses maintain the IELs and consequently sustain intestinal homeostasis via noncanonical RIG-I signaling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Statistical Analysis of Microbiome Data with R</title>
      <link>https://example.com/books/2019-02-02-stat-analy-microbiome-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/books/2019-02-02-stat-analy-microbiome-r/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This unique book addresses the statistical modelling and analysis of microbiome data using cutting-edge R software. It includes real-world data from the authors’ research and from the public domain, and discusses the implementation of R for data analysis step by step. The data and R computer programs are publicly available, allowing readers to replicate the model development and data analysis presented in each chapter, so that these new methods can be readily applied in their own research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The book also discusses recent developments in statistical modelling and data analysis in microbiome research, as well as the latest advances in next-generation sequencing and big data in methodological development and applications. This timely book will greatly benefit all readers involved in microbiome, ecology and microarray data analyses, as well as other fields of research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/books/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Books &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Virtual Metabolic Human database: integrating human and gut microbiome metabolism with nutrition and disease</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/30371894/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/30371894/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A multitude of factors contribute to complex diseases and can be measured with &amp;lsquo;omics&amp;rsquo; methods. Databases facilitate data interpretation for underlying mechanisms. Here, we describe the &lt;a href=&#34;www.vmh.life&#34;&gt;Virtual Metabolic Human (VMH)&lt;/a&gt; database encapsulating current knowledge of human metabolism within five interlinked resources &amp;lsquo;Human metabolism&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;Gut microbiome&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;Disease&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;Nutrition&amp;rsquo;, and &amp;lsquo;ReconMaps&amp;rsquo;. The &lt;a href=&#34;www.vmh.life&#34;&gt;VMH&lt;/a&gt; captures 5180 unique metabolites, 17 730 unique reactions, 3695 human genes, 255 Mendelian diseases, 818 microbes, 632 685 microbial genes and 8790 food items. The &lt;a href=&#34;www.vmh.life&#34;&gt;VMH&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s unique features are (i) the hosting of the metabolic reconstructions of human and gut microbes amenable for metabolic modeling; (ii) seven human metabolic maps for data visualization; (iii) a nutrition designer; (iv) a user-friendly webpage and application-programming interface to access its content; (v) user feedback option for community engagement and (vi) the connection of its entities to 57 other web resources. The &lt;a href=&#34;www.vmh.life&#34;&gt;VMH&lt;/a&gt; represents a novel, interdisciplinary database for data interpretation and hypothesis generation to the biomedical community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Disbiome database: linking the microbiome to disease</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/29866037/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/29866037/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Recent research has provided fascinating indications and evidence that the host health is linked to its microbial inhabitants. Due to the development of high-throughput sequencing technologies, more and more data covering microbial composition changes in different disease types are emerging. However, this information is dispersed over a wide variety of medical and biomedical disciplines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Description:&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://disbiome.ugent.be/home&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Disbiome&lt;/a&gt; is a database which collects and presents published microbiota-disease information in a standardized way. The diseases are classified using the MedDRA classification system and the micro-organisms are linked to their NCBI and SILVA taxonomy. Finally, each study included in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://disbiome.ugent.be/home&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Disbiome&lt;/a&gt; database is assessed for its reporting quality using a standardized questionnaire.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://disbiome.ugent.be/home&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Disbiome&lt;/a&gt; is the first database giving a clear, concise and up-to-date overview of microbial composition differences in diseases, together with the relevant information of the studies published. The strength of this database lies within the combination of the presence of references to other databases, which enables both specific and diverse search strategies within the &lt;a href=&#34;https://disbiome.ugent.be/home&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Disbiome&lt;/a&gt; database, and the human annotation which ensures a simple and structured presentation of the available data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Best practices for analysing microbiomes</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/29795328/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/29795328/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Complex microbial communities shape the dynamics of various environments, ranging from the mammalian gastrointestinal tract to the soil. Advances in DNA sequencing technologies and data analysis have provided drastic improvements in microbiome analyses, for example, in taxonomic resolution, false discovery rate control and other properties, over earlier methods. In this Review, we discuss the best practices for performing a microbiome study, including experimental design, choice of molecular analysis technology, methods for data analysis and the integration of multiple omics data sets. We focus on recent findings that suggest that operational taxonomic unit-based analyses should be replaced with new methods that are based on exact sequence variants, methods for integrating metagenomic and metabolomic data, and issues surrounding compositional data analysis, where advances have been particularly rapid. We note that although some of these approaches are new, it is important to keep sight of the classic issues that arise during experimental design and relate to research reproducibility. We describe how keeping these issues in mind allows researchers to obtain more insight from their microbiome data sets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rethinking Diet to Aid Human-Microbe Symbiosis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/27916707/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/27916707/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The spread of the Western lifestyle has been accompanied by microbial changes thought to underlie the emergence of chronic, nontransmissible, immune-related diseases. The past decade has seen the unprecedented development of therapies for &amp;lsquo;replenishing&amp;rsquo; the microbiota of sick individuals. However, functional and ecological solutions helping the host and the gut microbiota to cope with the ecological stressors of modern life are still lacking. In this review, we discuss how recent advances in gut microbiome science are leading to the identification of microbe-derived and health-relevant metabolites. These molecules will guide the selection of the next-generation of probiotics and dietary recommendations, which should also take the resident gut microbiota into account, to optimise efficacy. These solutions for maintaining a well-functioning gut ecosystem and promoting good health should be customised, palatable, and as widely accessible as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Mouse Intestinal Bacterial Collection (miBC) provides host-specific insight into cultured diversity and functional potential of the gut microbiota</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/27670113/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/27670113/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Erratum in:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Corrigendum: &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nature.com/articles/nmicrobiol2016219&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;The Mouse Intestinal Bacterial Collection (miBC) provides host-specific insight into cultured diversity and functional potential of the gut microbiota&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Intestinal bacteria influence mammalian physiology, but many types of bacteria are still uncharacterized. Moreover, reference strains of mouse gut bacteria are not easily available, although mouse models are extensively used in medical research. These are major limitations for the investigation of intestinal microbiomes and their interactions with diet and host. It is thus important to study in detail the diversity and functions of gut microbiota members, including those colonizing the mouse intestine. To address these issues, we aimed at establishing the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.dsmz.de/collection/catalogue/microorganisms/special-groups-of-organisms/dzif-sammlung/maus-mikrobiomliste&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Mouse Intestinal Bacterial Collection (miBC)&lt;/a&gt;, a public repository of bacterial strains and associated genomes from the mouse gut, and studied host-specificity of colonization and sequence-based relevance of the resource. The collection includes several strains representing novel species, genera and even one family. Genomic analyses showed that certain species are specific to the mouse intestine and that a minimal consortium of 18 strains covered 50-75% of the known functional potential of metagenomes. The present work will sustain future research on microbiota-host interactions in health and disease, as it will facilitate targeted colonization and molecular studies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commensal microbiota from patients with inflammatory bowel disease produce genotoxic metabolites</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36302024/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jun 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36302024/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Introduction&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gut microbiota can potentially contribute to the development and progression of colorectal cancer (CRC) by producing small-molecule genotoxins. For example, select commensal &lt;em&gt;Escherichia coli&lt;/em&gt; strains produce the canonical microbiota-derived genotoxin colibactin, which engenders the formation of DNA double-strand breaks (DSBs) in intestinal epithelial cells and exacerbates CRC in mouse models. Furthermore, human CRCs harbor colibactin-associated mutational signatures, implying a direct role for microbiota-induced DNA damage in CRC. However, the impacts of microbiota-derived genotoxins beyond colibactin remain largely unexplored.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rationale&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given the extensive diversity of small-molecule metabolites produced by bacteria, we hypothesized that additional taxa from the human gut microbiome might produce previously undiscovered small molecules that cause DNA damage in host cells. Identifying and characterizing such genotoxins and their respective biosynthetic pathways may reveal causal roles of gut microbes in shaping host biology and disease susceptibility. Thus, we designed a large-scale electrophoresis-based DNA damage screening pipeline to evaluate the genotoxicity of a collection of more than 100 gut commensals isolated from patients with inflammatory bowel disease (IBD).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We identified diverse bacteria from the human microbiota whose small-molecule metabolites caused genotoxicity in both cell-free and cell-based DNA damage assays. For example, small-molecule metabolites from gram-positive bacteria (including &lt;em&gt;Clostridium perfringens&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Clostridium ramosum&lt;/em&gt; strains) and gram-negative bacteria (including multiple &lt;em&gt;Morganella morganii&lt;/em&gt; strains) directly damaged DNA in cell-free assays and induced the expression of the DSB marker γ-H2AX and cell-cycle arrest in epithelial cells. However, the DNA damage patterns caused by these metabolites were distinct from colibactin-induced cross-links, and these isolates lacked the biosynthetic machinery to produce colibactin or other known genotoxins. These data thus implied the existence of previously unrecognized microbiota-derived genotoxins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;M. morganii&lt;/em&gt; is enriched in the gut microbiota of both IBD and CRC patients. Using a combination of comparative metabolomics and bioactivity-guided natural product-discovery techniques, we discovered a family of &lt;em&gt;M. morganii&lt;/em&gt;-derived small-molecule genotoxins—termed the indolimines—that elicited DNA damage in cell-based and cell-free assays. Furthermore, we identified a previously uncharacterized bacterial decarboxylase (annotated as an aspartate aminotransferase encoded by the &lt;em&gt;aat&lt;/em&gt; gene) that was essential for indolimine synthesis and constructed an isogenic aat mutant &lt;em&gt;M. morganii&lt;/em&gt; that lacked genotoxicity in both cell-free and cell-based DNA damage assays.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Compared with the non–indolimine-producing mutant, wild-type &lt;em&gt;M. morganii&lt;/em&gt; caused increased intestinal permeability and induced transcriptional signatures associated with abnormal DNA replication and intestinal epithelial cell proliferation in gnotobiotic mice. Furthermore, indolimine-producing &lt;em&gt;M. morganii&lt;/em&gt; induced increased colonic tumor burden in the context of a mock microbial community in a mouse model of CRC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By leveraging function-based assessments of the microbiome, we uncovered the existence of a broader universe of microbiota-derived small-molecule genotoxins. We found that diverse bacterial strains isolated from IBD patients exhibited DNA-damaging activities and discovered a previously undescribed family of genotoxins, termed the indolimines, produced by the IBD- and CRC-associated species &lt;em&gt;M. morganii&lt;/em&gt;. Indolimine-producing &lt;em&gt;M. morganii&lt;/em&gt; caused increased intestinal permeability and exacerbated colon tumorigenesis in gnotobiotic mice. Overall, these studies imply an expanded role for microbiota-derived genotoxins in shaping host biology and disease susceptibility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
