<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ferroptosis | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/ferroptosis/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/ferroptosis/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Ferroptosis</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Ferroptosis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/ferroptosis/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tripterygium wilfordii Hook.f. ameliorates paraquat-induced lung injury by reducing oxidative stress and ferroptosis via Nrf2/HO-1 pathway</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36706526/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36706526/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PQ poisoning can induce acute lung injury and fibrosis without effective treatment methods.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;TwHF possessed potential properties in therapies for PQ-induced lung injury and fibrosis.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The protective effect of TwHF may be due to the regulation of oxidative stress and ferroptosis.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paraquat (PQ) poisoning can induce acute lung injury and fibrosis and has an extremely high mortality rate. However, no effective treatments for PQ poisoning have been established. In this study, the potential efficacy of Tripterygium wilfordii Hook.f. (TwHF) in alleviating PQ-induced lung injury and fibrosis was investigated in a mouse model. Mice were randomly assigned to the control, PQ, PQ + TwHF1 (pretreatment before inducing poisoning), and PQ + TwHF2 (treatment after poisoning) groups. The mice in the PQ + TwHF1 group were pretreated with TwHF for 5 days before receiving one dose of PQ (120 mg/kg) and then received a daily oral gavage of the indicated dosages of TwHF until sacrifice. The mice in the PQ + TwHF2 group were treated with TwHF 2 h after PQ exposure until sacrifice. The pathological analysis and Fapi PET/CT showed that treatment with TwHF attenuated lung injury. And TwHF reduced pulmonary oxidative stress, as indicated by the reduction in, malondialdehyde (MDA), glutathione (GSH), and reactive oxygen species (ROS) levels, as well as by the increase in superoxide dismutase (SOD) levels. Accordingly, the Perls DAB staining showed increased iron concentrations and western blotting revealed a decreased GPX4 expression after PQ exposure, as well as the mitigation of the overexpression of Nrf2 and HO-1 induced by PQ. In conclusion, our study demonstrated the potential of TwHF as a treatment for PQ-induced lung injury and fibrosis. The protective mechanism of this medicinal herb may involve the regulation of ferroptosis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adaptor protein HIP-55-mediated signalosome protects against ferroptosis in myocardial infarction</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36639542/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36639542/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ischemic heart disease is a leading cause of death worldwide. Myocardial infarction (MI) results in cardiac damage due to cell death and insufficient cardiomyocyte self-renewal. Ferroptosis, a novel type of cell death, has recently been shown as a key cause of cardiomyocyte death after MI. However, the complicated regulation mechanisms involved in ferroptosis, especially how ferroptosis is integrated into classical cell survival/death pathways, are still unclear. Here, we discovered that HIP-55, a novel adaptor protein, acts as a hub protein for the integration of the ferroptosis mechanism into the classical AKT cell survival and MAP4K1 cell death pathways for MI injury. The expression of HIP-55 is induced in MI. Genetic deletion of HIP-55 increased cardiomyocyte ferroptosis and MI injury, whereas cardiac-specific overexpression of HIP-55 significantly alleviated cardiomyocyte ferroptosis and MI injury. Mechanistically, HIP-55 was identified as a new AKT substrate. AKT phosphorylates HIP-55 at S269/T291 sites and further HIP-55 directs AKT signaling to negatively regulate the MAP4K1 pathway against MI injury in a site-specific manner. S269A/T291A-mutated HIP-55 (HIP-55AA), which is defective in AKT phosphorylation and significantly decreases the interaction between HIP-55 and MAP4K1, failed to inhibit the MAP4K1/GPX4 ferroptosis pathway. In line with this mechanism, cardiac-specific overexpression of HIP-55WT mice, but not cardiac-specific overexpression of HIP-55AA mice, protected cardiomyocytes against MI-induced ferroptosis and cardiac injury in vivo. These findings suggest that HIP-55 rewired the classical AKT (cell survival) and MAPK (cell death) pathways into ferroptosis mechanism in MI injury. HIP-55 may be a new therapeutic target for myocardial damage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Copper-dependent autophagic degradation of GPX4 drives ferroptosis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36622894/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36622894/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ferroptosis is a type of iron-dependent regulated cell death characterized by unrestricted lipid peroxidation and membrane damage. Although GPX4 (glutathione peroxidase 4) plays a master role in blocking ferroptosis by eliminating phospholipid hydroperoxides, the regulation of GPX4 remains poorly understood. Here, we report an unexpected role for copper in promoting ferroptotic cell death, but not cuproptosis, by inducing macroautophagic/autophagic degradation of GPX4. Copper chelators reduce ferroptosis sensitivity but do not inhibit other types of cell death, such as apoptosis, necroptosis, and alkaliptosis. Conversely, exogenous copper increases GPX4 ubiquitination and the formation of GPX4 aggregates by directly binding to GPX4 protein cysteines C107 and C148. TAX1BP1 (Tax1 binding protein 1) then acts as an autophagic receptor for GPX4 degradation and subsequent ferroptosis in response to copper stress. Consequently, copper enhances ferroptosis-mediated tumor suppression in a mouse model of pancreatic cancer tumor, whereas copper chelators attenuate experimental acute pancreatitis associated with ferroptosis. Taken together, these findings provide new insights into the link between metal stress and autophagy-dependent cell death.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MiR-20a-5p alleviates kidney ischemia/reperfusion injury by targeting ACSL4-dependent ferroptosis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36695612/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36695612/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ischemia/reperfusion injury (IRI) is prone to occur after kidney transplantation, leading to delayed graft function (DGF). MicroRNAs play a crucial role in the pathogenesis of ischemia/reperfusion-induced acute kidney injury, and miR-20a-5p was found to be the most significantly upregulated gene in a DGF patient cohort. However, the roles of microRNAs in transplanted kidneys remain largely unknown. In this study, we found that miR-20a-5p was upregulated in the kidneys of acute kidney injury mice and in patients with DGF. We identified early growth response-1 as a critical upstream target and verified the binding of early growth response-1 to a predicted sequence in the promoter region of the miR-20a-5p gene. Functionally, the miR-20a-5p mimic attenuated IRI and postischemic renal fibrosis, whereas the miR-20a-5p inhibitor delivery aggravated IRI and fibrosis. Importantly, delivery of the miR-20a-5p mimic or inhibitor in the donor kidneys attenuated or aggravated renal loss and structural damage in cold storage transplantation injury. Furthermore, our study identified miR-20a-5p as a negative regulator of acyl-CoA synthetase long-chain family member 4 (ACSL4) by targeting the 3&amp;rsquo; untranslated region of ACSL4 mRNA, thereby inhibiting ACSL4-dependent ferroptosis. Our results suggest a potential therapeutic application of miR-20a-5p in kidney transplantation through the inhibition of ACSL4-dependent ferroptosis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mycobacterium tuberculosis Rv1324 Protein Contributes to Mycobacterial Persistence and Causes Pathological Lung Injury in Mice by Inducing Ferroptosis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36625672/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36625672/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Mycobacterium tuberculosis&lt;/em&gt; (Mtb) is the pathogenic agent of tuberculosis (TB). Intracellular survival plays a central role in the pathogenesis of Mtb, a process that depends on an array of virulence factors for Mtb to colonize and proliferate within a host. Reactive nitrogen and oxygen species (RNS and ROS) are among the most effective antimycobacterial molecules generated by the host during infection. However, Mtb has evolved a number of proteins and enzymes to detoxify ROS and RNS. Secretory protein Rv1324, as a possible thioredoxin, might also have oxidoreductase activity against ROS and RNS during Mtb infection, and it is a potential virulence factor of Mtb. In this study, we investigated the biochemical properties of Mtb Rv1324 and its role in mycobacterial survival and virulence. The results showed that the Rv1324 protein had antioxidant activity and increased the survival of &lt;em&gt;M. smegmatis&lt;/em&gt; that was exposed to ROS and RNS. In addition, Rv1324 enhanced the colonization ability of &lt;em&gt;M. smegmatis&lt;/em&gt; in the lungs of mice. Further, mice infected with &lt;em&gt;M. smegmatis&lt;/em&gt; harboring Rv1324 exhibited pathological injury and inflammation in the lung, which was mediated by ferroptosis. In summary, this study advances our understanding of the mechanisms of mycobacterial survival and pathogenesis, and it reveals a novel target for TB treatment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Importance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The intracellular survival of &lt;em&gt;M. tuberculosis&lt;/em&gt; (Mtb) plays a crucial role in its pathogenesis, which depends on various Mtb oxidoreductases that are resistant to reactive oxygen and nitrogen species (ROS and RNS) that are generated by the host during Mtb infection. Secretory protein Rv1324 is a potential virulence factor of Mtb and is a possible thioredoxin that has oxidoreductase activity against ROS and RNS during Mtb infection. We investigated the biochemical properties of Mtb Rv1324 and its role in mycobacterial survival and virulence. It was confirmed that the Rv1324 protein had antioxidant activity and an increased mycobacterial resistance to ROS and RNS. In addition, Rv1324 enhanced mycobacterial persistence and induced pathological injury and inflammation in the lungs of mice by activating ferroptosis. This study advances our understanding of the mechanisms of mycobacterial survival and pathogenesis, and it reveals a novel target for TB treatment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tryptophan Metabolism Acts as a New Anti-Ferroptotic Pathway to Mediate Tumor Growth</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36627132/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36627132/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Emerging evidence reveals that amino acid metabolism plays an important role in ferroptotic cell death. The conversion of methionine to cysteine is well known to protect tumour cells from ferroptosis upon cysteine starvation through transamination. However, whether amino acids-produced metabolites participate in ferroptosis independent of the cysteine pathway is largely unknown. Here, the authors show that the tryptophan metabolites serotonin (5-HT) and 3-hydroxyanthranilic acid (3-HA) remarkably facilitate tumour cells to escape from ferroptosis distinct from cysteine-mediated ferroptosis inhibition. Mechanistically, both 5-HT and 3-HA act as potent radical trapping antioxidants (RTA) to eliminate lipid peroxidation, thereby inhibiting ferroptotic cell death. Monoamine oxidase A (MAOA) markedly abrogates the protective effect of 5-HT via degrading 5-HT. Deficiency of MAOA renders cancer cells resistant to ferroptosis upon 5-HT treatment. Kynureninase (KYNU), which is essential for 3-HA production, confers cells resistant to ferroptotic cell death, whereas 3-hydroxyanthranilate 3,4-dioxygenase (HAAO) significantly blocks 3-HA mediated ferroptosis inhibition by consuming 3-HA. In addition, the expression level of HAAO is positively correlated with lipid peroxidation and clinical outcome. Together, the findings demonstrate that tryptophan metabolism works as a new anti-ferroptotic pathway to promote tumour growth, and targeting this pathway will be a promising therapeutic approach for cancer treatment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extracellular histone H3 facilitates ferroptosis in sepsis through ROS/JNK pathway</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36705411/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36705411/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Introduction:&lt;/em&gt; Previous evidence realized the critical role of histone in disease control. The anti-inflammatory function of estradiol (E2) in sepsis has been documented. We here intended to unveil the role of extracellular histone H3 in sepsis regarding cell ferroptosis and the role of E2 in a such mechanism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; Clinical sample, cecal ligation and puncture (CLP)-induced animal models and lipopolysaccharides (LPS)-induced cell models were prepared for testing relative expression of extracellular histone H3 and E2 as well as analyzing the role of extracellular histone H3 and E2 in sepsis concerning cell viability, reactive oxygen species (ROS), and ferroptosis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; Under sepsis, we found increased ferroptosis and extracellular histone H3 content, but reduced E2 concentration. Extracellular histone H3 facilitated ferroptosis of human umbilical vein endothelial cells (HUVECs) induced by LPS through activating the ROS/c-Jun N-terminal kinase (JNK) pathway. Moreover, E2 antagonized the effect of extracellular histone H3 on LPS-induced HUVEC ferroptosis and sepsis injury in CLP-induced animal models.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/em&gt; We highlighted that extracellular histone H3 facilitated lipopolysaccharides-induced HUVEC ferroptosis via activating ROS/JNK pathway, and such an effect could be antagonized by E2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Key points&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sepsis increases ferroptosis and extracellular histone H3 content, but reduces estradiol (E2) concentration.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Extracellular histone H3 induces ferroptosis of human umbilical vein endothelial cells (HUVECs) induced by lipopolysaccharides (LPS).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;E2 antagonizes the effect of extracellular histone H3 on LPS-induced HUVEC ferroptosis.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Extracellular histone H3 promotes the ferroptosis of HUVECs by activating JNK pathway.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;E2 antagonized the effect of extracellular histone H3 on sepsis injury in animal models.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The lipid flippase SLC47A1 blocks metabolic vulnerability to ferroptosis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36575162/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36575162/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ferroptosis is a type of regulated necrosis caused by unrestricted lipid peroxidation and subsequent plasma membrane rupture. However, the lipid remodeling mechanism that determines sensitivity to ferroptosis remains poorly understood. Here, we report a previously unrecognized role for the lipid flippase solute carrier family 47 member 1 (SLC47A1) as a regulator of lipid remodeling and survival during ferroptosis. Among 49 phospholipid scramblases, flippases, and floppases we analyzed, only SLC47A1 had mRNA that was selectively upregulated in multiple cancer cells exposed to ferroptotic inducers. Large-scale lipidomics and functional analyses revealed that the silencing of SLC47A1 increased RSL3- or erastin-induced ferroptosis by favoring ACSL4-SOAT1-mediated production of polyunsaturated fatty acid cholesterol esters. We identified peroxisome proliferator activated receptor alpha (PPARA) as a transcription factor that transactivates SLC47A1. The depletion of PPARA and SLC47A1 similarly sensitized cells to ferroptosis induction, whereas transfection-enforced re-expression of SLC47A1 restored resistance to ferroptosis in PPARA-deficient cells. Pharmacological or genetic blockade of the PPARA-SLC47A1 pathway increased the anticancer activity of a ferroptosis inducer in mice. These findings establish a direct molecular link between ferroptosis and lipid transporters, which may provide metabolic targets for overcoming drug resistance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UHRF1-mediated ferroptosis promotes pulmonary fibrosis via epigenetic repression of GPX4 and FSP1 genes</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36566325/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36566325/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pulmonary fibrosis (PF), as an end-stage clinical phenotype of interstitial lung diseases (ILDs), is frequently initiated after alveolar injury, in which ferroptosis has been identified as a critical event aggravating the pathophysiological progression of this disease. Here in, a comprehensive analysis of two mouse models of pulmonary fibrosis developed in our lab demonstrated that lung damage-induced ferroptosis of alveolar epithelial Type2 cells (AEC2) significantly accumulates during the development of pulmonary fibrosis while ferroptosis suppressor genes GPX4 and FSP1 are dramatically inactivated. Mechanistically, upregulation of de novo methylation regulator Uhrf1 sensitively elevates CpG site methylation levels in promoters of both GPX4 and FSP1 genes and induces the epigenetic repression of both genes, subsequently leading to ferroptosis in chemically interfered AEC2 cells. Meanwhile, specific inhibition of UHRF1 highly arrests the ferroptosis formation and blocks the progression of pulmonary fibrosis in both of our research models. This study first, to our knowledge, identified the involvement of Uhrf1 in mediating the ferroptosis of chemically injured AEC2s via de novo promoter-specific methylation of both GPX4 and FSP1 genes, which consequently accelerates the process of pulmonary fibrosis. The above findings also strongly suggested Uhrf1 as a novel potential target in the treatment of pulmonary fibrosis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>rmMANF prevents sepsis-associated lung injury via inhibiting endoplasmic reticulum stress-induced ferroptosis in mice</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36700778/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36700778/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The protein interaction network between MANF and biomarkers of inflammation, endoplasmic reticulum stress, and iron death was constructed by STRING and GeneMania.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;rmMANF pretreatment inhibits ferroptosis in septic associated-lung injury.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;rmMANF pretreatment inhibits ferroptosis by suppressing GRP78/PERK/ATF4 axis.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ferroptosis plays a critical role in LPS-induced acute lung injury and is modulated by endoplasmic reticulum stress (ERS). As a typical ER stress-responsive protein, recently mesencephalic astrocyte-derived neurotrophic factor (MANF) has been demonstrated to attenuate LPS-induced acute lung injury (ALI) through repressing macrophage activation. However, whether MANF exerts a preventive role on ferroptosis and excess ER stress remains unclear. Here, we first built a protein-protein interaction (PPI) network to obtain potential interacting proteins related to MANF through STRING and GeneMANIA. Then, male C57BL/6J mice were used to build a model of LPS-induced lung injury. Two days before LPS injection, the tail vein injected recombinant murine MANF (rmMANF) at 750 μg/kg. Twenty-four hours after the LPS injection, the histopathological changes and damage in the lung tissues were detected and scored by HE staining and TUNEL assay, respectively. Endogenous MANF levels, oxidative stress markers (GSH, SOD, CAT, and MDA), ERS markers (GRP78, PERK, and ATF4), and the ferroptosis markers (iron, GPX4, and 4-HNE) in the lung tissues were measured by IHC, western blotting, and commercial kits. Our results showed that LPS induced significant lung injury to the increase in MPO, MDA, and 4-HNE, a decrease in GPX4 and GSH, SOD, CAT, and total iron accumulation in LPS-exposed mice. Simultaneously, GRP78/PERK/ATF4 pathway was notably activated by LPS, accompanied by the down-regulation of MANF. Furthermore, rmMANF pretreatment markedly prevented LPS-induced lung tissue injury and ferroptosis characteristics with the increased GPX4 level in sepsis mice. Finally, we found that LPS-induced oxidative stress and activation of the GRP78/PERK/ATF4 pathway were significantly restrained by rmMANF pretreatment, except for endogenous MANF level. Overall, rmMANF pretreatment can prevent sepsis-associated lung injury by inhibiting ER stress-induced ferroptosis in mice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>β-hydroxybutyrate inhibits ferroptosis-mediated pancreatic damage in acute liver failure through the increase of H3K9bhb</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36543135/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36543135/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ferroptosis contributes to pancreatic injury after acute liver failure (ALF)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;β-hydroxybutyrate (β-HB) restoration alleviates pancreatic injury after ALF&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;β-HB induces enrichment of H3K9bhb in the promotor regions of ferroptosis-suppressor genes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;β-HB regulates chromatin accessibility and mRNA expression of ferroptosis-suppressor genes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acute pancreatitis and hyperamylasemia are often seen in patients with acute liver failure (ALF). However, the underlying mechanisms remain elusive. This study describes pancreatic tissue damage and exocrine dysfunction in a mouse model of major-liver-resection-induced ALF. The analysis of 1,264 clinical cases of liver failure (LF) showed that the incidence of hyperamylasemia and hyperlipasemia in patients with LF is 5.5% and 20%, respectively. Metabolomic studies indicate that glutathione (GSH)-deficiency-caused ferroptosis contributes to pancreatic damage in mouse ALF. β-hydroxybutyrate (β-HB) is the only metabolite downregulated in the liver, serum, and pancreas. Our data suggest that β-HB protects pancreatic cells and tissues from GSH-deficiency-caused ferroptosis. β-HB administration in ALF mice restores the expression of ferroptosis-suppressor genes through histone H3 lysine 9 β-hydroxybutyrylation (H3K9bhb)-mediated chromatin opening. Our findings highlight β-HB as an endogenous metabolite regulating ferroptosis in the pancreas and extend our understanding of the pathophysiology of ALF-induced pancreatitis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Herpes Simplex Virus 1-Induced Ferroptosis Contributes to Viral Encephalitis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36507835/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36507835/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Herpes simplex virus 1 (HSV-1) is a DNA virus belonging to the family Herpesviridae. HSV-1 infection causes severe neurological disease in the central nervous system (CNS), including encephalitis. Ferroptosis is a nonapoptotic form of programmed cell death that contributes to different neurological inflammatory diseases. However, whether HSV-1 induces ferroptosis in the CNS and the role of ferroptosis in viral pathogenesis remain unclear. Here, we demonstrate that HSV-1 induces ferroptosis, as hallmarks of ferroptosis, including Fe&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt; overload, reactive oxygen species (ROS) accumulation, glutathione (GSH) depletion, lipid peroxidation, and mitochondrion shrinkage, are observed in HSV-1-infected cultured human astrocytes, microglia cells, and murine brains. Moreover, HSV-1 infection enhances the E3 ubiquitin ligase Keap1 (Kelch-like ECH-related protein 1)-mediated ubiquitination and degradation of nuclear factor E2-related factor 2 (Nrf2), a transcription factor that regulates the expression of antioxidative genes, thereby disturbing cellular redox homeostasis and promoting ferroptosis. Furthermore, HSV-1-induced ferroptosis is tightly associated with the process of viral encephalitis in a mouse model, and the ferroptosis-activated upregulation of prostaglandin-endoperoxide synthase 2 (PTGS2) and prostaglandin E2 (PGE&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;) plays an important role in HSV-1-caused inflammation and encephalitis. Importantly, the inhibition of ferroptosis by a ferroptosis inhibitor or a proteasome inhibitor to suppress Nrf2 degradation effectively alleviated HSV-1 encephalitis. Together, our findings demonstrate the interaction between HSV-1 infection and ferroptosis and provide novel insights into the pathogenesis of HSV-1 encephalitis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Importance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ferroptosis is a nonapoptotic form of programmed cell death that contributes to different neurological inflammatory diseases. However, whether HSV-1 induces ferroptosis in the CNS and the role of ferroptosis in viral pathogenesis remain unclear. In the current study, we demonstrate that HSV-1 infection induces ferroptosis, as Fe&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt; overload, ROS accumulation, GSH depletion, lipid peroxidation, and mitochondrion shrinkage, all of which are hallmarks of ferroptosis, are observed in human cultured astrocytes, microglia cells, and murine brains infected with HSV-1. Moreover, HSV-1 infection enhances Keap1-dependent Nrf2 ubiquitination and degradation, which results in substantial reductions in the expression levels of antiferroptotic genes downstream of Nrf2, thereby disturbing cellular redox homeostasis and promoting ferroptosis. Furthermore, HSV-1-induced ferroptosis is tightly associated with the process of viral encephalitis in a mouse model, and the ferroptosis-activated upregulation of PTGS2 and PGE2 plays an important role in HSV-1-caused inflammation and encephalitis. Importantly, the inhibition of ferroptosis by either a ferroptosis inhibitor or a proteasome inhibitor to suppress HSV-1-induced Nrf2 degradation effectively alleviates HSV-1-caused neuro-damage and inflammation in infected mice. Overall, our findings uncover the interaction between HSV-1 infection and ferroptosis, shed novel light on the physiological impacts of ferroptosis on the pathogenesis of HSV-1 infection and encephalitis, and provide a promising therapeutic strategy to treat this important infectious disease with a worldwide distribution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When ferroptosis meets pathogenic infections</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/36496309/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/36496309/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pathogens regulate ferroptosis to promote their replication, dissemination, pathogenesis, or evade host immune responses, which benefits the survival of pathogens.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pathogens interact with the classic antioxidant system, the GPX4-dependent pathway, to disturb intracellular lipid ROS elimination, to manipulate ferroptosis execution.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pathogens commandeer lipid ROS by adjusting iron, lipid, and mitochondria metabolism.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Manipulation of pathogen-associated ferroptosis is a promising therapeutic strategy against infectious diseases.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apoptosis, necrosis, or autophagy are diverse types of regulated cell death (RCD), recognized as the strategies that host cells use to defend against pathogens such as viruses, bacteria, or fungi. Pathogens can induce or block different types of host cell RCD, promoting propagation or evading host immune surveillance. Ferroptosis is a newly identified RCD. Evidence has demonstrated how pathogens regulate ferroptosis to promote their replication, dissemination, and pathogenesis. However, the interaction between ferroptosis and pathogenic infections still needs to be completely elucidated. This review summarizes the advances in the interaction between pathogenic infections and host ferroptotic processes, focusing on the underlying mechanisms of how pathogens exploit ferroptosis, and discussing possible therapeutic measures against pathogen-associated diseases in a ferroptosis-dependent manner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Targeting ferroptosis to treat colorectal cancer</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/36473802/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/36473802/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ferroptosis has emerged as a promising target for colorectal cancer (CRC) treatment. Although disrupting glutathione metabolism is the primary strategy for ferroptosis induction, additional key pathways link ferroptosis to CRC pathogenesis. Here, we discuss arachidonic acid (AA), energy metabolism, AMP-activated protein kinase (AMPK), phosphatidylinositol-3-kinase (PI3K)-protein kinase B (Akt)-mammalian target of rapamycin (mTOR), and Hippo signaling, summarize key findings, and propose new conceptual avenues for CRC treatment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Molecular basis for DNA recognition by the maternal pioneer transcription factor FoxH1</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36435807/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36435807/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Forkhead box H1 (FoxH1) is an essential maternal pioneer factor during embryonic development that binds to specific GG/GT-containing DNA target sequences. Here we have determined high-resolution structures of three FoxH1 proteins (from human, frog and fish species) and four DNAs to clarify the way in which FoxH1 binds to these sites. We found that the protein-DNA interactions extend to both the minor and major DNA grooves and are thus almost twice as extensive as those of other FOX family members. Moreover, we identified two specific amino acid changes in FoxH1 that allowed the recognition of GG/GT motifs. Consistent with the pioneer factor activity of FoxH1, we found that its affinity for nucleosomal DNA is even higher than for linear DNA fragments. The structures reported herein illustrate how FoxH1 binding to distinct DNA sites provides specificity and avoids cross-regulation by other FOX proteins that also operate during the maternal-zygotic transition and select canonical forkhead sites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ferroptosis of tumour neutrophils causes immune suppression in cancer</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36385526/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36385526/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ferroptosis is a non-apoptotic form of regulated cell death that is triggered by the discoordination of regulatory redox mechanisms culminating in massive peroxidation of polyunsaturated phospholipids. Ferroptosis inducers have shown considerable effectiveness in killing tumour cells in vitro, yet there has been no obvious success in experimental animal models, with the notable exception of immunodeficient mice. This suggests that the effect of ferroptosis on immune cells remains poorly understood. Pathologically activated neutrophils (PMNs), termed myeloid-derived suppressor cells (PMN-MDSCs), are major negative regulators of anti-tumour immunity. Here we found that PMN-MDSCs in the tumour microenvironment spontaneously die by ferroptosis. Although decreasing the presence of PMN-MDSCs, ferroptosis induces the release of oxygenated lipids and limits the activity of human and mouse T cells. In immunocompetent mice, genetic and pharmacological inhibition of ferroptosis abrogates suppressive activity of PMN-MDSCs, reduces tumour progression and synergizes with immune checkpoint blockade to suppress the tumour growth. By contrast, induction of ferroptosis in immunocompetent mice promotes tumour growth. Thus, ferroptosis is a unique and targetable immunosuppressive mechanism of PMN-MDSCs in the tumour microenvironment that can be pharmacologically modulated to limit tumour progression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ferroptosis inhibitor liproxstatin-1 alleviates metabolic dysfunction-associated fatty liver disease in mice: potential involvement of PANoptosis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36323829/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36323829/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ferroptosis is a new form of regulated cell death characterized by excessive iron accumulation and uncontrollable lipid peroxidation. The role of ferroptosis in metabolic dysfunction-associated fatty liver disease (MAFLD) is not fully elucidated. In this study we compared the therapeutic effects of ferroptosis inhibitor liproxstatin-1 (LPT1) and iron chelator deferiprone (DFP) in MAFLD mouse models. This model was established in mice by feeding a high-fat diet with 30% fructose in water (HFHF) for 16 weeks. The mice then received LPT1 (10 mg·kg&lt;sup&gt;-1&lt;/sup&gt;·d&lt;sup&gt;-1&lt;/sup&gt;, ip) or DFP (100 mg·kg&lt;sup&gt;-1&lt;/sup&gt;·d&lt;sup&gt;-1&lt;/sup&gt;, ig) for another 2 weeks. We showed that both LPT1 and DFP treatment blocked the ferroptosis markers ACSL4 and ALOX15 in MAFLD mice. Furthermore, LPT1 treatment significantly reduced the liver levels of triglycerides and cholesterol, lipid peroxidation markers 4-hydroxynonenal (4-HNE) and malondialdehyde (MDA), and ameliorated the expression of lipid synthesis/oxidation genes (Pparα, Scd1, Fasn, Hmgcr and Cpt1a), insulin resistance, mitochondrial ROS content and liver fibrosis. Importantly, LPT1 treatment potently inhibited hepatic apoptosis (Bax/Bcl-xL ratio and TUNEL+ cell number), pyroptosis (cleavages of Caspase-1 and GSDMD) and necroptosis (phosphorylation of MLKL). Moreover, LPT1 treatment markedly inhibited cleavages of PANoptosis-related caspase-8 and caspase-6 in MAFLD mouse liver. In an in vitro MAFLD model, treatment with LPT1 (100 nM) prevented cultured hepatocyte against cell death induced by pro-PANoptosis molecules (TNF-α, LPS and nigericin) upon lipid stress. On the contrary, DFP treatment only mildly attenuated hepatic inflammation but failed to alleviate lipid deposition, insulin resistance, apoptosis, pyroptosis and necroptosis in MAFLD mice. We conclude that ferroptosis inhibitor LPT1 protects against steatosis and steatohepatitis in MAFLD mice, which may involve regulation of PANoptosis, a coordinated cell death pathway that involves apoptosis, pyroptosis and necroptosis. These results suggest a potential link between ferroptosis and PANoptosis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ROS-triggered endothelial cell death mechanisms: Focus on pyroptosis, parthanatos, and ferroptosis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/36389728/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/36389728/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The endothelium is a single layer of epithelium covering the surface of the vascular system, and it represents a physical barrier between the blood and vessel wall that plays an important role in maintaining intravascular homeostasis. However, endothelial dysfunction or endothelial cell death can cause vascular barrier disruption, vasoconstriction and diastolic dysfunction, vascular smooth muscle cell proliferation and migration, inflammatory responses, and thrombosis, which are closely associated with the progression of several diseases, such as atherosclerosis, hypertension, coronary atherosclerotic heart disease, ischemic stroke, acute lung injury, acute kidney injury, diabetic retinopathy, and Alzheimer&amp;rsquo;s disease. Oxidative stress caused by the overproduction of reactive oxygen species (ROS) is an important mechanism underlying endothelial cell death. Growing evidence suggests that ROS can trigger endothelial cell death in various ways, including pyroptosis, parthanatos, and ferroptosis. Therefore, this review will systematically illustrate the source of ROS in endothelial cells (ECs); reveal the molecular mechanism by which ROS trigger pyroptosis, parthanatos, and ferroptosis in ECs; and provide new ideas for the research and treatment of endothelial dysfunction-related diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FerrDb V2: update of the manually curated database of ferroptosis regulators and ferroptosis-disease associations</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36305834/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36305834/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.zhounan.org/ferrdb/current/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;FerrDb&lt;/a&gt; is the world&amp;rsquo;s first database that dedicates to ferroptosis regulators and ferroptosis-disease associations. There are two secondary categories of ferroptosis regulators: (1) genes and (2) substances. Gene regulators include driver, suppressor, marker, and unclassified regulator. Substances cover a wide range of chemical entities, including pure substances (e.g., iron, erastin) and mixtures (e.g., herbal extracts). Substance regulators include inducers and inhibitors. On the basis of this philosophy, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.zhounan.org/ferrdb/current/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;FerrDb&lt;/a&gt; consists of seven independent curated data sets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!---more---&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ferroptosis is a mode of regulated cell death characterized by iron-dependent accumulation of lipid peroxidation. It is closely linked to the pathophysiological processes in many diseases. Since our publication of the first ferroptosis database in 2020 (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.zhounan.org/ferrdb/current/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;FerrDb&lt;/a&gt; V1), many new findings have been published. To keep up with the rapid progress in ferroptosis research and to provide timely and high-quality data, here we present the successor, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.zhounan.org/ferrdb/current/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;FerrDb&lt;/a&gt; V2. It contains 1001 ferroptosis regulators and 143 ferroptosis-disease associations manually curated from 3288 articles. Specifically, there are 621 gene regulators, of which 264 are drivers, 238 are suppressors, 9 are markers, and 110 are unclassified genes; and there are 380 substance regulators, with 201 inducers and 179 inhibitors. Compared to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.zhounan.org/ferrdb/current/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;FerrDb&lt;/a&gt; V1, curated articles increase by &amp;gt;300%, ferroptosis regulators increase by 175%, and ferroptosis-disease associations increase by 50.5%. Circular RNA and pseudogene are novel regulators in &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.zhounan.org/ferrdb/current/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;FerrDb&lt;/a&gt; V2, and the percentage of non-coding RNA increases from 7.3% to 13.6%. External gene-related data were integrated, enabling thought-provoking and gene-oriented analysis in FerrDb V2. In conclusion, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.zhounan.org/ferrdb/current/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;FerrDb&lt;/a&gt; V2 will help to acquire deeper insights into ferroptosis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Naringenin attenuates inflammation, apoptosis, and ferroptosis in silver nanoparticle-induced lung injury through a mechanism associated with Nrf2/HO-1 axis: In vitro and in vivo studies</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36306867/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36306867/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the wide application of silver nanoparticles (AgNPs), their potential damage to human health needs to be investigated. Lung is one of the main target organs after inhalation of AgNPs. Naringenin has been reported to have anti-inflammatory and anti-oxidative properties. This study aims to evaluate the protective effects of naringenin against AgNPs-induced lung injury and determine the underlying mechanism. In in vivo experiments, AgNPs were intratracheally instilled into ICR mice (l mg/kg) to establish a lung injury model. These mice were then treated with naringenin by oral gavage (25, 50, 100 mg/kg) for three days. Naringenin treatment decreased the levels of white blood cells, neutrophils, and lymphocytes in the blood, ameliorated lung injury, suppressed the release of pro-inflammatory cytokines, normalized ferroptotic markers and prevented oxidative stress with elevating Nrf2 and HO-1 protein expressions in lung. In in vitro experiments, BEAS-2B cells were firstly treated with AgNPs (320 μg/mL) and then naringenin (25, 50, and 100 μM), respectively. Naringenin attenuated AgNPs-induced oxidative stress and inflammatory response. Moreover, naringenin attenuated AgNPs-induced apoptosis with modulated low BAX, CytC, cleaved Caspase9, cleaved Caspase3 but high Bcl2. Furthermore, naringenin effectively decreased ferroptotic markers and increased the protein expressions of Nrf2 and HO-1, as well as increased the nuclear translocation of Nrf2. Importantly, the anti-apoptotic and anti-ferroptotic effects of naringenin in BEAS-2B cells were found to be at least partially Nrf2-dependent. These results indicated that naringenin exerted anti-inflammation, anti-apoptosis, and anti-ferroptosis effects and protected against AgNPs-induced lung injury at least partly via activating Nrf2/HO-1 signaling pathway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inhibition of ferroptosis and iron accumulation alleviates pulmonary fibrosis in a bleomycin model</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36302319/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36302319/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis (IPF) is a chronic progressive disease characterized by excessive proliferation of fibroblasts and excessive accumulation of extracellular matrix (ECM). Ferroptosis is a novel form of cell death characterized by the lethal accumulation of iron and lipid peroxidation, which is associated with many diseases. Our study addressed the potential role played by ferroptosis and iron accumulation in the progression of pulmonary fibrosis. We found that the inducers of pulmonary fibrosis and injury, namely, bleomycin (BLM) and lipopolysaccharide (LPS), induced ferroptosis of lung epithelial cells. Both the ferroptosis inhibitor liproxstatin-1 (Lip-1) and the iron chelator deferoxamine (DFO) alleviated the symptoms of pulmonary fibrosis induced by bleomycin or LPS. TGF-β stimulation upregulated the expression of transferrin receptor protein 1 (TFRC) in the human lung fibroblast cell line (MRC-5) and mouse primary lung fibroblasts, resulting in increased intracellular Fe&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt;, which promoted the transformation of fibroblasts into myofibroblasts. Mechanistically, TGF-β enhanced the expression and nuclear localization of the transcriptional coactivator tafazzin (TAZ), which combined with the transcription factor TEA domain protein (TEAD)-4 to promote the transcription of TFRC. In addition, elevated Fe&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt; failed to induce the ferroptosis of fibroblasts, which might be related to the regulation of iron export and lipid metabolism. Finally, we specifically knocked out TFRC expression in fibroblasts in mice, and compared with those in the control mice, the symptoms of pulmonary fibrosis were reduced in the knockout mice after bleomycin induction. Collectively, these findings suggest the therapeutic potential of ferroptosis inhibitors and iron chelators in treating pulmonary fibrosis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Astaxanthin attenuates ferroptosis via Keap1-Nrf2/HO-1 signaling pathways in LPS-induced acute lung injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36252699/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36252699/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Astaxanthin prevents against LPS-induced acute lung injury.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Astaxanthin alleviates LPS-induced acute lung injury via inhibiting ferroptosis.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Astaxanthin attenuates ferroptosis against lps-induced acute lung injury by Keap1-Nrf2/HO-1 pathway.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ferroptosis is a form of regulated nonapoptotic cell death associated with iron-dependent lipid peroxidation. Previous studies have shown that ferroptosis is involved in the occurrence and development of acute lung injury (ALI). In this study, a systems pharmacology approach was performed through the overall process of target acquisition, network construction, and further analysis. Then, the effects of astaxanthin on LPS-induced inflammation and ferroptosis were investigated in RAW264.7 cells induced by LPS in vitro and ALI mice induced by LPS in vivo. The enrichment analysis of astaxanthin-target gene is closely related to the occurrence and development mechanism of ferroptosis. GO and KEGG enrichment analysis of astaxanthin acting on ALI found that these intersection genes are associated with ALI inflammatory pathway. In addition, astaxanthin can effectively inhibit LPS-induced production of pro-inflammatory cytokines and ferroptosis in RAW264.7 cells. Consistently, administration of astaxanthin protected mice against LPS-induced ALI and significantly decreased the extent of lung edema, inflammatory cells infiltration, and ferroptosis in vivo, and Keap1-Nrf2/HO-1 pathway is involved in astaxanthin inhibits LPS-induced ALI and ferroptosis. Taken together, these results demonstrate that astaxanthin inhibit inflammation and ferroptosis by regulating Keap1-Nrf2/HO-1 pathway to reduce LPS-induced ALI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Astragaloside IV regulates the ferroptosis signaling pathway via the Nrf2/SLC7A11/GPX4 axis to inhibit PM2.5-mediated lung injury in mice</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/36115280/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/36115280/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PM2.5-induced lung injury was associated with the ferroptosis and inflammation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Astragaloside IV pre-treatment attenuates PM2.5-induced lung injury by inhibiting ferroptosis via Nrf2/SLC7A11/GPX4 axis.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Astragaloside IV is a potential drug for prevention of PM2.5-induced respiratory disease.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Objective:&lt;/em&gt; Exposure to PM2.5 will increase the risk of respiratory disease and increase the burden of social health care. Astragaloside Ⅳ (Ast-IV) is one of the main biologically active substances form Chinese herb Astragalus membranaceus, which owns various pharmacological effects. Ferroptosis is a novel form of cell death characterized by accumulation of iron-dependent lipid reactive oxygen species (ROS). It is not clear whether there are typical features of ferroptosis in PM2.5-induced lung injury. This study investigates whether PM2.5-induced lung injury in mice has a special form of ferroptosis and the specific protective mechanism of Ast-IV.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Subjects and methods:&lt;/em&gt; Forty-two male C57BL/6J mice were randomly divided into six groups (n = 7 per group): NS group (normal saline), Ast group (Ast-IV 100 mg/kg), PM2.5 group, Ast-L group (Ast-IV 50 mg/kg + PM2.5), Ast-H group (Ast-IV 100 mg/kg + PM2.5) and Era group (Ast-IV 100 mg/kg + erastin 20 mg/kg + PM2.5). Mice were pre-treated with Ast-IV intraperitoneally for three days. Then, PM2.5 (7.5 mg/kg) was given by non-invasive tracheal instillation to induce lung injury. The ferroptosis&amp;rsquo; agonist erastin was used to verify the mechanism of Ast-IV anti-ferroptosis. 12 h after PM2.5 stimulation, the mice were euthanized. Bronchoalveolar lavage fluid (BALF) and serum were collected for oxidative stress and cytokine determination. Lung tissues were collected for glutathione (GSH), tissue iron content, histology, immunofluorescence, transmission electron microscopy, and western blot analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; Ast-IV reduced the lung wet-dry ratio and the levels of interleukin 6 (IL-6), tumor necrosis factor-α (TNF-α) and interleukin 1β (IL-1β) in serum. Ast-IV could also improve the oxidative stress level in BALF, restore the GSH level in the lung tissue, and reduce the iron content in the lung tissue. Western blot outcomes revealed that Ast-IV regulated the ferroptosis signaling pathway via the Nrf2/SLC7A11/GPX4 axis to protect PM2.5-mediated lung injury.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/em&gt; The protective effect of Ast-IV on PM2.5-induced lung injury in mice might be related to the inhibition of ferroptosis in lung tissue. Anti-ferroptosis might be a new mechanism of Ast-IV on PM2.5-induced lung injury.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pretreatment with rosavin attenuates PM2.5-induced lung injury in rats through antiferroptosis via PI3K/Akt/Nrf2 signaling pathway</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36097321/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36097321/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inflammation and oxidative stress caused by fine particulate matter (PM2.5) increase the incidence and mortality rates of respiratory disorders. Rosavin is the main chemical component of Rhodiola plants, which exerts anti-oxidative and antiinflammatory effects. In this research, the potential therapeutic effect of rosavin was investigated by the PM2.5-induced lung injury rat model. Rats were instilled with PM2.5 (7.5 mg/kg) suspension intratracheally, while rosavin (50 mg/kg, 100 mg/kg) was delivered by intraperitoneal injection before the PM2.5 injection. It was observed that rosavin could prevent lung injury caused by PM2.5. PM2.5 showed obvious ferroptosis-related ultrastructural alterations, which were significantly corrected by rosavin. The pretreatment with rosavin downregulated the levels of tissue iron, malondialdehyde, and 4-hydroxynonenal, and increased the levels of glutathione. The expression of nuclear factor E2-related factor 2 (Nrf2) was upregulated by rosavin, together with other ferroptosis-related proteins. RSL3, a specific ferroptosis agonist, reversed the beneficial impact of rosavin. The network pharmacology approach predicted the activation of rosavin on the phosphatidylinositol 3-kinase (PI3K)/protein kinase B (Akt) signaling pathway. LY294002, a potent PI3K inhibitor, decreased the upregulation of Nrf2 induced by rosavin. In conclusion, rosavin prevented lung injury induced by PM2.5 stimulation and suppressed ferroptosis via upregulating PI3K/Akt/Nrf2 signaling pathway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Molecular Mechanisms of Ferroptosis and Relevance to Cardiovascular Disease</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/36078133/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/36078133/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ferroptosis has recently been demonstrated to be a novel regulated non-apoptotic cell death characterized by iron-dependence and the accumulation of lipid peroxidation that results in membrane damage. Excessive iron induces ferroptosis by promoting the generation of both soluble and lipid ROS via an iron-dependent Fenton reaction and lipoxygenase (LOX) enzyme activity. Cytosolic glutathione peroxidase 4 (cGPX4) pairing with ferroptosis suppressor protein 1 (FSP1) and mitochondrial glutathione peroxidase 4 (mGPX4) pairing with dihydroorotate dehydrogenase (DHODH) serve as two separate defense systems to detoxify lipid peroxidation in the cytoplasmic as well as the mitochondrial membrane, thereby defending against ferroptosis in cells under normal conditions. However, disruption of these defense systems may cause ferroptosis. Emerging evidence has revealed that ferroptosis plays an essential role in the development of diverse cardiovascular diseases (CVDs), such as hemochromatosis-associated cardiomyopathy, doxorubicin-induced cardiotoxicity, ischemia/reperfusion (I/R) injury, heart failure (HF), atherosclerosis, and COVID-19-related arrhythmias. Iron chelators, antioxidants, ferroptosis inhibitors, and genetic manipulations may alleviate the aforementioned CVDs by blocking ferroptosis pathways. In conclusion, ferroptosis plays a critical role in the pathogenesis of various CVDs and suppression of cardiac ferroptosis is expected to become a potential therapeutic option. Here, we provide a comprehensive review on the molecular mechanisms involved in ferroptosis and its implications in cardiovascular disease.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Long noncoding RNA LINC00239 inhibits ferroptosis in colorectal cancer by binding to Keap1 to stabilize Nrf2</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36038548/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36038548/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ferroptosis, a novel regulated cell death induced by iron-dependent lipid peroxidation, plays an important role in tumor development and drug resistance. Long noncoding RNAs (lncRNAs) are associated with various types of cancer. However, the precise roles of many lncRNAs in tumorigenesis remain elusive. Here we explored the transcriptomic profiles of lncRNAs in primary CRC tissues and corresponding paired adjacent non-tumor tissues by RNA-seq and found that LINC00239 was significantly overexpressed in colorectal cancer tissues. Abnormally high expression of LINC00239 predicts poorer survival and prognosis in colorectal cancer patients. Concurrently, we elucidated the role of LINC00239 as a tumor-promoting factor in CRC through in vitro functional studies and in vivo tumor xenograft models. Importantly, overexpression of LINC00239 decreased the anti-tumor activity of erastin and RSL3 by inhibiting ferroptosis. Collectively, these data suggest that LINC00239 plays a novel and indispensable role in ferroptosis by nucleotides 1-315 of LINC00239 to interact with the Kelch domain (Nrf2-binding site) of Keap1, inhibiting Nrf2 ubiquitination and increasing Nrf2 protein stability. Considering the recurrence and chemoresistance constitute the leading cause of death in colorectal cancer (CRC), ferroptosis induction may be a promising therapeutic strategy for CRC patients with low LINC00239 expression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adipocyte-Derived Exosomal MTTP Suppresses Ferroptosis and Promotes Chemoresistance in Colorectal Cancer</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35978266/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35978266/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Obesity is closely related to a poor prognosis in patients with advanced colorectal cancer (CRC), but the mechanisms remain unclear. Ferroptosis is a form of nonapoptotic cell death characterized by lipid reactive oxygen species (ROS) accumulation and iron dependency and is associated with the chemoresistance of tumors. Here, it is shown that adipose-derived exosomes reduce ferroptosis susceptibility in CRC, thus promoting chemoresistance to oxaliplatin. It is found that microsomal triglyceride transfer protein (MTTP) expression is increased in the plasma exosomes of CRC patients with a high body fat ratio, serving as an inhibitor of ferroptosis and reducing sensitivity to chemotherapy. Mechanistically, the MTTP/proline-rich acidic protein 1 (PRAP1) complex inhibited zinc finger E-box binding homeobox 1 expression and upregulated glutathione peroxidase 4 and xCT, leading to a decreased polyunsaturated fatty acids ratio and lipid ROS levels. Moreover, experiments are carried out in organoids, and a tumor implantation model is established in obese mice, demonstrating that the inhibition of MTTP increases the sensitivity to chemotherapy. The results reveal a novel intracellular signaling pathway mediated by adipose-derived exosomes and suggest that treatments targeting secreted MTTP might reverse oxaliplatin resistance in CRC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Identification of the key ferroptosis-related genes involved in sepsis progression and experimental validation in vivo</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36188533/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36188533/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Ferroptosis has a vital role in sepsis, but the mechanism is not known. Understanding the mechanism of ferroptosis during sepsis will aid in developing improved therapeutic strategies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; We used the Gene Expression Omnibus database and FerrDb database to obtain ferroptosis-related differentially expressed genes (DEGs) between sepsis patients and healthy volunteers (HVs). Analyses of PPI networks, functional enrichment, as well as use of the MCODE algorithm were used to identify key ferroptosis-related DEGs. Expression of key ferroptosis-related DEGs was verified using: GSE57065 and GSE65682 datasets; rats in which ferroptosis was induced with erastin; sepsis-induced acute lung injury (siALI) rats. The effects of acupoint catgut embedding (ACE) on ferroptosis and expression of key ferroptosis-related DEGs in the lungs of siALI rats were also observed. A Cox proportional hazard model was used to verify the effect of key ferroptosis-related DEGs on the survival of sepsis patients. Cytoscape was used to construct ceRNA networks and gene-transcription factor networks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; Between sepsis patients and HVs, we identified 33 ferroptosis-related DEGs. According to analyses of PPI networks and the MCODE algorithm, we obtained four modules, of which the most significant module contained nine ferroptosis-related DEGs. Functional-enrichment analyses showed that four of the nine DEGs were enriched in the MAPK signaling pathway: &lt;em&gt;MAPK14&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;VEGFA&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;TGFBR1&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;DUSP1&lt;/em&gt;. We verified expression of these four genes in GSE57065 and GSE65682 datasets and ferroptosis rats. In addition, expression of these four genes and that of the oxidative-stress indicators GSSG and MDA was upregulated, and glutathione peroxidase-4 (GPX4) expression was downregulated, in siALI rats, but ACE reversed these changes. The Cox proportional hazard model showed that survival of sepsis patients in the high-risk group was shorter than that in the low-risk group. We found that the XIST-hsa-let-7b-5p-TGFBR1/DUSP1 ceRNA network and transcription factor E2F1 may be important regulators of these four DEGs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/em&gt; Our results suggest that &lt;em&gt;MAPK14&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;VEGFA,&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;TGFBR1&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;DUSP1&lt;/em&gt; may be key regulatory targets of ferroptosis in sepsis, and that ACE pretreatment may be antioxidant treatment for sepsis and alleviate ferroptosis. These findings provide a basis for further ferroptosis-related study in sepsis and provide new targets for its treatment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>YAP1 alleviates sepsis-induced acute lung injury via inhibiting ferritinophagy-mediated ferroptosis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35979359/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35979359/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ferroptosis is a phospholipid peroxidation-mediated and iron-dependent cell death form, involved in sepsis-induced organ injury and other lung diseases. Yes-associated protein 1 (YAP1), a key regulator of the Hippo signaling pathway, could target multiple ferroptosis regulators. Herein, this study aimed to explore the involvement of ferroptosis in the etiopathogenesis of sepsis-induced acute lung injury (ALI) and demonstrate that YAP1 could disrupt ferritinophagy and moderate sepsis-induced ALI. Cecal ligation and puncture (CLP) models were constructed in wild-type (WT) and pulmonary epithelium-conditional knockout (YAP1f/f) mice to induce ALI, while MLE-12 cells with or without YAP1 overexpression were stimulated by lipopolysaccharide (LPS) in vitro. In-vivo modes showed that YAP1 knockout aggravated CLP-induced ALI and also accelerated pulmonary ferroptosis, as presented by the downregulated expression of GPX4, FTH1, and SLC7A11, along with the upregulated expression of SFXN1 and NCOA4. Transcriptome research identified these key genes and ferroptosis pathways involved in sepsis-induced ALI. In-vitro modes consistently verified that YAP1 deficiency boosted the ferrous iron accumulation and mitochondrial dysfunction in response to LPS. Furthermore, the co-IP assay revealed that YAP1 overexpression could prevent the degradation of ferritin to a mass of Fe2+ (ferritinophagy) via disrupting the NCOA4-FTH1 interaction, which blocked the transport of cytoplasmic Fe2+ into the mitochondria via the mitochondrial membrane protein (SFXN1), further reducing the generation of mitochondrial ROS. Therefore, these findings revealed that YAP1 could inhibit ferroptosis in a ferritinophagy-mediated manner, thus alleviating sepsis-induced ALI, which may provide a new approach to the therapeutic orientation for sepsis-induced ALI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ACSL4 is essential for radiation-induced intestinal injury by initiating ferroptosis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35869042/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35869042/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lipid peroxidation-induced ferroptosis is a newly recognized type of programmed cell death. With the method of RNA sequencing, we found that irradiation (IR) markedly increased the expression of ferroptosis promotive genes, whereas reduced the expression of ferroptosis suppressive genes in murine intestine tissues, when compared with those of liver and lung tissues. By using ferroptosis inducer RSL-3 and inhibitor liproxstatin-1, we found that ferroptosis is essential for IR-induced intestinal injury. Acyl-CoA Synthetase Long-Chain Family Member 4 (ACSL4) is an important component for ferroptosis execution, and we found that ACSL4 expression was significantly upregulated in irradiated intestine tissues, but not in liver or lung tissues. Antibacterial and antifungal regents reduced the expression of ASCL4 and protected against tissue injury in irradiated intestine tissues. Further studies showed that troglitazone, a ACSL4 inhibitor, succeeded to suppresses intestine lipid peroxidation and tissue damage after IR.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mucin 1 Inhibits Ferroptosis and Sensitizes Vitamin E to Alleviate Sepsis-Induced Acute Lung Injury through GSK3 β/Keap1-Nrf2-GPX4 Pathway</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35910848/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35910848/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Ferroptosis is a nonapoptotic form of programmed cell death, which may be related to the occurrence and development of sepsis-induced acute respiratory distress syndrome (ARDS)/acute lung injury (ALI). Mucin 1 (MUC1) is a kind of macromolecule transmembrane glycoprotein. Previous studies have shown that MUC1 could relieve ALI in sepsis and predict whether sepsis patients would develop into ARDS. However, the role of MUC1 in the ferroptosis of sepsis-induced ALI/ARDS remains unclear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Materials and methods:&lt;/em&gt; Sera samples from 50 patients with sepsis/septic shock were used to detect iron metabolism-related markers. Western blot and qRT-PCR were conducted to detect the expression levels of ferroptosis-related genes. Enzyme-linked immunosorbent assay (ELISA) was performed to evaluate inflammatory factors. Transmission electron microscopy (TEM) was used to assess morphological changes of cells.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; The results showed that the iron metabolism-related indicators in sepsis-induced ARDS patients changed significantly, suggesting the iron metabolism disorder. The expression levels of ferroptosis-related genes in lung tissues of sepsis had marked changes, and the lipid peroxidation levels increased, while Ferrostatin-1 (Fer-1) could reverse the above results, which confirmed the occurrence of ferroptosis. In terms of mechanism studies, inhibition of MUC1 dimerization could increase the expression level of Keap1, reduce the phosphorylation level of GSK3β, inhibit the entry of Nrf2 into the nucleus, further inhibit the expression level of GPX4, enhance the lipid peroxidation level of lung tissues, trigger ferroptosis, and aggravate lung injury. Besides, inhibiting MUC1 reversed the alleviating effect of vitamin E on ALI caused by sepsis, increased the aggregation of inflammatory cells in lung tissues, and aggravated alveolar injury and edema.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; Our study was the first to explore the changes of iron metabolism indicators in ALI/ARDS of sepsis, clarify the important role of ferroptosis in ALI/ARDS induced by sepsis, and reveal the effects and specific mechanisms of MUC1 in regulating ferroptosis, as well as the sensitization on vitamin E.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exosomal lncRNA TUG1 derived from human urine-derived stem cells attenuates renal ischemia/reperfusion injury by interacting with SRSF1 to regulate ASCL4-mediated ferroptosis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35841017/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35841017/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;LncRNA TUG1 carried by USC-Exo regulates cell ferroptosis.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;LncRNA TUG1 regulates the stability of ACSL4 mRNA by interacting with SRSF1.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;LncRNA TUG1 alleviates IRI-induced AKI by suppressing ACSL4-mediated ferroptosis.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Human urine-derived stem cells (USCs)-derived exosomes (USC-Exo) could improve kidney ischemia/reperfusion injury (IRI), while the underlying mechanisms of this protective effect remain unclear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; Human USCs and USC-Exo were isolated and verified by morphology and specific biomarkers. The effects of USC-Exo on ferroptosis and kidney injury were detected in the IRI-induced acute kidney injury (AKI) model in C57BL/6 mice. The effects of USC-Exo on ferroptosis and lncRNA taurine-upregulated gene 1 (TUG1) were detected in hypoxia/reoxygenation (H/R)-treated human proximal tubular epithelial cells (HK-2). The interaction of SRSF1 and TUG1, ACSL4 was checked via RNA pull-down/RIP and RNA stability assays. The effects of LncRNA TUG1 on SRSF1/ACSL4-mediated ferroptosis were verified in H/R-treated HK-2 cells and the IRI-induced AKI mouse models.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; USC-Exo treatment improved kidney injury and ameliorated ferroptosis in IRI-induced AKI mouse models. USC-Exo were rich in lncRNA TUG1, which suppressed ferroptosis in HK-2 cells exposed to H/R. Mechanistically, lncRNA TUG1 regulates the stability of ACSL4 mRNA by interacting with RNA-binding protein SRSF1. In addition, SRSF1 upregulation or ACSL4 downregulation partially reversed the protective effect of lncRNA TUG1 on ferroptosis in H/R-treated HK-2 cells. Further, ACSL4 upregulation partially reversed TUG1&amp;rsquo;s repression on kidney injury and ferroptosis in IRI-induced AKI mice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/em&gt; Collectively, lncRNA TUG1 carried by USC-Exo regulated ASCL4-mediated ferroptosis by interacting with SRSF1 and then protected IRI-induced AKI. Potentially, USC-Exo rich in lncRNA TUG1 can serve as a promising therapeutic method for IRI-AKI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ferroptosis turns 10: Emerging mechanisms, physiological functions, and therapeutic applications</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/35803244/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/35803244/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ferroptosis, a form of cell death driven by iron-dependent lipid peroxidation, was identified as a distinct phenomenon and named a decade ago. Ferroptosis has been implicated in a broad set of biological contexts, from development to aging, immunity, and cancer. This review describes key regulators of this form of cell death within a framework of metabolism, ROS biology, and iron biology. Key concepts and major unanswered questions in the ferroptosis field are highlighted. The next decade promises to yield further breakthroughs in the mechanisms governing ferroptosis and additional ways of harnessing ferroptosis for therapeutic benefit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Activation of the P62-Keap1-NRF2 Pathway Protects against Ferroptosis in Radiation-Induced Lung Injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35847598/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35847598/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Radiation-induced lung injury (RILI) is one of the most common, serious, and dose-limiting toxicities of thoracic radiotherapy. A primary cause for this is the radiation-induced cell death. Ferroptosis is a recently recognized form of regulated cell death, characterized by the accumulation of lipid peroxidation products and lethal reactive oxygen species (ROS). The ROS generated by irradiation might be the original trigger of ferroptosis in RILI. In addition, activation of the P62-Kelch-like ECH-associated protein 1 (Keap1)-nuclear factor erythroid 2-related factor 2 (NRF2) pathway has been shown to blunt ferroptosis and thus acts as a protective factor. Therefore, this study aimed to explore the protective effect of the P62-Keap1-NRF2 pathway against radiation-induced ferroptosis in alveolar epithelial cells. First, we found that radiation induced ferroptosis in vitro using a RILI cell model, which could be significantly reduced by ferrostatin-1 (Fer-1), a specific ferroptosis inhibitor. Additionally, overexpression of P62 interacted with Keap1 to facilitate the translocation of NRF2 into the nucleus and promote the expression of its target proteins, including quinone oxidoreductase 1 (NQO1), heme oxygenase 1 (HO1), and ferritin heavy chain 1 (FTH1). In summary, our results demonstrated that the activation of the P62-Keap1-NRF2 pathway prevents radiation-induced ferroptosis in RILI cells, providing a theoretical basis of finding a potential therapeutic approach for RILI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Role of Ferroptosis in Acute Kidney Injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/35860360/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/35860360/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ferroptosis is a novel cell death method discovered in recent years. It is usually accompanied by massive accumulations of iron and lipid peroxidation during cell death. Recent studies have shown that ferroptosis is closely associated with the pathophysiological processes of many diseases, such as tumors, neurological diseases, localized ischemia-reperfusion injury, kidney injury, and hematological diseases. How to intervene in the incidence and development of associated diseases by regulating the ferroptosis of cells has become a hot topic of research. This article provides a review of the role of ferroptosis in the pathogenesis and potential treatment of acute kidney injury.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multifaceted Roles of Ferroptosis in Lung Diseases</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/35813823/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/35813823/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ferroptosis is a distinct type of programmed cell death (PCD) that depends on iron and is characterized by the accumulation of intracellular iron, exhaustion of glutathione, deactivation of glutathione peroxidase, and promotion of lipid peroxidation. Recently, accumulated investigations have demonstrated that ferroptosis is strongly correlated with the initiation and development of many lung diseases. In this review, we summarized the contribution of ferroptosis to the pathologic process of lung diseases, namely, obstructive lung diseases (chronic obstructive pulmonary disease, asthma, and cystic fibrosis), interstitial lung diseases (pulmonary fibrosis of different causes), pulmonary diseases of vascular origin (ischemia-reperfusion injury and pulmonary hypertension), pulmonary infections (bacteria, viruses, and fungi), acute lung injury, acute respiratory distress syndrome, obstructive sleep apnea, pulmonary alveolar proteinosis, and lung cancer. We also discussed the therapeutic potential of targeting ferroptosis for these lung diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Farnesoid X receptor protects against cisplatin-induced acute kidney injury by regulating the transcription of ferroptosis-related genes</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35767918/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35767918/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The side effects of cisplatin, a widely used chemotherapeutic agent, include nephrotoxicity. Previous studies have reported that cisplatin induces ferroptosis and lipid peroxide accumulation. Ferroptosis, a type of regulated cell death, is characterized by iron-dependent lipid peroxidation. Although previous studies have examined the regulation of ferroptosis in acute kidney injury (AKI), the regulatory mechanism of ferroptosis has not been elucidated. Here, the ability of activated farnesoid X receptor (FXR) to attenuate cisplatin-induced AKI through the regulation of ferroptosis was examined. FXR deficiency exhibited more ferroptosis responses, such as increase in lipid peroxidation, iron content and heme oxygenase 1 protein, and a decrease in glutathione/glutathione disulfide ratio and glutathione peroxidase 4 levels in HK2 cells and mice. Increased blood urea nitrogen, serum creatinine, and ferroptotic responses in the cisplatin-induced AKI mouse model were mitigated upon treatment with the FXR agonist GW4064 but were exacerbated in FXR knockout mice. RNA sequencing analysis revealed that ferroptosis-associated genes were novel targets of FXR. FXR agonist upregulated the expression of lipid and glutathione metabolism-related genes and downregulated cell death-related genes. Additionally, chromatin immunoprecipitation assays, using mice renal tissues, revealed that agonist-activated FXR could bind to its known target genes (Slc51a, Slc51b, Osgin1, and Mafg) and ferroptosis-related genes (Aifm2, Ggt6, and Gsta4). Furthermore, activated FXR-dependent MAFG, a transcriptional repressor, could bind to Hmox1, Nqo1, and Tf in the renal tissues of FXR agonist-treated mice. These findings indicate that activated FXR regulates the transcription of ferroptosis-related genes and protects against cisplatin-induced AKI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Targeting ferroptosis as a vulnerability in cancer</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/35338310/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/35338310/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ferroptosis is an iron-dependent form of regulated cell death that is triggered by the toxic build-up of lipid peroxides on cellular membranes. In recent years, ferroptosis has garnered enormous interest in cancer research communities, partly because it is a unique cell death modality that is mechanistically and morphologically different from other forms of cell death, such as apoptosis, and therefore holds great potential for cancer therapy. In this Review, we summarize the current understanding of ferroptosis-inducing and ferroptosis defence mechanisms, dissect the roles and mechanisms of ferroptosis in tumour suppression and tumour immunity, conceptualize the diverse vulnerabilities of cancer cells to ferroptosis, and explore therapeutic strategies for targeting ferroptosis in cancer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Isoliquiritin apioside relieves intestinal ischemia/reperfusion-induced acute lung injury by blocking Hif-1α-mediated ferroptosis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35597117/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35597117/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlight&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IA lightened intestinal I/R-induced injury, inflammation and ferroptosis in lung tissues.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hif-1α activation promoted lung epithelial ferroptosis.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hif-1α activation abolished the effect of IA on H/R-induced lung epithelial ferroptosis.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Isoliquiritin apioside (IA), a critical ingredient of Glycyrrhizae radix et rhizoma, has been unveiled to possess remarkable pharmacological activity against oxidative stress and inflammation. However, the potential roles of IA in intestinal ischemia/reperfusion (I/R)-induced acute lung injury (ALI) have not been reported yet. In the present study, we explored the effects of IA on I/R-induced ALI, and also clarified the possible mechanisms. To mimic intestinal I/R-induced ALI, the mice were subjected to 60 min of intestinal ischemia via clamping of the superior mesenteric artery followed by 60 min of reperfusion. IA was administered orally (20 mg/kg/day and 50 mg/kg/day) for 7 consecutive days before intestinal I/R. Lung epithelial MLE-2 cells were subjected to hypoxia for 2 h and regeneration for 3 h to mimic in vitro ALI. The results showed that IA administration prevented intestinal I/R-induced lung injury, inflammation and edema. Also, IA administration decreased the level of ferroptosis in murine lung tissues challenged with intestinal I/R. In terms of mechanism, IA administration inhibited the protein upregulation of Hif-1α and HO-1 in mice with ALI. In vitro experiments further demonstrated that IA treatment could inhibit the mRNA and protein levels of Hif-1α in hypoxia/regeneration (H/R)-induced MLE-2 cells in a concentration-dependent manner. Hif-1α stabilizer molidustat itself also significantly promoted ferroptosis of MLE-2 cells. And Hif-1α activation increased the mRNA levels of Ptgs2 and Acsl4 but decreased the mRNA level of Gpx4 in H/R-induced MLE-2 cells treated with IA. Taken together, our study unveiled IA could protect against intestinal I/R-induced ALI by decreasing lung epithelial ferroptosis in a Hif-1α-dependent manner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sipeimine ameliorates PM2.5-induced lung injury by inhibiting ferroptosis via the PI3K/Akt/Nrf2 pathway: A network pharmacology approach</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35567927/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35567927/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PM2.5 exposure can cause lung injury and a large number of respiratory disorders.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sipeimine ameliorated lung injury caused by PM2.5.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sipeimine decreased ferroptosis in type II alveolar epithelial cells.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The effects of sipeimine were mediated through the PI3K/Akt signaling pathway.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fine particulate matter (PM2.5) exposure can cause lung injury and a large number of respiratory diseases. Sipeimine is a steroidal alkaloid isolated from Fritillaria roylei which has been associated with anti-inflammatory, antitussive and antiasthmatic properties. In this study, we explored the potential effects of sipeimine against PM2.5-induced lung injury in Sprague Dawley rats. Sipeimine alleviated lung injury caused by PM2.5 and decreased pulmonary edema, inflammation and the levels of tumor necrosis factor-α (TNF-α) and interleukin-1β (IL-1β) in the bronchoalveolar lavage fluid. In addition, sipeimine upregulated the glutathione (GSH) expression and downregulated the expression of 4-hydroxynonenal (4-HNE), tissue iron and malondialdehyde (MDA). The downregulation of proteins involved in ferroptosis, including nuclear factor E2-related factor 2 (Nrf2), glutathione peroxidase 4 (GPX4), heme oxygenase-1 (HO-1) and solute carrier family 7 member 11 (SLC7A11) was reversed by sipeimine. The administration of RSL3, a potent ferroptosis-triggering agent, blocked the effects of sipeimine. Using network pharmacology, we found that the effects of sipeimine were presumably mediated through the phosphatidylinositol 3-kinase/protein kinase B (PI3K/Akt) signaling pathway. A PI3K inhibitor (LY294002) blocked the PI3K/Akt signaling pathway and reversed the effects of sipeimine. Overall, this study suggested that the protective effect of sipeimine against PM2.5-induced lung injury was mainly mediated through the PI3K/Akt pathway, ultimately leading to a reduction in ferroptosis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Patulin Induces Acute Kidney Injury in Mice through Autophagy-Ferroptosis Pathway</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35543324/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35543324/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Patulin (PAT) is a common mycotoxin, widely found in cereals, seafood, nuts, and especially in fruits and their products. Exposure to this mycotoxin has been reported to induce kidney injury. However, the possible mechanism remains unclear. In our study, short-term high-dose intake of PAT caused acute kidney injury (AKI) in mice. We performed high-throughput transcriptional sequencing to identify differentially expressed genes (DEGs) between the treatment and control groups. The ferroptosis signaling pathway had the highest enrichment, suggesting ferroptosis is involved in PAT-induced AKI. Further, the existence of ferroptosis and autophagy was confirmed by observing the changes of mitochondria morphology and the formation of autophagosomes by electron microscopy. And the expression of solute carrier family 7 member 11 (SLC7A11), glutathione peroxidase 4 (GPX4), p62, nuclear receptor coactivator 4 (NCOA4), and ferritin heavy chain 1 (FTH1) were downregulated, whereas acyl-CoA synthase long-chain family member 4 (ACSL4), transferrin (TF), LC3, and ferritin light chain (FTL) expression were upregulated in PAT-exposed mice. These results suggested autophagy-dependent ferroptosis occurred in the animal model. This view has also been confirmed in the human renal tubular epithelial cell (HKC) experiments. Autophagy inhibitor 3-methyladenine (3MA) attenuated PAT-induced ferroptosis and the iron contents in HKC cells. Simultaneous autophagy-dependent ferroptosis can be inhibited by ferroptosis inhibitors ferrostatin-1 (Fer-1) and desferrioxamine (DFO). In general, this study provides a new perspective for exploring the new mechanism of acute kidney injury caused by PAT.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neutrophil extracellular traps mediate m6A modification and regulates sepsis-associated acute lung injury by activating ferroptosis in alveolar epithelial cells</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35637949/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35637949/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Neutrophil extracellular traps (NETs) production is a major strategy employed by polymorphonuclear neutrophils (PMNs) to fight against microbes. NETs have been implicated in the pathogenesis of various lung injuries, although few studies have explored NETs in sepsis-associated acute lung injury (SI-ALI). Here, we demonstrate a major contribution of NETs to the pathology of sepsis-associated ALI by inducing ferroptosis of alveolar epithelial cells. Using both &lt;em&gt;in vitro&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt; studies, our findings show enhanced NETs accumulation in sepsis-associated ALI patients and mice, as well as the closely related upregulation of ferroptosis, the induction of which depends on METTL3-induced m&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;A modification of GPX4. Using a CLP-induced sepsis-associated ALI mouse model established with &lt;em&gt;METTL3&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; versus WT mice, in addition to METTL3 knockout and overexpression in vitro, we elucidated and confirmed the critical role of ferroptosis in NETs-induced ALI. These findings support a role for NETs-induced METTL3 modification and the subsequent induction of ferroptosis in the pathogenesis of sepsis-associated ALI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The N6-methyladenosine modification enhances ferroptosis resistance through inhibiting SLC7A11 mRNA deadenylation in hepatoblastoma</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35522946/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35522946/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Solute carrier family 7 member 11 (SLC7A11) is overexpressed in multiple human tumours and functions as a transporter importing cystine for glutathione biosynthesis. It promotes tumour development in part by suppressing ferroptosis, a newly identified form of cell death that plays a pivotal role in the suppression of tumorigenesis. However, the role and underlying mechanisms of SLC7A11-mediated ferroptosis in hepatoblastoma (HB) remain largely unknown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; Reverse transcription quantitative real-time PCR (RT-qPCR) and western blotting were used to measure SLC7A11 levels. Cell proliferation, colony formation, lipid reactive oxygen species (ROS), MDA concentration, 4-HNE, GSH/GSSG ratio and cell death assays as well as subcutaneous xenograft experiments were used to elucidate the effects of SLC7A11 in HB cell proliferation and ferroptosis. Furthermore, MeRIP-qPCR, dual luciferase reporter, RNA pulldown, RNA immunoprecipitation (RIP) and RACE-PAT assays were performed to elucidate the underlying mechanism through which SLC7A11 was regulated by the m6A modification in HB.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; SLC7A11 expression was highly upregulated in HB. SLC7A11 upregulation promoted HB cell proliferation in vitro and in vivo, inhibiting HB cell ferroptosis. Mechanistically, SLC7A11 mRNA exhibited abnormal METTL3-mediated m6A modification, which enhanced its stability and expression. IGF2 mRNA-binding protein 1 (IGF2BP1) was identified as the m6A reader of SLC7A11, enhancing &lt;em&gt;SLC7A11&lt;/em&gt; mRNA stability and expression by inhibiting &lt;em&gt;SLC7A11&lt;/em&gt; mRNA deadenylation in an m6A-dependent manner. Moreover, IGF2BP1 was found to block BTG2/CCR4-NOT complex recruitment via competitively binding to PABPC1, thereby suppressing &lt;em&gt;SLC7A11&lt;/em&gt; mRNA deadenylation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; Our findings demonstrated that the METTL3-mediated SLC7A11 m6A modification enhances HB ferroptosis resistance. The METTL3/IGF2BP1/m6A modification promotes &lt;em&gt;SLC7A11&lt;/em&gt; mRNA stability and upregulates its expression by inhibiting the deadenylation process. Our study highlights a critical role of the m6A modification in SLC7A11-mediated ferroptosis, providing a potential strategy for HB therapy through blockade of the m6A-SLC7A11 axis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arsenic induces ferroptosis and acute lung injury through mtROS-mediated mitochondria-associated endoplasmic reticulum membrane dysfunction</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35525119/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35525119/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Acute As exposure induced pulmonary function decline and ALI in mice.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Acute As exposure caused ferroptosis, MAMs dysfunction and mitochondrial stress in mice lungs and pulmonary epithelial cells.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pretreatment with ferrostatin-1 alleviated As-induced pulmonary function decline and ALI.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PERK inhibitor and Mfn-2-overexpression inhibited As-evoked ferroptosis in pulmonary epithelial cells.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MitoQ neutralized As-mediated MAMs dysfunction, mtROS production and ferroptosis in pulmonary epithelial cells.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MitoQ abolished As-induced decline of the interaction between PERK and Mfn-2 in pulmonary epithelial cells.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MitoQ attenuated As-caused ferroptosis and ALI in mice.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The goal of this study was to analyze whether mitochondria-associated endoplasmic reticulum membrane (MAMs) dysfunction mediated arsenic (As)-evoked pulmonary ferroptosis and acute lung injury (ALI). As exposure led to alveolar structure damage, inflammatory cell infiltration and pulmonary function decline in mice. Ferritin, the marker of iron overload, was increased, GPX4, the index of lipid peroxidation, was decreased in As-exposed lungs and pulmonary epithelial cells (MLE-12). Pretreatment with ferrostatin-1 (Fer-1), the inhibitor of ferroptosis, alleviated As-evoked ALI. In addition, As-induced non-heme iron deposition was inhibited in Fer-1 pretreated-mice. Moreover, As-triggered mitochondria damage and ferroptosis were mitigated in Fer-1 pretreated-MLE-12 cells. Mechanistically, PERK phosphorylation and mitofusin-2 (Mfn-2) reduction was observed in As-exposed MLE-12 cells and mice lungs. Additionally, the interaction between PERK and Mfn-2 was downregulated and MAMs dysfunction was observed in As-exposed MLE-12 cells. Intriguingly, PERK inhibitor and Mfn-2-overexpression all mitigated As-induced ferroptosis in MLE-12 cells. Additionally, CLPP and mtHSP70, the markers of mitochondrial stress, were upregulated, mitochondrial ROS (mtROS) was elevated, mitochondrial membrane potential (MMP) and ATP were decreased in As-exposed MLE-12 cells. Mitoquinone mesylate (MitoQ), a novel mitochondrial-targeted antioxidant, alleviated As-induced excess mtROS, mitochondrial stress, MAMs dysfunction in pulmonary epithelial cells. Similarly, in vivo experiments indicated that MitoQ pretreatment countered As-induced pulmonary ferroptosis and ALI. These data indicated that mtROS-initiated MAMs dysfunction is, at least partially, implicated in As-evoked ferroptosis and ALI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dynamic O-GlcNAcylation coordinates ferritinophagy and mitophagy to activate ferroptosis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35504898/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35504898/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ferroptosis is a regulated iron-dependent cell death characterized by the accumulation of lipid peroxidation. A myriad of facets linking amino acid, lipid, redox, and iron metabolisms were found to drive or to suppress the execution of ferroptosis. However, how the cells decipher the diverse pro-ferroptotic stress to activate ferroptosis remains elusive. Here, we report that protein O-GlcNAcylation, the primary nutrient sensor of glucose flux, orchestrates both ferritinophagy and mitophagy for ferroptosis. Following the treatment of ferroptosis stimuli such as RSL3, a commonly used ferroptosis inducer, there exists a biphasic change of protein O-GlcNAcylation to modulate ferroptosis. Pharmacological or genetic inhibition of O-GlcNAcylation promoted ferritinophagy, resulting in the accumulation of labile iron towards mitochondria. Inhibition of O-GlcNAcylation resulted in mitochondria fragmentation and enhanced mitophagy, providing an additional source of labile iron and rendering the cell more sensitive to ferroptosis. Mechanistically, we found that de-O-GlcNAcylation of the ferritin heavy chain at S179 promoted its interaction with NCOA4, the ferritinophagy receptor, thereby accumulating labile iron for ferroptosis. Our findings reveal a previously uncharacterized link of dynamic O-GlcNAcylation with iron metabolism and decision-making for ferroptosis, thus offering potential therapeutic intervention for fighting disease.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Long noncoding RNA LINC01606 protects colon cancer cells from ferroptotic cell death and promotes stemness by SCD1-Wnt/β-catenin-TFE3 feedback loop signalling</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35485210/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35485210/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Ferroptosis is principally caused by iron catalytic activity and intracellular lipid peroxidation. Long noncoding RNAs (lncRNAs) play crucial roles in tumorigenesis. However, the potential interplay between lncRNA LINC01606 and ferroptosis in colon cancer remains elusive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; The expression level of LNC01606 in colon cancer tissue was detected by quantitative real-time polymerase chain reaction. The functional role of LNC01606 was investigated by gain- and loss-of-function assays both in vitro and in vivo. The LINC01606-SCD1-Wnt/β-catenin-TFE3 axis were screened and validated by DNA/RNA pull down, gas chromatography-mass spectrometry, RNA immunoprecipitation and dual-luciferase reporter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; The expression of lncRNA LINC01606 was frequently upregulated in human colon cancer and strongly associated with a poor prognosis. LINC01606 functioned as an oncogene and promotes colon cancer cell growth, invasion and stemness both in vitro and in vivo. Moreover, LINC01606 protected colon cancer cells from ferroptosis by decreasing the concentration of iron, lipid reactive oxygen species, mitochondrial superoxide and increasing mitochondrial membrane potential. Mechanistically, LINC01606 enhanced the expression of stearoyl-CoA desaturase 1 (SCD1), serving as a competing endogenous RNA to modulate miR-423-5p expression, subsequently activating the canonical Wnt/β-catenin signaling, and transcription factor binding to IGHM enhancer 3 (TFE3) increased LINC01606 transcription after recruitment to the promoter regions of LINC01606. Furthermore, we confirmed that upregulated LINC01606 and Wnt/β-catenin formed a positive feedback regulatory loop, further inhibiting ferroptosis and enhancing stemness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; LINC01606 functions as an oncogene to facilitate tumor cell stemness, proliferation and inhibit ferroptosis and is a promising therapeutic target for colon cancer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Liproxstatin-1 alleviates LPS/IL-13-induced bronchial epithelial cell injury and neutrophilic asthma in mice by inhibiting ferroptosis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35483233/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35483233/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Corrigendum to &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S1567576922009675&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Liproxstatin-1 alleviates LPS/IL-13-induced bronchial epithelial cell injury and neutrophilic asthma in mice by inhibiting ferroptosis&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; [Int. Immunopharmacol. 109 (2022) 108770].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ferroptosis occurred in the lung of mice suffering OVA/LPS-induced neutrophilic asthma.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Liproxstatin-1 alleviated neutrophilic asthma in mice by inhibiting ferroptosis.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Liproxstatin-1 could prevent LPS/IL-13-induced ferroptosis and inflammatory factor release in HBE and BEAS-2B cells.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Liproxstatin-1 inhibited ferroptosis in asthmatic mice lung tissues and bronchial epithelial cells via the GPX4/SLC7A11 pathway.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background and purpose:&lt;/em&gt; Ferroptosis is closely associated with respiratory diseases; however, the relationship between ferroptosis and neutrophilic asthma remains unknown. This study investigated whether Liproxstatin-1 (Lip-1) affects the progression of neutrophilic asthma by inhibiting ferroptosis and inflammatory response, while dissecting the underlying molecular mechanisms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; The bronchial epithelial cells (16HBE and BEAS-2B) were administered with lipopolysaccharide (LPS) and interleukin-13 (IL-13) to generate a cell injury model. This cell model was employed to examine the effect of Lip-1 on airway epithelial-associated inflammation and ferroptosis as well as the underlying molecular mechanism. Meanwhile, we evaluated the effects of Lip-1 on neutrophilic asthma and ferroptosis by using the ovalbumin (OVA)/LPS-induced mouse model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; Lip-1 reversed the altered expression of ferroptotic regulators (glutathione peroxidase 4 (GPX4), solute carrier family 7 member 11 (SLC7A11) and prostaglandin-endoperoxide synthase 2 (PTGS2)), attenuated lipid reactive oxygen species (lipid ROS) and ameliorated cell viability in HBE and BEAS-2B cells administered with LPS and IL-13. Moreover, Lip-1 treatment led to a marked reduction in the expression of IL-33, TSLP, IL-8, IL-6, and HMGB1 in the HBE and BEAS-2B cells. In the meantime, administration with Lip-1 markedly relieved OVA/LPS-induced neutrophilic asthma, as indicated by significant improvement in lung pathological changes, airway mucus secretion, inflammation, and ferroptosis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/em&gt; This study provides data suggesting that Lip-1 alleviates neutrophilic asthma in vivo and in vitro through inhibiting ferroptosis, perhaps providing a new strategy for neutrophilic asthma treatment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Novel Identified Circular RNA, mmu_mmu_circRNA_0000309, Involves in Germacrone-Mediated Improvement of Diabetic Nephropathy Through Regulating Ferroptosis by Targeting miR-188-3p/GPX4 Signaling Axis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34913724/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34913724/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Aims:&lt;/em&gt; Diabetic nephropathy (DN) is characterized by microalbuminuria, mainly associated with pathological and morphological alterations of podocyte. New drug targeting podocyte injury is a promising approach for treating DN. The present study is aimed at developing new drug targeting podocyte injury for treating DN.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; In this study, germacrone ameliorated kidney damage and inhibited podocyte apoptosis in a DN mouse model. Based on RNA-seq, mmu_mmu_circRNA_0000309, located in host gene vascular endothelial zinc finger 1 (Vezf1), showed a sharp decline in DN mice and a remarkable recovery in germacrone-challenged DN mice. mmu_circRNA_0000309 silence or miR-188-3p mimics abrogated the antiapoptosis and anti-injury effects of germacrone through aggravating mitochondria damage, and elevating reactive oxygen species and ferroptosis-related protein levels. Mechanistically, mmu_circRNA_0000309 competitively sponged miR-188-3p, and subsequently promoted glutathione peroxidase 4 (GPX4) expression, thereby inactivating ferroptosis-dependent mitochondrial damage and podocyte apoptosis. In addition, GPX4 overexpression neutralized mmu_circRNA_0000309 silence-mediated mitochondria damage and ferroptosis in germacrone-exposed MPC5 cells.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Innovation:&lt;/em&gt; We describe the novel effect and mechanism of germacrone on treating DN, which is linked to ferroptosis for the first time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/em&gt; mmu_circRNA_0000309 silence mediates drug resistance to germacrone in DN mice. mmu_circRNA_0000309 sponges miR-188-3p, and subsequently upregulates GPX4 expression, inactivating ferroptosis-dependent mitochondrial function and podocyte apoptosis. Possibly germacrone-based treatment for DN can be further motivated by regulating mmu_circRNA_0000309/miR-188-3p/GPX4 signaling axis. Antioxid. Redox Signal. 36, 740-759.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CircEXOC5 promotes ferroptosis by enhancing ACSL4 mRNA stability via binding to PTBP1 in sepsis-induced acute lung injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35709678/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35709678/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Sepsis causes severe acute lung injury (ALI). Circular RNA is involved in the regulation of sepsis-related ALI progression. The regulation mechanism of circEXOC5 in sepsis-induced ALI is still unclear. Whether circEXOC5 is involved in the regulation of ferroptosis remains to be explored.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; We constructed a mouse model of sepsis through cecal ligation and puncture (CLP). LPS induced mouse lung microvascular endothelial cells (MPVECs) to construct a sepsis cell model. The expression of circEXOC5 in the sepsis model was detected by qPCR. The extent of lung injury in mice was analyzed by HE staining. The contents of GSH/GSSG, iron, MDA and 4HNE in mice lung tissues and cells were detected by the kit. And further the ROS content was detected in the cells. Finally, the binding relationship between circEXOC5 and PTBP1 was detected by RIP and RNA pulldown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; Our results showed that the circEXOC5 expression was significantly increased in the &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;in vitro&lt;/em&gt; models of sepsis. And after inhibiting circEXOC5, it improved the lung injury of septic mice. It was confirmed in cell models that ROS levels and ferroptosis in cells were reduced after knocking down circEXOC5. In addition, the expressions of ACSL4 and Gpx4 proteins were regulated by the level of circEXOC5. Finally, we also found that circEXOC5 had a direct binding relationship with PTBP1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/em&gt; Our study found that the expression of cell ferroptosis and circEXOC5 increased in ALI induced by sepsis, and circEXOC5 aggravated ferroptosis in septic cells by regulating the PTBP1/ACSL4 axis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hypoxia-induced HIF-1α/lncRNA-PMAN inhibits ferroptosis by promoting the cytoplasmic translocation of ELAVL1 in peritoneal dissemination from gastric cancer</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35447413/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35447413/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Erratum in:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Corrigendum to &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S2213231722001744&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Hypoxia-induced HIF-1α/lncRNA-PMAN inhibits ferroptosis by promoting the cytoplasmic translocation of ELAVL1 in peritoneal dissemination from gastric cancer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; [Redox Biol. 52C (2022) 102312].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;HIF-1⍺ mediates abnormally high expression of PMAN in PM from GC under hypoxia.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GC cells suppress ferroptosis by relieving ROS and irons accumulation through HIF-1⍺/PMAN under hypoxia.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Inhibition of ferroptosis may contributes to the development of PM from GC.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Increased cytoplasmic translocation of ELAVL1 is a key intermediate factor in PMAN inhibition of ferroptosis.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Peritoneal metastasis (PM) is the main site of gastric cancer (GC) distant metastasis and indicates an extremely poor prognosis and survival. Hypoxia is a common feature of peritoneal metastases and up-regulation of hypoxia inducible factor 1 alpha (HIF-1α) may be a potential driver in the occurrence of PM. Ferroptosis is a recently discovered form of regulated cell death and closely related to the occurrence and development of tumors. However, the underlying mechanism link HIF-1α to ferroptosis in PM of GC remains unknown. Here, lncRNA-microarrays and RNA library construction/lncRNA-seq results shown that lncRNA-PMAN was highly expressed in PM and significantly modulated by HIF-1α. Upregulation of PMAN is associated with poor prognosis and PM in patients with GC. PMAN was up-regulated by HIF-1α and improved the stability of SLC7A11 mRNA by promoting the cytoplasmic distribution of ELAVL1, which was identified in RNA-pulldown/mass spectrometry results. Accumulation of SLC7A11 increases the level of l-Glutathione (GSH) and inhibits the accumulation of reactive oxygen species (ROS) and irons in the GC cells. Finally protect GC cells against ferroptosis induced by Erastin and RSL3. Our findings have elucidated the effect of HIF-1α/PMAN/ELAVL1 in GC cells ferroptosis and provides theoretical support for the potential diagnostic biomarkers and therapeutic targets for PM in GC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mitochondria bridge HIF signaling and ferroptosis blockage in acute kidney injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/35387983/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/35387983/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ferroptosis, a form of regulated cell death, plays an important role in acute kidney injury (AKI). Previous studies have shown that prolyl hydroxylase domain protein (PHD) inhibitors that activate HIF signaling provide strong protection against AKI, which is characterized by marked cell death. However, the relationship between PHD inhibition/HIF signaling and ferroptosis in AKI has not been elucidated. Here, we review recent studies to explore the issue. First, we will review the literature concerning the functions of HIF in promoting mitophagy, suppressing mitochondrial respiration and modulating redox homeostasis. Second, we will describe the current understanding of ferroptosis and its role in AKI, particularly from the perspective of mitochondrial dysfunction. Finally, we will discuss the possibility that mitochondria link PHD inhibition/HIF signaling and ferroptosis in AKI. In conclusion, we propose that HIF may protect renal cells against ferroptosis in AKI by reducing mitochondrial oxidative stress and damage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Facts&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ferroptosis plays an important role in the development of AKI.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Activation of HIF signaling provides protection against AKI.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mitochondrial ROS facilitate ferroptosis in many cases.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;HIF signaling regulates multiple mitochondrial activities, including mitochondrial oxidative capacity, redox homeostasis and autophagy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Open questions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Can HIF signaling alleviate ferroptosis in AKI with different etiologies?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is mitochondrial pathway decisive for HIF-offered protection in situations like AKI, given that HIF signaling has extensive downstream effects?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Would PHD inhibitors be effective in AKI prevention and treatment clinically?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ferroptosis, a new target for treatment of renal injury and fibrosis in a 5/6 nephrectomy-induced CKD rat model</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35318301/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35318301/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The arginine methyltransferase PRMT7 promotes extravasation of monocytes resulting in tissue injury in COPD</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35288557/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35288557/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Extravasation of monocytes into tissue and to the site of injury is a fundamental immunological process, which requires rapid responses via post translational modifications (PTM) of proteins. Protein arginine methyltransferase 7 (PRMT7) is an epigenetic factor that has the capacity to mono-methylate histones on arginine residues. Here we show that in chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD) patients, PRMT7 expression is elevated in the lung tissue and localized to the macrophages. In mouse models of COPD, lung fibrosis and skin injury, reduced expression of PRMT7 associates with decreased recruitment of monocytes to the site of injury and hence less severe symptoms. Mechanistically, activation of NF-κB/RelA in monocytes induces PRMT7 transcription and consequential mono-methylation of histones at the regulatory elements of RAP1A, which leads to increased transcription of this gene that is responsible for adhesion and migration of monocytes. Persistent monocyte-derived macrophage accumulation leads to ALOX5 over-expression and accumulation of its metabolite LTB4, which triggers expression of ACSL4 a ferroptosis promoting gene in lung epithelial cells. Conclusively, inhibition of arginine mono-methylation might offer targeted intervention in monocyte-driven inflammatory conditions that lead to extensive tissue damage if left untreated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Poly(rC)-binding protein 1 represses ferritinophagy-mediated ferroptosis in head and neck cancer</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35290903/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35290903/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PCBP1 expression is related to head and neck cancer survival and response to ferroptosis inducers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Knockdown of PCBP1 increased ferroptosis sensitivity by inducing an increased labile iron pool.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PCBP1 negatively regulated ferritinophagy by the 3′-UTR binding of BECN1 mRNA.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Knockdown of PCBP1 increased lipid peroxidation by ALOX15 expression.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PCBP1 depletion promoted ferroptosis susceptibility in vitro and in vivo.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A cytosolic iron chaperone poly(rC)-binding protein 1 (PCBP1) is a multifunctional RNA-binding protein involving gene transcription, RNA regulation, and iron loading to ferritins. PCBP1 is also known to repress autophagy, but the role of PCBP1 in ferritinophagy and ferroptosis remains unrevealed. Therefore, we examined the role of PCBP1 in ferritinophagy-mediated ferroptosis in head and neck cancer (HNC) cells. The effects of system xc&lt;sup&gt;-&lt;/sup&gt; cystine/glutamate antiporter (xCT) inhibitors and PCBP1 gene silencing/overexpression were tested on HNC cell lines and mouse tumor xenograft models. These effects were analyzed by assessing cell viability and death, lipid reactive oxygen species and iron production, lipid, malondialdehyde, mRNA/protein expression, and autophagy flux assays. Interaction between PCBP1 and BECN1 mRNA was also examined by luciferase and RNA-protein pull-down assays. PCBP1 gene silencing increased autophagosome generation and autophagic flux. Conversely, PCBP1 upregulation inhibited autophagy activation via direct binding to the CU-rich elements on the 3&amp;rsquo;-untranslated region (3&amp;rsquo;-UTR) of BECN1 mRNA. The internal deletion or mutation of the 3&amp;rsquo;-UTR F2 region recovered BECN1 mRNA stability repressed by PCBP1, resulting in enhanced ferritinophagy-mediated ferroptosis. Besides, PCBP1 knockdown promoted polyunsaturated fatty acid peroxidation by increasing ALOX15 expression. Further, excess iron accumulation caused mitochondrial dysfunction in PCBP1-suppressed cells. A ferroptosis inducer sulfasalazine significantly suppressed tumor growth in mice with the transplantation of PCBP1-silenced HNC. Our data suggest that the dual functions of PCBP1 repressing BECN1 and ALOX15 mRNAs contribute to attenuating cancer susceptibility to ferroptosis inducers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ubiquitin ligase E3 HUWE1/MULE targets transferrin receptor for degradation and suppresses ferroptosis in acute liver injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35260822/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35260822/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hepatic ischemia followed by reperfusion (I/R), a major clinical problem during liver surgical procedures, can induce liver injury with severe cell death including ferroptosis which is characterized by iron-dependent accumulation of lipid peroxidation. The HECT domain-containing ubiquitin E3 ligase HUWE1 (also known as MULE) was initially shown to promote apoptosis. However, our preliminary study demonstrates that high expression of HUWE1 in the liver donors corelates with less injury and better hepatic function after liver transplantation in patients. Thus, we investigate the role of HUWE1 in acute liver injury, and identify HUWE1 as a negative ferroptosis modulator through transferrin receptor 1(TfR1). Deficiency of Huwe1 in mice hepatocytes (HKO) exacerbated I/R and CCl4-induced liver injury with more ferroptosis occurrence. Moreover, Suppression of Huwe1 remarkably enhances cellular sensitivity to ferroptosis in primary hepatocytes and mouse embryonic fibroblasts. Mechanistically, HUWE1 specifically targets TfR1 for ubiquitination and proteasomal degradation, thereby regulates iron metabolism. Importantly, chemical and genetic inhibition of TfR1 dramatically diminishes the ferroptotic cell death in Huwe1 KO cells and Huwe1 HKO mice. Therefore, HUWE1 is a potential protective factor to antagonize both aberrant iron accumulation and ferroptosis thereby mitigating acute liver injury. These findings may provide clinical implications for patients with the high-expression Huwe1 alleles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TIGAR drives colorectal cancer ferroptosis resistance through ROS/AMPK/SCD1 pathway</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35271998/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35271998/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Colorectal cancer (CRC) is the third most commonly diagnosed malignancy and major cause of cancer death in the world. Ferroptosis is a recently identified type of regulated cell death. Increasing evidence has shown that ferroptosis plays an important regulatory role in the occurrence and development of cancer. This study identified TIGAR as a potential regulator of ferroptosis resistance in the development of CRC. We showed that TIGAR expression in CRC tissues is significantly higher than that in adjacent normal tissues. Knockdown of TIGAR significantly caused an increase in erastin-induced ferroptosis in SW620 and HCT116 cells. Notably, knockdown of TIGAR significantly decreased GSH/GSSG ratio, increased lipid peroxidation production, and facilitated the accumulation of lipid peroxidation product malondialdehyde (MDA), and rendered CRC cells more sensitive to erastin induced ferroptosis. Furthermore, TIGAR inhibition repressed SCD1 expression in a redox and AMPK-dependent manner. Thus, these results suggest that TIGAR induces ferroptosis resistance in CRC cells via the ROS/AMPK/SCD1 signaling pathway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Phosphorylated NFS1 weakens oxaliplatin-based chemosensitivity of colorectal cancer by preventing PANoptosis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35221331/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35221331/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Metabolic enzymes have an indispensable role in metabolic reprogramming, and their aberrant expression or activity has been associated with chemosensitivity. Hence, targeting metabolic enzymes remains an attractive approach for treating tumors. However, the influence and regulation of cysteine desulfurase (NFS1), a rate-limiting enzyme in iron-sulfur (Fe-S) cluster biogenesis, in colorectal cancer (CRC) remain elusive. Here, using an in vivo metabolic enzyme gene-based clustered regularly interspaced short palindromic repeats (CRISPR)-Cas9 library screen, we revealed that loss of NFS1 significantly enhanced the sensitivity of CRC cells to oxaliplatin. In vitro and in vivo results showed that NFS1 deficiency synergizing with oxaliplatin triggered PANoptosis (apoptosis, necroptosis, pyroptosis, and ferroptosis) by increasing the intracellular levels of reactive oxygen species (ROS). Furthermore, oxaliplatin-based oxidative stress enhanced the phosphorylation level of serine residues of NFS1, which prevented PANoptosis in an S293 phosphorylation-dependent manner during oxaliplatin treatment. In addition, high expression of NFS1, transcriptionally regulated by MYC, was found in tumor tissues and was associated with poor survival and hyposensitivity to chemotherapy in patients with CRC. Overall, the findings of this study provided insights into the underlying mechanisms of NFS1 in oxaliplatin sensitivity and identified NFS1 inhibition as a promising strategy for improving the outcome of platinum-based chemotherapy in the treatment of CRC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ferroptotic stress promotes macrophages against intracellular bacteria</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35265210/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35265210/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rational:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Intracellular bacterial survival is a major factor causing chronic or recurrent infection, leading to the failure of both host defense and/or antibiotic treatment. However, the elimination of intracellular bacteria is challenging as they are protected from antibiotics and host immune attack. Recent studies have indicated that iron helps macrophages against intracellular bacteria, contradictory to traditional &amp;ldquo;nutritional immunity&amp;rdquo;, in which iron is considered a key nutrient for bacterial survival in host cells. However, how iron facilitates intracellular bacterial death has not been fully clarified. In this study, we found that ferroptotic stress can help macrophages suppress intracellular bacteria by reversing the importation of ferrous iron into bacterial vacuoles via ferroportin and thereby inducing in situ ferroptosis-like bacterial death.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A macrophage model of bacterial invasion was established to monitor dynamic changes in ferroptotic hallmarks, including ferrous iron and lipid peroxidation. Ferroptosis inducers and inhibitors were added to the model to evaluate the relationship between ferroptotic stress and intracellular bacterial survival. We then determined the spatiotemporal distributions of ferroportin, ferrous iron, and lipid peroxidation in macrophages and intracellular bacteria. A bacterial infection mouse model was established to evaluate the therapeutic effects of drugs that regulate ferroptotic stress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ferrous iron and lipid peroxidation increased sharply in the early stage of bacterial infection in the macrophages, then decreased to normal levels in the late stage of infection. The addition of ferroptosis inducers (ras-selective lethal small molecule 3, sulfasalazine, and acetaminophen) in macrophages promoted intracellular bacterial suppression. Further studies revealed that ferrous iron could be delivered to the intracellular bacterial compartment via inward ferroportin transportation, where ferrous iron induced ferroptosis-like death of bacteria. In addition, ferroptotic stress declined to normal levels in the late stage of infection by regulating iron-related pathways in the macrophages. Importantly, we found that enhancing ferroptotic stress with a ferroptosis inducer (sulfasalazine) successfully suppressed bacteria in the mouse infection models.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our study suggests that the spatiotemporal response to ferroptosis stress is an efficient pathway for macrophage defense against bacterial invasion, and targeting ferroptosis may achieve therapeutic targets for infectious diseases challenged by intracellular pathogens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Activation of MAT2A-ACSL3 pathway protects cells from ferroptosis in gastric cancer</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35182729/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35182729/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ferroptosis, a new form of programmed cell death caused by overwhelming lipid peroxidation, has gained a lot of interest in the field of cancer therapeutics.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;However, few studies have thoroughly investigated the association between methionine metabolism and ferroptosis.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MAT2A mediates the production of S-adenosylmethionine (SAM), which upregulates ACSL3 by increasing the trimethylation of lysine-4 on histone H3 (H3K4me3) at the promoter area, resulting in ferroptosis resistance.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Ferroptosis, a unique form of nonapoptotic-regulated cell death caused by overwhelming lipid peroxidation, represents an emerging tumor suppression mechanism. Growing evidence has demonstrated that cell metabolism plays an important role in the regulation of ferroptosis. Specifically, the association between methionine metabolism and ferroptosis remains undefined.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; We performed in vitro and in vivo experiments to evaluate the influence of methionine metabolism on ferroptosis sensitivity. Pharmacological and genetic blockade of the methionine cycle was utilized and relevant molecular analyses were performed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; We identified MAT2A as a driver of ferroptosis resistance. Mechanistically, MAT2A mediates the production of S-adenosylmethionine (SAM), which upregulates ACSL3 by increasing the trimethylation of lysine-4 on histone H3 (H3K4me3) at the promoter area, resulting in ferroptosis resistance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; Collectively, these results established a link between methionine cycle activity and ferroptosis vulnerability in gastric cancer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The role of ferroptosis in acute lung injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/35166985/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/35166985/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acute lung injury/acute respiratory distress syndrome (ALI/ARDS) is a common disease with high morbidity and mortality, and its pathogenesis is believed to be related to oxidative stress, apoptosis, inflammation, and hypoxia. Ferroptosis is a type of nonapoptotic cell death characterized by iron-dependent lipid peroxide accumulation and is involved in many cellular physiological processes. Recent studies have confirmed that ferroptosis may be involved in the development of ALI. This review summarizes the most recent discoveries on the role of ferroptosis in ALI to provide new strategies for its prevention and treatment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ACSL4 deficiency confers protection against ferroptosis-mediated acute kidney injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35180475/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35180475/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The term ferroptosis coined in 2012 causes acute kidney injury (AKI). However, its pathway mechanism in AKI is poorly understood. In this study, we conducted an RNA-sequence analysis of kidneys in AKI and normal mice to explore the pathway mechanism of ferroptosis. Consequently, differentially expressed genes highlighted Acyl-CoA synthetase long-chain family (ACSL4), a known promotor for ferroptosis. Besides, RT-PCR, Western blot, and immunohistochemical analyses confirmed its upregulation. HIF-1α was downregulated in I/R-AKI mice, and in vitro studies confirmed a negative regulation of HIF-1α on ACSL4. To explore the role of ACSL4 in AKI, we constructed ACSL4 knockout in kidney tubules of mice-as Cdh16Cre-ACSL4&lt;sup&gt;F/F&lt;/sup&gt; mice. Results revealed that ACSL4 knockout significantly reduced ferroptosis and inhibited the functional and pathological injury of AKI mice. Meanwhile, the kidneys of Cdh16Cre-ACSL4&lt;sup&gt;F/F&lt;/sup&gt; mice demonstrated a significantly decreased inflammation and macrophage infiltration. Further, additional explorations were explored to decipher a more thorough understanding of ferroptotic immunogenicity. As a result, neutrophils were not directly recruited by ferroptotic cells, but by ferroptotic cell-induced macrophages. Further, ACSL4 inhibitor rosiglitazone significantly inhibited AKI. Collectively, these data provide novel insights into the AKI pathogenesis, and defined ACSL4 as an effective target in AKI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dexamethasone sensitizes to ferroptosis by glucocorticoid receptor-induced dipeptidase-1 expression and glutathione depletion</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35108055/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35108055/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dexamethasone is widely used as an immunosuppressive therapy and recently as COVID-19 treatment. Here, we demonstrate that dexamethasone sensitizes to ferroptosis, a form of iron-catalyzed necrosis, previously suggested to contribute to diseases such as acute kidney injury, myocardial infarction, and stroke, all of which are triggered by glutathione (GSH) depletion. GSH levels were significantly decreased by dexamethasone. Mechanistically, we identified that dexamethasone up-regulated the GSH metabolism regulating protein dipeptidase-1 (DPEP1) in a glucocorticoid receptor (GR)-dependent manner. DPEP1 knockdown reversed the phenotype of dexamethasone-induced ferroptosis sensitization. Ferroptosis inhibitors, the DPEP1 inhibitor cilastatin, or genetic &lt;em&gt;DPEP1&lt;/em&gt; inactivation reversed the dexamethasone-induced increase in tubular necrosis in freshly isolated renal tubules. Our data indicate that dexamethasone sensitizes to ferroptosis by a GR-mediated increase in DPEP1 expression and GSH depletion. Together, we identified a previously unknown mechanism of glucocorticoid-mediated sensitization to ferroptosis bearing clinical and therapeutic implications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>p53 in ferroptosis regulation: the new weapon for the old guardian</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/35087226/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/35087226/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although the conventional activities of p53 such as cell cycle arrest, senescence, and apoptosis are well accepted as the major checkpoints in stress responses, accumulating evidence implicates the importance of other tumor suppression mechanisms. Among these unconventional activities, an iron-dependent form of non-apoptotic cell death, termed ferroptosis, attracts great interest. Unlike apoptotic cell death, activation of p53 alone is not sufficient to induce ferroptosis directly; instead, through its metabolic targets, p53 is able to modulate the ferroptosis response in the presence of ferroptosis inducers such as GPX4 inhibitors or high levels of ROS. Here, we review the role of ferroptosis in p53-mediated tumor suppression, with a focus on what cellular factors are critical for p53-dependent ferroptosis during tumor suppression and how p53 modulates both the canonical (GPX4-dependent) and the non-canonical (GPX4-independent) ferroptosis pathways. We also discuss the possibility of targeting p53-mediated ferroptotic responses for the treatment of human cancers and potentially, other diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A detrimental role of NLRP6 in host iron metabolism during Salmonella infection</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34942528/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34942528/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maintaining host iron homeostasis is an essential component of nutritional immunity responsible for sequestrating iron from pathogens and controlling infection. Nucleotide-oligomerization domain-like receptors (NLRs) contribute to cytoplasmic sensing and antimicrobial response orchestration. However, it remains unknown whether and how NLRs may regulate host iron metabolism, an important component of nutritional immunity. Here, we demonstrated that NLRP6, a member of the NLR family, has an unconventional role in regulating host iron metabolism that perturbs host resistance to bacterial infection. NLRP6 deficiency is advantageous for maintaining cellular iron homeostasis in both macrophages and enterocytes through increasing the unique iron exporter ferroportin-mediated iron efflux in a nuclear factor erythroid-derived 2-related factor 2 (NRF2)-dependent manner. Additional studies uncovered a novel mechanism underlying NRF2 regulation and operating through NLRP6/AKT interaction and that causes a decrease in AKT phosphorylation, which in turn reduces NRF2 nuclear translocation. In the absence of NLRP6, increased AKT activation promotes NRF2/KEAP1 dissociation via increasing mTOR-mediated p62 phosphorylation and downregulates KEAP1 transcription by promoting FOXO3A phosphorylation. Together, our observations provide new insights into the mechanism of nutritional immunity by revealing a novel function of NLRP6 in regulating iron metabolism, and suggest NLRP6 as a therapeutic target for limiting bacterial iron acquisition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A targetable LIFR-NF-κB-LCN2 axis controls liver tumorigenesis and vulnerability to ferroptosis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34921145/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34921145/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The growing knowledge of ferroptosis has suggested the role and therapeutic potential of ferroptosis in cancer, but has not been translated into effective therapy. Liver cancer, primarily hepatocellular carcinoma (HCC), is highly lethal with limited treatment options. LIFR is frequently downregulated in HCC. Here, by studying hepatocyte-specific and inducible Lifr-knockout mice, we show that loss of Lifr promotes liver tumorigenesis and confers resistance to drug-induced ferroptosis. Mechanistically, loss of LIFR activates NF-κB signaling through SHP1, leading to upregulation of the iron-sequestering cytokine LCN2, which depletes iron and renders insensitivity to ferroptosis inducers. Notably, an LCN2-neutralizing antibody enhances the ferroptosis-inducing and anticancer effects of sorafenib on HCC patient-derived xenograft tumors with low LIFR expression and high LCN2 expression. Thus, anti-LCN2 therapy is a promising way to improve liver cancer treatment by targeting ferroptosis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RBMS1 regulates lung cancer ferroptosis through translational control of SLC7A11</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34609966/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34609966/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ferroptosis, an iron-dependent nonapoptotic cell death, is a highly regulated tumor suppressing process. However, functions and mechanisms of RNA-binding proteins in regulation of evasion of ferroptosis during lung cancer progression are still largely unknown. Here, we report that the RNA-binding protein RBMS1 participates in lung cancer development via mediating ferroptosis evasion. Through an shRNA-mediated systematic screen, we discovered that RBMS1 is a key ferroptosis regulator. Clinically, RBMS1 was elevated in lung cancer and its high expression was associated with reduced patient survival. Conversely, depletion of RBMS1 inhibited lung cancer progression both in vivo and in vitro. Mechanistically, RBMS1 interacted with the translation initiation factor eIF3d directly to bridge the 3&amp;rsquo;- and 5&amp;rsquo;-UTR of SLC7A11. RBMS1 ablation inhibited the translation of SLC7A11, reduced SLC7A11-mediated cystine uptake, and promoted ferroptosis. In a drug screen that targeted RBMS1, we further uncovered that nortriptyline hydrochloride decreased the level of RBMS1, thereby promoting ferroptosis. Importantly, RBMS1 depletion or inhibition by nortriptyline hydrochloride sensitized radioresistant lung cancer cells to radiotherapy. Our findings established RBMS1 as a translational regulator of ferroptosis and a prognostic factor with therapeutic potential and clinical value.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CD63 is regulated by iron via the IRE-IRP system and is important for ferritin secretion by extracellular vesicles</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34265052/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34265052/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Extracellular vesicles (EVs) transfer functional molecules between cells. CD63 is a widely recognized EV marker that contributes to EV secretion from cells. However, the regulation of its expression remains largely unknown. Ferritin is a cellular iron storage protein that can also be secreted by the exosome pathway, and serum ferritin levels classically reflect body iron stores. Iron metabolism-associated proteins such as ferritin are intricately regulated by cellular iron levels via the iron responsive element-iron regulatory protein (IRE-IRP) system. Herein, we present a novel mechanism demonstrating that the expression of the EV-associated protein CD63 is under the regulation of the IRE-IRP system. We discovered a canonical IRE in the 5&amp;rsquo; untranslated region of CD63 messenger RNA that is responsible for regulating its expression in response to increased iron. Cellular iron loading caused a marked increase in CD63 expression and the secretion of CD63&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; EVs from cells, which were shown to contain ferritin-H and ferritin-L. Our results demonstrate that under iron loading, intracellular ferritin is transferred via nuclear receptor coactivator 4 (NCOA4) to CD63&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; EVs that are then secreted. Such iron-regulated secretion of the major iron storage protein ferritin via CD63&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; EVs, is significant for understanding the local cell-to-cell exchange of ferritin and iron.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Metformin induces Ferroptosis by inhibiting UFMylation of SLC7A11 in breast cancer</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34162423/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34162423/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ferroptosis is a newly defined form of regulated cell death characterized by the iron-dependent accumulation of lipid peroxidation and is involved in various pathophysiological conditions, including cancer. Targeting ferroptosis is considered to be a novel anti-cancer strategy. The identification of FDA-approved drugs as ferroptosis inducers is proposed to be a new promising approach for cancer treatment. Despite a growing body of evidence indicating the potential efficacy of the anti-diabetic metformin as an anti-cancer agent, the exact mechanism underlying this efficacy has not yet been fully elucidated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The UFMylation of SLC7A11 is detected by immunoprecipitation and the expression of UFM1 and SLC7A11 in tumor tissues was detected by immunohistochemical staining. The level of ferroptosis is determined by the level of free iron, total/lipid Ros and GSH in the cells and the morphological changes of mitochondria are observed by transmission electron microscope. The mechanism in vivo was verified by in situ implantation tumor model in nude mice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Metformin induces ferroptosis in an AMPK-independent manner to suppress tumor growth. Mechanistically, we demonstrate that metformin increases the intracellular Fe2+ and lipid ROS levels. Specifically, metformin reduces the protein stability of SLC7A11, which is a critical ferroptosis regulator, by inhibiting its UFMylation process. Furthermore, metformin combined with sulfasalazine, the system xc− inhibitor, can work in a synergistic manner to induce ferroptosis and inhibit the proliferation of breast cancer cells.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This study is the first to demonstrate that the ability of metformin to induce ferroptosis may be a novel mechanism underlying its anti-cancer effect. In addition, we identified SLC7A11 as a new UFMylation substrate and found that targeting the UFM1/SLC7A11 pathway could be a promising cancer treatment strategy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Genome-wide CRISPRi/a screens in human neurons link lysosomal failure to ferroptosis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34031600/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34031600/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Single-cell transcriptomics provide a systematic map of gene expression in different human cell types. The next challenge is to systematically understand cell-type-specific gene function. The integration of CRISPR-based functional genomics and stem cell technology enables the scalable interrogation of gene function in differentiated human cells. Here we present the first genome-wide CRISPR interference and CRISPR activation screens in human neurons. We uncover pathways controlling neuronal response to chronic oxidative stress, which is implicated in neurodegenerative diseases. Unexpectedly, knockdown of the lysosomal protein prosaposin strongly sensitizes neurons, but not other cell types, to oxidative stress by triggering the formation of lipofuscin, a hallmark of aging, which traps iron, generating reactive oxygen species and triggering ferroptosis. We also determine transcriptomic changes in neurons after perturbation of genes linked to neurodegenerative diseases. To enable the systematic comparison of gene function across different human cell types, we establish a data commons named &lt;a href=&#34;https://crisprbrain.org&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CRISPRbrain&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://crisprbrain.org&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CRISPRbrain&lt;/a&gt; is a data commons organizing results from genetic screens for different phenotypes in different human cell types, by different research groups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DHODH-mediated ferroptosis defence is a targetable vulnerability in cancer</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33981038/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33981038/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ferroptosis, a form of regulated cell death that is induced by excessive lipid peroxidation, is a key tumour suppression mechanism. Glutathione peroxidase 4 (GPX4) and ferroptosis suppressor protein 1 (FSP1) constitute two major ferroptosis defence systems. Here we show that treatment of cancer cells with GPX4 inhibitors results in acute depletion of N-carbamoyl-L-aspartate, a pyrimidine biosynthesis intermediate, with concomitant accumulation of uridine. Supplementation with dihydroorotate or orotate-the substrate and product of dihydroorotate dehydrogenase (DHODH)-attenuates or potentiates ferroptosis induced by inhibition of GPX4, respectively, and these effects are particularly pronounced in cancer cells with low expression of GPX4 (GPX4&lt;sup&gt;low&lt;/sup&gt;). Inactivation of DHODH induces extensive mitochondrial lipid peroxidation and ferroptosis in GPX4&lt;sup&gt;low&lt;/sup&gt; cancer cells, and synergizes with ferroptosis inducers to induce these effects in GPX4&lt;sup&gt;high&lt;/sup&gt; cancer cells. Mechanistically, DHODH operates in parallel to mitochondrial GPX4 (but independently of cytosolic GPX4 or FSP1) to inhibit ferroptosis in the mitochondrial inner membrane by reducing ubiquinone to ubiquinol (a radical-trapping antioxidant with anti-ferroptosis activity). The DHODH inhibitor brequinar selectively suppresses GPX4&lt;sup&gt;low&lt;/sup&gt; tumour growth by inducing ferroptosis, whereas combined treatment with brequinar and sulfasalazine, an FDA-approved drug with ferroptosis-inducing activity, synergistically induces ferroptosis and suppresses GPX4&lt;sup&gt;high&lt;/sup&gt; tumour growth. Our results identify a DHODH-mediated ferroptosis defence mechanism in mitochondria and suggest a therapeutic strategy of targeting ferroptosis in cancer treatment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Broadening horizons: the role of ferroptosis in cancer</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/33514910/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/33514910/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The discovery of regulated cell death processes has enabled advances in cancer treatment. In the past decade, ferroptosis, an iron-dependent form of regulated cell death driven by excessive lipid peroxidation, has been implicated in the development and therapeutic responses of various types of tumours. Experimental reagents (such as erastin and RSL3), approved drugs (for example, sorafenib, sulfasalazine, statins and artemisinin), ionizing radiation and cytokines (such as IFNγ and TGFβ1) can induce ferroptosis and suppress tumour growth. However, ferroptotic damage can trigger inflammation-associated immunosuppression in the tumour microenvironment, thus favouring tumour growth. The extent to which ferroptosis affects tumour biology is unclear, although several studies have found important correlations between mutations in cancer-relevant genes (for example, &lt;em&gt;RAS&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;TP53&lt;/em&gt;), in genes encoding proteins involved in stress response pathways (such as NFE2L2 signalling, autophagy and hypoxia) and the epithelial-to-mesenchymal transition, and responses to treatments that activate ferroptosis. Herein, we present the key molecular mechanisms of ferroptosis, describe the crosstalk between ferroptosis and tumour-associated signalling pathways, and discuss the potential applications of ferroptosis in the context of systemic therapy, radiotherapy and immunotherapy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ferroptosis: mechanisms, biology and role in disease</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/33495651/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/33495651/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The research field of ferroptosis has seen exponential growth over the past few years, since the term was coined in 2012. This unique modality of cell death, driven by iron-dependent phospholipid peroxidation, is regulated by multiple cellular metabolic pathways, including redox homeostasis, iron handling, mitochondrial activity and metabolism of amino acids, lipids and sugars, in addition to various signalling pathways relevant to disease. Numerous organ injuries and degenerative pathologies are driven by ferroptosis. Intriguingly, therapy-resistant cancer cells, particularly those in the mesenchymal state and prone to metastasis, are exquisitely vulnerable to ferroptosis. As such, pharmacological modulation of ferroptosis, via both its induction and its inhibition, holds great potential for the treatment of drug-resistant cancers, ischaemic organ injuries and other degenerative diseases linked to extensive lipid peroxidation. In this Review, we provide a critical analysis of the current molecular mechanisms and regulatory networks of ferroptosis, the potential physiological functions of ferroptosis in tumour suppression and immune surveillance, and its pathological roles, together with a potential for therapeutic targeting. Importantly, as in all rapidly evolving research areas, challenges exist due to misconceptions and inappropriate experimental methods. This Review also aims to address these issues and to provide practical guidelines for enhancing reproducibility and reliability in studies of ferroptosis. Finally, we discuss important concepts and pressing questions that should be the focus of future ferroptosis research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ferroptosis: molecular mechanisms and health implications</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/33268902/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/33268902/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cell death can be executed through different subroutines. Since the description of ferroptosis as an iron-dependent form of non-apoptotic cell death in 2012, there has been mounting interest in the process and function of ferroptosis. Ferroptosis can occur through two major pathways, the extrinsic or transporter-dependent pathway and the intrinsic or enzyme-regulated pathway. Ferroptosis is caused by a redox imbalance between the production of oxidants and antioxidants, which is driven by the abnormal expression and activity of multiple redox-active enzymes that produce or detoxify free radicals and lipid oxidation products. Accordingly, ferroptosis is precisely regulated at multiple levels, including epigenetic, transcriptional, posttranscriptional and posttranslational layers. The transcription factor NFE2L2 plays a central role in upregulating anti-ferroptotic defense, whereas selective autophagy may promote ferroptotic death. Here, we review current knowledge on the integrated molecular machinery of ferroptosis and describe how dysregulated ferroptosis is involved in cancer, neurodegeneration, tissue injury, inflammation, and infection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Metabolic Underpinnings of Ferroptosis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/33217331/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/33217331/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acute or chronic cellular stress resulting from aberrant metabolic and biochemical processes may trigger a pervasive non-apoptotic form of cell death, generally known as ferroptosis. Ferroptosis is unique among the different cell death modalities, as it has been mostly linked to pathophysiological conditions and because several metabolic pathways, such as (seleno)thiol metabolism, fatty acid metabolism, iron handling, mevalonate pathway, and mitochondrial respiration, directly impinge on the cells&amp;rsquo; sensitivity toward lipid peroxidation and ferroptosis. Additionally, key cellular redox systems, such as selenium-dependent glutathione peroxidase 4 and the NAD(P)H/ferroptosis suppressor protein-1/ubiquinone axis, are at play that constantly surveil and neutralize oxidative damage to cellular membranes. Since this form of cell death emerges to be the root cause of a number of diseases and since it offers various pharmacologically tractable nodes for therapeutic intervention, there has been overwhelming interest in the last few years aiming for a better molecular understanding of the ferroptotic death process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A gene expression signature of TREM2hi macrophages and γδ T cells predicts immunotherapy response</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33033253/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33033253/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Identifying factors underlying resistance to immune checkpoint therapy (ICT) is still challenging. Most cancer patients do not respond to ICT and the availability of the predictive biomarkers is limited. Here, we re-analyze a publicly available single-cell RNA sequencing (scRNA-seq) dataset of melanoma samples of patients subjected to ICT and identify a subset of macrophages overexpressing TREM2 and a subset of gammadelta T cells that are both overrepresented in the non-responding tumors. In addition, the percentage of a B cell subset is significantly lower in the non-responders. The presence of these immune cell subtypes is corroborated in other publicly available scRNA-seq datasets. The analyses of bulk RNA-seq datasets of the melanoma samples identify and validate a signature - ImmuneCells.Sig - enriched with the genes characteristic of the above immune cell subsets to predict response to immunotherapy. ImmuneCells.Sig could represent a valuable tool for clinical decision making in patients receiving immunotherapy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Targeting Ferroptosis: New Hope for As-Yet-Incurable Diseases</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/32958404/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/32958404/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Attaining control over life and death decisions facilitates the identification of new therapeutic strategies for diseases affected by early cell loss or resistance to cell death. In this context, ferroptosis, a prevailing form of non-apoptotic cell death marked by the iron-dependent oxidative destruction of lipid bilayers and metabolic aberrations, has attracted overwhelming interest among basic researchers and clinicians due to its relevance for a number of degenerative diseases, such as neurodegeneration, ischemia/reperfusion injury (IRI), and organ failure, as well as therapy-resistant tumors. As the ferroptotic death pathway offers various druggable nodes, it is anticipated that the preclinical and clinical development of ferroptosis modulators will unleash unprecedented opportunities for the treatment of as-yet-incurable diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hepatic transferrin plays a role in systemic iron homeostasis and liver ferroptosis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32374849/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32374849/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although the serum-abundant metal-binding protein transferrin (encoded by the &lt;em&gt;Trf&lt;/em&gt; gene) is synthesized primarily in the liver, its function in the liver is largely unknown. Here, we generated hepatocyte-specific &lt;em&gt;Trf&lt;/em&gt; knockout mice (&lt;em&gt;Trf&lt;/em&gt;-LKO), which are viable and fertile but have impaired erythropoiesis and altered iron metabolism. Moreover, feeding &lt;em&gt;Trf&lt;/em&gt;-LKO mice a high-iron diet increased their susceptibility to developing ferroptosis-induced liver fibrosis. Importantly, we found that treating &lt;em&gt;Trf&lt;/em&gt;-LKO mice with the ferroptosis inhibitor ferrostatin-1 potently rescued liver fibrosis induced by either high dietary iron or carbon tetrachloride (CCl&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;) injections. In addition, deleting hepatic Slc39a14 expression in &lt;em&gt;Trf&lt;/em&gt;-LKO mice significantly reduced hepatic iron accumulation, thereby reducing ferroptosis-mediated liver fibrosis induced by either a high-iron diet or CCl&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; injections. Finally, we found that patients with liver cirrhosis have significantly lower levels of serum transferrin and hepatic transferrin, as well as higher levels of hepatic iron and lipid peroxidation, compared with healthy control subjects. Taken together, these data indicate that hepatic transferrin plays a protective role in maintaining liver function, providing a possible therapeutic target for preventing ferroptosis-induced liver fibrosis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emerging Mechanisms and Disease Relevance of Ferroptosis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/32413317/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/32413317/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cell death is an essential feature of development in multicellular organisms, a critical driver of degenerative diseases, and can be harnessed for treating some cancers. Understanding the mechanisms governing cell death is critical for addressing its role in disease. Similarly, metabolism is essential for normal energy and biomolecule production, and goes awry in many diseases. Metabolism and cell death are tightly linked in the phenomenon of ferroptosis, a form of regulated cell death driven by peroxidation of phospholipids. Glutathione peroxidase 4 (GPX4) uses glutathione to protect cells from ferroptosis by eliminating phospholipid peroxides. Recent data have revealed glutathione/GPX4-independent axes for suppressing ferroptosis, and insight into the regulation of iron and mitochondria in ferroptosis. Ferroptosis has recently been implicated in multiple diseases, and functions as a tumor suppression mechanism. Ferroptosis induction is a promising approach in treating several conditions, including neoplastic diseases. Here, we summarize these recent advances.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mitochondrial DNA stress triggers autophagy-dependent ferroptotic death</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32186434/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32186434/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pancreatic cancer tends to be highly resistant to current therapy and remains one of the great challenges in biomedicine with very low 5-year survival rates. Here, we report that zalcitabine, an antiviral drug for human immunodeficiency virus infection, can suppress the growth of primary and immortalized human pancreatic cancer cells through the induction of ferroptosis, an iron-dependent form of regulated cell death. Mechanically, this effect relies on zalcitabine-induced mitochondrial DNA stress, which activates the STING1/TMEM173-mediated DNA sensing pathway, leading to macroautophagy/autophagy-dependent ferroptotic cell death via lipid peroxidation, but not a type I interferon response. Consequently, the genetic and pharmacological inactivation of the autophagy-dependent ferroptosis pathway diminishes the anticancer effects of zalcitabine in cell culture and animal models. Together, these findings not only provide a new approach for pancreatic cancer therapy but also increase our understanding of the interplay between autophagy and DNA damage response in shaping cell death.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FSP1 is a glutathione-independent ferroptosis suppressor</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/31634899/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/31634899/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ferroptosis is an iron-dependent form of necrotic cell death marked by oxidative damage to phospholipids. To date, ferroptosis has been thought to be controlled only by the phospholipid hydroperoxide-reducing enzyme glutathione peroxidase 4 (GPX4) and radical-trapping antioxidants. However, elucidation of the factors that underlie the sensitivity of a given cell type to ferroptosis is crucial to understand the pathophysiological role of ferroptosis and how it may be exploited for the treatment of cancer. Although metabolic constraints and phospholipid composition contribute to ferroptosis sensitivity, no cell-autonomous mechanisms have been identified that account for the resistance of cells to ferroptosis. Here we used an expression cloning approach to identify genes in human cancer cells that are able to complement the loss of GPX4. We found that the flavoprotein apoptosis-inducing factor mitochondria-associated 2 (AIFM2) is a previously unrecognized anti-ferroptotic gene. AIFM2, which we renamed ferroptosis suppressor protein 1 (FSP1) and which was initially described as a pro-apoptotic gene, confers protection against ferroptosis elicited by GPX4 deletion. We further demonstrate that the suppression of ferroptosis by FSP1 is mediated by ubiquinone (also known as coenzyme Q&lt;sub&gt;10&lt;/sub&gt;, CoQ&lt;sub&gt;10&lt;/sub&gt;): the reduced form, ubiquinol, traps lipid peroxyl radicals that mediate lipid peroxidation, whereas FSP1 catalyses the regeneration of CoQ&lt;sub&gt;10&lt;/sub&gt; using NAD(P)H. Pharmacological targeting of FSP1 strongly synergizes with GPX4 inhibitors to trigger ferroptosis in a number of cancer entities. In conclusion, the FSP1-CoQ&lt;sub&gt;10&lt;/sub&gt;-NAD(P)H pathway exists as a stand-alone parallel system, which co-operates with GPX4 and glutathione to suppress phospholipid peroxidation and ferroptosis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The CoQ oxidoreductase FSP1 acts parallel to GPX4 to inhibit ferroptosis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/31634900/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/31634900/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ferroptosis is a form of regulated cell death that is caused by the iron-dependent peroxidation of lipids. The glutathione-dependent lipid hydroperoxidase glutathione peroxidase 4 (GPX4) prevents ferroptosis by converting lipid hydroperoxides into non-toxic lipid alcohols. Ferroptosis has previously been implicated in the cell death that underlies several degenerative conditions, and induction of ferroptosis by the inhibition of GPX4 has emerged as a therapeutic strategy to trigger cancer cell death. However, sensitivity to GPX4 inhibitors varies greatly across cancer cell lines, which suggests that additional factors govern resistance to ferroptosis. Here, using a synthetic lethal CRISPR-Cas9 screen, we identify ferroptosis suppressor protein 1 (FSP1) (previously known as apoptosis-inducing factor mitochondrial 2 (AIFM2)) as a potent ferroptosis-resistance factor. Our data indicate that myristoylation recruits FSP1 to the plasma membrane where it functions as an oxidoreductase that reduces coenzyme Q&lt;sub&gt;10&lt;/sub&gt; (CoQ) (also known as ubiquinone-10), which acts as a lipophilic radical-trapping antioxidant that halts the propagation of lipid peroxides. We further find that FSP1 expression positively correlates with ferroptosis resistance across hundreds of cancer cell lines, and that FSP1 mediates resistance to ferroptosis in lung cancer cells in culture and in mouse tumour xenografts. Thus, our data identify FSP1 as a key component of a non-mitochondrial CoQ antioxidant system that acts in parallel to the canonical glutathione-based GPX4 pathway. These findings define a ferroptosis suppression pathway and indicate that pharmacological inhibition of FSP1 may provide an effective strategy to sensitize cancer cells to ferroptosis-inducing chemotherapeutic agents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Coming Decade of Cell Death Research: Five Riddles</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/31100266/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/31100266/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Active cell death, in its many forms, is a fundamental biological process. Studies over the past several decades have explored the functions and consequences of cellular demise and elucidated several of the key cell death pathways. Here, I pose five questions, or riddles, that might provide a guide to the next decade of cell death research. Focusing mainly on four types of active cell death (apoptosis, necroptosis, pyroptosis, and ferroptosis) mainly in mammals, this Perspective explores the possible research directions that might answer these riddles, or at least prompt new ones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ferroptosis: A Regulated Cell Death Nexus Linking Metabolism, Redox Biology, and Disease</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/28985560/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/28985560/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ferroptosis is a form of regulated cell death characterized by the iron-dependent accumulation of lipid hydroperoxides to lethal levels. Emerging evidence suggests that ferroptosis represents an ancient vulnerability caused by the incorporation of polyunsaturated fatty acids into cellular membranes, and cells have developed complex systems that exploit and defend against this vulnerability in different contexts. The sensitivity to ferroptosis is tightly linked to numerous biological processes, including amino acid, iron, and polyunsaturated fatty acid metabolism, and the biosynthesis of glutathione, phospholipids, NADPH, and coenzyme Q&lt;sub&gt;10&lt;/sub&gt;. Ferroptosis has been implicated in the pathological cell death associated with degenerative diseases (i.e., Alzheimer&amp;rsquo;s, Huntington&amp;rsquo;s, and Parkinson&amp;rsquo;s diseases), carcinogenesis, stroke, intracerebral hemorrhage, traumatic brain injury, ischemia-reperfusion injury, and kidney degeneration in mammals and is also implicated in heat stress in plants. Ferroptosis may also have a tumor-suppressor function that could be harnessed for cancer therapy. This Primer reviews the mechanisms underlying ferroptosis, highlights connections to other areas of biology and medicine, and recommends tools and guidelines for studying this emerging form of regulated cell death.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ferroptosis: an iron-dependent form of nonapoptotic cell death</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/22632970/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/22632970/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nonapoptotic forms of cell death may facilitate the selective elimination of some tumor cells or be activated in specific pathological states. The oncogenic RAS-selective lethal small molecule erastin triggers a unique iron-dependent form of nonapoptotic cell death that we term ferroptosis. Ferroptosis is dependent upon intracellular iron, but not other metals, and is morphologically, biochemically, and genetically distinct from apoptosis, necrosis, and autophagy. We identify the small molecule ferrostatin-1 as a potent inhibitor of ferroptosis in cancer cells and glutamate-induced cell death in organotypic rat brain slices, suggesting similarities between these two processes. Indeed, erastin, like glutamate, inhibits cystine uptake by the cystine/glutamate antiporter (system x(c)(-)), creating a void in the antioxidant defenses of the cell and ultimately leading to iron-dependent, oxidative death. Thus, activation of ferroptosis results in the nonapoptotic destruction of certain cancer cells, whereas inhibition of this process may protect organisms from neurodegeneration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Synthetic lethal screening identifies compounds activating iron-dependent, nonapoptotic cell death in oncogenic-RAS-harboring cancer cells</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/18355723/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/18355723/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We screened small molecules to identify two compounds, which we named RSL3 and RSL5, that have increased lethality in the presence of oncogenic RAS. Counter screening with biologically active compounds defined aspects of the mechanism of action for RSL3 and RSL5, such as a nonapoptotic, MEK-dependent, and iron-dependent oxidative cell death. Erastin, a previously reported compound with RAS-selective lethality, showed similar properties. RNA interference experiments targeting voltage-dependent anion channel 3 (VDAC3), a target of erastin, demonstrated that RSL5 is a scaffold that acts through VDACs to activate the observed pathway. RSL3 activated a similar death mechanism but in a VDAC-independent manner. We found that cells transformed with oncogenic RAS have increased iron content relative to their normal cell counterparts through upregulation of transferrin receptor 1 and downregulation of ferritin heavy chain 1 and ferritin light chain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RAS-RAF-MEK-dependent oxidative cell death involving voltage-dependent anion channels</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/17568748/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jun 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/17568748/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therapeutics that discriminate between the genetic makeup of normal cells and tumour cells are valuable for treating and understanding cancer. Small molecules with oncogene-selective lethality may reveal novel functions of oncoproteins and enable the creation of more selective drugs. Here we describe the mechanism of action of the selective anti-tumour agent erastin, involving the RAS-RAF-MEK signalling pathway functioning in cell proliferation, differentiation and survival. Erastin exhibits greater lethality in human tumour cells harbouring mutations in the oncogenes HRAS, KRAS or BRAF. Using affinity purification and mass spectrometry, we discovered that erastin acts through mitochondrial voltage-dependent anion channels (VDACs)&amp;ndash;a novel target for anti-cancer drugs. We show that erastin treatment of cells harbouring oncogenic RAS causes the appearance of oxidative species and subsequent death through an oxidative, non-apoptotic mechanism. RNA-interference-mediated knockdown of VDAC2 or VDAC3 caused resistance to erastin, implicating these two VDAC isoforms in the mechanism of action of erastin. Moreover, using purified mitochondria expressing a single VDAC isoform, we found that erastin alters the permeability of the outer mitochondrial membrane. Finally, using a radiolabelled analogue and a filter-binding assay, we show that erastin binds directly to VDAC2. These results demonstrate that ligands to VDAC proteins can induce non-apoptotic cell death selectively in some tumour cells harbouring activating mutations in the RAS-RAF-MEK pathway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
