<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Antagonist/Drugs | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/antagonist/drugs/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/antagonist/drugs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Antagonist/Drugs</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Antagonist/Drugs</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/antagonist/drugs/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Skullcapflavone II, a novel NQO1 inhibitor, alleviates aristolochic acid I-induced liver and kidney injury in mice</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36697978/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36697978/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aristolochic acid I (AAI) is a well established nephrotoxin and human carcinogen. Cytosolic NAD(P)H quinone oxidoreductase 1 (NQO1) plays an important role in the nitro reduction of aristolochic acids, leading to production of aristoloactam and AA-DNA adduct. Application of a potent NQO1 inhibitor dicoumarol is limited by its life-threatening side effect as an anticoagulant and the subsequent hemorrhagic complications. As traditional medicines containing AAI remain available in the market, novel NQO1 inhibitors are urgently needed to attenuate the toxicity of AAI exposure. In this study, we employed comprehensive 2D NQO1 biochromatography to screen candidate compounds that could bind with NQO1 protein. Four compounds, i.e., skullcapflavone II (SFII), oroxylin A, wogonin and tectochrysin were screened out from Scutellaria baicalensis. Among them, SFII was the most promising NQO1 inhibitor with a binding affinity (KD = 4.198 μmol/L) and inhibitory activity (IC50 = 2.87 μmol/L). In human normal liver cell line (L02) and human renal proximal tubular epithelial cell line (HK-2), SFII significantly alleviated AAI-induced DNA damage and apoptosis. In adult mice, oral administration of SFII dose-dependently ameliorated AAI-induced renal fibrosis and dysfunction. In infant mice, oral administration of SFII suppressed AAI-induced hepatocellular carcinoma initiation. Moreover, administration of SFII did not affect the coagulation function in short term in adult mice. In conclusion, SFII has been identified as a novel NQO1 inhibitor that might impede the risk of AAI to kidney and liver without obvious side effect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Discovery and pharmacological characterization of a novel benzimidazole TRPV4 antagonist with cyanocyclobutyl moiety</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36696767/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36696767/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2b displayed more potent &lt;em&gt;in vitro&lt;/em&gt; TRPV4 inhibition activity than GSK-Bz.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Single cell patch-clamp proved that 2b also gave significantly improved potency.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2b is a novel and highly potent TRPV4 antagonist &lt;em&gt;in vitro&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GSK-Bz, a TPRV4 antagonist discovered by GSK, displayed potent in vitro TRPV4 inhibition activity, and demonstrated ability to inhibit TRPV4-mediated pulmonary edema in an &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt; rat model. In this study, a series of GSK-Bz derivatives were designed and synthesized based on our previous findings. Compound 2b with cyanocyclobutyl moiety (IC&lt;sub&gt;50&lt;/sub&gt; = 22.65 nM) was found to be 5.3-fold more potent than GSK-Bz (IC&lt;sub&gt;50&lt;/sub&gt; = 121.6 nM) in the calcium imaging experiment. Patch-clamp experiments confirmed that compound 2b (IR = 77.1%) also gave significantly improved potency on TRPV4 currents measured at -60 mV. Furthermore, 2b effectively suppressed the permeability response to LPS in HUVEC with negligible cytotoxicity (CC&lt;sub&gt;50&lt;/sub&gt; &amp;gt; 100 μM). The &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt; protective effects of compounds 2b on acute lung injury were finally assessed in an LPS-induced ALI mice model. Notably, 2b gave better results than HC-067047 against all of the tested indexes (lung W/D ratios, the concentrations of BALF protein and pathological scores), indicating that 2b is a novel and highly potent TRPV4 antagonist which is worth for further development. Currently, evaluation for the drug-like properties of 2b is underway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
