<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Antagonist/Drugs | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/antagonist/drugs/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/antagonist/drugs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Antagonist/Drugs</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Antagonist/Drugs</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/antagonist/drugs/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Significant anti-inflammatory aziridine-containing indole alkaloids from the Chinese medicinal plant Alstonia scholaris</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36734477/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36734477/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two unique windmill-like aziridine-containing indole alkaloids, possessing an unprecedented 6/5/5/6/6/5/3 rigid ring system and an unusual azabicyclo[3.1.0]hexane core, were isolated from &lt;em&gt;Alstonia scholaris&lt;/em&gt;. Their structures were established by spectroscopy, X-ray diffraction, and electronic circular dichroism calculations. The novel compounds exhibited significant anti-inflammatory bioactivity in vitro and alleviated LPS-induced acute lung injury in mice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SGLT2 Inhibitors: The Sweet Success for Kidneys</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/36706745/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/36706745/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sodium-glucose cotransporter-2 inhibitors (SGLT2 inhibitors) were originally developed as antidiabetic agents, with cardiovascular (CV) outcome trials demonstrating improved CV outcomes in patients with type 2 diabetes mellitus (T2D). Secondary analyses of CV outcome trials and later dedicated kidney outcome trials consistently reported improved kidney-related outcomes independent of T2D status and across a range of kidney function and albuminuria. Importantly, SGLT2 inhibitors are generally safe and well tolerated, with clinical trials and real-world analyses demonstrating a decrease in the risk of acute kidney injury. The kidney protective effects of SGLT2 inhibitors generally extend across different members of the class, possibly on the basis of hemodynamic, metabolic, anti-inflammatory, and antifibrotic mechanisms. In this review, we summarize the effects of SGLT2 inhibitors on kidney outcomes in diverse patient populations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kirenol inhibits inflammation challenged by lipopolysaccharide through the AMPK-mTOR-ULK1 autophagy pathway</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36706589/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36706589/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kirenol is a bioactive substance isolated from &lt;em&gt;Herba Siegesbeckiae&lt;/em&gt;. Although the anti-inflammatory activity of kirenol has been well documented, its role in autophagy remains unknown. The present study aimed to investigate the protective role of kirenol on inflammation challenged by lipopolysaccharide (LPS) in acute lung injury (ALI) cell and mouse models and unravel the underlying mechanisms, with a particular focus on autophagy. For this purpose, an ALI cell and mouse models were established, and the effects of kirenol on the expression of molecules related to inflammation and autophagy were examined. The present results revealed that kirenol could significantly inhibit inflammatory cytokines secretion in cells and in the mice injured by LPS; this effect may be attributed to enhanced autophagy as evidenced by the up-regulation of LC3-II and the down-regulation of p62 both in vitro and in vivo. Phosphorylated AMPK and ULK1 increased, while phosphorylated mTOR decreased in the kirenol-treated ALI cell model. Moreover, inhibition of autophagy using AMPK inhibitor or 3-MA or chloroquine (CQ) reversed the anti-inflammatory and autophagy-enhancement effects of kirenol exposure in vitro, indicating that kirenol could enhance autophagy by activating the AMPK-mTOR-ULK1 pathway. The results of RNA sequencing suggested that kirenol was strongly related to the biological functions of acute inflammatory response and the AMPK signaling pathway. Further in vivo ALI mouse model studies demonstrated the protective role of kirenol against lung inflammation, such as improved histopathology, decreased lung edema, and leukocyte infiltration were abolished by 3-MA. These findings implicate that kirenol can inhibit LPS-induced inflammation via the AMPK-mTOR-ULK1 autophagy pathway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Skullcapflavone II, a novel NQO1 inhibitor, alleviates aristolochic acid I-induced liver and kidney injury in mice</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36697978/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36697978/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aristolochic acid I (AAI) is a well established nephrotoxin and human carcinogen. Cytosolic NAD(P)H quinone oxidoreductase 1 (NQO1) plays an important role in the nitro reduction of aristolochic acids, leading to production of aristoloactam and AA-DNA adduct. Application of a potent NQO1 inhibitor dicoumarol is limited by its life-threatening side effect as an anticoagulant and the subsequent hemorrhagic complications. As traditional medicines containing AAI remain available in the market, novel NQO1 inhibitors are urgently needed to attenuate the toxicity of AAI exposure. In this study, we employed comprehensive 2D NQO1 biochromatography to screen candidate compounds that could bind with NQO1 protein. Four compounds, i.e., skullcapflavone II (SFII), oroxylin A, wogonin and tectochrysin were screened out from Scutellaria baicalensis. Among them, SFII was the most promising NQO1 inhibitor with a binding affinity (KD = 4.198 μmol/L) and inhibitory activity (IC50 = 2.87 μmol/L). In human normal liver cell line (L02) and human renal proximal tubular epithelial cell line (HK-2), SFII significantly alleviated AAI-induced DNA damage and apoptosis. In adult mice, oral administration of SFII dose-dependently ameliorated AAI-induced renal fibrosis and dysfunction. In infant mice, oral administration of SFII suppressed AAI-induced hepatocellular carcinoma initiation. Moreover, administration of SFII did not affect the coagulation function in short term in adult mice. In conclusion, SFII has been identified as a novel NQO1 inhibitor that might impede the risk of AAI to kidney and liver without obvious side effect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tripterygium wilfordii Hook.f. ameliorates paraquat-induced lung injury by reducing oxidative stress and ferroptosis via Nrf2/HO-1 pathway</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36706526/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36706526/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PQ poisoning can induce acute lung injury and fibrosis without effective treatment methods.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;TwHF possessed potential properties in therapies for PQ-induced lung injury and fibrosis.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The protective effect of TwHF may be due to the regulation of oxidative stress and ferroptosis.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paraquat (PQ) poisoning can induce acute lung injury and fibrosis and has an extremely high mortality rate. However, no effective treatments for PQ poisoning have been established. In this study, the potential efficacy of Tripterygium wilfordii Hook.f. (TwHF) in alleviating PQ-induced lung injury and fibrosis was investigated in a mouse model. Mice were randomly assigned to the control, PQ, PQ + TwHF1 (pretreatment before inducing poisoning), and PQ + TwHF2 (treatment after poisoning) groups. The mice in the PQ + TwHF1 group were pretreated with TwHF for 5 days before receiving one dose of PQ (120 mg/kg) and then received a daily oral gavage of the indicated dosages of TwHF until sacrifice. The mice in the PQ + TwHF2 group were treated with TwHF 2 h after PQ exposure until sacrifice. The pathological analysis and Fapi PET/CT showed that treatment with TwHF attenuated lung injury. And TwHF reduced pulmonary oxidative stress, as indicated by the reduction in, malondialdehyde (MDA), glutathione (GSH), and reactive oxygen species (ROS) levels, as well as by the increase in superoxide dismutase (SOD) levels. Accordingly, the Perls DAB staining showed increased iron concentrations and western blotting revealed a decreased GPX4 expression after PQ exposure, as well as the mitigation of the overexpression of Nrf2 and HO-1 induced by PQ. In conclusion, our study demonstrated the potential of TwHF as a treatment for PQ-induced lung injury and fibrosis. The protective mechanism of this medicinal herb may involve the regulation of ferroptosis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Discovery of 4-oxo-N-phenyl-1,4-dihydroquinoline-3-carboxamide derivatives as novel anti-inflammatory agents for the treatment of acute lung injury and sepsis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36708679/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36708679/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acute lung injury (ALI) and sepsis, characterized by systemic inflammatory response syndrome, remain the major causes of death in severe patients. Inhibiting the release of proinflammatory cytokines is considered to be a promising method for the treatment of inflammation-related diseases. In this study, a total of 28 4-oxo-N-phenyl-1,4-dihydroquinoline-3-carboxamide derivatives were designed and synthesized and their anti-inflammatory activities in J774A.1 were evaluated. Among them, derivative 13a was found to significantly inhibit lipopolysaccharide (LPS)-induced expression of the proinflammatory cytokines interleukin-6 (IL-6) and tumor necrosis factor-α (TNF-α) on J774A.1, THP-1 and LX-2 cells, and inhibited the activation of the NF-κB pathway. Furthermore, administration of 13ain vivo significantly improved the symptoms in LPS-induced ALI mice, including alleviation of pathological changes in the lung tissue, reduction of pulmonary edema, and inhibition of macrophage infiltration. Moreover, the administration of 13ain vivo significantly promoted survival in LPS-induced sepsis mice. 13a demonstrated favorable pharmacokinetic properties with T&lt;sub&gt;1/2&lt;/sub&gt; value of 11.8 h and F value of 36.3%. Therefore, this study has identified a novel 4-oxo-N-phenyl-1,4-dihydroquinoline-3-carboxamide derivative, 13a, which is an effective anti-inflammatory agent. The findings have laid a foundation for the further development of agents to treat ALI and sepsis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Discovery and pharmacological characterization of a novel benzimidazole TRPV4 antagonist with cyanocyclobutyl moiety</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36696767/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36696767/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2b displayed more potent &lt;em&gt;in vitro&lt;/em&gt; TRPV4 inhibition activity than GSK-Bz.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Single cell patch-clamp proved that 2b also gave significantly improved potency.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2b is a novel and highly potent TRPV4 antagonist &lt;em&gt;in vitro&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GSK-Bz, a TPRV4 antagonist discovered by GSK, displayed potent in vitro TRPV4 inhibition activity, and demonstrated ability to inhibit TRPV4-mediated pulmonary edema in an &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt; rat model. In this study, a series of GSK-Bz derivatives were designed and synthesized based on our previous findings. Compound 2b with cyanocyclobutyl moiety (IC&lt;sub&gt;50&lt;/sub&gt; = 22.65 nM) was found to be 5.3-fold more potent than GSK-Bz (IC&lt;sub&gt;50&lt;/sub&gt; = 121.6 nM) in the calcium imaging experiment. Patch-clamp experiments confirmed that compound 2b (IR = 77.1%) also gave significantly improved potency on TRPV4 currents measured at -60 mV. Furthermore, 2b effectively suppressed the permeability response to LPS in HUVEC with negligible cytotoxicity (CC&lt;sub&gt;50&lt;/sub&gt; &amp;gt; 100 μM). The &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt; protective effects of compounds 2b on acute lung injury were finally assessed in an LPS-induced ALI mice model. Notably, 2b gave better results than HC-067047 against all of the tested indexes (lung W/D ratios, the concentrations of BALF protein and pathological scores), indicating that 2b is a novel and highly potent TRPV4 antagonist which is worth for further development. Currently, evaluation for the drug-like properties of 2b is underway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The antimicrobial peptide LK2(6)A(L) exhibits anti-inflammatory activity by binding to the myeloid differentiation 2 domain and protects against LPS-induced acute lung injury in mice</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36706531/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36706531/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;LK2(6)A(L) reflected anti-inflammatory activity through TLR4 signaling pathway.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;LK2(6)A(L) interacted with MD2 and the knockdown MD2 abolished its anti-inflammatory.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The key domain of LK2(6)A(L) binding to MD2 was its amino acid domain 7–13 (IS-7).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;LK2(6)A(L) and IS-7 displayed protective effects in LPS-induced ALI mice.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acute lung injury (ALI) is a life-threatening disease that is generally attributable to an uncontrolled inflammatory response in the lung, but there is a lack of effective treatments. At present, regulating the inflammatory response has become an important strategy for treating ALI. In the present study, LK2(6)A(L), a peptide derived from the natural antimicrobial peptide temporin-1CEa, inhibited lipopolysaccharide (LPS)-induced expression of tumor necrosis factor alpha (TNF-α), interleukin-6 (IL-6), and NO in RAW264.7 cells. Herein, the anti-inflammatory mechanism of LK2(6)A(L) was investigated. The RNA-sequencing (RNA-seq) results showed that LK2(6)A(L) significantly inhibited the TLR4-mediated NF-κB and MAPK signaling pathways in LPS-induced RAW264.7 cells. The results of co-immunoprecipitation (Co-IP), pull-down experiment, confocal laser scanning microscopy, and surface plasmon resonance (SPR) suggested that MD2 was the direct target of LK2(6)A(L). Chemical inhibition of MD2 and its knockdown abolished the anti-inflammatory effect of LK2(6)A(L). Molecular dynamic simulation indicated that LK2(6)A(L) could bind to the active domain of the MD2 hydrophobic pocket via six hydrogen bonds. The truncated peptides were designed based on analysis of the molecular docking of LK2(6)A(L) to MD2. The truncated peptide IS-7 showed strong affinity to MD2 and a remarkable inhibitory effect on pro-inflammatory factors that was comparable to the effect of LK2(6)A(L). Finally, LK2(6)A(L) and IS-7 relieved inflammatory symptoms and lung tissue destruction in the ALI mouse model. Overall, our study suggested that LK2(6)A(L) showed promising anti-inflammatory activity by targeting MD2, and the amino acid domain 7-13 was an important area that binds with MD2 and also an anti-inflammatory active region. LK2(6)A(L) and IS-7 may be potential new treatments for ALI and other acute inflammatory diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The c-Abl inhibitor IkT-148009 suppresses neurodegeneration in mouse models of heritable and sporadic Parkinson&#39;s disease</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36652533/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36652533/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Parkinson&amp;rsquo;s disease (PD) is the second most prevalent neurodegenerative disease of the central nervous system, with an estimated 5,000,000 cases worldwide. PD pathology is characterized by the accumulation of misfolded α-synuclein, which is thought to play a critical role in the pathogenesis of the disease. Animal models of PD suggest that activation of Abelson tyrosine kinase (c-Abl) plays an essential role in the initiation and progression of α-synuclein pathology and initiates processes leading to degeneration of dopaminergic and nondopaminergic neurons. Given the potential role of c-Abl in PD, a c-Abl inhibitor library was developed to identify orally bioavailable c-Abl inhibitors capable of crossing the blood-brain barrier based on predefined characteristics, leading to the discovery of IkT-148009. IkT-148009, a brain-penetrant c-Abl inhibitor with a favorable toxicology profile, was analyzed for therapeutic potential in animal models of slowly progressive, α-synuclein-dependent PD. In mouse models of both inherited and sporadic PD, IkT-148009 suppressed c-Abl activation to baseline and substantially protected dopaminergic neurons from degeneration when administered therapeutically by once daily oral gavage beginning 4 weeks after disease initiation. Recovery of motor function in PD mice occurred within 8 weeks of initiating treatment concomitantly with a reduction in α-synuclein pathology in the mouse brain. These findings suggest that IkT-148009 may have potential as a disease-modifying therapy in PD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nucleic acid drug vectors for diagnosis and treatment of brain diseases</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/36650130/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/36650130/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nucleic acid drugs have the advantages of rich target selection, simple in design, good and enduring effect. They have been demonstrated to have irreplaceable superiority in brain disease treatment, while vectors are a decisive factor in therapeutic efficacy. Strict physiological barriers, such as degradation and clearance in circulation, blood-brain barrier, cellular uptake, endosome/lysosome barriers, release, obstruct the delivery of nucleic acid drugs to the brain by the vectors. Nucleic acid drugs against a single target are inefficient in treating brain diseases of complex pathogenesis. Differences between individual patients lead to severe uncertainties in brain disease treatment with nucleic acid drugs. In this Review, we briefly summarize the classification of nucleic acid drugs. Next, we discuss physiological barriers during drug delivery and universal coping strategies and introduce the application methods of these universal strategies to nucleic acid drug vectors. Subsequently, we explore nucleic acid drug-based multidrug regimens for the combination treatment of brain diseases and the construction of the corresponding vectors. In the following, we address the feasibility of patient stratification and personalized therapy through diagnostic information from medical imaging and the manner of introducing contrast agents into vectors. Finally, we take a perspective on the future feasibility and remaining challenges of vector-based integrated diagnosis and gene therapy for brain diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nonsteroidal anti-inflammatory drugs (NSAIDs) and nucleotide analog GS-441524 conjugates with potent in vivo efficacy against coronaviruses</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36706621/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36706621/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ibuprofen and nucleotide analog GS-441524 conjugates (ATV041) were designed and demonstrated broad anti-CoV activities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ATV041 successfully improved the oral PK profile and tissue distribution relative to GS-441524 which has poor oral PK.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Oral ATV041 reduced viral loads, alleviated tissue damage and virus-induced inflammation in MHV-A59 mice.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coronaviruses (CoVs) infect a broad range of hosts, including humans and various animals, with a tendency to cross the species barrier, causing severe harm to human society and fostering the need for effective anti-coronaviral drugs. GS-441524 is a broad-spectrum antiviral nucleoside with potent anti-CoVs activities. However, its application is limited by poor oral bioavailability. Herein, we designed and synthesized several conjugates via covalently binding NSAIDs to 5&amp;rsquo;-OH of GS-441524 through ester bonds. The ibuprofen conjugate, ATV041, exhibited potent in vitro anti-coronaviral efficacy against four zoonotic coronaviruses in the alpha- and beta-genera. Oral-dosed ATV041 resulted in favorable bioavailability and rapid tissue distribution of GS-441524 and ibuprofen. In MHV-A59 infected mice, ATV041 dose-dependently decreased viral RNA replication and significantly reduced the proinflammatory cytokines in the liver and the lung at 3 dpi. As a result, the MHV-A59-induced lung and liver inflammatory injury was significantly alleviated. Taken together, this work provides a novel drug conjugate strategy to improve oral PK and offers a potent anti-coronaviral lead compound for further studies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Buformin alleviates sepsis-induced acute lung injury via inhibiting NLRP3-mediated pyroptosis through an AMPK-dependent pathway</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35132999/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35132999/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; NOD-like receptor family pyrin domain containing 3 (NLRP3)-mediated macrophage pyroptosis plays an important role in sepsis-induced acute lung injury (ALI). Inhibition of pyroptosis may be a way to alleviate inflammation as well as tissue damage triggered after lipopolysaccharide (LPS) stimulation. The aim of the present study was to explore whether buformin (BF), a hypoglycemic agent, could alleviate sepsis-induced ALI by inhibiting pyroptosis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; Wildtype C57BL/6 mice were randomly divided into control group, BF group, LPS group and LPS+BF group. BF group and LPS+BF group were pretreated with BF at a dose of 25 mg/kg, and the changes were observed. In addition, BF was used to interfere with THP-1 cells. The therapeutic effect of BF has been verified by intraperitoneal injection of BF in vivo after LPS stimulation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; Inflammation and injury was significantly reduced in BF pretreated mice, and the indexes related to pyroptosis were suppressed. The phosphorylation of AMP-activated protein kinase (AMPK) in lung tissues of mice in the BF and LPS+BF groups was significantly higher. In THP-1 cells, the AMPK inhibitor, Compound C was added to demonstrate that BF worked via AMPK to inhibit NLRP3 inflammasome. It was further demonstrated that BF up-regulated autophagy, which in turn promoted NLRP3 inflammasome degradation. On the other hand, BF decreased NLRP3 mRNA level by increasing nuclear factor-erythroid 2 related factor 2 (Nrf2). And BF showed a therapeutic effect after LPS challenge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/em&gt; Our study confirmed that BF inhibited NLRP3-mediated pyroptosis in sepsis-induced ALI by up-regulating autophagy and Nrf2 protein level through an AMPK-dependent pathway. This provides a new strategy for clinical mitigation of sepsis-induced ALI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plasma EFEMP1 Is Associated with Brain Aging and Dementia: The Framingham Heart Study</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34958018/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34958018/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Epidermal growth factor containing fibulin extracellular matrix protein-1 (EFEMP1) has been associated with increased white matter hyperintensities (WMH) burden and disorders of premature aging and may have a shared pathophysiological role in the development of WMH and dementia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Objective:&lt;/em&gt; To determine the association between plasma EFEMP1 levels and MRI markers of vascular brain injury and incident all-cause and Alzheimer&amp;rsquo;s disease (AD) dementia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; We measured plasma EFEMP1 levels in 1597 [53% women, mean age 68.7 (SD 5.7) years] dementia-free Framingham Offspring cohort participants between 1998-2001 and subsequently followed them for incident dementia. Secondary outcomes included stroke, structural MRI brain measures and neurocognitive test performance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; During a median 11.8 [Q1, Q3 : 7.1, 13.3] year follow-up, 131 participants developed dementia. The highest quintile of plasma EFEMP1, compared to the bottom four quintiles, was associated with an increased risk of time to incident all-cause dementia (HR 1.77, 95% CI 1.18-2.64) and AD dementia (HR 1.76, 95% CI 1.11-2.81) but not with markers of vascular brain injury (WMH, covert brain infarcts or stroke). Higher circulating EFEMP1 concentrations were also cross-sectionally associated with lower total brain (β±SE, -0.28±0.11, &lt;em&gt;p&lt;/em&gt; = 0.01) and hippocampal volumes (-0.006±0.003, &lt;em&gt;p&lt;/em&gt; = 0.04) and impaired abstract reasoning (Similarities test, -0.18±0.08, &lt;em&gt;p&lt;/em&gt; = 0.018 per standard deviation increment in EFEMP1).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/em&gt; Elevated circulating EFEMP1 is associated with an increased risk of all-cause and AD dementia, smaller hippocampal and total brain volumes, and poorer cognitive performance. EFEMP1 may play an important biological role in the development of AD dementia. Further studies to validate these findings are warranted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cytochrome P450 Monooxygenase for Catalyzing C-42 Hydroxylation of the Glycine-Derived Fragment in Hangtaimycin Biosynthesis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35138108/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35138108/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A hybrid &lt;em&gt;trans&lt;/em&gt;-AT PKS/NRPS gene cluster htm was identified with defined boundaries for hangtaimycin biosynthesis in &lt;em&gt;Streptomyces spectabilis&lt;/em&gt; CPCC200148. Deoxyhangtaimycin, a new derivative of hangtaimycin, was identified from the htm11 gene knockout mutant. In vitro biochemical assays demonstrated that the cytochrome P450 monooxygenase Htm11 was responsible for the stereoselective hydroxylation of deoxyhangtaimycin to hangtaimycin. More importantly, deoxyhangtaimycin showed activity against influenza A virus at the micromolar level, highlighting its potential as an antiviral lead compound.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Disulfiram inhibits neutrophil extracellular trap formation and protects rodents from acute lung injury and SARS-CoV-2 infection</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/35133984/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/35133984/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Severe acute lung injury has few treatment options and a high mortality rate. Upon injury, neutrophils infiltrate the lungs and form neutrophil extracellular traps (NETs), damaging the lungs and driving an exacerbated immune response. Unfortunately, no drug preventing NET formation has completed clinical development. Here, we report that disulfiram - an FDA-approved drug for alcohol use disorder - dramatically reduced NETs, increased survival, improved blood oxygenation, and reduced lung edema in a transfusion-related acute lung injury (TRALI) mouse model. We then tested whether disulfiram could confer protection in the context of SARS-CoV-2 infection, as NETs are elevated in patients with severe COVID-19. In SARS-CoV-2-infected golden hamsters, disulfiram reduced NETs and perivascular fibrosis in the lungs, and it downregulated innate immune and complement/coagulation pathways, suggesting that it could be beneficial for patients with COVID-19. In conclusion, an existing FDA-approved drug can block NET formation and improve disease course in 2 rodent models of lung injury for which treatment options are limited.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ruxolitinib attenuates secondary injury after traumatic spinal cord injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35142693/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35142693/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Excessive inflammation post-traumatic spinal cord injury (SCI) induces microglial activation, which leads to prolonged neurological dysfunction. However, the mechanism underlying microglial activation-induced neuroinflammation remains poorly understood. Ruxolitinib (RUX), a selective inhibitor of JAK1/2, was recently reported to inhibit inflammatory storms caused by SARS-CoV-2 in the lung. However, its role in disrupting inflammation post-SCI has not been confirmed. In this study, microglia were treated with RUX for 24 hours and then activated with interferon-γ for 6 hours. The results showed that interferon-γ-induced phosphorylation of JAK and STAT in microglia was inhibited, and the mRNA expression levels of pro-inflammatory cytokines tumor necrosis factor-α, interleukin-1β, interleukin-6, and cell proliferation marker Ki67 were reduced. In further in vivo experiments, a mouse model of spinal cord injury was treated intragastrically with RUX for 3 successive days, and the findings suggest that RUX can inhibit microglial proliferation by inhibiting the interferon-γ/JAK/STAT pathway. Moreover, microglia treated with RUX centripetally migrated toward injured foci, remaining limited and compacted within the glial scar, which resulted in axon preservation and less demyelination. Moreover, the protein expression levels of tumor necrosis factor-α, interleukin-1β, and interleukin-6 were reduced. The neuromotor function of SCI mice also recovered. These findings suggest that RUX can inhibit neuroinflammation through inhibiting the interferon-γ/JAK/STAT pathway, thereby reducing secondary injury after SCI and producing neuroprotective effects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Therapeutic effects of eperisone on pulmonary fibrosis via preferential suppression of fibroblast activity</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35136056/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35136056/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The murine caspase-11 non-canonical inflammasome responds to various bacterial infections. Caspase-11 activation-induced pyroptosis, in response to cytoplasmic lipopolysaccharide (LPS), is critical for endotoxic shock in mice. The mechanism underlying cytosolic LPS sensing and the responsible pattern recognition receptor are unknown. Here we show that human monocytes, epithelial cells and keratinocytes undergo necrosis upon cytoplasmic delivery of LPS. LPS-induced cytotoxicity was mediated by human caspase-4 that could functionally complement murine caspase-11. Human caspase-4 and the mouse homologue caspase-11 (hereafter referred to as caspase-4/11) and also human caspase-5, directly bound to LPS and lipid A with high specificity and affinity. LPS associated with endogenous caspase-11 in pyroptotic cells. Insect-cell purified caspase-4/11 underwent oligomerization upon LPS binding, resulting in activation of the caspases. Underacylated lipid IVa and lipopolysaccharide from Rhodobacter sphaeroides (LPS-RS) could bind to caspase-4/11 but failed to induce their oligomerization and activation. LPS binding was mediated by the CARD domain of the caspase. Binding-deficient CARD-domain point mutants did not respond to LPS with oligomerization or activation and failed to induce pyroptosis upon LPS electroporation or bacterial infections. The function of caspase-4/5/11 represents a new mode of pattern recognition in immunity and also an unprecedented means of caspase activation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dihydroartemisinin attenuates pulmonary inflammation and fibrosis in rats by suppressing JAK2/STAT3 signaling</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35120332/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35120332/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19), caused by SARS-CoV-2, has induced a worldwide pandemic since early 2020. COVID-19 causes pulmonary inflammation, secondary pulmonary fibrosis (PF); however, there are still no effective treatments for PF. The present study aimed to explore the inhibitory effect of dihydroartemisinin (DHA) on pulmonary inflammation and PF, and its molecular mechanism. Morphological changes and collagen deposition were analyzed using hematoxylin-eosin staining, Masson staining, and the hydroxyproline content. DHA attenuated early alveolar inflammation and later PF in a bleomycin-induced rat PF model, and inhibited the expression of interleukin (IL)-1β, IL-6, tumor necrosis factor α (TNFα), and chemokine (C-C Motif) Ligand 3 (CCL3) in model rat serum. Further molecular analysis revealed that both pulmonary inflammation and PF were associated with increased transforming growth factor-β1 (TGF-β1), Janus activated kinase 2 (JAK2), and signal transducer and activator 3(STAT3) expression in the lung tissues of model rats. DHA reduced the inflammatory response and PF in the lungs by suppressing TGF-β1, JAK2, phosphorylated (p)-JAK2, STAT3, and p-STAT3. Thus, DHA exerts therapeutic effects against bleomycin-induced pulmonary inflammation and PF by inhibiting JAK2-STAT3 activation. DHA inhibits alveolar inflammation, and attenuates lung injury and fibrosis, possibly representing a therapeutic candidate to treat PF associated with COVID-19.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FGF10 protects against particulate matter (PM)-induced lung injury via regulation of endoplasmic reticulum stress</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35114441/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35114441/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Particulate matter (PM)-induced lung injury is closely related to the development of respiratory diseases, and the genotoxicity of PM involves endoplasmic reticulum (ER) stress.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The ERS lays the basis of PM-induced lung injury characteristic of secretion of inflammatory mediators from bronchial epithelial cells, and fibroblast growth factor 10 (FGF10) protects against PM-induced lung injury through regulation of ERS.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The regulatory mechanism of FGF10 on ERS in PM-induced lung injury involves ERK1/2 and PI3K/Akt signaling.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Exposure of the lungs to particulate matter (PM) leads to the development of respiratory disease and involves mechanisms such as oxydative stress, mitochondrial dysfunction and endoplasmic reticulum (ER) stress. However, there are no effective therapies to treat PM-induced lung diseases. Fibroblast growth factor 10 (FGF10) is a multifunctional growth factor mediating mesenchymal-to-epithelial signaling and displaying a significant therapeutic potential following injury. The present research aims to investigate the regulatory mechanism of FGF10 on ER stress in PM-induced lung injury. PM-induced lung injury leads to peribronchial wall thickening and marked infiltration of inflammatory cells which is associated with increased secretion of inflammatory cytokines. The results show that FGF10 treatment attenuates PM-induced lung injury in vivo and reversed ER stress protein GRP78 and CHOP levels. Moreover, comparison of human bronchial epithelial cells cultured with PM and FGF10 vs PM alone shows sustained cell proliferation and restrained secretion of inflammatory cytokines supporting FGF10&amp;rsquo;s protective role. Significantly, both ERK1/2 and PI3K/AKT inhibitors largely abolished the impact of FGF10 on PM-induced ER stress. Taken together, both in vivo and in vitro experiments showed that FGF10, via the activation of ERK1/2 and PI3K/AKT signaling, protects against PM-induced lung injury through the regulation of ER stress. Therefore, FGF10 represents a potential therapy for PM-induced lung injury.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transforming the Chemical Structure and Bio-Nano Activity of Doxorubicin by Ultrasound for Selective Killing of Cancer Cells</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35100658/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35100658/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reconfiguring the structure and selectivity of existing chemotherapeutics represents an opportunity for developing novel tumor-selective drugs. Here, as a proof-of-concept, the use of high-frequency sound waves is demonstrated to transform the nonselective anthracycline doxorubicin into a tumor selective drug molecule. The transformed drug self-aggregates in water to form ≈200 nm nanodrugs without requiring organic solvents, chemical agents, or surfactants. The nanodrugs preferentially interact with lipid rafts in the mitochondria of cancer cells. The mitochondrial localization of the nanodrugs plays a key role in inducing reactive oxygen species mediated selective death of breast cancer, colorectal carcinoma, ovarian carcinoma, and drug-resistant cell lines. Only marginal cytotoxicity (80-100% cell viability) toward fibroblasts and cardiomyocytes is observed, even after administration of high doses of the nanodrug (25-40 µg mL&lt;sup&gt;-1&lt;/sup&gt;). Penetration, cytotoxicity, and selectivity of the nanodrugs in tumor-mimicking tissues are validated by using a 3D coculture of cancer and healthy cells and 3D cell-collagen constructs in a perfusion bioreactor. The nanodrugs exhibit tropism for lung and limited accumulation in the liver and spleen, as suggested by in vivo biodistribution studies. The results highlight the potential of this approach to transform the structure and bioactivity of anticancer drugs and antibiotics bearing sono-active moieties.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DL0805-1, a novel Rho-kinase inhibitor, attenuates lung injury and vasculopathy in a rat model of monocrotaline-induced pulmonary hypertension</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35092757/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35092757/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pulmonary hypertension (PH) is a severe chronic cardiopulmonary dysfunction characterized by impaired of pulmonary circulation. Current therapeutic drugs mainly act as vasodilators, leading to an unsatisfactory prognosis. The Rho/ROCK pathway plays an important role in the cardiovascular system. DL0805-1, a novel Rho kinase inhibitor, synthesized by our institute and showed a protective effect on lung tissues and reduced right ventricular systolic pressure in a hypertensive crisis rat model in our previous study. The present study aims to explore the efficacy of DL0805-1 on PH. The classical PH rat model induced by a single subcutaneous injection of monocrotaline was used to investigate the therapeutic effect of DL0805-1 on PH and the underlying mechanisms. The results showed that the high dose of DL0805-1 had a better effect on the survival rate and controlled right ventricular systolic pressure (RVSP) of PH rats than fasudil. DL0805-1 also exhibited a superior lung protective effect and significantly improved pulmonary vascular function compared with bosentan. Regarding molecular mechanisms, DL0805-1 inhibited the ROCK pathway in both pulmonary arteries and lung tissues. Taken together, DL0805-1 alleviated lung injury and vasculopathy in experimental PH rats. DL0805-1 has the potential to be developed as a candidate drug for the treatment of PH.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A novel nordihydroguaiaretic acid analog, compound 3a, alleviates acute lung injury by exerting antiapoptotic and antiinflammatory effects</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35085517/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35085517/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acute lung injury (ALI) is a continuum of pulmonary changes caused by various lung insults. Previously, we synthesized a series of nordihydroguaiaretic acid analogs; of these, compound 3a exhibited excellent antioxidant capacity in a murine model of middle cerebral artery occlusion. However, it remains unclear whether compound 3a can modulate lipopolysaccharide (LPS)-induced ALI. ALI was induced via tracheal LPS administration, and the pathological changes were assessed. The level of inflammation was verified by immunofluorescence and immunohistochemical analyses. Apoptosis was measured by terminal deoxynucleotidyl transferase dUTP nick-end labeling assays and Western blotting. Changes in the levels of mitogen-activated protein kinase (MAPK)/nuclear factor-κB (NF-κB) pathway proteins were assessed by immunofluorescence assays and Western blotting. In vitro, RAW 264.7 cells were treated with compound 3a prior to LPS challenge, and the intracellular level of inflammation was assessed by quantitative PCR (qPCR). Relevant proteins were detected via immunofluorescence assays and Western blotting. Mice developed extensive lung inflammation by 24 h after LPS challenge. Histological examination revealed signs typical of ALI. Preadministration of compound 3a markedly ameliorated the histopathological changes and reduced fluid exudation into the alveolar space. Compound 3a also greatly reduced the levels of inflammation and apoptosis both in vivo and in vitro. Moreover, compound 3a markedly reduced phosphorylation of MAPK/NF-κB pathway-related proteins and p65 translocation, consistent with the in vitro observations. In summary, administration of compound 3a prior to LPS suppressed ALI via inhibition of the MAPK/NF-κB pathway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Repurposed Drug Screen for Compounds Regulating Aquaporin 5 Stability in Lung Epithelial Cells</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35145418/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35145418/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aquaporin 5 (AQP5) is expressed in several cell types in the lung and regulates water transport, which contributes to barrier function during injury and the composition of glandular secretions. Reduced AQP5 expression is associated with barrier dysfunction during acute lung injury, and strategies to enhance its expression are associated with favorable phenotypes. Thus, pharmacologically enhancing AQP5 expression could be beneficial. Here, we optimized a high-throughput assay designed to detect AQP5 abundance using a cell line stably expressing bioluminescent-tagged AQP5. We then screened a library of 1153 compounds composed of FDA-approved drugs for their effects on AQP5 abundance. We show compounds Niclosamide, Panobinostat, and Candesartan Celexitil increased AQP5 abundance, and show that Niclosamide has favorable cellular toxicity profiles. We determine that AQP5 levels are regulated in part by ubiquitination and proteasomal degradation in lung epithelial cells, and mechanistically Niclosamide increases AQP5 levels by reducing AQP5 ubiquitination and proteasomal degradation. Functionally, Niclosamide stabilized AQP5 levels in response to hypotonic stress, a stimulus known to reduce AQP5 levels. In complementary assays, Niclosamide increased endogenous AQP5 in both A549 cells and in primary, polarized human bronchial epithelial cells compared to control-treated cells. Further, we measured rapid cell volume changes in A549 cells in response to osmotic stress, an effect controlled by aquaporin channels. Niclosamide-treated A549 cell volume changes occurred more rapidly compared to control-treated cells, suggesting that increased Niclosamide-mediated increases in AQP5 expression affects functional water transport. Taken together, we describe a strategy to identify repurposed compounds for their effect on AQP5 protein abundance. We validated the effects of Niclosamide on endogenous AQP5 levels and in regulating cell-volume changes in response to tonicity changes. Our findings highlight a unique approach to screen for drug effects on protein abundance, and our workflow can be applied broadly to study compound effects on protein abundance in lung epithelial cells.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Renal Nano-drug delivery for acute kidney Injury: Current status and future perspectives</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/35085695/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/35085695/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acute kidney injury (AKI) causes considerable morbidity and mortality, particularly in the case of post-cardiac infarction or kidney transplantation; however, the site-specific accumulation of small molecule reno-protective agents for AKI has often proved ineffective due to dynamic fluid and solute excretion and non-selectivity, which impedes therapeutic efficacy. This article reviews the current status and future trajectories of renal nanomedicine research for AKI management from pharmacological and clinical perspectives, with a particular focus on appraising nanosized drug carrier (NDC) use for the delivery of reno-protective agents of different pharmacological classes and the effectiveness of NDCs in improving renal tissue targeting selectivity and efficacy of said agents. This review reveals the critical shift in the role of the small molecule reno-protective agents in AKI pharmacotherapy - from prophylaxis to treatment - when using NDCs for delivery to the kidney. We also highlight the need to identify the accumulation sites of NDCs carrying reno-protective agents in renal tissues during in vivo assessments and detail the less-explored pharmacological classes of reno-protective agents whose efficacies may be improved via NDC-based delivery. We conclude the paper by outlining the challenges and future perspectives of NDC-based reno-protective agent delivery for better clinical management of AKI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Elastase Inhibitor Cyclotheonellazole A: Total Synthesis and In Vivo Biological Evaluation for Acute Lung Injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35005973/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35005973/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acute lung injury/acute respiratory distress syndrome (ALI/ARDS) is one of the most common complications in COVID-19. Elastase has been recognized as an important target to prevent ALI/ARDS in the patient of COVID-19. Cyclotheonellazole A (CTL-A) is a natural macrocyclic peptide reported to be a potent elastase inhibitor. Herein, we completed the first total synthesis of CTL-A in 24 linear steps. The key reactions include three-component MAC reactions and two late-stage oxidations. We also provided seven CTL-A analogues and elucidated preliminary structure-activity relationships. The in vivo ALI mouse model further suggested that CTL-A alleviated acute lung injury with reductions in lung edema and pathological deterioration, which is better than sivelestat, one approved elastase inhibitor. The activity of CTL-A against elastase, along with its cellular safety and well-established synthetic route, warrants further investigation of CTL-A as a candidate against COVID-19 pathogeneses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-developed NF-κB inhibitor 270 protects against LPS-induced acute kidney injury and lung injury through improving inflammation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35026488/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35026488/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Compound 270, a self-developed NF-κB inhibitor, possess anti-inflammation activity in vitro.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;NF-κB inhibitor 270 has protective effects against LPS-induced septic AKI and ALI in vivo.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;NF-κB inhibitor 270 is a potential candidate medicine in the treatment of AKI and ALI.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;NF-κB inhibitor 270 could be used in inflammatory associated diseases.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sepsis-induced acute kidney injury (AKI) and acute lung injury (ALI) have high morbidity and mortality, with no effective clinically available drugs. Anti-inflammation is effective strategy in the therapy of AKI and ALI. NF-κB is a target for the development of anti‑inflammatory agents. The purpose of the study is to evaluate the effect of 270, self-developed NF-κB inhibitor, in LPS-induced AKI and ALI. LPS-induced macrophages were used to examine the anti-inflammation activity of 270 in vitro. Sepsis-induced AKI and ALI mice models were established by intraperitoneal injection of LPS (10 mg/kg) for 24 h. Oral administration 270 for 14 days before LPS stimulation. Plasma, kidney and lung tissues were collected and used for histopathology, biochemical assay, ELISA, RT-PCR, and western blot analyses. In vitro, we showed that 270 suppressed the inflammation response in LPS-induced RAW 264.7 macrophages and bone marrow derived macrophages. In vivo, we found that 270 ameliorated LPS-induced AKI and ALI, as evidenced by improving various pathological changes, reducing the expression of pro-inflammation genes, blocking the activation of NF-κB and JNK pathways, attenuating the elevated myeloperoxidase (MPO) activity and malondialdehyde (MDA) content, ameliorating the activated ER stress, reversing the inhibition effect on autophagy in kidney and lung tissues, and alleviating the enhanced plasma level of creatinine (Crea), blood urea nitrogen (BUN) and pro-inflammation cytokines. Our investigations provides evidence that NF-κB inhibitor 270 is a potential drug that against LPS-induced AKI and ALI in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optical recording of action potentials in mammalian neurons using a microbial rhodopsin</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34995938/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34995938/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Post-Covid pulmonary fibrosis is evident following severe COVID-19. There is an urgent need to identify the cellular and pathophysiological characteristics of chronic lung squeals of Covid-19 for the development of future preventive and/or therapeutic interventions. Tissue-resident memory T (TRM) cells can mediate local immune protection against infections and cancer. Less beneficially, lung TRM cells cause chronic airway inflammation and fibrosis by stimulating pathologic inflammation. The effects of Janus kinase (JAK), an inducer pathway of cytokine storm, inhibition on acute Covid-19 cases have been previously evaluated. Here, we propose that Tofacitinib by targeting the CD8+ TRM cells could be a potential candidate for the treatment of chronic lung diseases induced by acute SARS-CoV-2 infection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Phospholipase A2 inhibitor and LY6/PLAUR domain-containing protein PINLYP regulates type I interferon innate immunity</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34969857/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34969857/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Significance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interferon (IFN)-mediated antiviral responses serve as the first line of the host innate immune defense against viral infection. Here we identify a previously uncharacterized protein designated phospholipase A2 inhibitor and LY6/PLAUR domain-containing protein (PINLYP), which is essential for embryonic development and plays an important role in type I IFN against pathogen infection. PINLYP deficiency impairs type I IFN production and dampens in vivo host defense against DNA and RNA virus infection. We unravel a unique actor in the type I IFN innate immunity and a potential target for the antiviral therapies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Type I interferons (IFNs) are the first frontline of the host innate immune response against invading pathogens. Herein, we characterized an unknown protein encoded by phospholipase A2 inhibitor and LY6/PLAUR domain-containing (PINLYP) gene that interacted with TBK1 and induced type I IFN in a TBK1- and IRF3-dependent manner. Loss of PINLYP impaired the activation of IRF3 and production of IFN-β induced by DNA virus, RNA virus, and various Toll-like receptor ligands in multiple cell types. Because PINLYP deficiency in mice engendered an early embryonic lethality in mice, we generated a conditional mouse in which PINLYP was depleted in dendritic cells. Mice lacking PINLYP in dendritic cells were defective in type I IFN induction and more susceptible to lethal virus infection. Thus, PINLYP is a positive regulator of type I IFN innate immunity and important for effective host defense against viral infection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Silymarin/curcumin loaded albumin nanoparticles coated by chitosan as muco-inhalable delivery system observing anti-inflammatory and anti COVID-19 characterizations in oleic acid triggered lung injury and in vitro COVID-19 experiment</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34968533/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34968533/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Respiratory infected by COVID-19 represents a major global health problem at moment even after recovery from virus corona. Since, the lung lesions for infected patients are still sufferings from acute respiratory distress syndrome including alveolar septal edema, pneumonia, hyperplasia, and hyaline membranes Therefore, there is an urgent need to identify additional candidates having ability to overcome inflammatory process and can enhance efficacy in the treatment of COVID-19. The polypenolic extracts were integrated into moeties of bovine serum albumin (BSA) and then were coated by chitosan as a mucoadhesion polymer. The results of interleukin-6, and c-reactive protein showed significant reduction in group treated by Encap. SIL + CUR (64 ± 0.8 Pg/μL &amp;amp; 6 ± 0.5 μg/μL) compared to group treated by Cham. + CUR (102 ± 0.8 Pg/μL &amp;amp; 7 ± 0.5 μg/μL) respectively and free capsules (with no any drug inside) (148 ± 0.6 Pg/μL &amp;amp; 10 ± 0.6 μg/μL) respectively. Histopathology profile was improved completely. Additionally, encapsulating silymarin showed anti-viral activity in vitro COVID-19 experiment. It can be summarized that muco-inhalable delivery system (MIDS) loaded by silymarin can be used to overcome inflammation induced by oleic acid and to overcome COVID-19.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Delivery Janus-Prodrug for Precise Immuno-Chemotherapy of Colitis-Associated Colorectal Cancer</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34958191/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34958191/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aromatized thioketal (ATK) linked the immunoregulatory molecule (budesonide, Bud) and the cytotoxic molecule (gemcitabine, Gem) to construct a ROS-activated Janus-prodrug, termed as BAG. Benefiting from the hydrogen bonding, π-π stacking, and other intermolecular interactions, BAG could self-assemble into nanoaggregates (BAG NA) with a well-defined spherical shape and uniform size distribution. Compared to the carrier-based drug delivery system, BAG NA have ultrahigh drug loading content and ROS concentration-dependent drug release. Colitis-associated colorectal cancer (CAC) is a typical disease in which chronic inflammation transforms into tumors. BAG NA can be internalized by colon cancer C26 cells and then triggered by excessive intracellular ROS to release nearly 100% of the drugs. Based on this, BAG NA showed a stronger pro-apoptotic effect than free Bud combined with free Gem. What is gratifying is that orally administered BAG NA can precisely accumulate in the diseased colon tissues of CAC mice induced by AOM/DSS and simultaneously release Bud and Gem. Bud can regulate the tumor immune microenvironment to restore and enhance the cytotoxicity of Gem. Therefore, BAG NA maximizes the synergistic therapeutic effect through co-delivery of Bud and Gem. This work provided a cutting-edge method for constructing self-delivery Janus-prodrug based on ATK and confirmed its potential application in inflammation-related carcinogenesis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Disulfiram attenuates MCMV-Induced pneumonia by inhibition of NF-κB/NLRP3 signaling pathway in immunocompromised mice</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34959186/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34959186/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Disulfiram (DSF) attenuated MCMV-infected pneumonia.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;DSF suppressed NF-κB/NLRP3 pathway in MCMV-infected mice.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;DSF inhibited inflammatory response in MCMV-infected BMDMs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;DSF reduced viral loads in MCMV-infected mice and BMDMs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cytomegalovirus (CMV) pneumonia in immunocompromised individuals is associated with damaging hyperinflammation and leads to high morbidity and mortality. It is urgently needed to develop new strategies to treat CMV-induced pneumonia. As disulfiram (DSF) reportedly inhibits inflammatory responses in different disease models, its therapeutic effects in CMV-induced pneumonia are proposed. In this study, we demonstrated that DSF effectively attenuated pulmonary injury and improved survival in murine CMV (MCMV) pneumonia model. DSF treatment inhibited lung inflammatory responses, e.g. reducing pro-inflammatory cytokines, upregulating anti-inflammatory cytokine, and lowering the accumulation of leukocytes in the lung. Similar to the in vivo results, DSF attenuated inflammatory responses and modulated NF-κB/NLRP3 inflammasome activation in MCMV-infected BMDMs. Furthermore, DSF reduced pulmonary fibrosis and viral loads in MCMV pneumonia mice and BMDMs. The mechanism of anti-inflammatory effects of DSF may due to its regulating NF-κB signaling and NLRP3 inflammasome activation. Collectively, our results suggest that DSF-mediated anti-hyperinflammatory effects have potentials for therapy of human CMV pneumonia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Protective effect of pteryxin on LPS-induced acute lung injury via modulating MAPK/NF-κB pathway and NLRP3 inflammasome activation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34942323/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34942323/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ethnopharmacological relevance:&lt;/em&gt; Peucedanum praeruptorum seed root is a common medicinal herb with antipyretic, expectorant, antitussive, and therapeutic effects against bronchitis and furuncle. The roots of this herb contain many coumarin compounds, including pteryxin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Aim of this study:&lt;/em&gt; To investigate whether pteryxin can alleviate the LPS-induced lung injury and the mechanism involved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Material and methods:&lt;/em&gt; Male BALB/C mice were orally given sodium carboxymethylcellulose (CMC-Na) (0.5%, 1mL/100g) and pteryxin (suspended in CMC-Na; 0.5%) at 5, 10, 25 mg/kg once daily for 7 days. Subsequently, the mice received a single intratracheal instillation of 5 mg/kg LPS or saline as the control. After 8 hours, the mice were sacrificed to collect bronchoalveolar lavage fluid (BALF) and lung tissues. These samples were used to determine the lung W/D (wet/dry) weight ratio, total protein (TP) levels, inflammatory cytokines (IL-6, TNF-α, and IL-1β) and expression of protein involved in MAPK/NF-κB pathway and NLRP3 inflammasome. H&amp;amp;E staining was carried out on tissue sections to explore the pathological alterations induced by LPS. The protein expression of F4/80 and NLRP3 in lung tissues was analyzed using immunohistochemical staining. The binding of pteryxin to target proteins (MAPK, NF-κB and NLRP3) was determined based on molecular docking tests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; Treatment with pteryxin reduced the lung W/D weight ratio, total protein (TP) level and levels of inflammatory cytokines (TNFα, IL-6 and IL-1 β) significantly. Therefore, it ameliorated LPS-induced inflammatory response in BALB/C mice. Moreover, pteryxin suppressed LPS-induced upregulation of proteins involved in MAPK/NF-κB signaling pathway and NLRP3 inflammasome activation. The expression level of F4/80 and NLRP3 was also downregulated by pteryxin pretreatment in lung tissues. Docking analysis revealed that pteryxin bound to target proteins (MAPK, NF- κB and NLRP3) with a fit-well pattern .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/em&gt; Pteryxin may attenuate LPS-induced acute lung injury by dampening MAPK/NF-κB signaling and NLRP 3 inflammasome activation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JFNE-A isolated from Jing-Fang n-butanol extract attenuates lipopolysaccharide-induced acute lung injury by inhibiting oxidative stress and the NF-κB signaling pathway via promotion of autophagy</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35026506/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35026506/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Jing-Fang powder consists of Jingjie (Nepeta tenuifolia Benth, (Lamiaceae)). and Fangfeng (Saposhnikovia divaricata (Turcz.) Schischk, (Apiaceae)) Previous studies have revealed that the Jing-Fang powder n-butanol extract (JFNE) has anti-acute lung injury (ALI) and anti-inflammatory properties; however, the active ingredient and mechanism remain unknown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Purpose:&lt;/em&gt; In the present study, we investigated the anti-inflammatory effect of a bioactive fraction obtained from JFNE(JFNE-A) on lipopolysaccharide (LPS)-induced ALI in mice and explored the underlying mechanism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Study design:&lt;/em&gt; The anti-acute lung injury effect and mechanism of JFNE-A was investigated by prophylactic administration of JFNE-A in mice with LPS-induced acute lung injury.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; The expression levels of myeloperoxidase(MPO) in lung tissues of mice and interleukin(IL)-6, tumor necrosis factor(TNF)-α, IL-1β, IL-5, interferon (IFN)-γ, monocyte chemotactic protein (MCP)-1, macrophage colony stimulating factor (M-CSF), macrophage inflammatory protein (MIP)-1α, and MIP-1β in bronchi alveolar lavage fluid (BALF) were detected by reagent kit and the histological changes were examined by hematoxylin and eosin (H &amp;amp; E) for general histopathological conditions under a light microscope. In addition, the ultrastructure of the cells in lung tissues were observed and photographed under a transmission electron microscope. The expression levels of protein were detected via Western blotting and the mRNA expression of relative genes were determined of via reverse transcriptase polymerase chain reaction (RT-PCR). What&amp;rsquo;s more, we also further clarified the potential targets of JFNE-A through network pharmacology analysis, which could be utilized in ALI treatment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; Our results showed that pretreatment with JFNE-A for 7 days significantly reduced the lung pathological injury score, alleviated pulmonary edema, and decreased the lung tissue MPO level. Mechanistically, JFNE-A dramatically downregulated the protein levels of IL-6, TNF-α, IL-1β, M-CSF, and IFN-γ in BALF and mRNA expression levels of IL-6, TNF-α, IL-1β, and IFN-γ in lung tissues. JFNE-A also significantly lowered the protein levels of iNOS and phosphorylated NF-κB (p65) and mRNA expression levels of iNOS, Rela, CHUK, and NF-κB1, and also elevated the protein expression levels of Nrf2, HO-1, and SOD1 and the mRNA expression levels of Nrf2, Hmox1, and Keap-1 in the lungs. Moreover, JFNE-A significantly decreased the protein expression of p62 and increased the ratio of LC3II/LC3I. It also upregulated the mRNA expression levels of Atg5 and Beclin-1, whereas it reduced the mRNA expression level of SQSTM1 and increased autophagosome structures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/em&gt; Overall, treatment with JFNE-A ameliorated LPS-induced ALI in mice by suppressing the NF-κB signaling pathways and promoting Nrf2 signaling pathways by accelerating autophagy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Structure-guided glyco-engineering of ACE2 for improved potency as soluble SARS-CoV-2 decoy receptor</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34927585/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34927585/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Infection and viral entry of SARS-CoV-2 crucially depends on the binding of its Spike protein to angiotensin converting enzyme 2 (ACE2) presented on host cells. Glycosylation of both proteins is critical for this interaction. Recombinant soluble human ACE2 can neutralize SARS-CoV-2 and is currently undergoing clinical tests for the treatment of COVID-19. We used 3D structural models and molecular dynamics simulations to define the ACE2 N-glycans that critically influence Spike-ACE2 complex formation. Engineering of ACE2 N-glycosylation by site-directed mutagenesis or glycosidase treatment resulted in enhanced binding affinities and improved virus neutralization without notable deleterious effects on the structural stability and catalytic activity of the protein. Importantly, simultaneous removal of all accessible N-glycans from recombinant soluble human ACE2 yields a superior SARS-CoV-2 decoy receptor with promise as effective treatment for COVID-19 patients.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tumour mutational burden predicts resistance to EGFR/BRAF blockade in BRAF-mutated microsatellite stable metastatic colorectal cancer</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34933155/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34933155/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Aim:&lt;/em&gt; To unveil genomic and immunohistochemical expression profiles associated with primary resistance to EGFR/BRAF targeted therapy in patients with BRAF-mutated and microsatellite stable (MSS) metastatic colorectal cancer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Experimental design:&lt;/em&gt; In this multicenter case-control study on patients treated with EGFR/BRAF ± MEK blockade, we compared a primary resistance cohort (N = 20; RECISTv1.1 PD/SD, and progression-free survival [PFS] &amp;lt;16 weeks) versus a sensitive one (N = 19; RECISTv1.1 PR/CR, and PFS ≥16 weeks) in terms of clinical and genomic/expression data by means of comprehensive genomic profiling, tumour mutational burden (TMB), BRAF-mutant transcriptional subtypes (BM) classification and PTEN expression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; Left-sided tumours (28% of the total) were enriched in the sensitive versus resistant cohort (53% versus 10%, &lt;em&gt;P&lt;/em&gt; = 0.010). Genomic alterations in the PIK3CA/MTOR pathway, BM1 status and PTEN loss were similarly distributed among patients with resistant and sensitive tumours. Amplification of CCND1-3 genes were found only in patients with primary resistance (20% versus 0%, &lt;em&gt;P&lt;/em&gt; = 0.106). TMB and prevalence of intermediate TMB (TMB-I 6-20 mutations/Mb) were higher in the resistant versus sensitive cohort (median TMB: 6 [IQR, 3-7.29] versus 3 [IQR, 1.26-3.5]; &lt;em&gt;P&lt;/em&gt; = 0.013; TMB-I/H: 60% versus 11%; &lt;em&gt;P&lt;/em&gt; = 0.001). Patients with TMB-I had shorter PFS (3.3 versus 5.9 months; HR = 2.19, 95%CI, 1.07-4.47, &lt;em&gt;P&lt;/em&gt; = 0.031) and overall survival (6.3 versus 10.5 months; HR = 2.22, 95%CI, 1.02-4.81, &lt;em&gt;P&lt;/em&gt; = 0.044).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/em&gt; Despite the small sample size, the association of a relatively higher TMB with limited benefit from EGFR/BRAF blockade in patients with MSS and BRAF-mutated mCRC deserves prospective validation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pathway network of pyroptosis and its potential inhibitors in acute kidney injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/34915124/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/34915124/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acute kidney injury (AKI) is a worldwide problem, and there is no effective drug to eliminate AKI. The death of renal cells is an important pathological basis of intrinsic AKI. At present, targeted therapy for TEC death is a research hotspot in AKI therapy. There are many ways of cell death involved in the occurrence and development of AKI, such as apoptosis, necrosis, ferroptosis, and pyroptosis. This article mainly focuses on the role of pyroptosis in AKI. The assembly and activation of NLRP3 inflammasome is a key event in the occurrence of pyroptosis, which is affected by many factors, such as the activation of the NF-κB signaling pathway, mitochondrial instability and excessive endoplasmic reticulum (ER) stress. The activation of NLRP3 inflammasome can trigger its downstream inflammatory cytokines, which will lead to pyroptosis and eventually induce AKI. In this paper, we reviewed the possible mechanism of pyroptosis in AKI and the potential effective inhibitors of various key targets in this process. It may provide potential therapeutic targets for novel intrinsic AKI therapies based on pyroptosis, so as to develop better therapeutic strategies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dimethyl fumarate attenuates LPS induced septic acute kidney injury by suppression of NFκB p65 phosphorylation and macrophage activation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34915410/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34915410/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Septic acute kidney injury (AKI) always accounts for high mortality of septic patients in ICU. Due to its not well understood mechanism for infection and immune-regulation in kidney dysfunction, there is a lack of effective therapy without side effects. Dimethyl fumarate (DMF) as an immunomodulatory molecule has been approved for treatment to multiple sclerosis. However, the therapeutic effect and immunomodulatory role underlying DMF action in septic AKI is unclear. This study aimed to elucidate the role of DMF in lipopolysaccharide (LPS)-induced septic AKI involving macrophage regulation. In current study, we administered DMF by oral gavage to mice with LPS-induced AKI, then harvested serum and kidney at three different time points. We further isolated Bone marrow-derived macrophages (BMDMs) from mice and stimulated them with LPS followed by DMF treatment. To explore immunomodulatory role of DMF in macrophages, we depleted macrophages in mice using liposomal clodronate after DMF treatment upon LPS-induced septic AKI. Then we observed that DMF attenuated renal dysfunction and murine pathological kidney injury after LPS injection. DMF could inhibit translocation of phosphorylated NF-κB p65 and suppress macrophage activation in LPS-induced AKI. DMF reduced the secretion of TNF-α and IL-6 whereas increased the secretion of IL-10 and Arg-1 in BMDMs after LPS stimulation. DMF also inhibited NF-κB p65 phosphorylation in BMDMs after LPS stimulation. Importantly, the effect of DMF against LPS-induced AKI, macrophage activation, and translocation of phosphorylated NF-κB p65 was impaired upon macrophage depletion. Thus, DMF could attenuate LPS-induced septic AKI by suppression of NF-κB p65 phosphorylation and macrophage activation. This work suggested the potential therapeutic role of DMF for patients in ICU threatened by septic AKI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fe-Curcumin Nanozyme-Mediated Reactive Oxygen Species Scavenging and Anti-Inflammation for Acute Lung Injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35106369/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35106369/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pneumonia, such as acute lung injury (ALI), has been a type of lethal disease that is generally caused by uncontrolled inflammatory response and excessive generation of reactive oxygen species (ROS). Herein, we report Fe-curcumin-based nanoparticles (Fe-Cur NPs) with nanozyme functionalities in guiding the intracellular ROS scavenging and meanwhile exhibiting anti-inflammation efficacy for curing ALI. The nanoparticles are noncytotoxic when directing these biological activities. Mechanism studies for the anti-inflammation aspects of Fe-Cur NPs were systematically carried out, in which the infected cells and tissues were alleviated through downregulating levels of several important inflammatory cytokines (such as TNF-α, IL-1β, and IL-6), decreasing the intracellular Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt; release, inhibiting NLRP3 inflammasomes, and suppressing NF-κB signaling pathways. In addition, we performed both the intratracheal and intravenous injection of Fe-Cur NPs in mice experiencing ALI and, importantly, found that the accumulation of such nanozymes was enhanced in lung tissue (better than free curcumin drugs), demonstrating its promising therapeutic efficiency in two different administration methods. We showed that the inflammation reduction of Fe-Cur NPs was effective in animal experiments and that ROS scavenging was also effectively achieved in lung tissue. Finally, we revealed that Fe-Cur NPs can decrease the level of macrophage cells (CD11b&lt;sup&gt;lo&lt;/sup&gt;F4/80&lt;sup&gt;hi&lt;/sup&gt;) and CD3&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt;CD45&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T cells in mice, which could help suppress the inflammation cytokine storm caused by ALI. Overall, this work has developed the strategy of using Fe-Cur NPs as nanozymes to scavenge intracellular ROS and as an anti-inflammation nanodrugs to synergistically cure ALI, which may serve as a promising therapeutic agent in the clinical treatment of this deadly disease. Fe-Cur NP nanozymes were designed to attenuate ALI by clearing intracellular ROS and alleviating inflammation synergistically. Relevant cytokines, inflammasomes, and signaling pathways were studied.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
