<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Immune Escape | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/immune-escape/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/immune-escape/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Immune Escape</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Immune Escape</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/immune-escape/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>DCLK1 Suppresses Tumor-Specific Cytotoxic T Lymphocyte Function Through Recruitment of MDSCs via the CXCL1-CXCR2 Axis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36309200/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36309200/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background &amp;amp; Aims&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gastrointestinal cancer stem cell marker doublecortin-like kinase (DCLK1) is strongly associated with poor outcomes in colorectal cancer (CRC). Although DCLK1’s regulatory effect on the tumor immune microenvironment has been hypothesized, its mode of action has not been shown previously in vivo, which hampers the potential intervention based on this molecule for clinical practice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To define the immunomodulatory mechanisms of DCLK1 in vivo, we generated DCLK1&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt; tumor cells by Clustered regularly interspaced short palindromic repeats (CRISPR)-CRISPR-associated protein 9 (Cas9) and developed subcutaneous and intestinal orthotopic transplantation tumor models. Tumor tissues were harvested and subjected to immunofluorescence staining, flow cytometry analysis of tumor-infiltrating immune cell populations, tumor myeloid-derived suppressor cell (MDSC) sorting by isolation kit and then co-culture with spleen T cells, and RNA sequencing for transcriptomic analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We found that DCLK1&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt; tumor cells lose their tumorigenicity under immune surveillance. Failed tumor establishment of DCLK1&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt; was associated with an increase in infiltration of CD8&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T cells and effector CD4&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T cells, and reduced numbers of MDSCs in the tumor tissue. Furthermore, DCLK1 promoted the up-regulation of C-X-C motif ligand 1, which recruits MDSCs in CRC through chemokine C-X-C motif receptor 2. The ability of in vivo tumor growth of DCLK1&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt; tumor cells was rescued by C-X-C motif ligand 1 overexpression. Collectively, we validated that DCLK1 promotes tumor growth in CRC through recruitment of T-cell–suppressive MDSCs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DCLK1-mediated immune suppression in tumor models allows escaping from the host’s antitumor response. Because DCLK1 is one of the most common markers in gastrointestinal tumors, these results identify a precise therapeutic target for related clinical interventions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LncNSPL facilitates influenza A viral immune escape by restricting TRIM25-mediated K63-linked RIG-I ubiquitination</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35800772/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35800772/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;NS1 protein of Influenza A virus (IAV) promotes lncNSPL expression&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deficiency of lncNSPL specifically enhances retinoic acid-inducible gene I (RIG-I) initiated IFN production&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;lncNSPL competes with tripartite interaction motif 25 (TRIM25) for binding RIG-I and inhibits its K63 ubiquitination&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;lncNSPL inhibits innate antiviral immune responses and enhances viral replication&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Long noncoding RNAs (lncRNAs) participate in host antiviral responses; however, how viruses exploit host lncRNAs for immune evasion remains largely unexplored. Functional screening of differentially expressed lncRNA profile in patients infected with influenza A virus (IAV) revealed that lncNSPL (Gene Symbol: LOC105370355) was highly expressed in monocytes. Deregulated lncNSPL expression in infected monocytes significantly increased type I interferon (IFN-I) production and inhibited IAV replication. Moreover, lncNSPL overexpression in mice increased the susceptibility to IAV infection and impaired IFN-I production. LncNSPL directly bound to retinoic acid-inducible gene I (RIG-I) and blocked the interaction between RIG-I and E3 ligase tripartite interaction motif 25 (TRIM25), reducing TRIM25-mediated lysine 63 (K63)-linked RIG-I ubiquitination and limiting the downstream production of antiviral mediators during the late stage of IAV infection. Our findings provide mechanistic insights into the means by which lncNSPL promotes IAV replication and immune escape via restricting the TRIM25-mediated RIG-I K63-linked ubiquitination. Thus, lncNSPL may represent a promising pharmaceutical target for anti-IAV therapy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Avian influenza viruses suppress innate immunity by inducing trans-transcriptional readthrough via SSU72</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35332300/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35332300/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Innate immunity plays critical antiviral roles. The highly virulent avian influenza viruses (AIVs) H5N1, H7N9, and H5N6 can better escape host innate immune responses than the less virulent seasonal H1N1 virus. Here, we report a mechanism by which transcriptional readthrough (TRT)-mediated suppression of innate immunity occurs post AIV infection. By using cell lines, mouse lungs, and patient PBMCs, we showed that genes on the complementary strand (&amp;ldquo;trans&amp;rdquo; genes) influenced by TRT were involved in the disruption of host antiviral responses during AIV infection. The trans-TRT enhanced viral lethality, and TRT abolishment increased cell viability and STAT1/2 expression. The viral NS1 protein directly bound to SSU72, and degradation of SSU72 induced TRT. SSU72 overexpression reduced TRT and alleviated mouse lung injury. Our results suggest that AIVs infection induce TRT by reducing SSU72 expression, thereby impairing host immune responses, a molecular mechanism acting through the NS1-SSU72-trans-TRT-STAT1/2 axis. Thus, restoration of SSU72 expression might be a potential strategy for preventing AIV pandemics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aberrant Cellular Glycosylation May Increase the Ability of Influenza Viruses to Escape Host Immune Responses through Modification of the Viral Glycome</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35285699/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35285699/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Individuals with metabolic dysregulation of cellular glycosylation often experience severe influenza disease, with a poor immune response to the virus and low vaccine efficacy. Here, we investigate the consequences of aberrant cellular glycosylation for the glycome and the biology of influenza virus. We transiently induced aberrant N-linked glycosylation in cultured cells with an oligosaccharyltransferase inhibitor, NGI-1. Cells treated with NGI-1 produced morphologically unaltered viable influenza virus with sequence-neutral glycosylation changes (primarily reduced site occupancy) in the hemagglutinin and neuraminidase proteins. Hemagglutinin with reduced glycan occupancy required a higher concentration of surfactant protein D (an important innate immunity respiratory tract collectin) for inhibition compared to that with normal glycan occupancy. Immunization of mice with NGI-1-treated virus significantly reduced antihemagglutinin and antineuraminidase titers of total serum antibody and reduced hemagglutinin protective antibody responses. Our data suggest that aberrant cellular glycosylation may increase the risk of severe influenza as a result of the increased ability of glycome-modified influenza viruses to evade the immune response.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Importance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People with disorders such as cancer, autoimmune disease, diabetes, or obesity often have metabolic dysregulation of cellular glycosylation and also have more severe influenza disease, a reduced immune response to the virus, and reduced vaccine efficacy. Since influenza viruses that infect such people do not show consistent genomic variations, it is generally assumed that the altered biology is mainly related to host factors. However, since host cells are responsible for glycosylation of influenza virus hemagglutinin and neuraminidase, and glycosylation is important for interactions of these proteins with the immune system, the viruses may have functional differences that are not reflected by their genomic sequence. Here, we show that imbalanced cellular glycosylation can modify the viral glycome without genomic changes, leading to reduced innate and adaptive host immune responses to infection. Our findings link metabolic dysregulation of host glycosylation to increased risk of severe influenza and reduced influenza virus vaccine efficacy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Molecular Prerequisites for Neutrophil Extracellular Trap Formation and Evasion Mechanisms of Staphylococcus aureus</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/35237275/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/35237275/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NETosis is a multi-facetted cellular process that promotes the formation of neutrophil extracellular traps (NETs). NETs as web-like structures consist of DNA fibers armed with granular proteins, histones, and microbicidal peptides, thereby exhibiting pathogen-immobilizing and antimicrobial attributes that maximize innate immune defenses against invading microbes. However, clinically relevant pathogens often tolerate entrapment and even take advantage of the remnants of NETs to cause persistent infections in mammalian hosts. Here, we briefly summarize how &lt;em&gt;Staphylococcus aureus&lt;/em&gt;, a high-priority pathogen and causative agent of fatal diseases in humans as well as animals, catalyzes and concurrently exploits NETs during pathogenesis and recurrent infections. Specifically, we focus on toxigenic and immunomodulatory effector molecules produced by staphylococci that prime NET formation, and further highlight the molecular and underlying principles of suicidal NETosis compared to vital NET-formation by viable neutrophils in response to these stimuli. We also discuss the inflammatory potential of NET-controlled microenvironments, as excessive expulsion of NETs from activated neutrophils provokes local tissue injury and may therefore amplify staphylococcal disease severity in hospitalized or chronically ill patients. Combined with an overview of adaptation and counteracting strategies evolved by S. aureus to impede NET-mediated killing, these insights may stimulate biomedical research activities to uncover novel aspects of NET biology at the host-microbe interface.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MGF360-9L Is a Major Virulence Factor Associated with the African Swine Fever Virus by Antagonizing the JAK/STAT Signaling Pathway</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35076286/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35076286/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;African swine fever (ASF)-an aggressive infectious disease caused by the African swine fever virus (ASFV)-is significantly unfavorable for swine production. ASFV has a complex structure and encodes 150-167 proteins; however, the function of most of these proteins is unknown. This study identified ASFV MGF360-9L as a negative regulator of the interferon (IFN)-β signal. Further evidence showed that MGF360-9L interacts with signal transducer and activator of transcription (STAT) 1 and STAT2 and degrades STAT1 and STAT2 through apoptosis and ubiquitin-proteasome pathways, respectively. Subsequently, the activation of IFN-β signaling was inhibited. Naturally isolated or genetically manipulated live attenuated viruses are known to protect against the virulent parental ASFV strains. Therefore, through homologous recombination, we deleted MGF360-9L from the virulent ASFV CN/GS/2018 strain to construct a recombinant strain, ASFV-Δ360-9L. Compared with the parent ASFV CN/GS/2018 strain, the replication level of ASFV-Δ360-9L decreased in primary porcine alveolar macrophage cultures at 24 h postinfection, but the difference is unlikely to be biologically relevant. Notably, ASFV-Δ360-9L was partially attenuated in pigs. To our knowledge, this study is the first to uncover the function of MGF360-9L during ASFV infection. MGF360-9L inhibits IFN-β signaling through the targeted degradation of STAT1 and STAT2. Furthermore, MGF360-9L is a key virulence gene of ASFV. Our findings reveal a new mechanism by which ASFV inhibits host antiviral response; this might facilitate the development of live attenuated ASFV vaccines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Importance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;African swine fever-an acute, febrile, hemorrhagic, highly contacting, and highly lethal disease caused by African swine fever virus (ASFV)-jeopardizes the global pig industry. Understanding the mechanism ASFV employs to evade host defense during infection is essential for developing targeted drugs and vaccines against ASFV. To our knowledge, this study identifies the mechanism of innate immunity against by MGF360-9L and the effect of MGF360-9L on ASFV pathogenicity. The results showed that MGF360-9L may help ASFV escape the host immunity by degrading STAT1 and STAT2 and thus inhibiting IFN-β signaling. MGF360-9L is also an important virulence factor of ASFV. The deletion of MGF360-9L reduces ASFV virulence in pigs. This study explored a new mechanism of ASFV against innate immunity and identified a new ASFV virulence factor; these findings may guide the development of live attenuated ASFV vaccines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SARS-CoV-2 prolonged infection during advanced HIV disease evolves extensive immune escape</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35120605/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35120605/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Characterizing SARS-CoV-2 evolution in specific geographies may help predict properties of the variants that come from these regions. We mapped neutralization of a SARS-CoV-2 strain that evolved over 6 months from ancestral virus in a person with advanced HIV disease in South Africa; this person was infected prior to emergence of the Beta and Delta variants. We longitudinally tracked the evolved virus and tested it against self-plasma and convalescent plasma from ancestral, Beta, and Delta infections. Early virus was similar to ancestral, but it evolved a multitude of mutations found in Omicron and other variants. It showed substantial but incomplete Pfizer BNT162b2 escape, weak neutralization by self-plasma, and despite pre-dating Delta, it also showed extensive escape of Delta infection-elicited neutralization. This example is consistent with the notion that SARS-CoV-2 evolving in individual immune-compromised hosts, including those with advanced HIV disease, may gain immune escape of vaccines and enhanced escape of Delta immunity, and this has implications for vaccine breakthrough and reinfections.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
