<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Citrullination | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/citrullination/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/citrullination/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Citrullination</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Citrullination</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/citrullination/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chloroquine reduces neutrophil extracellular trap (NET) formation through inhibition of peptidyl arginine deiminase 4 (PAD4)</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36655514/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36655514/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Neutrophil extracellular traps (NETs) occur when chromatin is decondensed and extruded from the cell, generating a web-like structure. NETs have been implicated in the pathogenesis of several sterile disease states and thus a potential therapeutic target. Various pathways have been shown to induce NETs, including autophagy, with several key enzymes being activated like peptidyl arginine deiminase 4 (PAD4), an enzyme responsible for citrullination of histones, allowing for DNA unwinding and subsequent release from the cell. Pre-clinical studies have already demonstrated that chloroquine (CQ) and hydroxychloroquine (HCQ) are able to reduce NETs and slow disease progression. The exact mechanism as to how these drugs reduce NETs has yet to be elucidated. CQ and HCQ decrease NET formation from various NET activators, independent of their autophagy inhibitory function. CQ and HCQ were found to inhibit PAD4 exclusively, in a dose dependent manner, confirmed with reduced CitH3+ NETs after CQ or HCQ treatment. Circulating CitH3 levels were reduced in pancreatic cancer patients after HCQ treatment. In silico screening of PAD4 protein structure identified a likely binding site interaction at Arg639 for CQ and Trp347, Ser468 and Glu580 for HCQ. SPR analysis confirmed binding of HCQ and CQ with PAD4 with KD values of 54.1 µM (CQ) and 88.1 µM (HCQ). This data provides evidence of direct PAD4 inhibition as a mechanism for CQ/HCQ inhibition of NETs. We propose that these drugs likely reduce NET formation through multiple mechanisms; the previously established TLR9 and autophagy inhibitory mechanism and the novel PAD4 inhibitory mechanism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Histone Citrullination Mediates a Protective Role in Endothelium and Modulates Inflammation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36552833/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36552833/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NETosis is a key host immune process against a pathogenic infection during innate immune activation, consisting of a neutrophil &amp;ldquo;explosion&amp;rdquo; and, consequently, NET formation, containing mainly DNA, histones, and other nuclear proteins. During sepsis, an exacerbated immune host response to an infection occurs, activating the innate immunity and NETosis events, which requires histone H3 citrullination. Our group compared the circulating histone levels with those citrullinated H3 levels in plasma samples of septic patients. In addition, we demonstrated that citrullinated histones were less cytotoxic for endothelial cells than histones without this post-translational modification. Citrullinated histones did not affect cell viability and did not activate oxidative stress. Nevertheless, citrullinated histones induced an inflammatory response, as well as regulatory endothelial mechanisms. Furthermore, septic patients showed elevated levels of circulating citrullinated histone H3, indicating that the histone citrullination is produced during the first stages of sepsis, probably due to the NETosis process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Insights into peptidylarginine deiminase expression and citrullination pathways</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/35197210/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/35197210/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Peptidylarginine deiminases (PADs) are calcium-dependent enzymes that mediate citrullination, an irreversible post-translational modification (PTM). PAD enzymes have received increasing attention in (patho-)physiology since multi-omics analysis accelerated their expression profiling. Here, we provide a comprehensive overview of PAD expression at the RNA and protein levels, and a list of annotated substrates per PAD isozyme. We discuss novel roles of citrullination in cellular growth, epigenetic regulation, tissue remodeling, inflammation, and cancer in mouse models and humans. Additionally, we cluster similar effects of protein deimination to offer a different perspective and improve our understanding of citrullination in health and disease. Citrullination should no longer be considered as a rare PTM, but as an important regulatory mechanism in physiology and pathology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
