<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Citrullination | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/citrullination/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/citrullination/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Citrullination</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Citrullination</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/citrullination/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Histone Citrullination Mediates a Protective Role in Endothelium and Modulates Inflammation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36552833/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36552833/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NETosis is a key host immune process against a pathogenic infection during innate immune activation, consisting of a neutrophil &amp;ldquo;explosion&amp;rdquo; and, consequently, NET formation, containing mainly DNA, histones, and other nuclear proteins. During sepsis, an exacerbated immune host response to an infection occurs, activating the innate immunity and NETosis events, which requires histone H3 citrullination. Our group compared the circulating histone levels with those citrullinated H3 levels in plasma samples of septic patients. In addition, we demonstrated that citrullinated histones were less cytotoxic for endothelial cells than histones without this post-translational modification. Citrullinated histones did not affect cell viability and did not activate oxidative stress. Nevertheless, citrullinated histones induced an inflammatory response, as well as regulatory endothelial mechanisms. Furthermore, septic patients showed elevated levels of circulating citrullinated histone H3, indicating that the histone citrullination is produced during the first stages of sepsis, probably due to the NETosis process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
