<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>mTOR | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/mtor/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/mtor/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>mTOR</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>mTOR</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/mtor/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>An mTOR siRNA-Loaded Spermidine/DNA Tetrahedron Nanoplatform with a Synergistic Anti-Inflammatory Effect on Acute Lung Injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35167728/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35167728/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acute lung injury (ALI) is characterized by severe inflammation and damage to the lung air-blood barrier, resulting in respiratory function damage and life-threatening outcomes. Macrophage polarization plays an essential role in the occurrence, development, and outcome of ALI. As drug carriers, self-assembled DNA nanostructures can potentially overcome the drawbacks and limitations of traditional anti-inflammatory agents owing to their nontoxicity, programmability, and excellent structural control at the nanoscale. A small interfering RNA (siRNA) and drug dual therapy nanoplatform are proposed and constructed here to combat ALI. The nanoplatform consists of a spermidine-assembled DNA tetrahedron and four mammalian target of rapamycin siRNAs. Spermidine serves as a mediator of drug delivery vehicle synthesis and a drug that alters macrophage polarization. Both spermidine and siRNA exert anti-inflammatory effects in vitro and in vivo by regulating the macrophage phenotype. More importantly, these factors exhibit a synergistic anti-inflammatory effect by promoting macrophage autophagy. For the first time, an anti-inflammatory dual therapy strategy that uses self-assembled DNA nanostructures as nontoxic, programmable delivery vehicles is proposed and demonstrated through this work. Future work on utilizing DNA nanostructures for the treatment of noncancerous diseases such as ALI is highly promising and desirable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nicotinamide breaks effector CD8 T cell responses by targeting mTOR signaling</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35243268/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35243268/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;NAM increases glycolysis while reducing effector cytokine production&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;NAM inhibits mTORC1 activation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In T cells NAM induces the expression of memory markers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;NAM diet supplementation modulates T cell effector potential &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nicotinamide (NAM) shapes T cell responses but its precise molecular mechanism of action remains elusive. Here, we show that NAM impairs naive T cell effector transition but also effector T cells themselves. Although aerobic glycolysis is a hallmark of activated T cells, CD8&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T cells exposed to NAM displayed enhanced glycolysis, yet producing significantly less IFNγ. Mechanistically, NAM reduced mTORC1 activity independently of NAD&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; metabolism, decreasing IFNγ translation and regulating T cell transcriptional factors critical to effector/memory fate. Finally, the role of NAM in a biomedically relevant model of lung injury was tested. Specifically, a NAM-supplemented diet reduced systemic IL-2, antigen-specific T cell clonal expansion, and effector function after inhalation of &lt;em&gt;Staphylococcus aureus&lt;/em&gt; enterotoxin A. These findings identify NAM as a potential therapeutic supplement that uncouples glycolysis from effector cytokine production and may be a powerful treatment for diseases associated with T cell hyperactivation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>E3 ligase RNF167 and deubiquitinase STAMBPL1 modulate mTOR and cancer progression</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35114100/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35114100/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RNF167 and STAMBPL1 modulate Sestrin2 ubiquitination in response to leucine status&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ubiquitinated Sestrin2 inhibits mTORC1 activity by sequestering GATOR2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Suppression of STAMBPL1 function inhibits tumor growth&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;STAMBPL1 is a potential therapeutic target in colorectal cancer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The mTOR complex 1 (mTORC1) is an essential metabolic hub that coordinates cellular metabolism with the availability of nutrients, including amino acids. Sestrin2 has been identified as a cytosolic leucine sensor that transmits leucine status signals to mTORC1. In this study, we identify an E3 ubiquitin ligase RING finger protein 167 (RNF167) and a deubiquitinase STAMBPL1 that function in concert to control the polyubiquitination level of Sestrin2 in response to leucine availability. Ubiquitination of Sestrin2 promotes its interaction with GATOR2 and inhibits mTORC1 signaling. Bioinformatic analysis reveals decreased RNF167 expression and increased STAMBPL1 expression in gastric and colorectal tumors. Knockout of STAMBPL1 or correction of the heterozygous STAMBPL1 mutation in a human colon cancer cell line suppresses xenograft tumor growth. Lastly, a cell-permeable peptide that blocks the STAMBPL1-Sestrin2 interaction inhibits mTORC1 and provides a potential option for cancer therapy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
