<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>siRNA | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/sirna/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/sirna/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>siRNA</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>siRNA</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/sirna/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oral Delivery of siRNA Using Fluorinated, Small-Sized Nanocapsules Toward Anti-Inflammation Treatment</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36574636/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36574636/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oral delivery of siRNA provides a promising paradigm for treating diseases that require regular injections. However, the multiple gastrointestinal and systemic barriers often lead to inefficient oral absorption and low bioavailability of siRNA. Technologies that can overcome these barriers are still lacking, which hurdles the clinical potential of orally delivered siRNA. Herein, small-sized, fluorinated nanocapsules (F-NCs) were developed to mediate efficient oral delivery of TNF-α siRNA for anti-inflammation treatment. The NCs possessed a disulfide-cross-linked shell structure, thus featuring robust stability in the gastrointestinal tract. Because of their small size (∼30 nm) and fluorocarbon-assisted repelling of mucin adsorption, the best-performing F&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;-NCs showed excellent mucus penetration and intestinal transport capabilities without impairing the intestinal tight junction, conferring the oral bioavailability of 20.4% in relative to i.v. injection. The disulfide cross-linker could be cleaved inside target cells, causing NCs dissociation and siRNA release to potentiate the TNF-α silencing efficiency. In murine models of acute and chronic inflammation, orally delivered F&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;-NCs provoked efficient TNF-α silencing and pronounced anti-inflammatory efficacies. This study therefore provides a transformative strategy for oral siRNA delivery, and would render promising utilities for anti-inflammation treatment. This article is protected by copyright. All rights reserved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hydrogel-metal-organic-framework hybrids mediated efficient oral delivery of siRNA for the treatment of ulcerative colitis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36064365/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36064365/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Ulcerative colitis (UC) is a major type of inflammatory bowel disease (IBD), which could induce bloody stool, diarrhea, colon atrophy and eventually lead to colorectal cancer. The conventional daily oral administration of drugs only relieve the inflammatory response of colon in the short term, Biological agents such as antibody drugs has proven its efficiency in inhibiting colitis, while the low drug bioavailability means that large doses of antibodies are required, ultimately causing systemic toxicity. Small interfering RNA (siRNA) has significant advantages over antibody drugs in terms of safety and efficacy, and it have been widely applied as potential candidates for a variety of inflammation-related diseases. However, oral delivery of siRNA fails to overcome the degradation of the gastrointestinal environment to produce a significant therapeutic effect in ulcerative colitis. Herein, we design the hybrid delivery system that the siRNA loaded MOF encapsulated in the sodium alginate particles to overcome the barriers in the oral process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; The hybrid delivery system (SA@MOF-siRNA&lt;sup&gt;TNFα&lt;/sup&gt;) was successfully constructed, and it could not only survive the low pH environment in the stomach and small intestine, but also taken up more by inflammatory macrophages, as well as released much more MOF-siRNA&lt;sup&gt;TNFα&lt;/sup&gt;. Moreover, SA@MOF-siRNA&lt;sup&gt;TNFα&lt;/sup&gt; tended to enriched and infiltrated into local colon tissues. As a result, SA@MOF-siRNA&lt;sup&gt;TNFα&lt;/sup&gt; significantly reduced the progression of colitis, of which the treated mice did not experience significant weight loss, bloody stools and diarrhea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/em&gt; We confirmed that the formulation of hydrogel-metal-organic framework hybrids could improve the protection of incorporated payload in the gastric and early small intestine, enhancing the delivery of MOF-siRNA to colon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intermittent fasting attenuates lipopolysaccharide-induced acute lung injury in mice by modulating macrophage polarization</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36028098/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36028098/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acute lung injury (ALI) is a spectrum of acute and life-threatening pulmonary inflammatory conditions. Treatment of ALI remains a clinical challenge. Recently, intermittent fasting (IF) has been shown to improve health and alleviate many diseases. In this study, we tested whether IF attenuated ALI and investigated the mechanism underlying this process. &lt;em&gt;In vivo&lt;/em&gt;, the effects of IF on ALI were evaluated in a lipopolysaccharide (LPS)-induced murine ALI model. We found that two times of 24-h fasting in a week before ALI efficiently ameliorated LPS-induced lung injury in mice, characterized by alleviated lung lesions, wet-to-dry weight ratio, myeloperoxidase activity, malondialdehyde content, and lower levels of tumor necrosis factor-α, interleukin-6, and interleukin-1β. &lt;em&gt;In vitro&lt;/em&gt;, functional assays were conducted to assess IF on the inflammatory response and macrophage polarization of bone marrow-derived macrophages (BMDMs) treated with LPS or IL-4. And PPARγ antagonist GW9662 and AMPK siRNA were used to test the role of PPARγ and AMPK in the IF-mediated improvement of ALI. The results showed that IF (serum deprivation) suppressed macrophage M1 activation and promoted M2 activation in LPS-treated BMDMs. While, IF also augmented macrophage M2 polarization in IL-4-treated BMDMs. Further mechanistic studies showed that the promotive effect of IF on M2 polarization was related to the activation of the PPARγ and AMPK pathways. In conclusion, this study suggests that IF enhances M2 polarization by activating the AMPK and PPARγ pathways, thus facilitating anti-inflammatory response and ameliorating ALI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exosomes deliver lncRNA DARS-AS1 siRNA to inhibit chronic unpredictable mild stress-induced TNBC metastasis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35688263/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35688263/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Exosomes are natural nanocarriers for efficient delivery of siRNA to recipient cells.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SiRNA-loaded exosomes were performed by modified calcium-mediated transfection method.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SiRNA-loaded exosomes demonstrated dose-dependent knockdown efficiency.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SiRNA-loaded exosomes showed strong antitumor activity on TNBC cells in vitro.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SiRNA-loaded exosomes intensively inhibited TNBC tumor growth and metastasis in vivo.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Triple-negative breast cancer (TNBC) is a rapidly recurring and highly metastatic malignancy with high heterogeneity and chemoradiotherapy resistance. Chronic unpredictable mild stress (CUMS) can induce the occurrence of tumors and enhance lymphatic infiltration and distant metastasis through direct interaction with the sympathetic nervous system; however, its relevance in TNBC is yet to be clarified. In this study, DARS-AS1, a newly reported CUMS-responsive lncRNA, was found to be enriched in TNBC clinical tumors and cells and positively correlated with late clinical stage in patients with TNBC. DARS-AS1 overexpression significantly enhanced the migration and invasion of TNBC tumors by inhibiting miR-129-2-3p and upregulated CDK1 to activate the NF-κB/STAT3 signaling pathway both &lt;em&gt;in vitro&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt;. Treatment with DARS-AS1 siRNA-loaded exosomes (EXOs) substantially slowed CUMS-induced TNBC cell growth and liver metastasis. Therefore, DARS-AS1 represents a potential therapeutic target for metastatic TNBC, and EXOs may serve as siRNA delivery carriers in clinical therapy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mouse circulating extracellular vesicles contain virus-derived siRNAs active in antiviral immunity</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35343600/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35343600/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Induction and suppression of antiviral RNA interference (RNAi) has been observed in mammals during infection with at least seven distinct RNA viruses, including some that are pathogenic in humans. However, while the cell-autonomous immune response mediated by antiviral RNAi is gradually being recognized, little is known about systemic antiviral RNAi in mammals. Furthermore, extracellular vesicles (EVs) also function in viral signal spreading and host immunity. Here, we show that upon antiviral RNAi activation, virus-derived small-interfering RNAs (vsiRNAs) from Nodamura virus (NoV), Sindbis virus (SINV), and Zika virus (ZIKV) enter the murine bloodstream via EVs for systemic circulation. vsiRNAs in the EVs are biologically active, since they confer RNA-RNA homology-dependent antiviral activity in both cultured cells and infant mice. Moreover, we demonstrate that vaccination with a live-attenuated virus, rendered deficient in RNAi suppression, induces production of stably maintained vsiRNAs and confers protective immunity against virus infection in mice. This suggests that vaccination with live-attenuated VSR (viral suppressor of RNAi)-deficient mutant viruses could be a new strategy to induce immunity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Activation of AMPK/NRF2 Pathway in Lung Epithelial Cells Is Involved in the Protective Effects of Kinsenoside on Lipopolysaccharide-Induced Acute Lung Injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35340214/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35340214/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The disorder of mitochondrial dynamic equilibrium of lung epithelial cell is one of the critical causes of acute lung injury (ALI). Kinsenoside (Kin) serves as an active small-molecule component derived from traditional medicinal herb displaying multiple pharmacological actions in cancers, hyperglycemia, and liver disease. The objective of this study was to investigate the effects of Kin on lipopolysaccharide- (LPS-) induced ALI and further explore possible molecular mechanisms. Kin was administered orally (100 mg/kg/day) for 7 consecutive days before LPS instillation (5 mg/kg). After 12 hours, pathological injury, inflammatory response, and oxidative stress were detected. The results demonstrated that Kin significantly alleviated lung pathological injury and decreased the infiltration of inflammatory cells and the release of inflammatory mediators in bronchoalveolar lavage fluid (BALF), apart from inhibiting the production of reactive oxygen species (ROS) and lipid peroxidation. Meanwhile, Kin also promoted mitochondrial fusion and restrained mitochondrial fission in mice with ALI. In terms of mechanism, Kin pretreatment increased the phosphorylation of AMP-activated protein kinase (AMPK) and the protein level of nuclear factor erythroid 2-related factor 2 (NRF2). In &lt;em&gt;Ampk-α&lt;/em&gt; knockout mice challenged with LPS, Kin lost its pulmonary protective effects, accompanied by lower NRF2 level. &lt;em&gt;In vitro&lt;/em&gt; experiments further unveiled that either AMPK inhibition by Compound C or NRF2 knockdown by siRNA abolished the protective roles of Kin in LPS-treated A549 lung epithelial cells. And NRF2 activator TAT-14 could reverse the effects of &lt;em&gt;Ampk-α&lt;/em&gt; deficiency. In conclusion, Kin possesses the ability to prevent LPS-induced ALI by modulating mitochondrial dynamic equilibrium in lung epithelial cell in an AMPK/NRF2-dependent manner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emodin Protects Against Lipopolysaccharide-Induced Acute Lung Injury via the JNK/Nur77/c-Jun Signaling Pathway</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35370650/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35370650/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Acute lung injury (ALI) is a serious inflammatory disease with clinical manifestations of hypoxemia and respiratory failure. Presently, there is no effective treatment of ALI. Although emodin from Rheum palmatum L. exerts anti-ALI properties, the underlying mechanisms have not been fully explored.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Purpose:&lt;/em&gt; This study aimed to investigate the therapeutic effect and mechanism of emodin on LPS-induced ALI in mice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; RAW264.7 cells and zebrafish larvae were stimulated by LPS to establish inflammatory models. The anti-inflammatory effect of emodin was assessed by ELISA, flow cytometric analysis, and survival analysis. &lt;em&gt;In vitro&lt;/em&gt; mechanisms were explored by using Western blotting, luciferase assay, electrophoretic mobility shift assay (EMSA), and small interfering RNA (siRNA) approach. The acute lung injury model in mice was established by the intratracheal administration of LPS, and the underlying mechanisms were assessed by detecting changes in histopathological and inflammatory markers and Western blotting in lung tissues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; Emodin inhibited the inflammatory factor production and oxidative stress in RAW264.7 cells, and prolonged the survival of zebrafish larvae after LPS stimulation. Emodin suppressed the expression levels of phosphorylated JNK at Thr183/tyr182 and phosphorylated Nur77 at Ser351 and c-Jun, and increased the expression level of Nur77 in LPS-stimulated RAW264.7 cells, while these regulatory effects of emodin on Nur77/c-Jun were counteracted by JNK activators. The overexpression of JNK dampened the emodin-mediated increase in Nur77 luciferase activity and Nur77 expression. Moreover, the inhibitory effect of emodin on c-Jun can be attenuated by Nur77 siRNA. Furthermore, emodin alleviated LPS-induced ALI in mice through the regulation of the JNK/Nur77/c-Jun pathway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; Emodin protects against LPS-induced ALI through regulation on JNK/Nur77/c-Jun signaling. Our results indicate the potential of emodin in the treatment of ALI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PUMILIO proteins promote colorectal cancer growth via suppressing p21</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35338151/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35338151/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PUMILIO (PUM) proteins belong to the highly conserved PUF family post-transcriptional regulators involved in diverse biological processes. However, their function in carcinogenesis remains under-explored. Here, we report that &lt;em&gt;Pum1&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Pum2&lt;/em&gt; display increased expression in human colorectal cancer (CRC). Intestine-specific knockout of &lt;em&gt;Pum1&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Pum2&lt;/em&gt; in mice significantly inhibits the progression of colitis-associated cancer in the AOM/DSS model. Knockout or knockdown of &lt;em&gt;Pum1&lt;/em&gt; and/or &lt;em&gt;Pum2&lt;/em&gt; in human CRC cells result in a significant decrease in the tumorigenicity and delayed G1/S transition. We identify p21/Cdkn1a as a direct target of PUM1. Abrogation of the PUM1 binding site in the p21 mRNA also results in decreased cancer cell growth and delayed G1/S transition. Furthermore, intravenous injection of nanoparticle-encapsulated anti-&lt;em&gt;Pum1&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Pum2&lt;/em&gt; siRNAs reduces colorectal tumor growth in murine orthotopic colon cancer models. These findings reveal the requirement of PUM proteins for CRC progression and their potential as therapeutic targets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
