<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Prostate | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/prostate/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/prostate/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Prostate</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Prostate</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/prostate/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>The transcriptional terminator XRN2 and the RNA-binding protein Sam68 link alternative polyadenylation to cell cycle progression in prostate cancer</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36344846/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36344846/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alternative polyadenylation (APA) yields transcripts differing in their 3′-end, and its regulation is altered in cancer, including prostate cancer. Here we have uncovered a mechanism of APA regulation impinging on the interaction between the exonuclease XRN2 and the RNA-binding protein Sam68, whose increased expression in prostate cancer is promoted by the transcription factor MYC. Genome-wide transcriptome profiling revealed a widespread impact of the Sam68/XRN2 complex on APA. XRN2 promotes recruitment of Sam68 to its target transcripts, where it competes with the cleavage and polyadenylation specificity factor for binding to strong polyadenylation signals at distal ends of genes, thus promoting usage of suboptimal proximal polyadenylation signals. This mechanism leads to 3′ untranslated region shortening and translation of transcripts encoding proteins involved in G1/S progression and proliferation. Thus, our findings indicate that the APA program driven by Sam68/XRN2 promotes cell cycle progression and may represent an actionable target for therapeutic intervention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Long non‑coding RNA CASC11 interacts with YBX1 to promote prostate cancer progression by suppressing the p53 pathway</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35904175/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35904175/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prostate cancer (PCa) is one of the principal causes of cancer‑related death worldwide. The roles and mechanisms of long non‑coding RNA (lncRNA) involved in the development of PCa remain incompletely understood. The present study aimed to investigate the role and mechanism of lncRNA in PCa tumorigenesis. In the present study, lncRNA cancer susceptibility candidate 11 (CASC11) was revealed to be a crucial regulator of PCa progression. The expression profiles of CASC11 in PCa were identified through analysis of The Cancer Genome Atlas and Gene Expression Omnibus datasets, and validated in human PCa specimens and cell lines. Gain‑ and loss‑of‑function assays were utilized to explore the biological role of CASC11 in PCa initiation and progression. RNA‑sequencing, RNA pull‑down and RNA immunoprecipitation analyses were used to explore potential mechanisms with which CASC11 may be associated. Rescue experiments were further conducted to confirm this association. The present results revealed that CASC11 was dominantly distributed in the nuclei of PCa cells, and was highly expressed in PCa tissues and cells. Overexpression of CASC11 was markedly associated with increased tumor proliferation and migratory ability. Functionally, decreased proliferation and migration, as well as inhibited xenograft tumor growth, were observed in CASC11‑silenced PCa cells, whereas the opposite effects were detected in CASC11‑overexpressing cells. Mechanistically, CASC11 promoted progression of the cell cycle and competitively interacted with Y‑box binding protein 1 (YBX1) to block the p53 pathway. Given this, poly (β‑amino ester) (PBAE)/small interfering RNA‑CASC11 (si‑CASC11) nanoparticles were applied to inhibit CASC11 expression and enhance the antitumor effect in vivo. The results revealed that PBAE/si‑CASC11 nanoparticles augmented the antitumor efficacy of CASC11 knockdown in vivo. In conclusion, the present study suggested that CASC11 may regulate PCa progression and elucidated a novel CASC11/YBX1/p53 signaling axis, providing a potential lncRNA‑directed therapeutic strategy particularly for the treatment of patients with PCa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docetaxel resistance-derived LINC01085 contributes to the immunotherapy of hormone-independent prostate cancer by activating the STING/MAVS signaling pathway</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35868534/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35868534/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;LINC01085&lt;/em&gt; is deleted in hormone-independent prostate cancer (HIPC) which can predict better outcomes of HIPC patients.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;LINC01085 acts as a tumor suppressor in the tumourigenicity and metastasis of HIPC.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;LINC01085 exerts its functions by both interacting with TBK1 and GSK3β, accelerated TBK1 phosphorylation at the Ser-172 site, in HIPC.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;LINC01085 combined with PARP inhibitor and anti-PD-L1 treatment may be pivotal in the treatment of HIPC patients.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acquired docetaxel (doc) resistance, one of the major reasons for unfavorable prognosis in patients with aggressive hormone-independent prostate cancer (HIPC), is a major obstacle for patient treatment. Dysregulation of long non-coding RNAs promotes or suppresses chemoresistance in multiple cancers; however, the specific molecular mechanisms underlying HIPC remain unknown. In this study, we found that the LINC01085, as a tumor-suppressor, which showed significant clinically relevant in HIPC patients with doc-resistance. Mechanistically, in docetaxel-sensitive cells, LINC01085 could specifically bind to both TANK-binding kinase 1 (TBK1) and glycogen synthase kinase 3β (GSK3β), and higher LINC01085 RNA levels could inhibit TBK1 dimerization. Whereas, in doc-resistant cells, lower LINC01085 RNA level lost the strong binding with both, meanwhile, the interaction between TBK1 and GSK3β enhanced which accelerated TBK1 phosphorylation at the Ser-172 site, resulting in decreased expression levels of PD-L1 and NF-κB as well as the secretion of type I/III interferons. Thus, Overexpression of LINC01085 combined with immune checkpoint blockade is an effective strategy for the treatment of HIPC patients.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LINC00893 inhibits the progression of prostate cancer through miR-3173-5p/SOCS3/JAK2/STAT3 pathway</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35818076/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35818076/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Prostate cancer (PCa) is one of the most common malignant tumors in the male urinary system. In recent years, the morbidity and mortality of PCa have been increasing due to the limited effects of existing treatment strategies. Long non-coding RNA (lncRNA) LINC00893 was reported to inhibit the proliferation and metastasis of papillary thyroid cancer cells, but its role in PCa has not been reported. This study aims to investigate the role and underlying mechanism of LINC00893 in regulating the progression of PCa cells.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; We first compared LINC00893 expression levels between PCa tissues and normal prostate tissues through TCGA database. The relative LINC00893 expression levels were further validated in 66 pairs of PCa tissues and para-cancerous normal tissues, as well as in PCa cell lines. Gain-of-function experiment was performed by transfecting PCa cell with LINC00893 expression vector, and CCK (Cell count kit)-8, 5-Ethynyl-2&amp;rsquo;-deoxyuridine (EdU) incorporation, colony information and transwell assays were conducted to assess the functional phenotypes. Dual-luciferase reporter, RNA-binding protein immunoprecipitation (RIP) and RNA pull-down assays were performed to evaluate the molecular interactions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; LINC00893 was downregulated in PCa tissues and cell lines, and patients with low expression of LINC00893 were associated with a poorer overall survival rate. LINC00893 overexpression hindered the proliferation, epithelial-mesenchymal transition (EMT) as well as the migratory ability of PCa cells, and suppressed the tumorigenesis of PCa cells in nude mice. We further demonstrated that LINC00893 acted as a sponge for miR-3173-5p and inhibited its activity, which in turn regulated the suppressor of cytokine signaling 3 (SOCS3)/Janus Kinase 2 (JAK2)/signal transducer and activator of transcription 3 (STAT3) signaling axis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; Our study demonstrated that LINC00893 suppresses the progression of PCa cells through targeting miR-3173-5p/SOCS3/JAK2/STAT3 axis. Our data uncovers a novel tumor-suppressor role of LINC00893 in PCa, which may serve as a potential strategy for targeted therapy in PCa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gut dysbiosis promotes prostate cancer progression and docetaxel resistance via activating NF-κB-IL6-STAT3 axis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35710492/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35710492/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; The gut microbiota is reportedly involved in the progression and chemoresistance of various human malignancies. However, the underlying mechanisms behind how it exerts some effect on prostate cancer, as an extra-intestinal tumor, in a contact-independent way remain elusive and deserve exploration. Antibiotic exposure, one of the various factors affecting the gut microbiota community and capable of causing gut dysbiosis, is associated with multiple disorders. This study aims to preliminarily clarify the link between gut dysbiosis and prostate cancer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; First, we discovered that perturbing the gut microbiota by consuming broad-spectrum antibiotics in water promoted the growth of subcutaneous and orthotopic tumors in mice. Fecal microbiota transplantation could transmit the effect of antibiotic exposure on tumor growth. Then, 16S rRNA sequencing for mouse feces indicated that the relative abundance of Proteobacteria was significantly higher after antibiotic exposure. Meanwhile, intratumoral lipopolysaccharide (LPS) profoundly increased under the elevation of gut permeability. Both in vivo and in vitro experiments revealed that the NF-κB-IL6-STAT3 axis activated by intratumoral LPS facilitated prostate cancer proliferation and docetaxel chemoresistance. Finally, 16S rRNA sequencing of patients&amp;rsquo; fecal samples revealed that Proteobacteria was enriched in patients with metastatic prostate cancer and was positively correlated with plasma IL6 level, regional lymph node metastasis status, and distant metastasis status. The receiver operating characteristic (ROC) curves showed that the relative abundance of Proteobacteria had better performance than the prostate-specific antigen (PSA) level in predicting the probability of distant metastasis in prostate cancer (area under the ROC curve, 0.860; p &amp;lt; 0.001).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/em&gt; Collectively, this research demonstrated that gut dysbiosis, characterized by the enrichment of Proteobacteria due to antibiotic exposure, resulted in the elevation of gut permeability and intratumoral LPS, promoting the development of prostate cancer via the NF-κB-IL6-STAT3 axis in mice. Considering findings from human patients, Proteobacteria might act as an intestinal biomarker for progressive prostate cancer. Video Abstract.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CircCEMIP promotes anoikis-resistance by enhancing protective autophagy in prostate cancer cells</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35655258/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35655258/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Circular RNAs (circRNAs) are essential participants in the development and progression of various malignant tumors. Previous studies have shown that cell migration-inducing protein (CEMIP) accelerates prostate cancer (PCa) anoikis resistance (AR) by activating autophagy. This study focused on the effect of circCEMIP on PCa metastasis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; This study gradually revealed the role of circ_0004585 in PCa anoikis resistance via quantitative real-time PCR (qRT-PCR) analysis, western blotting, pull-down assays, and dual fluorescence reporter assays.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; Functionally, circ_0004585 promoted PCa cells invasion and metastasis both in vitro and in vivo. Mechanistically, circ_0004585 directly interacted with miR-1248 to upregulate target gene expression. Furthermore, target prediction and dual-luciferase reporter assays identified transmembrane 9 superfamily member 4 (TM9SF4) as a potential miR-1248 target. Pathway analysis revealed that TM9SF4 activated autophagy to promote PCa cells anoikis resistance via mTOR phosphorylation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; These results demonstrated that circ_0004585 played an oncogenic role during PCa invasion and metastasis by targeting the miR-1248/TM9SF4 axis while providing new insight into therapeutic strategy development for metastatic PCa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Targeted inhibition of SIRT6 via engineered exosomes impairs tumorigenesis and metastasis in prostate cancer</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33995674/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33995674/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The treatment for metastatic castration-resistant prostate cancer patients remains a great challenge in the clinic and continuously demands discoveries of new targets and therapies. Here, we assess the function and therapeutic value of SIRT6 in metastatic castration-resistant prostate cancer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The expression of SIRT6 was examined in prostate cancer tissue microarray by immunohistochemistry staining. The functions of SIRT6 and underlying mechanisms were elucidated by in vitro and in vivo experiments. We also developed an efficient method to silence SIRT6 by aptamer-modified exosomes carrying small interfering RNA and tested the therapeutic effect in the xenograft mice models.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SIRT6 expression is positively correlated with prostate cancer progression. Loss of SIRT6 significantly suppressed proliferation and metastasis of prostate cancer cell lines both in vitro and in vivo. SIRT6-driven prostate cancer displays activation of multiple cancer-related signaling pathways, especially the Notch pathway. Silencing SIRT6 by siRNA delivered through engineered exosomes inhibited tumor growth and metastasis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SIRT6 is identified as a driver and therapeutic target for metastatic prostate cancer in our findings, and inhibition of SIRT6 by engineered exosomes can serve as a promising therapeutic tool for clinical application.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Downregulation of nc886 contributes to prostate cancer cell invasion and TGFβ1-induced EMT</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35685460/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35685460/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Epithelial-to-mesenchymal transition (EMT) activation is important in cancer progression and metastasis. Evidence indicates that &lt;em&gt;nc886&lt;/em&gt; is a representative Pol III gene that processes microRNA products via Dicer and further downregulates its target gene transforming growth factor- β1 (TGF-β1), which is the most prominent inducer of EMT in prostate cancer (PC). Consistent with the previous literature, we found that &lt;em&gt;nc886&lt;/em&gt; downregulation was strongly associated with metastatic behavior and showed worse outcomes in PC patients. However, little is known about the association between &lt;em&gt;nc886&lt;/em&gt; and the EMT signaling pathway. We developed a PC cell model with stable overexpression of &lt;em&gt;nc886&lt;/em&gt; and found that &lt;em&gt;nc886&lt;/em&gt; changed cellular morphology and drove MET. The underlying mechanism may be related to its promotion of SNAIL protein degradation via ubiquitination, but not to its neighboring genes, TGFβ-induced protein (&lt;em&gt;TGFBI&lt;/em&gt;) and &lt;em&gt;SMAD5&lt;/em&gt;, which are Pol II-transcribed. TGF-β1 also override &lt;em&gt;nc886&lt;/em&gt; promotion of MET via transient suppression the transcription of &lt;em&gt;nc886&lt;/em&gt;, promotion of &lt;em&gt;TGFBI&lt;/em&gt; or increase in SMAD5 phosphorylation. Both &lt;em&gt;nc886&lt;/em&gt; inhibition and &lt;em&gt;TGFBI&lt;/em&gt; activation occur regardless of their methylation status. The literature suggests that MYC inhibition by TGF-β1 is attributed to &lt;em&gt;nc886&lt;/em&gt; downregulation. We incidentally identified MYC-associated zinc finger protein (MAZ) as a suppressive transcription factor of TGFBI, which is controlled by TGF-β1. We elucidate a new mechanism of TGF-β1 differential control of Pol II and the transcription of its neighboring Pol III gene and identify a new EMT unit consisting of &lt;em&gt;nc886&lt;/em&gt; and its neighboring genes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
