<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Liver | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/liver/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/liver/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Liver</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Liver</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/liver/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lactylome analysis suggests lactylation-dependent mechanisms of metabolic adaptation in hepatocellular carcinoma</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/23-01-03-08-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/23-01-03-08-19/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enhanced glycolysis and accumulation of lactate is a common feature in various types of cancer. Intracellular lactate drives a recently described type of posttranslational modification, lysine lactylation (Kla), on core histones. However, the impact of lactylation on biological processes of tumour cells remains largely unknown. Here we show a global lactylome profiling on a prospectively collected hepatitis B virus-related hepatocellular carcinoma (HCC) cohort. Integrative lactylome and proteome analysis of the tumours and adjacent livers identifies 9,275 Kla sites, with 9,256 sites on non-histone proteins, indicating that Kla is a prevalent modification beyond histone proteins and transcriptional regulation. Notably, Kla preferentially affects enzymes involved in metabolic pathways, including the tricarboxylic acid cycle, and carbohydrate, amino acid, fatty acid and nucleotide metabolism. We further verify that lactylation at K28 inhibits the function of adenylate kinase 2, facilitating the proliferation and metastasis of HCC cells. Our study therefore reveals that Kla plays an important role in regulating cellular metabolism and may contribute to HCC progression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Heparan sulfate proteoglycan-mediated internalization of extracellular vesicles ameliorates liver fibrosis by targeting hepatic stellate cells</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/2022-12-14-1024/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/2022-12-14-1024/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Accumulating evidence shows that stem cell-derived extracellular vesicles (EVs) have shown great promise for tissue regeneration and are considered an alternative to cell-based therapy. However, the mechanisms by which EVs induce tissue repair have not been well demonstrated. Previous work indicates that activation of hepatic stellate cells (HSCs) may contribute to the progression of liver fibrosis. Here, we investigate the therapeutic potential of EVs derived from human placental mesenchymal stem cells (hP-MSCs) for the treatment of carbon tetrachloride (CCl4)-induced liver injury. Our data revealed that EVs derived from hP-MSCs effectively ameliorate liver injury by attenuating inflammation and fibrosis. Further data revealed that heparan sulfate proteoglycans (HSPGs) on the surface of HSCs mediate the internalization of EVs. Furthermore, EVs could inhibit the epithelial–mesenchymal transition (EMT) process in HSCs through the downregulated TGF-/Smad pathway, which was mediated by miR-744-5p in EVs. Meanwhile, glycosaminoglycans on the surface of EVs play a crucial anti-inflammatory role. In conclusion, our results provide evidence that hP-MSC-derived EVs promote the recovery of liver injury by targeting HSPGs on HSCs and inhibiting liver inflammation through glycosaminoglycans from EVs. These findings may provide a novel theoretical basis for the treatment of liver fibrosis based on EVs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Endotoxin Delivery Protein HMGB1 Mediates Caspase-11-Dependent Lethality in Sepsis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/30314759/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/30314759/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hepatocyte-released HMGB1 mediates caspase-11-dependent lethality in sepsis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;HMGB1-LPS complexes are taken up by macrophages and endothelial cells via RAGE&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;HMGB1 destabilizes phagolysosomes for the transfer of LPS to cytosolic caspase-11&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Neutralizing extracellular HMGB1 inhibits caspase-11 activation in sepsis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Summary&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Caspase-11, a cytosolic endotoxin (lipopolysaccharide: LPS) receptor, mediates pyroptosis, a lytic form of cell death. Caspase-11-dependent pyroptosis mediates lethality in endotoxemia, but it is unclear how LPS is delivered into the cytosol for the activation of caspase-11. Here we discovered that hepatocyte-released high mobility group box 1 (HMGB1) was required for caspase-11-dependent pyroptosis and lethality in endotoxemia and bacterial sepsis. Mechanistically, hepatocyte-released HMGB1 bound LPS and targeted its internalization into the lysosomes of macrophages and endothelial cells via the receptor for advanced glycation end-products (RAGE). Subsequently, HMGB1 permeabilized the phospholipid bilayer in the acidic environment of lysosomes. This resulted in LPS leakage into the cytosol and caspase-11 activation. Depletion of hepatocyte HMGB1, inhibition of hepatocyte HMGB1 release, neutralizing extracellular HMGB1, or RAGE deficiency prevented caspase-11-dependent pyroptosis and death in endotoxemia and bacterial sepsis. These findings indicate that HMGB1 interacts with LPS to mediate caspase-11-dependent pyroptosis in lethal sepsis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Landscape of Infiltrating T Cells in Liver Cancer Revealed by Single-Cell Sequencing</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/28622514/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/28622514/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Systematic interrogation of tumor-infiltrating lymphocytes is key to the development of immunotherapies and the prediction of their clinical responses in cancers. Here, we perform deep single-cell RNA sequencing on 5,063 single T cells isolated from peripheral blood, tumor, and adjacent normal tissues from six hepatocellular carcinoma patients. The transcriptional profiles of these individual cells, coupled with assembled T cell receptor (TCR) sequences, enable us to identify 11 T cell subsets based on their molecular and functional properties and delineate their developmental trajectory. Specific subsets such as exhausted CD8+ T cells and Tregs are preferentially enriched and potentially clonally expanded in hepatocellular carcinoma (HCC), and we identified signature genes for each subset. One of the genes, layilin, is upregulated on activated CD8+ T cells and Tregs and represses the CD8+ T cell functions in vitro. This compendium of transcriptome data provides valuable insights and a rich resource for understanding the immune landscape in cancers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
