<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Liver | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/liver/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/liver/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Liver</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Liver</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/liver/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blockade of NMT1 enzymatic activity inhibits N-myristoylation of VILIP3 protein and suppresses liver cancer progression</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36617552/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36617552/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hepatocellular carcinoma (HCC) is one of the most common malignant tumors. Identification of the underlying mechanism of HCC progression and exploration of new therapeutic drugs are urgently needed. Here, a compound library consisting of 419 FDA-approved drugs was taken to screen potential anticancer drugs. A series of functional assays showed that desloratadine, an antiallergic drug, can repress proliferation in HCC cell lines, cell-derived xenograft (CDX), patient-derived organoid (PDO) and patient-derived xenograft (PDX) models. N-myristoyl transferase 1 (NMT1) was identified as a target protein of desloratadine by drug affinity responsive target stability (DARTS) and surface plasmon resonance (SPR) assays. Upregulation of NMT1 expression enhanced but NMT1 knockdown suppressed tumor growth in vitro and in vivo. Metabolic labeling and mass spectrometry analyses revealed that Visinin-like protein 3 (VILIP3) was a new substrate of NMT1 in protein N-myristoylation modification, and high NMT1 or VILIP3 expression was associated with advanced stages and poor survival in HCC. Mechanistically, desloratadine binds to Asn-246 in NMT1 and inhibits its enzymatic activity, disrupting the NMT1-mediated myristoylation of the VILIP3 protein and subsequent NFκB/Bcl-2 signaling. Conclusively, this study demonstrates that desloratadine may be a novel anticancer drug and that NMT1-mediated myristoylation contributes to HCC progression and is a potential biomarker and therapeutic target in HCC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CD44-targeting Drug Delivery System of Exosomes Loading Forsythiaside A Combats Liver Fibrosis via Regulating NLRP3-mediated Pyroptosis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36603210/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36603210/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Liver fibrosis is a progressive pathological process induced by various stimuli and may progress to liver cirrhosis and cancer. Forsythiaside A (FA) is an active ingredient extracted from traditional Chinese medicine Forsythiae Fructus and has prominent hepatoprotective activities. However, the unsatisfactory pharmacokinetic properties restrict its clinical application. In this study, the nanocarrier of CD44-specific ligand Hyaluronic acid (HA)-modified milk-derived exosomes (mExo) encapsulated with FA (HA-mExo-FA) is developed. As a result, HA modification could deliver drug-loaded exosomes to the target cells and form a specific ligand-receptor interaction with CD44, thus improving the anti-liver fibrosis effect of FA. In vitro findings indicate that HA-mExo-FA could inhibit TGF-β1-induced LX2 cell proliferation, reduce α-SMA and collagen gene and protein levels, and promote the apoptosis of activated LX2 cells. In vivo results demonstrate that HA-mExo-FA could improve liver morphology and function changes in zebrafish larvae. The anti-liver fibrosis mechanism of HA-mExo-FA may be attributed to the inhibition of NLRP3-mediated pyroptosis. In addition, the effect of HA-mExo-FA on TAA-induced increase in NLRP3 production is attenuated by NLRP3 inhibitor MCC950. Collectively, this study demonstrates the promising application of HA-mExo-FA in drug delivery with high specificity and provides a powerful and novel delivery platform for liver fibrosis therapy. This article is protected by copyright.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Diurnal transcriptome landscape of a multi-tissue response to time-restricted feeding in mammals</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36599299/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36599299/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;80% of genes are differentially expressed or rhythmic under TRF in at least one tissue&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;TRF decreases genes involved in inflammatory signaling and glycerolipid metabolism&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;TRF increases genes involved in RNA processing, protein folding, and autophagy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;TRF causes multi-tissue rewiring of BCAA, glucose, and lipid metabolism&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Summary&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Time-restricted feeding (TRF) is an emerging behavioral nutrition intervention that involves a daily cycle of feeding and fasting. In both animals and humans, TRF has pleiotropic health benefits that arise from multiple organ systems, yet the molecular basis of TRF-mediated benefits is not well understood. Here, we subjected mice to isocaloric &lt;em&gt;ad libitum&lt;/em&gt; feeding (ALF) or TRF of a western diet and examined gene expression changes in samples taken from 22 organs and brain regions collected every 2 h over a 24-h period. We discovered that TRF profoundly impacts gene expression. Nearly 80% of all genes show differential expression or rhythmicity under TRF in at least one tissue. Functional annotation of these changes revealed tissue- and pathway-specific impacts of TRF. These findings and resources provide a critical foundation for future mechanistic studies and will help to guide human time-restricted eating (TRE) interventions to treat various disease conditions with or without pharmacotherapies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lactylome analysis suggests lactylation-dependent mechanisms of metabolic adaptation in hepatocellular carcinoma</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36593272/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36593272/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enhanced glycolysis and accumulation of lactate is a common feature in various types of cancer. Intracellular lactate drives a recently described type of posttranslational modification, lysine lactylation (Kla), on core histones. However, the impact of lactylation on biological processes of tumour cells remains largely unknown. Here we show a global lactylome profiling on a prospectively collected hepatitis B virus-related hepatocellular carcinoma (HCC) cohort. Integrative lactylome and proteome analysis of the tumours and adjacent livers identifies 9,275 Kla sites, with 9,256 sites on non-histone proteins, indicating that Kla is a prevalent modification beyond histone proteins and transcriptional regulation. Notably, Kla preferentially affects enzymes involved in metabolic pathways, including the tricarboxylic acid cycle, and carbohydrate, amino acid, fatty acid and nucleotide metabolism. We further verify that lactylation at K28 inhibits the function of adenylate kinase 2, facilitating the proliferation and metastasis of HCC cells. Our study therefore reveals that Kla plays an important role in regulating cellular metabolism and may contribute to HCC progression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Age-related liver endothelial zonation triggers steatohepatitis by inactivating pericentral endothelium-derived C-kit</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/23-01-10-21-23/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/23-01-10-21-23/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aging leads to systemic metabolic disorders, including steatosis. Here we show that liver sinusoidal endothelial cell (LSEC) senescence accelerates liver sinusoid capillarization and promotes steatosis by reprogramming liver endothelial zonation and inactivating pericentral endothelium-derived C-kit, which is a type III receptor tyrosine kinase. Specifically, inhibition of endothelial C-kit triggers cellular senescence, perturbing LSEC homeostasis in male mice. During diet-induced nonalcoholic steatohepatitis (NASH) development, Kit deletion worsens hepatic steatosis and exacerbates NASH-associated fibrosis and inflammation. Mechanistically, C-kit transcriptionally inhibits chemokine (C–X–C motif) receptor (CXCR)4 via CCAAT enhancer-binding protein α (CEBPA). Blocking CXCR4 signaling abolishes LSEC–macrophage–neutrophil cross-talk and leads to the recovery of C-kit-deficient mice with NASH. Of therapeutic relevance, infusing C-kit-expressing LSECs into aged mice or mice with diet-induced NASH counteracts age-associated senescence and steatosis and improves the symptoms of diet-induced NASH by restoring metabolic homeostasis of the pericentral liver endothelium. Our work provides an alternative approach that could be useful for treating aging- and diet-induced NASH.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Discovery of a first-in-class orally available HBV cccDNA inhibitor</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36587899/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36587899/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background &amp;amp; Aims&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The persistence of covalently closed circular DNA (cccDNA) in infected hepatocytes is the major barrier preventing viral eradication with existing therapies in patients with chronic hepatitis B (CHB). Therapeutic agents that can eliminate cccDNA are urgently needed to achieve virus eradication and thus HBV cure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A phenotypic assay with HBV-infected primary human hepatocytes (PHHs) was employed to screen for novel cccDNA inhibitors. A HBVcircle mouse model and a urokinase-type plasminogen activator-severe combined immunodeficiency (uPA-SCID) humanized liver mouse model were used to evaluate the anti-HBV efficacy of the discovered cccDNA inhibitors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Potent and dose-dependent reductions in extracellular HBV DNA, HBsAg, and HBeAg levels were achieved upon the initiation of ccc_R08 treatment two days after the HBV infection of PHHs. More importantly, the level of cccDNA was specifically reduced by ccc_R08, while it did not obviously affect mitochondrial DNA. Additionally, ccc_R08 showed no significant cytotoxicity in PHHs or in multiple proliferating cell lines. The twice daily oral administration of ccc_R08 to HBVcircle model mice, which contained surrogate cccDNA molecules, significantly decreased the serum levels of HBV DNA and antigens, and these effects were sustained during the off-treatment follow-up period. Moreover, at the end of the follow-up, the levels of surrogate cccDNA molecules in the livers of ccc_R08-treated HBVcircle mice were reduced to below the lower limit of quantification (LLOQ).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have discovered a small molecule cccDNA inhibitor that reduces HBV cccDNA levels. cccDNA inhibitors potentially represent a new approach to completely cure patients chronically infected with HBV.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Impact and Implications&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;cccDNA persistence in HBV-infected hepatocytes is the root cause of chronic hepatitis B. We discovered a novel small molecule cccDNA inhibitor that can specifically reduce cccDNA levels in HBV infected hepatocytes. This type of molecule offers a new approach to completely cure patients chronically infected with HBV.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Genetic dissection of intercellular interactions in vivo by membrane-permeable protein</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36574652/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36574652/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unraveling cell-cell interaction is fundamental to understanding many biological processes. To date, genetic tools for labeling neighboring cells in mammals are not available. Here, we developed a labeling strategy based on the Cre-induced intercellular labeling protein (CILP). Cre-expressing donor cells release a lipid-soluble and membrane-permeable fluorescent protein that is then taken up by recipient cells, enabling fluorescent labeling of neighboring cells. Using CILP, we specifically labeled endothelial cells surrounding a special population of hepatocytes in adult mice and revealed their distinct gene signatures. Our results highlight the potential of CILP as a platform to reveal cell-cell interactions and communications &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A researcher&#39;s guide to preclinical mouse NASH models</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/36539621/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/36539621/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Non-alcoholic fatty liver disease (NAFLD) and its inflammatory form, non-alcoholic steatohepatitis (NASH), have quickly risen to become the most prevalent chronic liver disease in the Western world and are risk factors for the development of hepatocellular carcinoma (HCC). HCC is not only one of the most common cancers but is also highly lethal. Nevertheless, there are currently no clinically approved drugs for NAFLD, and NASH-induced HCC poses a unique metabolic microenvironment that may influence responsiveness to certain treatments. Therefore, there is an urgent need to better understand the pathogenesis of this rampant disease to devise new therapies. In this line, preclinical mouse models are crucial tools to investigate mechanisms as well as novel treatment modalities during the pathogenesis of NASH and subsequent HCC in preparation for human clinical trials. Although, there are numerous genetically induced, diet-induced and toxin-induced models of NASH, not all of these models faithfully phenocopy and mirror the human pathology very well. In this Perspective, we shed some light onto the most widely used mouse models of NASH and highlight some of the key advantages and disadvantages of the various models with an emphasis on &amp;lsquo;Western diets&amp;rsquo;, which are increasingly recognized as some of the best models in recapitulating the human NASH pathology and comorbidities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>β-hydroxybutyrate inhibits ferroptosis-mediated pancreatic damage in acute liver failure through the increase of H3K9bhb</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36543135/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36543135/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ferroptosis contributes to pancreatic injury after acute liver failure (ALF)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;β-hydroxybutyrate (β-HB) restoration alleviates pancreatic injury after ALF&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;β-HB induces enrichment of H3K9bhb in the promotor regions of ferroptosis-suppressor genes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;β-HB regulates chromatin accessibility and mRNA expression of ferroptosis-suppressor genes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acute pancreatitis and hyperamylasemia are often seen in patients with acute liver failure (ALF). However, the underlying mechanisms remain elusive. This study describes pancreatic tissue damage and exocrine dysfunction in a mouse model of major-liver-resection-induced ALF. The analysis of 1,264 clinical cases of liver failure (LF) showed that the incidence of hyperamylasemia and hyperlipasemia in patients with LF is 5.5% and 20%, respectively. Metabolomic studies indicate that glutathione (GSH)-deficiency-caused ferroptosis contributes to pancreatic damage in mouse ALF. β-hydroxybutyrate (β-HB) is the only metabolite downregulated in the liver, serum, and pancreas. Our data suggest that β-HB protects pancreatic cells and tissues from GSH-deficiency-caused ferroptosis. β-HB administration in ALF mice restores the expression of ferroptosis-suppressor genes through histone H3 lysine 9 β-hydroxybutyrylation (H3K9bhb)-mediated chromatin opening. Our findings highlight β-HB as an endogenous metabolite regulating ferroptosis in the pancreas and extend our understanding of the pathophysiology of ALF-induced pancreatitis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hepatic neddylation deficiency triggers fatal liver injury via inducing NF-κB-inducing kinase in mice</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36526632/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36526632/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The conjugation of neural precursor cell expressed, developmentally downregulated 8 (NEDD8) to target proteins, termed neddylation, participates in many cellular processes and is aberrant in various pathological diseases. Its relevance to liver function and failure remains poorly understood. Herein, we show dysregulated expression of NAE1, a regulatory subunit of the only NEDD8 E1 enzyme, in human acute liver failure. Embryonic- and adult-onset deletion of NAE1 in hepatocytes causes hepatocyte death, inflammation, and fibrosis, culminating in fatal liver injury in mice. Hepatic neddylation deficiency triggers oxidative stress, mitochondrial dysfunction, and hepatocyte reprogramming, potentiating liver injury. Importantly, NF-κB-inducing kinase (NIK), a serine/Thr kinase, is a neddylation substrate. Neddylation of NIK promotes its ubiquitination and degradation. Inhibition of neddylation conversely causes aberrant NIK activation, accentuating hepatocyte damage and inflammation. Administration of N-acetylcysteine, a glutathione surrogate and antioxidant, mitigates liver failure caused by hepatic NAE1 deletion in adult male mice. Therefore, hepatic neddylation is important in maintaining postnatal and adult liver homeostasis, and the identified neddylation targets/pathways provide insights into therapeutically intervening acute liver failure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Heparan sulfate proteoglycan-mediated internalization of extracellular vesicles ameliorates liver fibrosis by targeting hepatic stellate cells</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/22-12-14-10-24/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/22-12-14-10-24/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Accumulating evidence shows that stem cell-derived extracellular vesicles (EVs) have shown great promise for tissue regeneration and are considered an alternative to cell-based therapy. However, the mechanisms by which EVs induce tissue repair have not been well demonstrated. Previous work indicates that activation of hepatic stellate cells (HSCs) may contribute to the progression of liver fibrosis. Here, we investigate the therapeutic potential of EVs derived from human placental mesenchymal stem cells (hP-MSCs) for the treatment of carbon tetrachloride (CCl4)-induced liver injury. Our data revealed that EVs derived from hP-MSCs effectively ameliorate liver injury by attenuating inflammation and fibrosis. Further data revealed that heparan sulfate proteoglycans (HSPGs) on the surface of HSCs mediate the internalization of EVs. Furthermore, EVs could inhibit the epithelial–mesenchymal transition (EMT) process in HSCs through the downregulated TGF-/Smad pathway, which was mediated by miR-744-5p in EVs. Meanwhile, glycosaminoglycans on the surface of EVs play a crucial anti-inflammatory role. In conclusion, our results provide evidence that hP-MSC-derived EVs promote the recovery of liver injury by targeting HSPGs on HSCs and inhibiting liver inflammation through glycosaminoglycans from EVs. These findings may provide a novel theoretical basis for the treatment of liver fibrosis based on EVs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Immune checkpoint therapy-elicited sialylation of IgG antibodies impairs antitumorigenic type I interferon responses in hepatocellular carcinoma</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36563676/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36563676/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ICB therapy catalyzes IgG sialylation in HCC that predicts an improved outcome&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Effector T cells trigger sialylated IgG via IFN-γ-ST6Gal-I-dependent pathways&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sialylated IgG binding to DC-SIGN abrogates macrophage type I IFN production&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Impeding IgG sialylation enhances antitumorigenic T cell immunity during ICB therapy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Summary&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reinvigoration of anti-tumor T cells in response to immune checkpoint blockade (ICB) therapy is well established. Whether and how ICB therapy manipulates antibody-mediated immune response in cancer environments, however, remains elusive. Using tandem mass spectrometric analysis of modification of immunoglobulin G (IgG) from hepatoma tissues, we identified a role of ICB therapy in catalyzing IgG sialylation in the Fc region. Effector T cells triggered sialylation of IgG via an interferon (IFN)-γ-ST6Gal-I-dependent pathway. DC-SIGN&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; macrophages represented the main target cells of sialylated IgG. Upon interacting with sialylated IgG, DC-SIGN stimulated Raf-1-elicited elevation of ATF3, which inactivated cGAS-STING pathway and eliminated subsequent type-I-IFN-triggered antitumorigenic immunity. Although enhanced IgG sialylation in tumors predicted improved therapeutic outcomes for patients receiving ICB therapy, impeding IgG sialylation augmented antitumorigenic T cell immunity after ICB therapy. Thus, targeting antibody-based negative feedback action of ICB therapy has potential for improving efficacy of cancer immunotherapies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PRDM1/BLIMP1 induces cancer immune evasion by modulating the USP22-SPI1-PD-L1 axis in hepatocellular carcinoma cells</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36509766/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36509766/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Programmed death receptor-1 (PD-1) blockade have achieved some efficacy but only in a fraction of patients with hepatocellular carcinoma (HCC). Programmed cell death 1 ligand 1 (PD-L1) binds to its receptor PD1 on T cells to dampen antigen-tumor immune responses. However, the mechanisms underlying PD-L1 regulation are not fully elucidated. Herein, we identify that tumoral &lt;em&gt;Prdm1&lt;/em&gt; overexpression inhibits cell growth in immune-deficient mouse models. Further, tumoral &lt;em&gt;Prdm1&lt;/em&gt; overexpression upregulates PD-L1 levels, dampening anti-tumor immunity in vivo, and neutralizes the anti-tumor efficacy of &lt;em&gt;Prdm1&lt;/em&gt; overexpression in immune-competent mouse models. Mechanistically, &lt;em&gt;PRDM1&lt;/em&gt; enhances &lt;em&gt;USP22&lt;/em&gt; transcription, thus reducing &lt;em&gt;SPI1&lt;/em&gt; protein degradation through deubiquitination, which enhances &lt;em&gt;PD-L1&lt;/em&gt; transcription. Functionally, PD-1 mAb treatment reinforces the efficacy of &lt;em&gt;Prdm1&lt;/em&gt;-overexpressing HCC immune-competent mouse models. Collectively, we demonstrate that the PRDM1-USP22-SPI1 axis regulates PD-L1 levels, resulting in infiltrated CD8&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T cell exhaustion. Furthermore, &lt;em&gt;PRDM1&lt;/em&gt; overexpression combined with PD-(L)1 mAb treatment provides a therapeutic strategy for HCC treatment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prolonged hypernutrition impairs TREM2-dependent efferocytosis to license chronic liver inflammation and NASH development</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36521495/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36521495/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;TREM2-dependent macrophage efferocytosis maintains immune homeostasis in the fatty liver&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hepatocyte-derived S1P upregulates TREM2 in infiltrated liver macrophages&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Persistent obesity causes TREM2 shedding via TNF and IL-1β-induced proteolytic cleavage&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Loss of TREM2 disables efferocytosis to license chronic liver inflammation and NASH&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Summary&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Obesity-induced chronic liver inflammation is a hallmark of nonalcoholic steatohepatitis (NASH)—an aggressive form of nonalcoholic fatty liver disease. However, it remains unclear how such a low-grade, yet persistent, inflammation is sustained in the liver. Here, we show that the macrophage phagocytic receptor TREM2, induced by hepatocyte-derived sphingosine-1-phosphate, was required for efferocytosis of lipid-laden apoptotic hepatocytes and thereby maintained liver immune homeostasis. However, prolonged hypernutrition led to the production of proinflammatory cytokines TNF and IL-1β in the liver to induce TREM2 shedding through ADAM17-dependent proteolytic cleavage. Loss of TREM2 resulted in aberrant accumulation of dying hepatocytes, thereby further augmenting proinflammatory cytokine production. This ultimately precipitated a vicious cycle that licensed chronic inflammation to drive simple steatosis transition to NASH. Therefore, impaired macrophage efferocytosis is a previously unrecognized key pathogenic event that enables chronic liver inflammation in obesity. Blocking TREM2 cleavage to restore efferocytosis may represent an effective strategy to treat NASH.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Common mechanisms in pediatric acute liver failure</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/36496278/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/36496278/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;n 2022 an epidemic of acute hepatitis causing ALF, which affected children aged &amp;lt;5 years, has drawn attention to the lack of knowledge regarding the pathogenesis of ALF.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Most children with ALF during this epidemic were positive for human adenovirus and adeno-associated virus 2 (AAV2), neither of which is typically linked to ALF in immunocompetent children.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Children with mutations in genes that form part of the ISR (e.g., PERK) can develop ALF in response to non-hepatotropic viruses.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Activity in the innate immune system is potentiated by factors derived from the intestinal microbiome and is dependent on Myc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Regulation of p53 activity is important for determining the balance of hepatocyte senescence and therefore the ability to regenerate during ALF.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acute liver failure (ALF) is a rare but potentially fatal disease in children. The etiology is multifactorial, including infection, autoimmune, and genetic disorders, as well as indeterminate hepatitis, which has a higher requirement for liver transplantation. Activation of the innate and adaptive immune systems leads to hepatocyte-specific injury which is mitigated by T regulatory cell activation. Recovery of the native liver depends on activation of apoptotic and regenerative pathways, including the integrated stress response (ISR; e.g., PERK), p53, and HNF4α. Loss-of-function mutations in these pathways cause recurrent ALF in response to non-hepatotropic viruses. Deeper understanding of these mechanisms will lead to improved diagnosis, management, and outcomes for pediatric ALF.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HTLV-1 infection of donor-derived T cells might promote acute graft-versus-host disease following liver transplantation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36450748/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36450748/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acute graft versus host disease (aGVHD) is a rare, but severe complication of liver transplantation (LT). It is caused by the activation of donor immune cells in the graft against the host shortly after transplantation, but the contributing pathogenic factors remain unclear. Here we show that human T cell lymphotropic virus type I (HTLV-1) infection of donor T cells is highly associated with aGVHD following LT. The presence of HTLV-1 in peripheral blood and tissue samples from a discovery cohort of 7 aGVHD patients and 17 control patients is assessed with hybridization probes (TargetSeq), mass cytometry (CyTOF), and multiplex immunohistology (IMC). All 7 of our aGVHD patients display detectable HTLV-1 Tax signals by IMC. We identify donor-derived cells based on a Y chromosome-specific genetic marker, EIF1AY. Thus, we confirm the presence of CD4+Tax+EIF1AY+ T cells and Tax+CD68+EIF1AY+ antigen-presenting cells, indicating HTLV-1 infection of donor immune cells. In an independent cohort of 400 patients, we verify that HTLV-1 prevalence correlates with aGVHD incidence, while none of the control viruses shows significant associations. Our findings thus provide new insights into the aetio-pathology of liver-transplantation-associated aGVHD and raise the possibility of preventing aGVHD prior to transplantation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IL6 supports long-term expansion of hepatocytes in vitro</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36446858/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36446858/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hepatocytes are very difficult to expand in vitro. A few studies have demonstrated that chemical cocktails with growth factors or Wnt ligands can support long-term expansion of hepatocytes via dedifferentiation. However, the culture conditions are complex, and clonal expansion of hepatic progenitors with full differentiation capacity are rarely reported. Here, we discover IL6, combined with EGF and HGF, promotes long-term expansion (&amp;gt;30 passages in ~150 days with theoretical expansion of ~1035 times) of primary mouse hepatocytes in vitro in simple 2D culture, by converting hepatocytes into induced hepatic progenitor cells (iHPCs), which maintain the capacity of differentiation into hepatocytes. IL6 also supports the establishment of single hepatocyte-derived iHPC clones. The summation of the downstream STAT3, ERK and AKT pathways induces a number of transcription factors which support rapid growth. This physiological and simple way may provide ideas for culturing previously difficult-to-culture cell types and support their future applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integrated multi-omics Landscape of liver metastases</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36574521/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36574521/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;BACKGROUND &amp;amp; AIMS&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lack of thorough knowledge for complicated immune-microenvironment (IM) within a variety of liver metastases (LMs) leads to inappropriate treatment and unsatisfactory prognosis. We aimed to characterize IM subtypes and investigate potential mechanisms in LMs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;METHODS&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mass cytometry was applied to characterize immune landscape of primary liver cancers and liver metastases cohort. Transcriptomic and whole exome sequencing were used to explore potential mechanisms across distinct IM subtypes. Single cell transcriptomic sequencing, multiplex fluorescent immunohistochemistry, cell culture, mouse model, western blot, quantitative polymerase chain reaction and immunohistochemistry were used for validation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;RESULTS&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Five IM subtypes were revealed in 100 LMs and 50 primary liver cancers. Patients featured terminally exhausted (IM1) or rare-T-cell-inflamed (IM2 and IM3) immune characteristics showed worse outcome. Increased intra-tumor heterogeneity, enriched somatic TP53, KRAS, APC, PIK3CA mutations and hyper-activated hypoxia signaling accounted for the formation of vicious subtypes. SLC2A1 promoted immune suppression and desert via increasing proportion of Spp1&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; macrophages and their inhibitory interactions with T cells in liver metastatic lesions. Furthermore, SLC2A1 promoted immune escape and liver metastasis through inducing regulatory T cells including Tregs and LAG3&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt;CD4&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T cells in primary colorectal cancer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;CONCLUSION&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The study provided integrated multi-omics landscape of liver metastasis, uncovering potential mechanisms for vicious IM subtypes and confirming the roles of SLC2A1 in regulating tumor microenvironment remodeling in both primary tumor and liver metastatic lesions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SENP1 prevents steatohepatitis by suppressing RIPK1-driven apoptosis and inflammation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36414671/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36414671/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Activation of RIPK1-driven cell death and inflammation play important roles in the progression of nonalcoholic steatohepatitis (NASH). However, the mechanism underlying RIPK1 activation in NASH remains unclear. Here we identified SENP1, a SUMO-specific protease, as a key endogenous inhibitor of RIPK1. SENP1 is progressively reduced in proportion to NASH severity in patients. Hepatocyte-specific SENP1-knockout mice develop spontaneous NASH-related phenotypes in a RIPK1 kinase-dependent manner. We demonstrate that SENP1 deficiency sensitizes cells to RIPK1 kinase-dependent apoptosis by promoting RIPK1 activation following TNFα stimulation. Mechanistically, SENP1 deSUMOylates RIPK1 in TNF-R1 signaling complex (TNF-RSC), keeping RIPK1 in check. Loss of SENP1 leads to SUMOylation of RIPK1, which re-orchestrates TNF-RSC and modulates the ubiquitination patterns and activity of RIPK1. Notably, genetic inhibition of RIPK1 effectively reverses disease progression in hepatocyte-specific SENP1-knockout male mice with high-fat-diet-induced nonalcoholic fatty liver. We propose that deSUMOylation of RIPK1 by SENP1 provides a pathophysiologically relevant cell death-restricting checkpoint that modulates RIPK1 activation in the pathogenesis of nonalcoholic steatohepatitis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A human kidney and liver organoid-based multi-organ-on-a-chip model to study the therapeutic effects and biodistribution of mesenchymal stromal cell-derived extracellular vesicles</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36382606/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36382606/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mesenchymal stromal cell (MSC)-derived small extracellular vesicles (sEVs) show therapeutic potential in multiple disease models, including kidney injury. Clinical translation of sEVs requires further preclinical and regulatory developments, including elucidation of the biodistribution and mode of action (MoA). Biodistribution can be determined using labelled sEVs in animal models which come with ethical concerns, are time-consuming and expensive, and may not well represent human physiology. We hypothesised that, based on developments in microfluidics and human organoid technology, in vitro multi-organ-on-a-chip (MOC) models allow us to study effects of sEVs in modelled human organs like kidney and liver in a semi-systemic manner. Human kidney- and liver organoids combined by microfluidic channels maintained physiological functions, and a kidney injury model was established using hydrogenperoxide. MSC-sEVs were isolated, and their size, density and potential contamination were analysed. These sEVs stimulated recovery of the renal epithelium after injury. Microscopic analysis shows increased accumulation of PKH67-labelled sEVs not only in injured kidney cells, but also in the unharmed liver organoids, compared to healthy control conditions. In conclusion, this new MOC model recapitulates therapeutic efficacy and biodistribution of MSC-sEVs as observed in animal models. Its human background allows for in-depth analysis of the MoA and identification of potential side effects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In vivo partial reprogramming by bacteria promotes adult liver organ growth without fibrosis and tumorigenesis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36384103/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36384103/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ideal therapies for regenerative medicine or healthy aging require healthy organ growth and rejuvenation, but no organ-level approach is currently available. Using Mycobacterium leprae (ML) with natural partial cellular reprogramming capacity and its animal host nine-banded armadillos, we present an evolutionarily refined model of adult liver growth and regeneration. In infected armadillos, ML reprogram the entire liver and significantly increase total liver/body weight ratio by increasing healthy liver lobules, including hepatocyte proliferation and proportionate expansion of vasculature, and biliary systems. ML-infected livers are microarchitecturally and functionally normal without damage, fibrosis, or tumorigenesis. Bacteria-induced reprogramming reactivates liver progenitor/developmental/fetal genes and upregulates growth-, metabolism-, and anti-aging-associated markers with minimal change in senescence and tumorigenic genes, suggesting bacterial hijacking of homeostatic, regeneration pathways to promote de novo organogenesis. This may facilitate the unraveling of endogenous pathways that effectively and safely re-engage liver organ growth, with broad therapeutic implications including organ regeneration and rejuvenation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Liver tumour immune microenvironment subtypes and neutrophil heterogeneity</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36352227/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36352227/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The heterogeneity of the tumour immune microenvironment (TIME), organized by various immune and stromal cells, is a major contributing factor of tumour metastasis, relapse and drug resistance1-3, but how different TIME subtypes are connected to the clinical relevance in liver cancer remains unclear. Here we performed single-cell RNA-sequencing (scRNA-seq) analysis of 189 samples collected from 124 patients and 8 mice with liver cancer. With more than 1 million cells analysed, we stratified patients into five TIME subtypes, including immune activation, immune suppression mediated by myeloid or stromal cells, immune exclusion and immune residence phenotypes. Different TIME subtypes were spatially organized and associated with chemokine networks and genomic features. Notably, tumour-associated neutrophil (TAN) populations enriched in the myeloid-cell-enriched subtype were associated with an unfavourable prognosis. Through in vitro induction of TANs and ex vivo analyses of patient TANs, we showed that CCL4&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; TANs can recruit macrophages and that PD-L1&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; TANs can suppress T cell cytotoxicity. Furthermore, scRNA-seq analysis of mouse neutrophil subsets revealed that they are largely conserved with those of humans. In vivo neutrophil depletion in mouse models attenuated tumour progression, confirming the pro-tumour phenotypes of TANs. With this detailed cellular heterogeneity landscape of liver cancer, our study illustrates diverse TIME subtypes, highlights immunosuppressive functions of TANs and sheds light on potential immunotherapies targeting TANs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The microbiota and the gut-liver axis in primary sclerosing cholangitis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/36352157/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/36352157/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Primary sclerosing cholangitis (PSC) offers unique opportunities to explore the gut-liver axis owing to the close association between liver disease and colonic inflammation. It is well established that the gut microbiota in people with PSC differs from that of healthy individuals, but details of the microbial factors that demarcate PSC from inflammatory bowel disease (IBD) without PSC are poorly understood. In this Review, we aim to provide an overview of the latest literature on the gut microbiome in PSC and PSC with IBD, critically examining hypotheses on how microorganisms could contribute to the pathogenesis of PSC. A particular emphasis will be put on pathogenic features of the gut microbiota that might explain the occurrence of bile duct inflammation and liver disease in the context of IBD, and we postulate the potential existence of a specific yet unknown factor related to the gut-liver axis as causative in PSC. Available data are scrutinized in the perspective of therapeutic approaches related to the gut-liver axis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ferroptosis inhibitor liproxstatin-1 alleviates metabolic dysfunction-associated fatty liver disease in mice: potential involvement of PANoptosis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36323829/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36323829/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ferroptosis is a new form of regulated cell death characterized by excessive iron accumulation and uncontrollable lipid peroxidation. The role of ferroptosis in metabolic dysfunction-associated fatty liver disease (MAFLD) is not fully elucidated. In this study we compared the therapeutic effects of ferroptosis inhibitor liproxstatin-1 (LPT1) and iron chelator deferiprone (DFP) in MAFLD mouse models. This model was established in mice by feeding a high-fat diet with 30% fructose in water (HFHF) for 16 weeks. The mice then received LPT1 (10 mg·kg&lt;sup&gt;-1&lt;/sup&gt;·d&lt;sup&gt;-1&lt;/sup&gt;, ip) or DFP (100 mg·kg&lt;sup&gt;-1&lt;/sup&gt;·d&lt;sup&gt;-1&lt;/sup&gt;, ig) for another 2 weeks. We showed that both LPT1 and DFP treatment blocked the ferroptosis markers ACSL4 and ALOX15 in MAFLD mice. Furthermore, LPT1 treatment significantly reduced the liver levels of triglycerides and cholesterol, lipid peroxidation markers 4-hydroxynonenal (4-HNE) and malondialdehyde (MDA), and ameliorated the expression of lipid synthesis/oxidation genes (Pparα, Scd1, Fasn, Hmgcr and Cpt1a), insulin resistance, mitochondrial ROS content and liver fibrosis. Importantly, LPT1 treatment potently inhibited hepatic apoptosis (Bax/Bcl-xL ratio and TUNEL+ cell number), pyroptosis (cleavages of Caspase-1 and GSDMD) and necroptosis (phosphorylation of MLKL). Moreover, LPT1 treatment markedly inhibited cleavages of PANoptosis-related caspase-8 and caspase-6 in MAFLD mouse liver. In an in vitro MAFLD model, treatment with LPT1 (100 nM) prevented cultured hepatocyte against cell death induced by pro-PANoptosis molecules (TNF-α, LPS and nigericin) upon lipid stress. On the contrary, DFP treatment only mildly attenuated hepatic inflammation but failed to alleviate lipid deposition, insulin resistance, apoptosis, pyroptosis and necroptosis in MAFLD mice. We conclude that ferroptosis inhibitor LPT1 protects against steatosis and steatohepatitis in MAFLD mice, which may involve regulation of PANoptosis, a coordinated cell death pathway that involves apoptosis, pyroptosis and necroptosis. These results suggest a potential link between ferroptosis and PANoptosis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Long-Term Dietary Lycium ruthenicum Murr. Anthocyanins Intake Alleviated Oxidative Stress-Mediated Aging-Related Liver Injury and Abnormal Amino Acid Metabolism</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36359989/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36359989/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In recent years, the relationship between Lycium ruthenicum Murr. anthocyanins (LRA) and health has attracted increasing attention. The purpose of this study is to investigate the anti-aging effect and mechanism of LRA through a D-galactose (DG)-induced aging rat model. Our results showed that the long-term intake of LRA, for 8 weeks, improved motor function, reduced serum aging markers, promoted the endogenous antioxidant system, and suppressed the serum inflammatory cytokines in aging rats. Besides, the LRA treatment alleviated DG-induced liver injuries by relieving the inflammation and inhibiting Fas/FasL-mediated cell death. More importantly, the abnormal serum metabolome profiles of the aging rats were restored by the LRA, relating to 38 metabolites and 44 pathways. Specifically, the LRA significantly affected the amino acid and protein-related metabolic pathways by regulating the levels of L-threonine, L-aspartic acid, glycine, L-histidine, D-homocysteine, L-homocitrulline, L-homoserine, guanidineacetic acid, and kynurenine. These results have important implications for the development of LRA as an anti-aging and liver-protective ingredient.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multiomics study of nonalcoholic fatty liver disease</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36280732/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36280732/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nonalcoholic fatty liver (NAFL) and its sequelae are growing health problems. We performed a genome-wide association study of NAFL, cirrhosis and hepatocellular carcinoma, and integrated the findings with expression and proteomic data. For NAFL, we utilized 9,491 clinical cases and proton density fat fraction extracted from 36,116 liver magnetic resonance images. We identified 18 sequence variants associated with NAFL and 4 with cirrhosis, and found rare, protective, predicted loss-of-function variants in MTARC1 and GPAM, underscoring them as potential drug targets. We leveraged messenger RNA expression, splicing and predicted coding effects to identify 16 putative causal genes, of which many are implicated in lipid metabolism. We analyzed levels of 4,907 plasma proteins in 35,559 Icelanders and 1,459 proteins in 47,151 UK Biobank participants, identifying multiple proteins involved in disease pathogenesis. We show that proteomics can discriminate between NAFL and cirrhosis. The present study provides insights into the development of noninvasive evaluation of NAFL and new therapeutic options.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gut bacteria alleviate smoking-related NASH by degrading gut nicotine</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36261549/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36261549/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tobacco smoking is positively correlated with non-alcoholic fatty liver disease (NAFLD), but the underlying mechanism for this association is unclear. Here we report that nicotine accumulates in the intestine during tobacco smoking and activates intestinal AMPKα. We identify the gut bacterium Bacteroides xylanisolvens as an effective nicotine degrader. Colonization of B.xylanisolvens reduces intestinal nicotine concentrations in nicotine-exposed mice, and it improves nicotine-exacerbated NAFLD progression. Mechanistically, AMPKα promotes the phosphorylation of sphingomyelin phosphodiesterase 3 (SMPD3), stabilizing the latter and therefore increasing intestinal ceramide formation, which contributes to NAFLD progression to non-alcoholic steatohepatitis (NASH). Our results establish a role for intestinal nicotine accumulation in NAFLD progression and reveal an endogenous bacterium in the human intestine with the ability to metabolize nicotine. These findings suggest a possible route to reduce tobacco smoking-exacerbated NAFLD progression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two circPPFIA1s negatively regulate liver metastasis of colon cancer via miR-155-5p/CDX1 and HuR/RAB36</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36224588/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36224588/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Circular RNAs (circRNAs) play a critical role in colorectal cancer (CRC) progression, including metastasis. However, the detailed molecular mechanism is not fully understood.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; Differentially expressed circRNAs between primary KM12C and liver metastatic KM12L4 colon cancer cells were identified by microarray. The expression of circRNAs was measured by semi-quantitative (semi-qPCR) and real time-quantitative PCR (RT-qPCR). Metastatic potential including invasive and migratory abilities, and liver metastasis were examined by transwell assays and intrasplenic injection, respectively. CircPPFIA1-associated microRNA (miRNA) and RNA-binding protein (RBP) were screened by an antisense oligonucleotide (ASO) pulldown experiment. The effects of circPPFIA1 on target gene expression were evaluated by RT-qPCR and western blot analyses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; By analyzing circRNA microarray data, we identified two anti-metastatic circRNAs generated from PPFIA1 with different length, which named circPPFIA1-L (long) and -S (short). They were significantly downregulated in liver metastatic KM12L4 cells compared to primary KM12C cells. The knockdown of circPPFIA1s in KM12C enhanced metastatic potential and increased liver metastasis. Conversely, overexpression of circPPFIA1s weakened metastatic potential and inhibited liver metastasis. circPPFIA1s were found to function as sponges of oncogenic miR-155-5p and Hu antigen R (HuR) by an ASO pulldown experiment. circPPFIA1s upregulated tumor-suppressing CDX1 expression and conversely downregulated oncogenic RAB36 by decoying miR-155-5p and by sequestering HuR, respectively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/em&gt; Our findings demonstrate that circPPFIA1s inhibit the liver metastasis of CRC via the miR-155-5p/CDX1 and HuR/RAB36 pathways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Single-cell spatial transcriptomics reveals a dynamic control of metabolic zonation and liver regeneration by endothelial cell Wnt2 and Wnt9b</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36220068/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36220068/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Conserved expression of Wnt2 and Wnt9b in liver endothelial cells is identified&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wnt2 and Wnt9b deletion from endothelial cells affects gene expression in zone 3&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Endothelial Wnt2 and Wnt9b deletion affects liver regeneration after hepatectomy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Late treatment with Wnt agonist rescues regeneration after acetaminophen overdose&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Summary&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The conclusive identity of Wnts regulating liver zonation (LZ) and regeneration (LR) remains unclear despite an undisputed role of β-catenin. Using single-cell analysis, we identified a conserved Wnt2 and Wnt9b expression in endothelial cells (ECs) in zone 3. EC-elimination of Wnt2 and Wnt9b led to both loss of β-catenin targets in zone 3, and re-appearance of zone 1 genes in zone 3, unraveling dynamicity in the LZ process. Impaired LR observed in the knockouts phenocopied models of defective hepatic Wnt signaling. Administration of a tetravalent antibody to activate Wnt signaling rescued LZ and LR in the knockouts and induced zone 3 gene expression and LR in controls. Administration of the agonist also promoted LR in acetaminophen overdose acute liver failure (ALF) fulfilling an unmet clinical need. Overall, we report an unequivocal role of EC-Wnt2 and Wnt9b in LZ and LR and show the role of Wnt activators as regenerative therapy for ALF.
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CircPAK1 promotes the progression of hepatocellular carcinoma via modulation of YAP nucleus localization by interacting with 14-3-3ζ</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36131287/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36131287/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Circular RNA (circRNA), a new class of non-coding RNA, has obvious correlations with the occurrence and development of many diseases, including tumors. This study aimed to investigate the potential roles of circPAK1 in hepatocellular carcinoma (HCC).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; High-throughput sequencing was performed on 3 pairs of HCC and matched normal tissues to determine the upregulated circRNAs. The expression level of circPAK1 was detected by qRT-PCR in HCC and paired with normal liver tissue samples. The effects of circPAK1 on proliferation, invasion, metastasis and apoptosis of HCC cells were evaluated by in vitro and in vivo experiments. We also constructed Chitosan/si-circPAK1 (CS/si-circPAK1) nanocomplexes using Chitosan material to evaluate its in vivo therapeutic effect on HCC. High-throughput sequencing, RNA-sequencing, RNA probe pull-down, RNA immunoprecipitation and Co-Immunoprecipitation assays were performed to explore the relationship between circPAK1, 14-3-3ζ, p-LATS1 and YAP. Exosomes isolated from lenvatinib-resistant HCC cell lines were used to evaluate the relationship between exosomal circPAK1 and lenvatinib resistance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; CircPAK1, a novel circRNA, is highly expressed in HCC tumor tissues and cell lines as well as correlated with poor outcomes in HCC patients. Functionally, circPAK1 knockdown inhibited HCC cell proliferation, migration, invasion and angiogenesis while circPAK1 overexpression promoted HCC progression. The tumor-promoting phenotypes of circPAK1 on HCC were also confirmed by animal experiments. Importantly, the application of CS/si-circPAK1 nanocomplexes showed a better therapeutic effect on tumor growth and metastasis. Mechanistically, circPAK1 enhanced HCC progression by inactivating the Hippo signaling pathway, and this kind of inactivation is based on its competitively binding of 14-3-3 ζ with YAP, which weakens the recruitment and cytoplasmic fixation of 14-3-3 ζ to YAP, thus promoting YAP nucleus localization. Additionally, circPAK1 could be transported by exosomes from lenvatinib-resistant cells to sensitive cells and induce lenvatinib resistance of receipt cells.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/em&gt; CircPAK1 exerts its oncogenic function by competitively binding 14-3-3 ζ with YAP, thus promoting YAP nucleus localization, leading to the inactivation of a Hippo signaling pathway. Exosomal circPAK1 may drive resistance to lenvatinib, providing a potential therapeutic target for HCC patients.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Liver-heart cross-talk mediated by coagulation factor XI protects against heart failure</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36137043/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36137043/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tissue-tissue communication by endocrine factors is a vital mechanism for physiologic homeostasis. A systems genetics analysis of transcriptomic and functional data from a cohort of diverse, inbred strains of mice predicted that coagulation factor XI (FXI), a liver-derived protein, protects against diastolic dysfunction, a key trait of heart failure with preserved ejection fraction. This was confirmed using gain- and loss-of-function studies, and FXI was found to activate the bone morphogenetic protein (BMP)-SMAD1/5 pathway in the heart. The proteolytic activity of FXI is required for the cleavage and activation of extracellular matrix-associated BMP7 in the heart, thus inhibiting genes involved in inflammation and fibrosis. Our results reveal a protective role of FXI in heart injury that is distinct from its role in coagulation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exosome-mediated delivery of Cas9 ribonucleoprotein complexes for tissue-specific gene therapy of liver diseases</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36103526/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36103526/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CRISPR-Cas9 gene editing has emerged as a powerful therapeutic technology, but the lack of safe and efficient in vivo delivery systems, especially for tissue-specific vectors, limits its broad clinical applications. Delivery of Cas9 ribonucleoprotein (RNP) owns competitive advantages over other options; however, the large size of RNPs exceeds the loading capacity of currently available delivery vectors. Here, we report a previously unidentified genome editing delivery system, named exosome&lt;sup&gt;RNP&lt;/sup&gt;, in which Cas9 RNPs were loaded into purified exosomes isolated from hepatic stellate cells through electroporation. Exosome&lt;sup&gt;RNP&lt;/sup&gt; facilitated effective cytosolic delivery of RNP in vitro while specifically accumulated in the liver tissue in vivo. Exosome&lt;sup&gt;RNP&lt;/sup&gt; showed vigorous therapeutic potential in acute liver injury, chronic liver fibrosis, and hepatocellular carcinoma mouse models via targeting p53 up-regulated modulator of apoptosis (&lt;em&gt;PUMA&lt;/em&gt;), cyclin E1 (&lt;em&gt;CcnE1&lt;/em&gt;), and K (lysine) acetyltransferase 5 (&lt;em&gt;KAT5&lt;/em&gt;), respectively. The developed exosomeRNP provides a feasible platform for precise and tissue-specific gene therapies of liver diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FOXO3 mutation predicting gefitinib-induced hepatotoxicity in NSCLC patients through regulation of autophagy</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36176901/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36176901/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hepatotoxicity is a common side effect for patients treated with gefitinib, but the related pathogenesis is unclear and lacks effective predictor and management strategies. A multi-omics approach integrating pharmacometabolomics, pharmacokinetics and pharmacogenomics was employed in non-small cell lung cancer patients to identify the effective predictor for gefitinib-induced hepatotoxicity and explore optional therapy substitution. Here, we found that patients with rs4946935 AA, located in Forkhead Box O3 (&lt;em&gt;FOXO3&lt;/em&gt;) which is a well-known autophagic regulator, had a higher risk of hepatotoxicity than those with the GA or GG variant (OR = 18.020, 95%CI = 2.473 to 459.1784, P = 0.018) in a gefitinib-concentration dependent pattern. Furthermore, functional experiments identified that rs4946935_A impaired the expression of &lt;em&gt;FOXO3&lt;/em&gt; by inhibiting the promotor activity, increasing the threshold of autophagy initiation and inhibiting the autophagic activity which contributed to gefitinib-induced liver injury. In contrast, erlotinib-induced liver injury was independent on the variant and expression levels of &lt;em&gt;FOXO3&lt;/em&gt;. This study reveals that &lt;em&gt;FOXO3&lt;/em&gt; mutation, leading to autophagic imbalance, plays important role in gefitinib-induced hepatotoxicity, especially for patients with high concentration of gefitinib. In conclusion, &lt;em&gt;FOXO3&lt;/em&gt; mutation is an effective predictor and erlotinib might be an appropriately and well-tolerated treatment option for patients carrying rs4946935 AA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extracellular vesicles from colorectal cancer cells promote metastasis via the NOD1 signalling pathway</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36068649/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36068649/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pattern-recognition receptors (PRRs) have been shown to promote tumour metastasis via sensing tumour cell-derived small extracellular vesicles (EVs). Nucleotide-binding oligomerisation domain 1 (NOD1), a cytoplasmic PRR, plays a role in colorectal cancer (CRC) by detecting bacterial products. However, the precise mechanisms underlying the effects of NOD1, following identification of CRC cell-derived EVs (CRC-EVs), to potentiate CRC liver metastasis (CRC-LM), remain poorly understood. Here, we demonstrate that CRC-EVs activate NOD1 in macrophages to initiate secretion of inflammatory cytokines and chemokines. NOD1-activated macrophages also promote CRC cell migration, while in a murine model of liver metastasis (LM), NOD1-deficient mice exhibit reduced metastasis following CRC-EV treatment. Furthermore, cell division cycle 42 (CDC42), a small Rho guanosine-5&amp;rsquo;-triphosphate (GTP)ase, is delivered by CRC-EVs into macrophages where it activates NOD1. In addition, EVs from the plasma of patients with CRC-LM mediate NOD1 activation in human peripheral blood mononuclear cells. Moreover, high NOD1 expression in tumour tissues is associated with poor prognosis of CRC-LM. Our findings suggest that CRC-EVs activate NOD1 to promote tumour metastasis, thus, NOD1 may serve as a potential target in the diagnosis and treatment of CRC-LM.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sirtuin 6 protects against hepatic fibrogenesis by suppressing the YAP and TAZ function</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36036554/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36036554/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Erratum in:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Erratum to &lt;a href=&#34;https://faseb.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1096/fsb2.22572&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sirtuin 6 protects against hepatic fibrogenesis by suppressing the YAP and TAZ function&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hepatic fibrosis occurs in response to prolonged tissue injury in the liver, which results in abnormal accumulation of extracellular matrix. Hepatic stellate cells (HSCs) have been suggested to play a major role in liver fibrosis. However, the molecular mechanisms remain incompletely understood. Sirtuin 6 (SIRT6), an NAD+ -dependent deacetylase, has been previously implicated in the regulation of the transforming growth factor β (TGFβ)-SMAD3 pathway that plays a significant role in liver fibrosis. In this work, we aimed to identify other important players during hepatic fibrogenesis, which are modulated by SIRT6. Yes-associated protein (YAP) and transcriptional coactivator with PDZ-binding motif (TAZ or WWTR1), key players in the Hippo pathway, have been implicated in the promotion of hepatic fibrosis. Our data show that HSC-specific Sirt6 knockout mice are more susceptible to high-fat-cholesterol-cholate diet-induced hepatic fibrosis than their wildtype counterparts. Our signaling analyses suggest that in addition to the TGFβ-SMAD3 pathway, YAP and TAZ are also highly activated in the SIRT6-deficient HSCs. As it is not clear how SIRT6 might regulate YAP and TAZ, we have decided to elucidate the mechanism underlying the regulation of YAP and TAZ by SIRT6 in HSCs. Overexpression or knockdown of SIRT6 corroborates the role of SIRT6 in the negative regulation of YAP and TAZ. Further biochemical analyses reveal that SIRT6 deacetylates YAP and TAZ and reprograms the composition of the TEA domain transcription factor complex to suppress their downstream target genes, particularly those involved in hepatic fibrosis. In conclusion, our data suggest that SIRT6 plays a critical role in the regulation of the Hippo pathway to protect against hepatic fibrosis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Long non-coding RNA SNHG6 couples cholesterol sensing with mTORC1 activation in hepatocellular carcinoma</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35995997/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35995997/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Erratum in:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Publisher Correction: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nature.com/articles/s42255-022-00650-5&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Long non-coding RNA SNHG6 couples cholesterol sensing with mTORC1 activation in hepatocellular carcinoma&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cholesterol contributes to the structural basis of biological membranes and functions as a signaling molecule, whose dysregulation has been associated with various human diseases. Here, we report that the long non-coding RNA (lncRNA) SNHG6 increases progression from non-alcoholic fatty liver disease (NAFLD) to hepatocellular carcinoma (HCC) by modulating cholesterol-induced mTORC1 activation. Mechanistically, cholesterol binds ER-anchored FAF2 protein to promote the formation of a SNHG6-FAF2-mTOR complex. As a putative cholesterol effector, SNHG6 enhances cholesterol-dependent mTORC1 lysosomal recruitment and activation via enhancing FAF2-mTOR interaction at ER-lysosome contacts, thereby coordinating mTORC1 kinase cascade activation with cellular cholesterol biosynthesis in a self-amplified cycle to accelerate cholesterol-driven NAFLD-HCC development. Notably, loss of SNHG6 inhibits mTORC1 signaling and impairs growth of patient-derived xenograft liver cancer tumors, identifyifng SNHG6 as a potential target for liver cancer treatment. Together, our findings illustrate the crucial role of organelle-associated lncRNA in organelle communication, nutrient sensing, and kinase cascades.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Circular RNA circSFMBT2 downregulation by HBx promotes hepatocellular carcinoma metastasis via the miR-665/TIMP3 axis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36159591/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36159591/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hepatitis B virus X protein (HBx) is considered as an oncogene in tumorigenesis and progression of hepatocellular carcinoma (HCC). In recent years, the important role of circular RNAs (circRNAs) in HCC has been increasingly demonstrated. However, the regulatory mechanisms of HBx on circRNAs remains largely unknown. In this study, we identified that a novel circRNA, circSFMBT2, was markedly downregulated by HBx. Low expression of circSFMBT2 was correlated with poor prognosis and vascular invasion. Functionally, overexpression of circSFMBT2 significantly inhibited HCC metastasis both in vitro and in vivo. The mechanism of circSFMBT2 was to as a sponge of miR-665, which is a negative regulator of tissue inhibitor of metalloproteinases 3 (TIMP3). However, HBx downregulated circSFMBT2 via the interaction with DExH-box helicase 9 (DHX9), which binds to flanking circRNA-forming introns. In conclusion, circSFMBT2, which is downregulated by HBx, acts as a tumor suppressor to inhibit tumor metastasis through the miR-665/TIMP3 axis. Our study suggests that circSFMBT2 could be a potential prognostic biomarker and therapeutic target for HCC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lgr5 &#43; cell fate regulation by coordination of metabolic nuclear receptors during liver repair</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36168631/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36168631/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Leucine-rich repeat-containing G protein-coupled receptor 5 (&lt;em&gt;Lgr5&lt;/em&gt;) is a target gene of Wnt/β-Catenin which plays a vital role in hepatic development and regeneration. However, the regulation of &lt;em&gt;Lgr5&lt;/em&gt; gene and the fate of &lt;em&gt;Lgr5&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; cells in hepatic physiology and pathology are little known. This study aims to clarify the effect of metabolic nuclear receptors on &lt;em&gt;Lgr5&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; cell fate in liver.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; We performed cell experiments with primary hepatocytes, Hep 1-6, Hep G2, and Huh 7 cells, and animal studies with wild-type (WT), farnesoid X receptor (FXR) knockout mice, peroxisome proliferator-activated receptor α (PPARα) knockout mice and &lt;em&gt;Lgr5&lt;/em&gt;-Cre&lt;sup&gt;ERT2&lt;/sup&gt;; Rosa26-mTmG mice. GW4064 and CDCA were used to activate FXR. And GW7647 or Wy14643 was used for PPARα activation. Regulation of &lt;em&gt;Lgr5&lt;/em&gt; by FXR and PPARα was determined by QRT-PCR, western blot (WB) and RNAscope® &lt;em&gt;in situ&lt;/em&gt; hybridization (ISH) and immunofluorescence (IF), luciferase reporter assay, electrophoretic mobility shift assay (EMSA) and chromatin immunoprecipitation (ChIP). Diethyl 1,4-dihydro-2,4,6-trimethyl-3,5-pyridinedicarboxylate (DDC) diet was used to induce liver injury.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; Pharmacologic activation of FXR induced &lt;em&gt;Lgr5&lt;/em&gt; expression, whereas activation of PPARα suppressed &lt;em&gt;Lgr5&lt;/em&gt; expression. Furthermore, FXR and PPARα competed for binding to shared site on &lt;em&gt;Lgr5&lt;/em&gt; promoter with opposite transcriptional outputs. DDC diet triggered the transition of &lt;em&gt;Lgr5&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; cells from resting state to proliferation. FXR activation enhanced &lt;em&gt;Lgr5&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; cell expansion mainly by symmetric cell division, but PPARα activation prevented &lt;em&gt;Lgr5&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; cell proliferation along with asymmetric cell division.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/em&gt; Our findings unravel the opposite regulatory effects of FXR and PPARα on &lt;em&gt;Lgr5&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; cell fate in liver under physiological and pathological conditions, which will greatly assist novel therapeutic development targeting nuclear receptors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CuO-NPs-triggered heterophil extracellular traps exacerbate liver injury in chicks by promoting oxidative stress and inflammatory responses</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35962800/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35962800/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the widespread use of copper oxide nanoparticles (CuO-NPs), their potential toxicity to the environment and biological health has attracted close attention. Heterophil extracellular traps (HETs) are an innate immune mechanism of chicken heterophils against adverse stimuli, but excessive HETs cause damage. Here, we explored the effect and mechanism of CuO-NPs on HETs formation in vitro and further evaluated the potential role of HETs in chicken liver and kidney injury. Heterophils were exposed to 5, 10, and 20 µg/mL of CuO-NPs for 2 h. The results showed that CuO-NPs induced typical HETs formation, which was dependent on NADPH oxidase, P38 and extracellular regulated protein kinases (ERK&lt;sub&gt;1/2&lt;/sub&gt;) pathways, and glycolysis. In in vivo experiments, fluorescence microplate and morphological analysis showed that CuO-NPs elevated the level of HETs in chicken serum and caused liver and kidney damage. Meanwhile, CuO-NPs caused hepatic oxidative stress (MDA, SOD, CAT, and GSH-PX imbalance), and also induced an increase in mRNA expression of their inflammatory and apoptosis-related factors (IL-1β, IL-6, TNF-α, COX-2, iNOS, NLRP3, and Caspase-1, 3, 11). However, these results were significantly altered by DNase I (HETs degradation reagent). In conclusion, the present study demonstrates for the first time that CuO-NPs induce the formation of HETs and that HETs exacerbate pathological damage in chicken liver and kidney by promoting oxidative stress and inflammation, providing insights into immunotoxicity and potential prevention and treatment targets caused by CuO-NPs overexposure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In Vivo Genome-Wide CRISPR Activation Screening Identifies Functionally Important Long Noncoding RNAs in Hepatocellular Carcinoma</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35944892/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35944892/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background &amp;amp; aims:&lt;/em&gt; Long noncoding RNAs (lncRNAs) are found to have profound impacts on diverse cellular processes. Although high-throughput sequencing studies have shown the differential lncRNA expression profiles between hepatocellular carcinoma (HCC) and nontumor livers, the functional impacts of lncRNAs on HCC development await further investigation. Herein, we sought to address the functional roles of lncRNAs in HCC pathogenesis by in vivo functional screening.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; We performed genome-wide clustered regularly interspaced short palindromic repeats (CRISPR)/dead CRISPR-associated protein 9 (dCas9) lncRNA activation screening in HCC xenografts. We characterized the clinical relevance of positively selected lncRNAs using transcriptomic data sets. We used CRISPR-based gene activation and knockdown approaches to show the functional roles of positively selected lncRNAs including Cancer Susceptibility 11 (CASC11) in HCC. RNA sequencing and chromatin isolation by RNA purification sequencing were used to investigate the molecular mechanisms of CASC11 in HCC progression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; The in vivo functional screening identified 1603 positively selected lncRNAs, 538 of which were overexpressed in HCC patients. Systematic transcriptomic data analysis and clinical investigation showed that patients with high expression of these lncRNA candidates correlated with aggressive tumor behaviors. Overexpression of these lncRNAs aggravated HCC cell growth. Detailed characterization of a lncRNA candidate, CASC11, showed its pivotal role in cell proliferation and tumor growth. Mechanistically, chromatin isolation by RNA purification sequencing showed that CASC11 was bound to the CASC11/MYC proto-oncogene shared promoter region on chromosome 8q24. CASC11 modulated the transcriptional activity of MYC in a cis-regulatory manner, which affected the expression of MYC downstream target genes, consequently promoting G1/S progression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; Our study showed the power of in vivo CRISPR screening, which comprehensively investigated the functionality of lncRNAs in HCC progression, providing a rationale for targeting these lncRNAs clinically.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transfer RNA-derived fragment 5&#39;tRF-Gly promotes the development of hepatocellular carcinoma by direct targeting of carcinoembryonic antigen-related cell adhesion molecule 1</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35879647/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35879647/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Transfer RNA-derived fragments are a group of small noncoding single-stranded RNA that play essential roles in multiple diseases. However, their biological functions in carcinogenesis are not well understood. In this study, 5&amp;rsquo;tRF-Gly was found to have significantly high expression in hepatocellular carcinoma (HCC), and the upregulation of 5&amp;rsquo;tRF-Gly was positively correlated with tumor size and tumor metastasis. Overexpression of 5&amp;rsquo;tRF-Gly induced increased growth rate and metastasis in HCC cells in vitro and in nude mice, while knockdown showed the opposite effect. Carcinoembryonic antigen-related cell adhesion molecule 1 (CEACAM1) was confirmed to be a direct target of 5&amp;rsquo;tRF-Gly in HCC. In addition, the cytological effect of CEACAM1 knockdown proved to be similar to the overexpression of 5&amp;rsquo;tRF-Gly. Moreover, attenuation of CEACAM1 expression rescued the 5&amp;rsquo;tRF-Gly-mediated promoting effects on HCC cells. These data show that 5&amp;rsquo;tRF-Gly is a new tumor-promoting factor and could be a potential diagnostic biomarker or new therapeutic target for HCC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MgIG exerts therapeutic effects on crizotinib-induced hepatotoxicity by limiting ROS-mediated autophagy and pyroptosis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35855570/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35855570/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Crizotinib (CRIZO) has been widely employed to treat non-small-cell lung cancer. However, hepatic inflammatory injury is the major toxicity of CRIZO, which limits its clinical application, and the underlying mechanism of CRIZO-induced hepatotoxicity has not been fully explored. Herein, we used cell counting kit-8 assay and flow cytometry to detect CRIZO-induced cytotoxicity on human hepatocytes (HL-7702). CRIZO significantly reduced the survival rate of hepatocytes in a dose-dependent manner. Furthermore, the reactive oxygen species (ROS) assay kit showed that CRIZO treatment strongly increased the level of ROS. In addition, CRIZO treatment caused the appearance of balloon-like bubbles and autophagosomes in HL-7702 cells. Subsequently, Western blotting, quantitative real-time PCR and ELISA assays revealed that ROS-mediated pyroptosis and autophagy contributed to CRIZO-induced hepatic injury. Based on the role of ROS in CRIZO-induced hepatotoxicity, magnesium isoglycyrrhizinate (MgIG) was used as an intervention drug. MgIG activated the Nrf2/HO-1 signalling pathway and reduced ROS level. Additionally, MgIG suppressed hepatic inflammation by inhibiting NF-κB activity, thereby reducing CRIZO-induced hepatotoxicity. In conclusion, CRIZO promoted autophagy activation and pyroptosis via the accumulation of ROS in HL-7702 cells. MgIG exerts therapeutic effects on CRIZO-induced hepatotoxicity by decreasing the level of ROS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Role of Immuno-Inflammatory Signals in Liver Ischemia-Reperfusion Injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/35883665/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/35883665/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ischemia reperfusion injury (IRI) is a major obstacle in liver resection and liver transplantation. The initial step of IRI is mediated through ischemia which promotes the production of reactive oxygen species in Kupffer cells. This furthermore promotes the activation of pro-inflammatory signaling cascades, including tumor necrosis factor-alpha, IL-6, interferon, inducible nitric oxide synthase, TLR9/nuclear-factor kappa B pathway, and the production of damage-associated molecular patterns (DAMPs), such as ATP, histone, high mobility group box 1 (HMGB1), urate, mitochondrial formyl peptides and S100 proteins. With ongoing cell death of hepatocytes during the ischemic phase, DAMPs are built up and released into the circulation upon reperfusion. This promotes a cytokines/chemokine storm that attracts neutrophils and other immune cells to the site of tissue injury. The effect of IRI is further aggravated by the release of cytokines and chemokines, such as epithelial neutrophil activating protein (CXCL5), KC (CXCL1) and MIP-2 (CXCL2), the complement proteins C3a and C5a, mitochondrial-derived formyl peptides, leukotriene B4 and neutrophil extracellular traps (NETs) from migrating neutrophils. These NETs can also activate platelets and form Neutrophil-platelet microthrombi to further worsen ischemia in the liver. In this review we aim to summarize the current knowledge of mediators that promote liver IRI, and we will discuss the role of neutrophils and neutrophil extracellular traps in mediating IRI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Partial freezing of rat livers extends preservation time by 5-fold</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35840553/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35840553/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The limited preservation duration of organs has contributed to the shortage of organs for transplantation. Recently, a tripling of the storage duration was achieved with supercooling, which relies on temperatures between -4 and -6 °C. However, to achieve deeper metabolic stasis, lower temperatures are required. Inspired by freeze-tolerant animals, we entered high-subzero temperatures (-10 to -15 °C) using ice nucleators to control ice and cryoprotective agents (CPAs) to maintain an unfrozen liquid fraction. We present this approach, termed partial freezing, by testing gradual (un)loading and different CPAs, holding temperatures, and storage durations. Results indicate that propylene glycol outperforms glycerol and injury is largely influenced by storage temperatures. Subsequently, we demonstrate that machine perfusion enhancements improve the recovery of livers after freezing. Ultimately, livers that were partially frozen for 5-fold longer showed favorable outcomes as compared to viable controls, although frozen livers had lower cumulative bile and higher liver enzymes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>B7-1 mediates podocyte injury and glomerulosclerosis through communication with Hsp90ab1-LRP5-β-catenin pathway</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35710882/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35710882/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Podocyte injury is a hallmark of glomerular diseases; however, the underlying mechanisms remain unclear. B7-1 is increased in injured podocytes, but its intrinsic role is controversial. The clinical data here revealed the intimate correlation of urinary B7-1 with severity of glomerular injury. Through transcriptomic and biological assays in B7-1 transgenic and adriamycin nephropathy models, we identified B7-1 is a key mediator in podocyte injury and glomerulosclerosis through a series of signal transmission to β-catenin. Using LC-MS/MS, Hsp90ab1, a conserved molecular chaperone, was distinguished to be an anchor for transmitting signals from B7-1 to β-catenin. Molecular docking and subsequent mutant analysis further identified the residue K69 in the N terminal domain of Hsp90ab1 was the key binding site for B7-1 to activate LRP5/β-catenin pathway. The interaction and biological functions of B7-1-Hsp90ab1-LRP5 complex were further demonstrated in vitro and in vivo. We also found B7-1 is a novel downstream target of β-catenin. Our results indicate an intercrossed network of B7-1, which collectively induces podocyte injury and glomerulosclerosis. Our study provides an important clue to improve the therapeutic strategies to target B7-1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>STING signaling sensing of DRP1-dependent mtDNA release in kupffer cells contributes to lipopolysaccharide-induced liver injury in mice</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35724543/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35724543/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aberrant pro-inflammatory activation of Kupffer cells (KCs) is strongly involved in the pathogenesis of septic liver injury. Recent evidence indicates the crucial roles of excessive stimulator of interferon genes (STING) signaling activation during sepsis. However, the role of STING signaling in septic liver injury remains unclear. In this study, we demonstrated that STING signaling was markedly activated in KCs isolated from wild type mice after lipopolysaccharide (LPS) treatment. STING deficiency effectively protected liver function, attenuated systemic inflammatory response and decreased mortality in LPS-treated mice, which were aggravated by STING agonist (DMXAA). Importantly, STING signaling activation in KCs contributed to LPS-induced liver injury through promoting hepatocyte death. Mechanistically, STING signaling could be activated by release of mitochondrial DNA (mtDNA) through dynamin-related protein 1 (DRP1)-dependent mitochondrial fission in LPS-treated KCs. Additionally, LPS stimulation enhanced DRP1-dependent mitochondrial ROS production, which promoted the leak of mtDNA into the cytosol and subsequent STING signaling activation in KCs. The in vivo experiments showed that pharmacological inhibition of DRP1 with Mdivi-1 partially prevented the activation of STING signaling in KCs isolated from LPS-challenged mice, as well as alleviated liver injury and inhibited systemic inflammatory response. In summary, our study comprehensively confirmed that STING signaling senses the DRP1-dependent release of mtDNA in KCs and its activation might play a key role in LPS-induced liver injury, which offers new sights and therapeutic targets for management of septic liver injury.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Therapeutic potential of traditional Chinese medicine for the treatment of NAFLD: A promising drug Potentilla discolor Bunge</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/36176915/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/36176915/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nonalcoholic fatty liver disease (NAFLD) is characterized by excessive accumulation of hepatic lipids and metabolic stress-induced liver injury. There are currently no approved effective pharmacological treatments for NAFLD. Traditional Chinese medicine (TCM) has been used for centuries to treat patients with chronic liver diseases without clear disease types and mechanisms. More recently, TCM has been shown to have unique advantages in the treatment of NAFLD. We performed a systematic review of the medical literature published over the last two decades and found that many TCM formulas have been reported to be beneficial for the treatment of metabolic dysfunctions, including &lt;em&gt;Potentilla discolor&lt;/em&gt; Bunge (PDB). PDB has a variety of active compounds, including flavonoids, terpenoids, organic acids, steroids and tannins. Many compounds have been shown to exhibit a series of beneficial effects for the treatment of NAFLD, including anti-oxidative and anti-inflammatory functions, improvement of lipid metabolism and reversal of insulin resistance. In this review, we summarize potential therapeutic effects of TCM formulas for the treatment of NAFLD, focusing on the medicinal properties of natural active compounds from PDB and their underlying mechanisms. We point out that PDB can be classified as a novel candidate for the treatment and prevention of NAFLD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Functional metabolomics revealed functional metabolic-characteristics of chronic hepatitis that is significantly differentiated from acute hepatitis in mice</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35537579/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35537579/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Diagnosis and therapeutics of acute- and chronic- hepatitis (A-H and C-H) cannot be distinguished during clinical practice because functional molecular-characteristics of two conditions remains elusive. Here, we employed a functional metabolomics strategy to discover functional metabolites that can readily distinguish C-H from A-H in CCl&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; treated mice. Metabolic-differentiation between A-H and C-H was identified as A-H was largely characterized by the dysregulated purine cycle and amino acid metabolism, while the disorders of hepatic taurine-conjugated bile acids and glycerolipid biosynthesis were observed with C-H. Excitingly, we found that the enhanced conversation of C&lt;sub&gt;18-22&lt;/sub&gt; PUFA-containing TAGs to MUFA-containing TAGs promoted the development of C-H, which was also closely associated with the changes of TCA intermediates regulated by gut microbiota (Muribaculaceae and Prevotellaceae). Such metabolic discovery on hepatitis was validated by the functional annotation of metabolic genes, as the decreased expressions of Slc27a2, Acaa1a and Acaa1b mostly account for the dysregulation of purine degradation with AH, then the lowered expressions of Cyp2e1, Cat, Slc27a5 and Klb are significantly related to the dysregulated bile acids with C-H. Collecting clinical samples from the patients with hepatitis to compare serum metabolomes with A-H and C-H mice, the determinant functional metabolites were identified to significantly distinguish C-H from A-H in both experimental and clinical settings, suggesting metabolic discovery with CCl&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; treated mice could be further efficiently explored to guide clinical research of A-H and C-H. Collectively, our study is providing novel insight into distinctive metabolic-characteristics of A-H and C-H underlying the innovative diagnosis and therapeutics of hepatitis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Long noncoding RNA TLNC1 promotes the growth and metastasis of liver cancer via inhibition of p53 signaling</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35477447/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35477447/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Long non-coding RNAs (lncRNAs) have been demonstrated to play vital roles in cancer development and progression. However, their biological roles and function mechanisms in liver cancer remain largely unknown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; RNA-seq was performed with clinical hepatoma tissues and paired adjacent normal liver tissues to identify differentially expressed lncRNAs. qPCR was utilized to examine the expression levels of lncRNAs. We studied the function of TLNC1 in cell growth and metastasis of hepatoma with both cell and mouse models. RNA-seq, RNA pull-down coupled with mass spectrometry, RNA immunoprecipitation, dual luciferase reporter assay, and surface plasmon resonance analysis were used to analyze the functional mechanism of TLNC1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; Based on the intersection of our own RNA-seq, TCGA RNA-seq, and TCGA survival analysis data, TLNC1 was identified as a potential tumorigenic lncRNA of liver cancer. TLNC1 significantly enhanced the growth and metastasis of hepatoma cells both in vitro and in vivo. TLNC1 exerted its tumorigenic function through interaction with TPR and inducing the TPR-mediated transportation of p53 from nucleus to cytoplasm, thus repressing the transcription of p53 target genes and finally contributing to the progression of liver cancer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; TLNC1 is a promising prognostic factor of liver cancer, and the TLNC1-TPR-p53 axis can serve as a potential therapeutic target for hepatoma treatment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Loss of Sam50 in hepatocytes induces cardiolipin-dependent mitochondrial membrane remodeling to trigger mtDNA release and liver injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35313046/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35313046/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background and aims:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sam50, a key component of the sorting and assembly machinery (SAM) complex, is also involved in bridging mitochondrial outer-membrane and inner-membrane contacts. However, the physiological and pathological functions of Sam50 remain largely unknown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Approach and results:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here we show that Sam50 interacts with MICOS (mitochondrial contact site and cristae organizing system) and ATAD3 (ATPase family AAA domain-containing protein 3) to form the Sam50-MICOS-ATAD3-mtDNA axis, which maintains mtDNA stability. Loss of Sam50 causes mitochondrial DNA (mtDNA) aggregation. Furthermore, Sam50 cooperates with Mic60 to bind to cardiolipin, maintaining the integrity of mitochondrial membranes. Sam50 depletion leads to cardiolipin externalization, which causes mitochondrial outer-membrane and inner-membrane (including crista membrane) remodeling, triggering Bax mitochondrial recruitment, mtDNA aggregation, and release. Physiologically, acetaminophen (an effective antipyretic and analgesic)-caused Sam50 reduction or Sam50 liver-specific knockout induces mtDNA release, leading to activation of the cGAS-STING pathway and liver inflammation in mice. Moreover, exogenous expression of Sam50 remarkably attenuates APAP-induced liver hepatoxicity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our findings uncover the critical role of Sam50 in maintaining mitochondrial membrane integrity and mtDNA stability in hepatocytes and reveal that Sam50 depletion-induced cardiolipin externalization is a signal of mtDNA release and controls mtDNA-dependent innate immunity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ubiquitin ligase E3 HUWE1/MULE targets transferrin receptor for degradation and suppresses ferroptosis in acute liver injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35260822/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35260822/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hepatic ischemia followed by reperfusion (I/R), a major clinical problem during liver surgical procedures, can induce liver injury with severe cell death including ferroptosis which is characterized by iron-dependent accumulation of lipid peroxidation. The HECT domain-containing ubiquitin E3 ligase HUWE1 (also known as MULE) was initially shown to promote apoptosis. However, our preliminary study demonstrates that high expression of HUWE1 in the liver donors corelates with less injury and better hepatic function after liver transplantation in patients. Thus, we investigate the role of HUWE1 in acute liver injury, and identify HUWE1 as a negative ferroptosis modulator through transferrin receptor 1(TfR1). Deficiency of Huwe1 in mice hepatocytes (HKO) exacerbated I/R and CCl4-induced liver injury with more ferroptosis occurrence. Moreover, Suppression of Huwe1 remarkably enhances cellular sensitivity to ferroptosis in primary hepatocytes and mouse embryonic fibroblasts. Mechanistically, HUWE1 specifically targets TfR1 for ubiquitination and proteasomal degradation, thereby regulates iron metabolism. Importantly, chemical and genetic inhibition of TfR1 dramatically diminishes the ferroptotic cell death in Huwe1 KO cells and Huwe1 HKO mice. Therefore, HUWE1 is a potential protective factor to antagonize both aberrant iron accumulation and ferroptosis thereby mitigating acute liver injury. These findings may provide clinical implications for patients with the high-expression Huwe1 alleles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Berberine Relieves Metabolic Syndrome in Mice by Inhibiting Liver Inflammation Caused by a High-Fat Diet and Potential Association With Gut Microbiota</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35095784/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35095784/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whether berberine mediates its anti-inflammatory and blood sugar and lipid-lowering effects solely by adjusting the structure of the gut microbiota or by first directly regulating the expression of host pro-inflammatory proteins and activation of macrophages and subsequently acting on gut microbiota, is currently unclear. To clarify the mechanism of berberine-mediated regulation of metabolism, we constructed an obese mouse model using SPF-grade C57BL/6J male mice and conducted a systematic study of liver tissue pathology, inflammatory factor expression, and gut microbiota structure. We screened the gut microbiota targets of berberine and showed that the molecular mechanism of berberine-mediated treatment of metabolic syndrome involves the regulation of gut microbiota structure and the expression of inflammatory factors. Our results revealed that a high-fat diet (HFD) significantly changed mice gut microbiota, thereby probably increasing the level of toxins in the intestine, and triggered the host inflammatory response. The HFD also reduced the proportion of short-chain fatty acid (SCFA)-producing genes, thereby hindering mucosal immunity and cell nutrition, and increased the host inflammatory response and liver fat metabolism disorders. Further, berberine could improve the chronic HFD-induced inflammatory metabolic syndrome to some extent and effectively improved the metabolism of high-fat foods in mice, which correlated with the gut microbiota composition. Taken together, our study may improve our understanding of host-microbe interactions during the treatment of metabolic diseases and provide useful insights into the action mechanism of berberine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A targetable LIFR-NF-κB-LCN2 axis controls liver tumorigenesis and vulnerability to ferroptosis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34921145/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34921145/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The growing knowledge of ferroptosis has suggested the role and therapeutic potential of ferroptosis in cancer, but has not been translated into effective therapy. Liver cancer, primarily hepatocellular carcinoma (HCC), is highly lethal with limited treatment options. LIFR is frequently downregulated in HCC. Here, by studying hepatocyte-specific and inducible Lifr-knockout mice, we show that loss of Lifr promotes liver tumorigenesis and confers resistance to drug-induced ferroptosis. Mechanistically, loss of LIFR activates NF-κB signaling through SHP1, leading to upregulation of the iron-sequestering cytokine LCN2, which depletes iron and renders insensitivity to ferroptosis inducers. Notably, an LCN2-neutralizing antibody enhances the ferroptosis-inducing and anticancer effects of sorafenib on HCC patient-derived xenograft tumors with low LIFR expression and high LCN2 expression. Thus, anti-LCN2 therapy is a promising way to improve liver cancer treatment by targeting ferroptosis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Pannexin 1/Purinergic Receptor P2X4 Pathway Controls the Secretion of MicroRNA-Containing Exosomes by HCV-Infected Hepatocytes</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34218459/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34218459/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background and aims:&lt;/em&gt; HCV infection is a major risk factor that can lead to chronic liver disease, including fibrosis, cirrhosis, and HCC. Progression of chronic liver disease by HCV infection is caused by a complex intercellular reaction. Especially, exosomes and microRNAs (miRNAs) from HCV-infected hepatocytes play a role in the pathogenesis of liver disease by facilitating cellular communication between parenchymal and nonparenchymal cells. However, the underlying mechanism of secretions of exosome and miRNAs during HCV infection is still open for study.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Approach and results:&lt;/em&gt; In this study, we demonstrated a pathway for the release of exosome and exosomal miRNAs through caspase-3/pannexin 1 (Panx1)/P2X4 activation during HCV infection in hepatocytes. We found that HCV infection induced the stimulation of exosome release and activation of the caspase-3/Panx1/P2X4 pathway in Huh7.5.1 cells. In addition, miR-122 and miR-146a levels in extracellular exosomes from HCV-infected cells were dramatically increased whereas intracellular miR122 and miR-146a expression had no large changes. Notably, secretions of exosomes and exosomal miRNAs were decreased by inhibition of caspase 3, Panx1, and P2X4 whereas inhibition of ROCK-1 cleavage did not affect these during HCV infection in Huh7.5.1 cells.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; These results suggested that HCV infection caused secretions of exosomes and exosomal miRNAs dependent on the caspase 3/Panx1/P2X4 pathway. Our study provides a possible therapeutic intervention using Panx1 suppression for liver disease development mediated by exosomes from HCV-infected hepatocytes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spatiotemporal Immune Landscape of Colorectal Cancer Liver Metastasis at Single-Cell Level</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34417225/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34417225/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Liver metastasis, the leading cause of colorectal cancer mortality, exhibits a highly heterogeneous and suppressive immune microenvironment. Here, we sequenced 97 matched samples by using single-cell RNA sequencing and spatial transcriptomics. Strikingly, the metastatic microenvironment underwent remarkable spatial reprogramming of immunosuppressive cells such as &lt;em&gt;MRC1&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;CCL18&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; M2-like macrophages. We further developed scMetabolism, a computational pipeline for quantifying single-cell metabolism, and observed that those macrophages harbored enhanced metabolic activity. Interestingly, neoadjuvant chemotherapy could block this status and restore the antitumor immune balance in responsive patients, whereas the nonresponsive patients deteriorated into a more suppressive one. Our work described the immune evolution of metastasis and uncovered the black box of how tumors respond to neoadjuvant chemotherapy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Significance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We present a single-cell and spatial atlas of colorectal liver metastasis and found the highly metabolically activated &lt;em&gt;MRC1&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;CCL18&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; M2-like macrophages in metastatic sites. Efficient neoadjuvant chemotherapy can slow down such metabolic activation, raising the possibility to target metabolism pathways in metastasis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enterically derived high-density lipoprotein restrains liver injury through the portal vein</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34437091/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34437091/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The biogenesis of high-density lipoprotein (HDL) requires apoA1 and the cholesterol transporter ABCA1. Although the liver generates most of the HDL in the blood, HDL synthesis also occurs in the small intestine. Here, we show that intestine-derived HDL traverses the portal vein in the HDL3 subspecies form, in complex with lipopolysaccharide (LPS)-binding protein (LBP). HDL3, but not HDL2 or low-density lipoprotein, prevented LPS binding to and inflammatory activation of liver macrophages and instead supported extracellular inactivation of LPS. In mouse models involving surgical, dietary, or alcoholic intestinal insult, loss of intestine-derived HDL worsened liver injury, whereas outcomes were improved by therapeutics that elevated and depended upon raising intestinal HDL. Thus, protection of the liver from injury in response to gut-derived LPS is a major function of intestinally synthesized HDL.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Identification and Characterization of Robust Hepatocellular Carcinoma Prognostic Subtypes Based on an Integrative Metabolite-Protein Interaction Network</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34247449/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34247449/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Metabolite-protein interactions (MPIs) play key roles in cancer metabolism. However, our current knowledge about MPIs in cancers remains limited due to the complexity of cancer cells. Herein, the authors construct an integrative MPI network and propose a MPI network based hepatocellular carcinoma (HCC) subtyping and mechanism exploration workflow. Based on the expressions of hub proteins on the MPI network, two prognosis-distinctive HCC subtypes are identified. Meanwhile, multiple interdependent features of the poor prognostic subtype are observed, including hypoxia, DNA hypermethylation of metabolic pathways, fatty acid accumulation, immune pathway up-regulation, and exhausted T-cell infiltration. Notably, the immune pathway up-regulation is probably induced by accumulated unsaturated fatty acids which are predicted to interact with multiple immune regulators like SRC and TGFB1. Moreover, based on tumor microenvironment compositions, the poor prognostic subtype is further divided into two sub-populations showing remarkable differences in metabolism. The subtyping shows a strong consistency across multiple HCC cohorts including early-stage HCC. Overall, the authors redefine robust HCC prognosis subtypes and identify potential MPIs linking metabolism to immune regulations, thus promoting understanding and clinical applications about HCC metabolism heterogeneity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hepatitis C virus modulates signal peptide peptidase to alter host protein processing</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34035171/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34035171/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Immunoevasins are viral proteins that prevent antigen presentation on major histocompatibility complex (MHC) class I, thus evading host immune recognition. Hepatitis C virus (HCV) evades immune surveillance to induce chronic infection; however, how HCV-infected hepatocytes affect immune cells and evade immune recognition remains unclear. Herein, we demonstrate that HCV core protein functions as an immunoevasin. Its expression interfered with the maturation of MHC class I molecules catalyzed by the signal peptide peptidase (SPP) and induced their degradation via HMG-CoA reductase degradation 1 homolog, thereby impairing antigen presentation to CD8&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T cells. The expression of MHC class I in the livers of HCV core transgenic mice and chronic hepatitis C patients was impaired but was restored in patients achieving sustained virological response. Finally, we show that the human cytomegalovirus US2 protein, possessing a transmembrane region structurally similar to the HCV core protein, targets SPP to impair MHC class I molecule expression. Thus, SPP represents a potential target for the impairment of MHC class I molecules by DNA and RNA viruses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The mirror site can be freely accessed by &lt;a href=&#34;http://bioinfo.org/kobas&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;clicking here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Selective inhibition of cullin 3 neddylation through covalent targeting DCN1 protects mice from acetaminophen-induced liver toxicity</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33976147/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33976147/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cullin-RING E3 ligases (CRLs) regulate the turnover of approximately 20% of mammalian cellular proteins. Neddylation of individual cullin proteins is essential for the activation of each CRL. We report herein the discovery of DI-1548 and DI-1859 as two potent, selective and covalent DCN1 inhibitors. These inhibitors selectively inhibit neddylation of cullin 3 in cells at low nanomolar concentrations and are 2–3 orders of magnitude more potent than our previously reported reversible DCN1 inhibitor. Mass spectrometric analysis and co-crystal structures reveal that these compounds employ a unique mechanism of covalent bond formation with DCN1. DI-1859 induces a robust increase of NRF2 protein, a CRL3 substrate, in mouse liver and effectively protects mice from acetaminophen-induced liver damage. Taken together, this study demonstrates the therapeutic potential of selective inhibition of cullin neddylation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A tumor-suppressive circular RNA mediates uncanonical integrin degradation by the proteasome in liver cancer</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33762338/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33762338/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Circular RNAs (circRNAs) have emerged as important regulators of various cellular processes and have been implicated in cancer. Previously, we reported the discovery of several dysregulated circRNAs including circPABPC1 (polyadenylate-binding protein 1) in human hepatocellular carcinoma (HCC), although their roles in HCC development remained unclear. Here, we show that circPABPC1 is preferentially lost in tumor cells from clinical samples and inhibits both intrahepatic and distant metastases in a mouse xenograft model. This tumor-suppressive function of circPABPC1 can be attributed to its inhibition of cell adhesion and migration through down-regulating a key member of the integrin family, ITGB1 (β&lt;sub&gt;1&lt;/sub&gt; integrin). Mass spectrometry and biochemical evidence demonstrate that circPABPC1 directly links ITGB1 to the 26S proteasome for degradation in a ubiquitination-independent manner. Our data have revealed an uncanonical route for integrin turnover and a previously unidentified mode of action for circRNAs in HCC that can be harnessed for anticancer&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integrated Protein-Protein Interaction and Weighted Gene Co-expression Network Analysis Uncover Three Key Genes in Hepatoblastoma</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33718368/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33718368/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hepatoblastoma (HB) is the most common liver tumor in the pediatric population, with typically poor outcomes for advanced-stage or chemotherapy-refractory HB patients. The objective of this study was to identify genes involved in HB pathogenesis via microarray analysis and subsequent experimental validation. We identified 856 differentially expressed genes (DEGs) between HB and normal liver tissue based on two publicly available microarray datasets (GSE131329 and GSE75271) after data merging and batch effect correction. Protein-protein interaction (PPI) analysis and weighted gene co-expression network analysis (WGCNA) were conducted to explore HB-related critical modules and hub genes. Subsequently, Gene Ontology (GO) analysis was used to reveal critical biological functions in the initiation and progression of HB. Kyoto Encyclopedia of Genes and Genomes (KEGG) analysis showed that genes involved in cell cycle phase transition and the PI3K/AKT signaling were associated with HB. The intersection of hub genes identified by both PPI and WGCNA analyses revealed five potential candidate genes. Based on receiver operating characteristic (ROC) curve analysis and reports in the literature, we selected CCNA2, CDK1, and CDC20 as key genes of interest to validate experimentally. CCNA2, CDK1, or CDC20 small interfering RNA (siRNA) knockdown inhibited aggressive biological properties of both HepG2 and HuH-6 cell lines in vitro. In conclusion, we identified CCNA2, CDK1, and CDC20 as new potential therapeutic biomarkers for HB, providing novel insights into important and viable targets in future HB treatment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>microRNA-199a-3p inhibits hepatic apoptosis and hepatocarcinogenesis by targeting PDCD4</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33099584/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33099584/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hepatic apoptosis and the initiated liver inflammation play the initial roles in inflammation-induced hepatocarcinogenesis. Molecular mechanisms underlying the regulation of hepatocyte apoptosis and their roles in hepatocarcinogenesis have attracted much attention. A set of microRNAs (miRNAs) have been determined to be dysregulated in hepatocellular carcinoma (HCC) and participated in cancer progression, however, the roles of these dysregulated miRNAs in carcinogenesis are still poorly understood. We previously analyzed the dysregulated miRNAs in HCC using high-throughput sequencing, and found that miR-199a/b-3p was abundantly expressed in human normal liver while markedly decreased in HCC, which promotes HCC progression. Whether miR-199a/b-3p participates in HCC carcinogenesis is still unknown up to now. Hence, we focused on the role and mechanism of miR-199a/b-3p in hepatocarcinogenesis in this study. Hepatic miR-199a/b-3p was determined to be expressed by miR-199a-2 gene in mice, and we constructed miR-199a-2 knockout and hepatocyte-specific miR-199a-2 knockout mice. Diethylnitrosamine (DEN)-induced hepatocarcinogenesis were markedly increased by hepatocyte-specific miR-199a-3p knockout, which is mediated by the enhanced hepatocyte apoptosis and hepatic injury by DEN administration. In acetaminophen (APAP)-induced acute hepatic injury model, hepatocyte-specific miR-199a-3p knockout also aggravated hepatic apoptosis. By proteomic screening and reporter gene validation, we identified and verified that hepatic programed cell death 4 (PDCD4), which promotes apoptosis, was directly targeted by miR-199a-3p. Furthermore, we confirmed that miR-199a-3p-suppressed hepatocyte apoptosis and hepatic injury by targeting and suppressing PDCD4. Thus, hepatic miR-199a-3p inhibits hepatocyte apoptosis and hepatocarcinogenesis, and decreased miR-199a-3p in hepatocytes may aggravate hepatic injury and HCC development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hepatic transferrin plays a role in systemic iron homeostasis and liver ferroptosis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32374849/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32374849/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although the serum-abundant metal-binding protein transferrin (encoded by the &lt;em&gt;Trf&lt;/em&gt; gene) is synthesized primarily in the liver, its function in the liver is largely unknown. Here, we generated hepatocyte-specific &lt;em&gt;Trf&lt;/em&gt; knockout mice (&lt;em&gt;Trf&lt;/em&gt;-LKO), which are viable and fertile but have impaired erythropoiesis and altered iron metabolism. Moreover, feeding &lt;em&gt;Trf&lt;/em&gt;-LKO mice a high-iron diet increased their susceptibility to developing ferroptosis-induced liver fibrosis. Importantly, we found that treating &lt;em&gt;Trf&lt;/em&gt;-LKO mice with the ferroptosis inhibitor ferrostatin-1 potently rescued liver fibrosis induced by either high dietary iron or carbon tetrachloride (CCl&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;) injections. In addition, deleting hepatic Slc39a14 expression in &lt;em&gt;Trf&lt;/em&gt;-LKO mice significantly reduced hepatic iron accumulation, thereby reducing ferroptosis-mediated liver fibrosis induced by either a high-iron diet or CCl&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; injections. Finally, we found that patients with liver cirrhosis have significantly lower levels of serum transferrin and hepatic transferrin, as well as higher levels of hepatic iron and lipid peroxidation, compared with healthy control subjects. Taken together, these data indicate that hepatic transferrin plays a protective role in maintaining liver function, providing a possible therapeutic target for preventing ferroptosis-induced liver fibrosis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Decreased Hepatocyte Autophagy Leads to Synergistic IL-1β and TNF Mouse Liver Injury and Inflammation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32108953/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32108953/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background and aims:&lt;/em&gt; The proinflammatory cytokine IL-1β has been implicated in the pathophysiology of nonalcoholic and alcoholic steatohepatitis. How IL-1β promotes liver injury in these diseases is unclear, as no IL-1β receptor-linked death pathway has been identified. Autophagy functions in hepatocyte resistance to injury and death, and findings of decreased hepatic autophagy in many liver diseases suggest a role for impaired autophagy in disease pathogenesis. Recent findings that autophagy blocks mouse liver injury from lipopolysaccharide led to an examination of autophagy&amp;rsquo;s function in hepatotoxicity from proinflammatory cytokines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Approach and results:&lt;/em&gt; AML12 cells with decreased autophagy from a lentiviral autophagy-related 5 (Atg5) knockdown were resistant to toxicity from TNF, but sensitized to death from IL-1β, which was markedly amplified by TNF co-treatment. IL-1β/TNF death was necrosis by trypan blue and propidium iodide positivity, absence of mitochondrial death pathway and caspase activation, and failure of a caspase inhibitor or necrostatin-1s to prevent death. IL-1β/TNF depleted autophagy-deficient cells of ATP, and ATP depletion and cell death were prevented by supplementation with the energy substrate pyruvate or oleate. Pharmacological inhibitors and genetic knockdown studies demonstrated that IL-1β/TNF-induced necrosis resulted from lysosomal permeabilization and release of cathepsins B and L in autophagy-deficient cells. Mice with a tamoxifen-inducible, hepatocyte-specific Atg5 knockout were similarly sensitized to cathepsin-dependent hepatocellular injury and death from IL-1β/TNF in combination, but neither IL-1β nor TNF alone. Knockout mice had increased hepatic inflammation, and IL-1β/TNF-treated, autophagy-deficient AML12 cells secreted exosomes with proinflammatory damage-associated molecular patterns.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; The findings delineate mechanisms by which decreased hepatocyte autophagy promotes IL-1β/TNF-induced necrosis from impaired energy homeostasis and lysosomal permeabilization and inflammation through the secretion of exosomal damage-associated molecular patterns.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Innate immune cells in cirrhosis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/32240716/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/32240716/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cirrhosis is a multisystemic disease wherein inflammatory responses originating from advanced liver disease and its sequelae affect distant compartments. Patients with cirrhosis are susceptible to bacterial infections, which may precipitate acute decompensation and acute-on-chronic liver failure, both of which are associated with high short-term mortality. Innate immune cells are an essential first line of defence against pathogens. Activation of liver macrophages (Kupffer cells) and resident mastocytes generate proinflammatory and vaso-permeating mediators that induce accumulation of neutrophils, lymphocytes, eosinophils and monocytes in the liver, and promote tissue damage. During cirrhosis progression, damage- and pathogen-associated molecular patterns activate immune cells and promote development of systemic inflammatory responses which may involve different tissues and compartments. The antibacterial function of circulating neutrophils and monocytes is gradually and severely impaired as cirrhosis worsens, contributing to disease progression. The mechanisms underlying impaired antimicrobial responses are complex and incompletely understood. This review focuses on the continuous and distinct perturbations arising in innate immune cells during cirrhosis, including their impact on disease progression, as well as reviewing potential therapeutic targets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Endotoxin Delivery Protein HMGB1 Mediates Caspase-11-Dependent Lethality in Sepsis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/30314759/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/30314759/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hepatocyte-released HMGB1 mediates caspase-11-dependent lethality in sepsis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;HMGB1-LPS complexes are taken up by macrophages and endothelial cells via RAGE&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;HMGB1 destabilizes phagolysosomes for the transfer of LPS to cytosolic caspase-11&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Neutralizing extracellular HMGB1 inhibits caspase-11 activation in sepsis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Summary&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Caspase-11, a cytosolic endotoxin (lipopolysaccharide: LPS) receptor, mediates pyroptosis, a lytic form of cell death. Caspase-11-dependent pyroptosis mediates lethality in endotoxemia, but it is unclear how LPS is delivered into the cytosol for the activation of caspase-11. Here we discovered that hepatocyte-released high mobility group box 1 (HMGB1) was required for caspase-11-dependent pyroptosis and lethality in endotoxemia and bacterial sepsis. Mechanistically, hepatocyte-released HMGB1 bound LPS and targeted its internalization into the lysosomes of macrophages and endothelial cells via the receptor for advanced glycation end-products (RAGE). Subsequently, HMGB1 permeabilized the phospholipid bilayer in the acidic environment of lysosomes. This resulted in LPS leakage into the cytosol and caspase-11 activation. Depletion of hepatocyte HMGB1, inhibition of hepatocyte HMGB1 release, neutralizing extracellular HMGB1, or RAGE deficiency prevented caspase-11-dependent pyroptosis and death in endotoxemia and bacterial sepsis. These findings indicate that HMGB1 interacts with LPS to mediate caspase-11-dependent pyroptosis in lethal sepsis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Landscape of Infiltrating T Cells in Liver Cancer Revealed by Single-Cell Sequencing</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/28622514/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/28622514/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Systematic interrogation of tumor-infiltrating lymphocytes is key to the development of immunotherapies and the prediction of their clinical responses in cancers. Here, we perform deep single-cell RNA sequencing on 5,063 single T cells isolated from peripheral blood, tumor, and adjacent normal tissues from six hepatocellular carcinoma patients. The transcriptional profiles of these individual cells, coupled with assembled T cell receptor (TCR) sequences, enable us to identify 11 T cell subsets based on their molecular and functional properties and delineate their developmental trajectory. Specific subsets such as exhausted CD8+ T cells and Tregs are preferentially enriched and potentially clonally expanded in hepatocellular carcinoma (HCC), and we identified signature genes for each subset. One of the genes, layilin, is upregulated on activated CD8+ T cells and Tregs and represses the CD8+ T cell functions in vitro. This compendium of transcriptome data provides valuable insights and a rich resource for understanding the immune landscape in cancers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ly6Chi monocytes regulate T cell responses in viral hepatitis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/27777980/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/27777980/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Viral hepatitis remains a global health challenge despite recent progress in the development of more effective therapies. Although virus-specific CD8+ and CD4+ T cell responses are essential for viral clearance, it remains largely unknown what regulates T cell-mediated viral clearance. Thus, a better understanding of the regulation of anti-viral T cell immunity would be critical for the design of more effective therapies for viral hepatitis. Using a model of adenovirus-induced hepatitis, here we showed that adenoviral infection induced recruitment of Ly6C&lt;sup&gt;hi&lt;/sup&gt; monocytes to the liver in a CCR2-dependent manner. These recruited Ly6C&lt;sup&gt;hi&lt;/sup&gt; monocytes suppressed CD8&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; and CD4&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T cell responses to adenoviral infection, leading to a delay in viral clearance. In vivo depletion of Ly6C&lt;sup&gt;hi&lt;/sup&gt; monocytes markedly enhanced anti-viral T cell responses and promoted viral clearance. Mechanistically, we showed that induction of iNOS and the production of NO by Ly6C&lt;sup&gt;hi&lt;/sup&gt; monocytes are critical for the suppression of T cell responses. In addition, a contact-dependent mechanism mediated by PD-1 and PD-L1 interaction is also required for T cell suppression by Ly6C&lt;sup&gt;hi&lt;/sup&gt; monocytes. These findings suggest a critical role for Ly6C&lt;sup&gt;hi&lt;/sup&gt; monocytes in the regulation of T cell immunity in viral hepatitis and may provide new insights into development of more effective therapies for treating viral hepatitis based on targeting the immunosuppressing monocytes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
