<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ophthalmology | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/ophthalmology/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/ophthalmology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Ophthalmology</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Ophthalmology</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/ophthalmology/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Light modulates glucose metabolism by a retina-hypothalamus-brown adipose tissue axis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/cell.2022.12.024/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/cell.2022.12.024/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Photoreception of ipRGCs mediates light modulation of glucose tolerance (GT) in mice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hypothalamic supraoptic nucleus is essential for light modulation of GT in mice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Light modulates GT via a neuro circuit that alters adaptive thermogenesis in mice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Light modulates human GT at the temperature where brown adipose tissue is active&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Public health studies indicate that artificial light is a high-risk factor for metabolic disorders. However, the neural mechanism underlying metabolic modulation by light remains elusive. Here, we found that light can acutely decrease glucose tolerance (GT) in mice by activation of intrinsically photosensitive retinal ganglion cells (ipRGCs) innervating the hypothalamic supraoptic nucleus (SON). Vasopressin neurons in the SON project to the paraventricular nucleus, then to the GABAergic neurons in the solitary tract nucleus, and eventually to brown adipose tissue (BAT). Light activation of this neural circuit directly blocks adaptive thermogenesis in BAT, thereby decreasing GT. In humans, light also modulates GT at the temperature where BAT is active. Thus, our work unveils a retina-SON-BAT axis that mediates the effect of light on glucose metabolism, which may explain the connection between artificial light and metabolic dysregulation, suggesting a potential prevention and treatment strategy for managing glucose metabolic disorders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PANoptosis-like cell death in ischemia/reperfusion injury of retinal neurons</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35900430/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35900430/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We screened small molecules to identify two compounds, which we named RSL3 and RSL5, that have increased lethality in the presence of oncogenic RAS. Counter screening with biologically active compounds defined aspects of the mechanism of action for RSL3 and RSL5, such as a nonapoptotic, MEK-dependent, and iron-dependent oxidative cell death. Erastin, a previously reported compound with RAS-selective lethality, showed similar properties. RNA interference experiments targeting voltage-dependent anion channel 3 (VDAC3), a target of erastin, demonstrated that RSL5 is a scaffold that acts through VDACs to activate the observed pathway. RSL3 activated a similar death mechanism but in a VDAC-independent manner. We found that cells transformed with oncogenic RAS have increased iron content relative to their normal cell counterparts through upregulation of transferrin receptor 1 and downregulation of ferritin heavy chain 1 and ferritin light chain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Injectable double-network hydrogel for corneal repair</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/cej.2022.140698/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/cej.2022.140698/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Injuries to the cornea can cause corneal opacity or even blindness. Especially scald wounds and chemical burns to the cornea can usually lead to loss of corneal epithelium function and deep damage to the corneal stroma. Injectable hydrogel has been widely applied in corneal tissue engineering because it is easy to handle and can completely fill the defect area with minimally invasive surgical procedures. To reduce the risk and complications of penetrating keratoplasty and lamellar keratoplasty and to meet the demand for donated cornea, an injectable double-network (IDN) hydrogel based on methacrylated gelatin (Gel-MA) and oxidized hyaluronic acid (OHA) was constructed for focal corneal defect repairing. The Gel-MA/OHA IDN hydrogel had an interconnected porous microstructure and tunable mechanical properties with a modulus between 3.4 and 176.4 kPa. The hydrogel could promote cell adhesion and proliferation and afford the sustained release of hydrophilic/hydrophobic drugs. &lt;em&gt;In-vivo&lt;/em&gt; corneal repair was performed by injecting the precursors into the pre-drilled epithelial-stromal defects of New Zealand White rabbits followed by immediate &lt;em&gt;in-situ&lt;/em&gt; UV crosslinking. The results showed that the hydrogel had a strong capacity to promote corneal regeneration. Optical coherence tomography, slip lamp, fluorescein staining, scanning electron microscopy (SEM), and haematoxylin &amp;amp; eosin (H&amp;amp;E) staining were employed to illustrate the effectiveness and safety of corneal tissue regeneration. All the results showed that the optimized Gel-MA/OHA IDN hydrogel possessed excellent biocompatibility and could promote cornea repair &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt;. This study suggests that the injectable biocompatible double network hydrogel may provide a good choice for corneal repair and regeneration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Melanopsin retinal ganglion cells mediate light-promoted brain development</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35944541/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35944541/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Light sensation through ipRGCs early in life promotes cortical synaptogenesis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Light enhances CSF oxytocin level via an ipRGCs-SON-PVN oxytocin neuron circuit&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Oxytocin is essential for light-promoted ipRGC-mediated synaptogenesis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lack of light sensation in early development impairs learning ability in adult mice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During development, melanopsin-expressing intrinsically photosensitive retinal ganglion cells (ipRGCs) become light sensitive much earlier than rods and cones. IpRGCs project to many subcortical areas, whereas physiological functions of these projections are yet to be fully elucidated. Here, we found that ipRGC-mediated light sensation promotes synaptogenesis of pyramidal neurons in various cortices and the hippocampus. This phenomenon depends on activation of ipRGCs and is mediated by the release of oxytocin from the supraoptic nucleus (SON) and the paraventricular nucleus (PVN) into cerebral-spinal fluid. We further characterized a direct connection between ipRGCs and oxytocin neurons in the SON and mutual projections between oxytocin neurons in the SON and PVN. Moreover, we showed that the lack of ipRGC-mediated, light-promoted early cortical synaptogenesis compromised learning ability in adult mice. Our results highlight the importance of light sensation early in life on the development of learning ability and therefore call attention to suitable light environment for infant care.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
