<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Single Cell | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/single-cell/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/single-cell/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Single Cell</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Single Cell</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/single-cell/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Methods for inference and analysis of cell-cell communication</title>
      <link>https://example.com/blog/2023-01-02-infer-anal-ccc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/blog/2023-01-02-infer-anal-ccc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cellphonedb.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CellPhoneDB&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a publicly available repository of curated receptors, ligands and their interactions. Subunit architecture is included for both ligands and receptors, representing heteromeric complexes accurately. This is crucial, as cell-cell communication relies on multi-subunit protein complexes that go beyond the binary representation used in most databases and studies. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cellphonedb.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CellPhoneDB&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; integrates existing datasets that pertain to cellular communication and new manually reviewed information. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cellphonedb.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CellPhoneDB&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; utilises information from the following data bases: UniProt, Ensembl, PDB, the IMEx consortium, IUPHAR. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cellphonedb.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CellPhoneDB&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; can be used to search for a particular ligand/receptor or interrogate your own single-cell transcriptomics data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Reference(s):&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/34857954/&#34;&gt;Mapping the temporal and spatial dynamics of the human endometrium in vivo and in vitro&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/32103204/&#34;&gt;CellPhoneDB: Inferring cell-cell communication from combined expression of multi-subunit receptor-ligand complexes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Research into the Human Connectome has exploded since the original Human Connectome Project grants were awarded by the NIH in 2011. Over the next decade, we expect to see dozens of new projects at institutions around the world researching aspects of how age, growth, disease, and other factors can affect the ever-changing connections in the human brain. The &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.humanconnectome.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Connectome Coordination Facility (CCF)&lt;/a&gt; has been chartered to help coordinate these myriad research projects, harmonize their data, and facilitate the distribution and dissemination of results. The CCF has three primary aims:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Run a “data acquisition help desk,” to facilitate in the collection of HCP-style data for optimal comparability.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Maintain and expand the HCP informatics infrastructure, to host and distribute connectome data from multiple studies on &lt;a href=&#34;https://db.humanconnectome.org/app/template/Login.vm&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ConnectomeDB&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and Amazon Web Services.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Serve as a “harmonization center,” to make data from multiple studies and institutions as comparable as possible.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The goal of &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/arc85/celltalker&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;celltalker&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is to infer putative ligand and receptor interactions from single-cell RNAseq data. This is accomplished by evaluating known cognate ligand/receptor interactions across groups of cells. Interactions are scored by jointly weighting the expression levels of ligands and receptors, and significance is evaluated by comparing to a background distribution of scrambled ligands and receptors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Coolgenome/iTALK&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;iTALK&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is an R toolkit for characterizing and illustrating intercellular communication, developed and maintained by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mdanderson.org/research/departments-labs-institutes/labs/linghua-wang-laboratory.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Linghua Wang Lab&lt;/a&gt; at the University of Texas MD Anderson Cancer Center. &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Coolgenome/iTALK&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;iTALK&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; can be used to visualize the complexity, diversity and dynamics of cell-cell communication in a wide range of biological processes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Reference(s):&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/italk/&#34;&gt;iTALK: an R Package to Characterize and Illustrate Intercellular Communication&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Recent development of high throughput single-cell sequencing technologies has made it cost-effective to profile thousands of cells from a complex sample. Examining ligand and receptor expression patterns in the cell types identified from these datasets allows prediction of cell-to-cell communication at the level of niches, tissues and organism-wide. Here, we developed &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/forrest-lab/NATMI/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NATMI (Network Analysis Toolkit for Multicellular Interactions)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, a Python-based toolkit for multi-cellular communication network construction and network analysis of multispecies single-cell and bulk gene expression and proteomic data. &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/forrest-lab/NATMI/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NATMI&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; uses connectomeDB2020 (the most up-to-date manually curated ligand-receptor interaction list) and user supplied gene expression tables with cell type labels to predict and visualize cell-to-cell communication networks. By interrogating the Tabula Muris cell atlas we demonstrate the utility of &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/forrest-lab/NATMI/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NATMI&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; to identify cellular communities and the key ligands and receptors involved. Notably, we confirm our previous predictions from bulk data that autocrine signalling is a major feature of cell-to-cell communication networks and for the first time ever show a substantial potential for self-signalling of individual cells through hundreds of co-expressed ligand-receptor pairs. Lastly, we identify age related changes in intercellular communication between the mammary gland of 3 and 18-month-old mice in the Tabula Muris dataset. &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/forrest-lab/NATMI/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NATMI&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and our updated ligand-receptor lists are freely available to the research community.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fast, flexible and easy-to-use command-line tool to construct cell-to-cell communication networks from user-supplied multi-omics data (single-cell and bulk) in a variety of species.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Python-based (software requirements), but no additional coding in python is required. After the analysis is finished, results can be viewed directly or imported to other software of choice such as, for example, R or excel.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Built on connectomeDB2020 (default), but users can also add and interrogate their own interactions in any species or explore existing Tabula Muris, Tabula Muris Senis and FANTOM5 cell atlas datastets.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Reference(s):&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/33024107/&#34;&gt;Predicting cell-to-cell communication networks using NATMI&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cellchat.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CellChat Explorer&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; contains two major components: (a) Ligand-Receptor Interaction Explorer that allows easy exploration of our ligand-receptor interaction database, and (b) Cell-Cell Communication Atlas Explorer that allows easy exploration of the cell-cell communications for any given scRNA-seq dataset that has been processed by &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/sqjin/CellChat&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;R toolkit CellChat&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Reference(s):&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/33597522/&#34;&gt;Inference and analysis of cell-cell communication using CellChat&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/SCA-IRCM&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SingleCellSignalR&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a R package to study Cell Signaling Using Single Cell RNAseq Data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Reference(s):&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/32196115/&#34;&gt;SingleCellSignalR: inference of intercellular networks from single-cell transcriptomics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The goal of &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/saeyslab/nichenetr&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NicheNet&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is to study intercellular communication from a computational perspective. &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/saeyslab/nichenetr&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NicheNet&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; uses human or mouse gene expression data of interacting cells as input and combines this with a prior model that integrates existing knowledge on ligand-to-target signaling paths. This allows to predict ligand-receptor interactions that might drive gene expression changes in cells of interest.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Reference(s):&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/31819264/&#34;&gt;NicheNet: modeling intercellular communication by linking ligands to target genes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/blog/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Blog &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SpatialDB: a database for spatially resolved transcriptomes</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/31713629/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/31713629/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spatially resolved transcriptomic techniques allow the characterization of spatial organization of cells in tissues, which revolutionize the studies of tissue function and disease pathology. New strategies for detecting spatial gene expression patterns are emerging, and spatially resolved transcriptomic data are accumulating rapidly. However, it is not convenient for biologists to exploit these data due to the diversity of strategies and complexity in data analysis. Here, we present &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.spatialomics.org/SpatialDB&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;SpatialDB&lt;/a&gt;, the first manually curated database for spatially resolved transcriptomic techniques and datasets. The current version of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.spatialomics.org/SpatialDB&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;SpatialDB&lt;/a&gt; contains 24 datasets (305 sub-datasets) from 5 species generated by 8 spatially resolved transcriptomic techniques. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.spatialomics.org/SpatialDB&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;SpatialDB&lt;/a&gt; provides a user-friendly web interface for visualization and comparison of spatially resolved transcriptomic data. To further explore these data, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.spatialomics.org/SpatialDB&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;SpatialDB&lt;/a&gt; also provides spatially variable genes and their functional enrichment annotation. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.spatialomics.org/SpatialDB&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;SpatialDB&lt;/a&gt; offers a repository for research community to investigate the spatial cellular structure of tissues, and may bring new insights into understanding the cellular microenvironment in disease.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Single-Cell Virus Sequencing of Influenza Infections That Trigger Innate Immunity</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/31068418/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/31068418/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Influenza virus-infected cells vary widely in their expression of viral genes and only occasionally activate innate immunity. Here, we develop a new method to assess how the genetic variation in viral populations contributes to this heterogeneity. We do this by determining the transcriptome and full-length sequences of all viral genes in single cells infected with a nominally &amp;ldquo;pure&amp;rdquo; stock of influenza virus. Most cells are infected by virions with defects, some of which increase the frequency of innate-immune activation. These immunostimulatory defects are diverse and include mutations that perturb the function of the viral polymerase protein PB1, large internal deletions in viral genes, and failure to express the virus&amp;rsquo;s interferon antagonist NS1. However, immune activation remains stochastic in cells infected by virions with these defects and occasionally is triggered even by virions that express unmutated copies of all genes. Our work shows that the diverse spectrum of defects in influenza virus populations contributes to-but does not completely explain-the heterogeneity in viral gene expression and immune activation in single infected cells.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Importance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because influenza virus has a high mutation rate, many cells are infected by mutated virions. But so far, it has been impossible to fully characterize the sequence of the virion infecting any given cell, since conventional techniques such as flow cytometry and single-cell transcriptome sequencing (scRNA-seq) only detect if a protein or transcript is present, not its sequence. Here we develop a new approach that uses long-read PacBio sequencing to determine the sequences of virions infecting single cells. We show that viral genetic variation explains some but not all of the cell-to-cell variability in viral gene expression and innate immune induction. Overall, our study provides the first complete picture of how viral mutations affect the course of infection in single cells.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PAGA: graph abstraction reconciles clustering with trajectory inference through a topology preserving map of single cells</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/30890159/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/30890159/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Single-cell RNA-seq quantifies biological heterogeneity across both discrete cell types and continuous cell transitions. &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/theislab/paga&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Partition-based graph abstraction (PAGA)&lt;/a&gt; provides an interpretable graph-like map of the arising data manifold, based on estimating connectivity of manifold partitions. &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/theislab/paga&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;PAGA&lt;/a&gt; maps preserve the global topology of data, allow analyzing data at different resolutions, and result in much higher computational efficiency of the typical exploratory data analysis workflow. We demonstrate the method by inferring structure-rich cell maps with consistent topology across four hematopoietic datasets, adult planaria and the zebrafish embryo and benchmark computational performance on one million neurons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Developmental Heterogeneity of Microglia and Brain Myeloid Cells Revealed by Deep Single-Cell RNA Sequencing</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/30606613/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/30606613/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Microglia are increasingly recognized for their major contributions during brain development and neurodegenerative disease. It is currently unknown whether these functions are carried out by subsets of microglia during different stages of development and adulthood or within specific brain regions. Here, we performed deep single-cell RNA sequencing (scRNA-seq) of microglia and related myeloid cells sorted from various regions of embryonic, early postnatal, and adult mouse brains. We found that the majority of adult microglia expressing homeostatic genes are remarkably similar in transcriptomes, regardless of brain region. By contrast, early postnatal microglia are more heterogeneous. We discovered a proliferative-region-associated microglia (PAM) subset, mainly found in developing white matter, that shares a characteristic gene signature with degenerative disease-associated microglia (DAM). Such PAM have amoeboid morphology, are metabolically active, and phagocytose newly formed oligodendrocytes. This scRNA-seq atlas will be a valuable resource for dissecting innate immune functions in health and disease.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-renewing resident cardiac macrophages limit adverse remodeling following myocardial infarction</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/30538339/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/30538339/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Erratum in:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Publisher Correction: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nature.com/articles/s41590-019-0363-8&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Self-renewing resident cardiac macrophages limit adverse remodeling following myocardial infarction&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Macrophages promote both injury and repair after myocardial infarction, but discriminating functions within mixed populations remains challenging. Here we used fate mapping, parabiosis and single-cell transcriptomics to demonstrate that at steady state, TIMD4&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt;LYVE1&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt;MHC-II&lt;sup&gt;lo&lt;/sup&gt;CCR2&lt;sup&gt;-&lt;/sup&gt; resident cardiac macrophages self-renew with negligible blood monocyte input. Monocytes partially replaced resident TIMD4&lt;sup&gt;-&lt;/sup&gt;LYVE1&lt;sup&gt;-&lt;/sup&gt;MHC-II&lt;sup&gt;hi&lt;/sup&gt;CCR2&lt;sup&gt;-&lt;/sup&gt; macrophages and fully replaced TIMD4&lt;sup&gt;-&lt;/sup&gt;LYVE1&lt;sup&gt;-&lt;/sup&gt;MHC-II&lt;sup&gt;hi&lt;/sup&gt;CCR2&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; macrophages, revealing a hierarchy of monocyte contribution to functionally distinct macrophage subsets. Ischemic injury reduced TIMD4&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; and TIMD4&lt;sup&gt;-&lt;/sup&gt; resident macrophage abundance, whereas CCR2&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; monocyte-derived macrophages adopted multiple cell fates within infarcted tissue, including those nearly indistinguishable from resident macrophages. Recruited macrophages did not express TIMD4, highlighting the ability of TIMD4 to track a subset of resident macrophages in the absence of fate mapping. Despite this similarity, inducible depletion of resident macrophages using a Cx3cr1-based system led to impaired cardiac function and promoted adverse remodeling primarily within the peri-infarct zone, revealing a nonredundant, cardioprotective role of resident cardiac macrophages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Single-cell transcriptomics of the mouse kidney reveals potential cellular targets of kidney disease</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/29622724/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/29622724/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Touring the kidney, cell by cell&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our kidneys play a critical role in keeping us healthy, a fact of which we are reminded several times each day. This organ&amp;rsquo;s cellular complexity has hindered progress in understanding the mechanisms underlying chronic kidney disease, which affects 10% of the world&amp;rsquo;s population. Using single-cell transcriptional profiling, Park et al. produced a comprehensive cell atlas of the healthy mouse kidney (see the Perspective by Humphreys). An unexpected cell type in the collecting duct appears to be a transitional state between two known cell types. The transition from one cell type to the other is regulated by the Notch signaling pathway and is associated with metabolic acidosis. The authors also find that genetically distinct kidney diseases with common clinical features share common cellular origins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our understanding of kidney disease pathogenesis is limited by an incomplete molecular characterization of the cell types responsible for the organ’s multiple homeostatic functions. To help fill this knowledge gap, we characterized 57,979 cells from healthy mouse kidneys by using unbiased single-cell RNA sequencing. On the basis of gene expression patterns, we infer that inherited kidney diseases that arise from distinct genetic mutations but share the same phenotypic manifestation originate from the same differentiated cell type. We also found that the collecting duct in kidneys of adult mice generates a spectrum of cell types through a newly identified transitional cell. Computational cell trajectory analysis and in vivo lineage tracing revealed that intercalated cells and principal cells undergo transitions mediated by the Notch signaling pathway. In mouse and human kidney disease, these transitions were shifted toward a principal cell fate and were associated with metabolic acidosis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reversed graph embedding resolves complex single-cell trajectories</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/28825705/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/28825705/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Single-cell trajectories can unveil how gene regulation governs cell fate decisions. However, learning the structure of complex trajectories with multiple branches remains a challenging computational problem. We present Monocle 2, an algorithm that uses reversed graph embedding to describe multiple fate decisions in a fully unsupervised manner. We applied Monocle 2 to two studies of blood development and found that mutations in the genes encoding key lineage transcription factors divert cells to alternative fates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Landscape of Infiltrating T Cells in Liver Cancer Revealed by Single-Cell Sequencing</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/28622514/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/28622514/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Systematic interrogation of tumor-infiltrating lymphocytes is key to the development of immunotherapies and the prediction of their clinical responses in cancers. Here, we perform deep single-cell RNA sequencing on 5,063 single T cells isolated from peripheral blood, tumor, and adjacent normal tissues from six hepatocellular carcinoma patients. The transcriptional profiles of these individual cells, coupled with assembled T cell receptor (TCR) sequences, enable us to identify 11 T cell subsets based on their molecular and functional properties and delineate their developmental trajectory. Specific subsets such as exhausted CD8+ T cells and Tregs are preferentially enriched and potentially clonally expanded in hepatocellular carcinoma (HCC), and we identified signature genes for each subset. One of the genes, layilin, is upregulated on activated CD8+ T cells and Tregs and represses the CD8+ T cell functions in vitro. This compendium of transcriptome data provides valuable insights and a rich resource for understanding the immune landscape in cancers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Single-cell mRNA quantification and differential analysis with Census</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/28114287/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/28114287/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Single-cell gene expression studies promise to reveal rare cell types and cryptic states, but the high variability of single-cell RNA-seq measurements frustrates efforts to assay transcriptional differences between cells. We introduce the Census algorithm to convert relative RNA-seq expression levels into relative transcript counts without the need for experimental spike-in controls. Analyzing changes in relative transcript counts led to dramatic improvements in accuracy compared to normalized read counts and enabled new statistical tests for identifying developmentally regulated genes. Census counts can be analyzed with widely used regression techniques to reveal changes in cell-fate-dependent gene expression, splicing patterns and allelic imbalances. We reanalyzed single-cell data from several developmental and disease studies, and demonstrate that Census enabled robust analysis at multiple layers of gene regulation. Census is freely available through our updated single-cell analysis toolkit, Monocle 2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The dynamics and regulators of cell fate decisions are revealed by pseudotemporal ordering of single cells</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/24658644/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/24658644/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Defining the transcriptional dynamics of a temporal process such as cell differentiation is challenging owing to the high variability in gene expression between individual cells. Time-series gene expression analyses of bulk cells have difficulty distinguishing early and late phases of a transcriptional cascade or identifying rare subpopulations of cells, and single-cell proteomic methods rely on a priori knowledge of key distinguishing markers. Here we describe Monocle, an unsupervised algorithm that increases the temporal resolution of transcriptome dynamics using single-cell RNA-Seq data collected at multiple time points. Applied to the differentiation of primary human myoblasts, Monocle revealed switch-like changes in expression of key regulatory factors, sequential waves of gene regulation, and expression of regulators that were not known to act in differentiation. We validated some of these predicted regulators in a loss-of function screen. Monocle can in principle be used to recover single-cell gene expression kinetics from a wide array of cellular processes, including differentiation, proliferation and oncogenic transformation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
