<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Single Cell | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/single-cell/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/single-cell/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Single Cell</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Single Cell</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/single-cell/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>A single-cell transcriptomic atlas of exercise-induced anti-inflammatory and geroprotective effects across the body</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/23-01-07-09-09/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/23-01-07-09-09/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therapeutics that discriminate between the genetic makeup of normal cells and tumour cells are valuable for treating and understanding cancer. Small molecules with oncogene-selective lethality may reveal novel functions of oncoproteins and enable the creation of more selective drugs. Here we describe the mechanism of action of the selective anti-tumour agent erastin, involving the RAS-RAF-MEK signalling pathway functioning in cell proliferation, differentiation and survival. Erastin exhibits greater lethality in human tumour cells harbouring mutations in the oncogenes HRAS, KRAS or BRAF. Using affinity purification and mass spectrometry, we discovered that erastin acts through mitochondrial voltage-dependent anion channels (VDACs)&amp;ndash;a novel target for anti-cancer drugs. We show that erastin treatment of cells harbouring oncogenic RAS causes the appearance of oxidative species and subsequent death through an oxidative, non-apoptotic mechanism. RNA-interference-mediated knockdown of VDAC2 or VDAC3 caused resistance to erastin, implicating these two VDAC isoforms in the mechanism of action of erastin. Moreover, using purified mitochondria expressing a single VDAC isoform, we found that erastin alters the permeability of the outer mitochondrial membrane. Finally, using a radiolabelled analogue and a filter-binding assay, we show that erastin binds directly to VDAC2. These results demonstrate that ligands to VDAC proteins can induce non-apoptotic cell death selectively in some tumour cells harbouring activating mutations in the RAS-RAF-MEK pathway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Identification of astrocyte regulators by nucleic acid cytometry</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36599367/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36599367/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Multiple sclerosis (MS) is a chronic inflammatory disease of the central nervous system (CNS). Astrocytes are heterogeneous CNS-resident glial cells that participate in the pathogenesis of MS and its model experimental autoimmune encephalomyelitis (EAE). However, few unique surface markers are available for the isolation of astrocyte subsets, preventing their analysis and the identification of candidate therapeutic targets; these limitations are further amplified by the rarity of pathogenic astrocytes. To address these challenges, we developed FIND-seq (&lt;u&gt;F&lt;/u&gt;ocused &lt;u&gt;I&lt;/u&gt;nterrogation of cells by &lt;u&gt;N&lt;/u&gt;ucleic acid &lt;u&gt;D&lt;/u&gt;etection and &lt;u&gt;Seq&lt;/u&gt;uencing), a high-throughput microfluidic cytometry method that combines encapsulation of cells in droplets, PCR-based detection of target nucleic acids, and droplet sorting to enable in-depth transcriptomic analyses of cells of interest at single-cell resolution. We applied FIND-seq to study the regulation of astrocytes characterized by the splicing-driven activation of the transcription factor XBP1, which promotes disease pathology in MS and EAE. Using FIND-seq in combination with conditional knock-out mice, in vivo CRISPR/Cas9-driven genetic perturbation studies, and bulk and single-cell RNA-seq analyses of mouse EAE and human MS samples, we identified a new role for the nuclear receptor NR3C2 and its corepressor NCOR2 in limiting XBP1-driven pathogenic astrocyte responses. In summary, FIND-seq enabled the identification of a therapeutically targetable mechanism that limits XBP1-driven pathogenic astrocyte responses. FIND-seq allows the investigation of previously inaccessible cells, including rare cell subsets defined by unique gene expression signatures or other nucleic acid markers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Methods for inference and analysis of cell-cell communication</title>
      <link>https://example.com/blog/2023-01-02-infer-anal-ccc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/blog/2023-01-02-infer-anal-ccc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cellphonedb.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CellPhoneDB&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a publicly available repository of curated receptors, ligands and their interactions. Subunit architecture is included for both ligands and receptors, representing heteromeric complexes accurately. This is crucial, as cell-cell communication relies on multi-subunit protein complexes that go beyond the binary representation used in most databases and studies. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cellphonedb.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CellPhoneDB&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; integrates existing datasets that pertain to cellular communication and new manually reviewed information. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cellphonedb.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CellPhoneDB&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; utilises information from the following data bases: UniProt, Ensembl, PDB, the IMEx consortium, IUPHAR. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cellphonedb.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CellPhoneDB&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; can be used to search for a particular ligand/receptor or interrogate your own single-cell transcriptomics data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Reference(s):&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/34857954/&#34;&gt;Mapping the temporal and spatial dynamics of the human endometrium in vivo and in vitro&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/32103204/&#34;&gt;CellPhoneDB: Inferring cell-cell communication from combined expression of multi-subunit receptor-ligand complexes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Research into the Human Connectome has exploded since the original Human Connectome Project grants were awarded by the NIH in 2011. Over the next decade, we expect to see dozens of new projects at institutions around the world researching aspects of how age, growth, disease, and other factors can affect the ever-changing connections in the human brain. The &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.humanconnectome.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Connectome Coordination Facility (CCF)&lt;/a&gt; has been chartered to help coordinate these myriad research projects, harmonize their data, and facilitate the distribution and dissemination of results. The CCF has three primary aims:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Run a “data acquisition help desk,” to facilitate in the collection of HCP-style data for optimal comparability.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Maintain and expand the HCP informatics infrastructure, to host and distribute connectome data from multiple studies on &lt;a href=&#34;https://db.humanconnectome.org/app/template/Login.vm&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ConnectomeDB&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and Amazon Web Services.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Serve as a “harmonization center,” to make data from multiple studies and institutions as comparable as possible.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The goal of &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/arc85/celltalker&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;celltalker&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is to infer putative ligand and receptor interactions from single-cell RNAseq data. This is accomplished by evaluating known cognate ligand/receptor interactions across groups of cells. Interactions are scored by jointly weighting the expression levels of ligands and receptors, and significance is evaluated by comparing to a background distribution of scrambled ligands and receptors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Coolgenome/iTALK&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;iTALK&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is an R toolkit for characterizing and illustrating intercellular communication, developed and maintained by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mdanderson.org/research/departments-labs-institutes/labs/linghua-wang-laboratory.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Linghua Wang Lab&lt;/a&gt; at the University of Texas MD Anderson Cancer Center. &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Coolgenome/iTALK&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;iTALK&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; can be used to visualize the complexity, diversity and dynamics of cell-cell communication in a wide range of biological processes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Reference(s):&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/italk/&#34;&gt;iTALK: an R Package to Characterize and Illustrate Intercellular Communication&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Recent development of high throughput single-cell sequencing technologies has made it cost-effective to profile thousands of cells from a complex sample. Examining ligand and receptor expression patterns in the cell types identified from these datasets allows prediction of cell-to-cell communication at the level of niches, tissues and organism-wide. Here, we developed &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/forrest-lab/NATMI/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NATMI (Network Analysis Toolkit for Multicellular Interactions)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, a Python-based toolkit for multi-cellular communication network construction and network analysis of multispecies single-cell and bulk gene expression and proteomic data. &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/forrest-lab/NATMI/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NATMI&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; uses connectomeDB2020 (the most up-to-date manually curated ligand-receptor interaction list) and user supplied gene expression tables with cell type labels to predict and visualize cell-to-cell communication networks. By interrogating the Tabula Muris cell atlas we demonstrate the utility of &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/forrest-lab/NATMI/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NATMI&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; to identify cellular communities and the key ligands and receptors involved. Notably, we confirm our previous predictions from bulk data that autocrine signalling is a major feature of cell-to-cell communication networks and for the first time ever show a substantial potential for self-signalling of individual cells through hundreds of co-expressed ligand-receptor pairs. Lastly, we identify age related changes in intercellular communication between the mammary gland of 3 and 18-month-old mice in the Tabula Muris dataset. &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/forrest-lab/NATMI/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NATMI&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and our updated ligand-receptor lists are freely available to the research community.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fast, flexible and easy-to-use command-line tool to construct cell-to-cell communication networks from user-supplied multi-omics data (single-cell and bulk) in a variety of species.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Python-based (software requirements), but no additional coding in python is required. After the analysis is finished, results can be viewed directly or imported to other software of choice such as, for example, R or excel.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Built on connectomeDB2020 (default), but users can also add and interrogate their own interactions in any species or explore existing Tabula Muris, Tabula Muris Senis and FANTOM5 cell atlas datastets.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Reference(s):&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/33024107/&#34;&gt;Predicting cell-to-cell communication networks using NATMI&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cellchat.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CellChat Explorer&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; contains two major components: (a) Ligand-Receptor Interaction Explorer that allows easy exploration of our ligand-receptor interaction database, and (b) Cell-Cell Communication Atlas Explorer that allows easy exploration of the cell-cell communications for any given scRNA-seq dataset that has been processed by &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/sqjin/CellChat&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;R toolkit CellChat&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Reference(s):&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/33597522/&#34;&gt;Inference and analysis of cell-cell communication using CellChat&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/SCA-IRCM&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SingleCellSignalR&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a R package to study Cell Signaling Using Single Cell RNAseq Data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Reference(s):&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/32196115/&#34;&gt;SingleCellSignalR: inference of intercellular networks from single-cell transcriptomics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The goal of &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/saeyslab/nichenetr&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NicheNet&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is to study intercellular communication from a computational perspective. &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/saeyslab/nichenetr&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NicheNet&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; uses human or mouse gene expression data of interacting cells as input and combines this with a prior model that integrates existing knowledge on ligand-to-target signaling paths. This allows to predict ligand-receptor interactions that might drive gene expression changes in cells of interest.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Reference(s):&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/31819264/&#34;&gt;NicheNet: modeling intercellular communication by linking ligands to target genes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/blog/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Blog &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Molecular and spatial signatures of mouse brain aging at single-cell resolution</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36580914/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36580914/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Molecular and cellular architecture of aging frontal cortex and striatum is mapped&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Aging induces spatially dependent cell-state changes in non-neuronal cells&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;White matter is a hotspot for aging-related glial and immune cell activation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Aging- and LPS-induced brain inflammation exhibit similarities and differences&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Summary&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The diversity and complex organization of cells in the brain have hindered systematic characterization of age-related changes in its cellular and molecular architecture, limiting our ability to understand the mechanisms underlying its functional decline during aging. Here, we generated a high-resolution cell atlas of brain aging within the frontal cortex and striatum using spatially resolved single-cell transcriptomics and quantified changes in gene expression and spatial organization of major cell types in these regions over the mouse lifespan. We observed substantially more pronounced changes in cell state, gene expression, and spatial organization of non-neuronal cells over neurons. Our data revealed molecular and spatial signatures of glial and immune cell activation during aging, particularly enriched in the subcortical white matter, and identified both similarities and notable differences in cell-activation patterns induced by aging and systemic inflammatory challenge. These results provide critical insights into age-related decline and inflammation in the brain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multimodal chromatin profiling using nanobody-based single-cell CUT&amp;Tag</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36536148/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36536148/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Probing histone modifications at a single-cell level in thousands of cells has been enabled by technologies such as single-cell CUT&amp;amp;Tag. Here we describe nano-CUT&amp;amp;Tag (nano-CT), which allows simultaneous mapping of up to three epigenomic modalities at single-cell resolution using nanobody-Tn5 fusion proteins. Multimodal nano-CT is compatible with starting materials as low as 25,000-200,000 cells and has significantly higher sensitivity and number of fragments per cell than single-cell CUT&amp;amp;Tag. We use nano-CT to simultaneously profile chromatin accessibility, H3K27ac, and H3K27me3 in juvenile mouse brain, allowing for discrimination of more cell types and states than unimodal single-cell CUT&amp;amp;Tag. We also infer chromatin velocity between assay for transposase-accessible chromatin (ATAC) and H3K27ac in the oligodendrocyte lineage and deconvolute H3K27me3 repressive states, finding two sequential waves of H3K27me3 repression at distinct gene modules during oligodendrocyte lineage progression. Given its high resolution, versatility, and multimodal features, nano-CT allows unique insights in epigenetic landscapes in complex biological systems at the single-cell level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A human fetal lung cell atlas uncovers proximal-distal gradients of differentiation and key regulators of epithelial fates</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36493756/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36493756/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spatiotemporal atlas of human lung development identifies 144 cell types/states&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tracking the developmental origins of multiple cell types, including new progenitors&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Functional diversity of fibroblasts in distinct anatomical signaling niches&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Experimental validation of TFs controlling neuroendocrine cell heterogeneity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We present a multiomic cell atlas of human lung development that combines single-cell RNA and ATAC sequencing, high-throughput spatial transcriptomics, and single-cell imaging. Coupling single-cell methods with spatial analysis has allowed a comprehensive cellular survey of the epithelial, mesenchymal, endothelial, and erythrocyte/leukocyte compartments from 5–22 post-conception weeks. We identify previously uncharacterized cell states in all compartments. These include developmental-specific secretory progenitors and a subtype of neuroendocrine cell related to human small cell lung cancer. Our datasets are available through our web interface (&lt;a href=&#34;https://lungcellatlas.org&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://lungcellatlas.org&lt;/a&gt;). To illustrate its general utility, we use our cell atlas to generate predictions about cell-cell signaling and transcription factor hierarchies which we rigorously test using organoid models.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Complexity of enhancer networks predicts cell identity and disease genes revealed by single-cell multi-omics analysis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36464486/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36464486/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many enhancers exist as clusters in the genome and control cell identity and disease genes; however, the underlying mechanism remains largely unknown. Here, we introduce an algorithm, eNet, to build enhancer networks by integrating single-cell chromatin accessibility and gene expression profiles. The complexity of enhancer networks is assessed by two metrics: the number of enhancers and the frequency of predicted enhancer interactions (PEIs) based on chromatin co-accessibility. We apply eNet algorithm to a human blood dataset and find cell identity and disease genes tend to be regulated by complex enhancer networks. The network hub enhancers (enhancers with frequent PEIs) are the most functionally important. Compared with super-enhancers, enhancer networks show better performance in predicting cell identity and disease genes. eNet is robust and widely applicable in various human or mouse tissues datasets. Thus, we propose a model of enhancer networks containing three modes: Simple, Multiple and Complex, which are distinguished by their complexity in regulating gene expression. Taken together, our work provides an unsupervised approach to simultaneously identify key cell identity and disease genes and explore the underlying regulatory relationships among enhancers in single cells.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>B cell expansion hinders the stroma-epithelium regenerative cross talk during mucosal healing</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36462502/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36462502/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;B cells are the dominant immune cell type during colonic mucosal healing (MH)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;IFN-induced B cells are associated with injury and expand during MH&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;B cell depletion results in enhanced MH following intestinal injury&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;B cells impair the interactions between IEC and stromal cells during MH&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therapeutic promotion of intestinal regeneration holds great promise, but defining the cellular mechanisms that influence tissue regeneration remains an unmet challenge. To gain insight into the process of mucosal healing, we longitudinally examined the immune cell composition during intestinal damage and regeneration. B cells were the dominant cell type in the healing colon, and single-cell RNA sequencing (scRNA-seq) revealed expansion of an IFN-induced B cell subset during experimental mucosal healing that predominantly located in damaged areas and associated with colitis severity. B cell depletion accelerated recovery upon injury, decreased epithelial ulceration, and enhanced gene expression programs associated with tissue remodeling. scRNA-seq from the epithelial and stromal compartments combined with spatial transcriptomics and multiplex immunostaining showed that B cells decreased interactions between stromal and epithelial cells during mucosal healing. Activated B cells disrupted the epithelial-stromal cross talk required for organoid survival. Thus, B cell expansion during injury impairs epithelial-stromal cell interactions required for mucosal healing, with implications for the treatment of IBD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>High-resolution single-cell atlas reveals diversity and plasticity of tissue-resident neutrophils in non-small cell lung cancer</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36368318/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36368318/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Non-small cell lung cancer (NSCLC) is characterized by molecular heterogeneity with diverse immune cell infiltration patterns, which has been linked to therapy sensitivity and resistance. However, full understanding of how immune cell phenotypes vary across different patient subgroups is lacking. Here, we dissect the NSCLC tumor microenvironment at high resolution by integrating 1,283,972 single cells from 556 samples and 318 patients across 29 datasets, including our dataset capturing cells with low mRNA content. We stratify patients into immune-deserted, B cell, T cell, and myeloid cell subtypes. Using bulk samples with genomic and clinical information, we identify cellular components associated with tumor histology and genotypes. We then focus on the analysis of tissue-resident neutrophils (TRNs) and uncover distinct subpopulations that acquire new functional properties in the tissue microenvironment, providing evidence for the plasticity of TRNs. Finally, we show that a TRN-derived gene signature is associated with anti-programmed cell death ligand 1 (PD-L1) treatment failure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Single-cell transcriptome analysis of the in vivo response to viral infection in the cave nectar bat Eonycteris spelaea</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36351376/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36351376/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;scRNAseq analyses of bat lung immune cells upon &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt; viral infection&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;E. spelaea&lt;/em&gt; neutrophils have high basal expression of IDO1&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Antiviral responses upon &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt; infection driven primarily by lung myeloid cells&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Transcriptional evidence of broad NK and T cells activation early after infection&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bats are reservoir hosts of many zoonotic viruses with pandemic potential. We utilized single-cell transcriptome sequencing (scRNA-seq) to analyze the immune response in bat lungs upon &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt; infection with a double-stranded RNA virus, &lt;em&gt;Pteropine orthoreovirus&lt;/em&gt; PRV3M. Bat neutrophils were distinguished by high basal &lt;em&gt;IDO1&lt;/em&gt; expression. NK cells and T cells were the most abundant immune cells in lung tissue. Three distinct CD8&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; effector T cell populations could be delineated by differential expression of &lt;em&gt;KLRB1&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;GFRA2&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;DPP4&lt;/em&gt;. Select NK and T clusters increased expression of genes involved in T cell activation and effector function early after viral infection. Alveolar macrophages and classical monocytes drove antiviral interferon signaling. Infection expanded a &lt;em&gt;CSF1R&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; population expressing collagen-like genes, which became the predominant myeloid cell type post-infection. This work uncovers features relevant to viral disease tolerance in bats, lays a foundation for future experimental work, and serves as a resource for comparative immunology studies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integrating bulk and single-cell sequencing reveals the phenotype-associated cell subpopulations in sepsis-induced acute lung injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36405762/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36405762/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The dysfunctional immune response and multiple organ injury in sepsis is a recurrent theme impacting prognosis and mortality, while the lung is the first organ invaded by sepsis. To systematically elucidate the transcriptomic changes in the main constituent cells of sepsis-injured lung tissue, we applied single-cell RNA sequencing to the lung tissue samples from septic and control mice and created a comprehensive cellular landscape with 25044 cells, including 11317 immune and 13727 non-immune cells. Sepsis alters the composition of all cellular compartments, particularly neutrophils, monocytes, T cells, endothelial, and fibroblasts populations. Our study firstly provides a single-cell view of cellular changes in septic lung injury. Furthermore, by integrating bulk sequencing data and single-cell data with the Scissors-method, we identified the cell subpopulations that are most associated with septic lung injury phenotype. The phenotypic-related cell subpopulations identified by Scissors-method were consistent with the cell subpopulations with significant composition changes. The function analysis of the differentially expressed genes (DEGs) and the cell-cell interaction analysis further reveal the important role of these phenotype-related subpopulations in septic lung injury. Our research provides a rich resource for understanding cellular changes and provides insights into the contributions of specific cell types to the biological processes that take place during sepsis-induced lung injury.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spatially resolved epigenomic profiling of single cells in complex tissues</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36272405/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36272405/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Epigenomic MERFISH enables spatially resolved single-cell epigenomic profiling&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Epigenomic MERFISH maps active promoters and putative enhancers in mouse brain&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Epigenomic MERFISH reveals putative enhancer hubs in embryonic mouse brain&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Epigenomic MERFISH images show sub-nuclear distributions of epigenetic loci&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The recent development of spatial omics methods has enabled single-cell profiling of the transcriptome and 3D genome organization with high spatial resolution. Expanding the repertoire of spatial omics tools, a spatially resolved single-cell epigenomics method will accelerate understanding of the spatial regulation of cell and tissue functions. Here, we report a method for spatially resolved epigenomic profiling of single cells using in situ tagmentation and transcription followed by multiplexed imaging. We demonstrated the ability to profile histone modifications marking active promoters, putative enhancers, and silent promoters in individual cells, and generated high-resolution spatial atlas of hundreds of active promoters and putative enhancers in embryonic and adult mouse brains. Our results suggested putative promoter-enhancer pairs and enhancer hubs regulating developmentally important genes. We envision this approach will be generally applicable to spatial profiling of epigenetic modifications and DNA-binding proteins, advancing our understanding of how gene expression is spatiotemporally regulated by the epigenome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Single-cell technologies: From research to application</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/36353677/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/36353677/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In recent years, more and more single-cell technologies have been developed. A vast amount of single-cell omics data has been generated by large projects, such as the Human Cell Atlas, the Mouse Cell Atlas, the Mouse RNA Atlas, the Mouse ATAC Atlas, and the Plant Cell Atlas. Based on these single-cell big data, thousands of bioinformatics algorithms for quality control, clustering, cell-type annotation, developmental inference, cell-cell transition, cell-cell interaction, and spatial analysis are developed. With powerful experimental single-cell technology and state-of-the-art big data analysis methods based on artificial intelligence, the molecular landscape at the single-cell level can be revealed. With spatial transcriptomics and single-cell multi-omics, even the spatial dynamic multi-level regulatory mechanisms can be deciphered. Such single-cell technologies have many successful applications in oncology, assisted reproduction, embryonic development, and plant breeding. We not only review the experimental and bioinformatics methods for single-cell research, but also discuss their applications in various fields and forecast the future directions for single-cell technologies. We believe that spatial transcriptomics and single-cell multi-omics will become the next booming business for mechanism research and commercial industry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comprehensive single-cell transcriptional profiling defines shared and unique epithelial injury responses during kidney fibrosis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36265491/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36265491/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The underlying cellular events driving kidney fibrogenesis and metabolic dysfunction are incompletely understood. Here, we employed single-cell combinatorial indexing RNA sequencing to analyze 24 mouse kidneys from two fibrosis models. We profiled 309,666 cells in one experiment, representing 50 cell types/states encompassing epithelial, endothelial, immune, and stromal populations. Single-cell analysis identified diverse injury states of the proximal tubule, including two distinct early-phase populations with dysregulated lipid and amino acid metabolism, respectively. Lipid metabolism was defective in the chronic phase but was transiently activated in the very early stages of ischemia-induced injury, where we discovered increased lipid deposition and increased fatty acid β-oxidation. Perilipin 2 was identified as a surface marker of intracellular lipid droplets, and its knockdown in vitro disrupted cell energy state maintenance during lipid accumulation. Surveying epithelial cells across nephron segments identified shared and unique injury responses. Stromal cells exhibited high heterogeneity and contributed to fibrogenesis by epithelial-stromal crosstalk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Single-cell spatial transcriptomics reveals a dynamic control of metabolic zonation and liver regeneration by endothelial cell Wnt2 and Wnt9b</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36220068/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36220068/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Conserved expression of Wnt2 and Wnt9b in liver endothelial cells is identified&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wnt2 and Wnt9b deletion from endothelial cells affects gene expression in zone 3&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Endothelial Wnt2 and Wnt9b deletion affects liver regeneration after hepatectomy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Late treatment with Wnt agonist rescues regeneration after acetaminophen overdose&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Summary&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The conclusive identity of Wnts regulating liver zonation (LZ) and regeneration (LR) remains unclear despite an undisputed role of β-catenin. Using single-cell analysis, we identified a conserved Wnt2 and Wnt9b expression in endothelial cells (ECs) in zone 3. EC-elimination of Wnt2 and Wnt9b led to both loss of β-catenin targets in zone 3, and re-appearance of zone 1 genes in zone 3, unraveling dynamicity in the LZ process. Impaired LR observed in the knockouts phenocopied models of defective hepatic Wnt signaling. Administration of a tetravalent antibody to activate Wnt signaling rescued LZ and LR in the knockouts and induced zone 3 gene expression and LR in controls. Administration of the agonist also promoted LR in acetaminophen overdose acute liver failure (ALF) fulfilling an unmet clinical need. Overall, we report an unequivocal role of EC-Wnt2 and Wnt9b in LZ and LR and show the role of Wnt activators as regenerative therapy for ALF.
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HTCA: a database with an in-depth characterization of the single-cell human transcriptome</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36130266/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36130266/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Single-cell RNA-sequencing (scRNA-seq) is one of the most used single-cell omics in recent decades. The exponential growth of single-cell data has immense potential for large-scale integration and in-depth explorations that are more representative of the study population. Efforts have been made to consolidate published data, yet extensive characterization is still lacking. Many focused on raw-data database constructions while others concentrate mainly on gene expression queries. Hereby, we present &lt;a href=&#34;www.htcatlas.org&#34;&gt;HTCA&lt;/a&gt;, an interactive database constructed based on ∼2.3 million high-quality cells from ∼3000 scRNA-seq samples and comprised in-depth phenotype profiles of 19 healthy adult and matching fetal tissues. &lt;a href=&#34;www.htcatlas.org&#34;&gt;HTCA&lt;/a&gt; provides a one-stop interactive query to gene signatures, transcription factor (TF) activities, TF motifs, receptor-ligand interactions, enriched gene ontology (GO) terms, etc. across cell types in adult and fetal tissues. At the same time, &lt;a href=&#34;www.htcatlas.org&#34;&gt;HTCA&lt;/a&gt; encompasses single-cell splicing variant profiles of 16 adult and fetal tissues, spatial transcriptomics profiles of 11 adult and fetal tissues, and single-cell ATAC-sequencing (scATAC-seq) profiles of 27 adult and fetal tissues. Besides, &lt;a href=&#34;www.htcatlas.org&#34;&gt;HTCA&lt;/a&gt; provides online analysis tools to perform major steps in a typical scRNA-seq analysis. Altogether, &lt;a href=&#34;www.htcatlas.org&#34;&gt;HTCA&lt;/a&gt; allows real-time explorations of multi-omics adult and fetal phenotypic profiles and provides tools for a flexible scRNA-seq analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Long-primed germinal centres with enduring affinity maturation and clonal migration</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36131022/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36131022/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Germinal centres are the engines of antibody evolution. Here, using human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) Env protein immunogen priming in rhesus monkeys followed by a long period without further immunization, we demonstrate germinal centre B (B&lt;sub&gt;GC&lt;/sub&gt;) cells that last for at least 6 months. A 186-fold increase in B&lt;sub&gt;GC&lt;/sub&gt; cells was present by week 10 compared with conventional immunization. Single-cell transcriptional profiling showed that both light- and dark-zone germinal centre states were sustained. Antibody somatic hypermutation of B&lt;sub&gt;GC&lt;/sub&gt; cells continued to accumulate throughout the 29-week priming period, with evidence of selective pressure. Env-binding B&lt;sub&gt;GC&lt;/sub&gt; cells were still 49-fold above baseline at 29 weeks, which suggests that they could remain active for even longer periods of time. High titres of HIV-neutralizing antibodies were generated after a single booster immunization. Fully glycosylated HIV trimer protein is a complex antigen, posing considerable immunodominance challenges for B cells. Memory B cells generated under these long priming conditions had higher levels of antibody somatic hypermutation, and both memory B cells and antibodies were more likely to recognize non-immunodominant epitopes. Numerous B&lt;sub&gt;GC&lt;/sub&gt; cell lineage phylogenies spanning more than the 6-month germinal centre period were identified, demonstrating continuous germinal centre activity and selection for at least 191 days with no further antigen exposure. A long-prime, slow-delivery (12 days) immunization approach holds promise for difficult vaccine targets and suggests that patience can have great value for tuning of germinal centres to maximize antibody responses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Single-cell and spatial analysis reveal interaction of FAP&#43; fibroblasts and SPP1&#43; macrophages in colorectal cancer</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35365629/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35365629/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Colorectal cancer (CRC) is among the most common malignancies with limited treatments other than surgery. The tumor microenvironment (TME) profiling enables the discovery of potential therapeutic targets. Here, we profile 54,103 cells from tumor and adjacent tissues to characterize cellular composition and elucidate the potential origin and regulation of tumor-enriched cell types in CRC. We demonstrate that the tumor-specific FAP&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; fibroblasts and SPP1&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; macrophages were positively correlated in 14 independent CRC cohorts containing 2550 samples and validate their close localization by immuno-fluorescent staining and spatial transcriptomics. This interaction might be regulated by chemerin, TGF-β, and interleukin-1, which would stimulate the formation of immune-excluded desmoplasic structure and limit the T cell infiltration. Furthermore, we find patients with high FAP or SPP1 expression achieved less therapeutic benefit from an anti-PD-L1 therapy cohort. Our results provide a potential therapeutic strategy by disrupting FAP&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; fibroblasts and SPP1&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; macrophages interaction to improve immunotherapy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multi-omic analysis reveals divergent molecular events in scarring and regenerative wound healing</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35077667/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35077667/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Verteporfin (YAP inhibitor) treatment yields wound regeneration in mice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Divergent molecular pathways of scarring versus regeneration are defined by differential mechanical versus Wnt signaling&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Trps1 drives wound regeneration in the context of blocked mechanical signaling&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Summary&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regeneration is the holy grail of tissue repair, but skin injury typically yields fibrotic, non-functional scars. Developing pro-regenerative therapies requires rigorous understanding of the molecular progression from injury to fibrosis or regeneration. Here, we report the divergent molecular events driving skin wound cells toward scarring or regenerative fates. We profile scarring versus YAP-inhibition-induced wound regeneration at the transcriptional (single-cell RNA sequencing), protein (timsTOF proteomics), and tissue (extracellular matrix ultrastructural analysis) levels. Using cell-surface barcoding, we integrate these data to reveal fibrotic and regenerative “molecular trajectories” of healing. We show that disrupting YAP mechanotransduction yields regenerative repair by fibroblasts with activated Trps1 and Wnt signaling. Finally, via in vivo gene knockdown and overexpression in wounds, we identify Trps1 as a key regulatory gene that is necessary and partially sufficient for wound regeneration. Our findings serve as a multi-omic map of wound regeneration and could have therapeutic implications for pathologic fibroses.
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coal dust exposure triggers heterogeneity of transcriptional profiles in mouse pneumoconiosis and Vitamin D remedies</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35057792/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35057792/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Coal dust particles (CDP), an inevitable by-product of coal mining for the environment, mainly causes coal workers&amp;rsquo; pneumoconiosis (CWP). Long-term exposure to coal dust leads to a complex alternation of biological processes during regeneration and repair in the healing lung. However, the cellular and complete molecular changes associated with pulmonary homeostasis caused by respiratory coal dust particles remain unclear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; This study mainly investigated the pulmonary toxicity of respirable-sized CDP in mice using unbiased single-cell RNA sequencing. CDP (&amp;lt; 5 μm) collected from the coal mine was analyzed by Scanning Electron Microscope (SEM) and Mass Spectrometer. In addition, western blotting, Elisa, QPCR was used to detect gene expression at mRNA or protein levels. Pathological analysis including HE staining, Masson staining, immunohistochemistry, and immunofluorescence staining were performed to characterize the structure and functional alternation in the pneumoconiosis mouse and verify the reliability of single-cell sequencing results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; SEM image and Mass Spectrometer analysis showed that coal dust particles generated during coal mine production have been crushed and screened with a diameter of less than 5 µm and contained less than 10% silica. Alveolar structure and pulmonary microenvironment were destroyed, inflammatory and death (apoptosis, autophagy, and necrosis) pathways were activated, leading to pneumoconiosis in post 9 months coal dust stimulation. A distinct abnormally increased alveolar type 2 epithelial cell (AT2) were classified with a highly active state but reduced the antimicrobial-related protein expression of LYZ and Chia1 after CDP exposure. Beclin1, LC3B, LAMP2, TGF-ß, and MLPH were up-regulated induced by CDP, promoting autophagy and pulmonary fibrosis. A new subset of macrophages with M2-type polarization double expressed MLPH + /CD206 + was found in mice having pneumoconiosis but markedly decreased after the Vitamin D treatment. Activated MLPH + /CD206 + M2 macrophages secreted TGF-β1 and are sensitive to Vitamin D treatment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; This is the first study to reconstruct the pathologic progression and transcriptome pattern of coal pneumoconiosis in mice. Coal dust had obvious toxic effects on lung epithelial cells and macrophages and eventually induced pulmonary fibrosis. CDP-induced M2-type macrophages could be inhibited by VD, which may be related to the alleviation of the pulmonary fibrosis process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mapping the temporal and spatial dynamics of the human endometrium in vivo and in vitro</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34857954/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34857954/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The endometrium, the mucosal lining of the uterus, undergoes dynamic changes throughout the menstrual cycle in response to ovarian hormones. We have generated dense single-cell and spatial reference maps of the human uterus and three-dimensional endometrial organoid cultures. We dissect the signaling pathways that determine cell fate of the epithelial lineages in the lumenal and glandular microenvironments. Our benchmark of the endometrial organoids reveals the pathways and cell states regulating differentiation of the secretory and ciliated lineages both in vivo and in vitro. In vitro downregulation of WNT or NOTCH pathways increases the differentiation efficiency along the secretory and ciliated lineages, respectively. We utilize our cellular maps to deconvolute bulk data from endometrial cancers and endometriotic lesions, illuminating the cell types dominating in each of these disorders. These mechanistic insights provide a platform for future development of treatments for common conditions including endometriosis and endometrial carcinoma.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>scMethBank: a database for single-cell whole genome DNA methylation maps</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34570235/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34570235/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Single-cell bisulfite sequencing methods are widely used to assess epigenomic heterogeneity in cell states. Over the past few years, large amounts of data have been generated and facilitated deeper understanding of the epigenetic regulation of many key biological processes including early embryonic development, cell differentiation and tumor progression. It is an urgent need to build a functional resource platform with the massive amount of data. Here, we present scMethBank, the first open access and comprehensive database dedicated to the collection, integration, analysis and visualization of single-cell DNA methylation data and metadata. Current release of scMethBank includes processed single-cell bisulfite sequencing data and curated metadata of 8328 samples derived from 15 public single-cell datasets, involving two species (human and mouse), 29 cell types and two diseases. In summary, scMethBank aims to assist researchers who are interested in cell heterogeneity to explore and utilize whole genome methylation data at single-cell level by providing browse, search, visualization, download functions and user-friendly online tools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>scAPAdb: a comprehensive database of alternative polyadenylation at single-cell resolution</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34508354/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34508354/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alternative polyadenylation (APA) is a widespread regulatory mechanism of transcript diversification in eukaryotes, which is increasingly recognized as an important layer for eukaryotic gene expression. Recent studies based on single-cell RNA-seq (scRNA-seq) have revealed cell-to-cell heterogeneity in APA usage and APA dynamics across different cell types in various tissues, biological processes and diseases. However, currently available APA databases were all collected from bulk 3′-seq and/or RNA-seq data, and no existing database has provided APA information at single-cell resolution. Here, we present a user-friendly database called &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bmibig.cn/scAPAdb&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;scAPAdb&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, which provides a comprehensive and manually curated atlas of poly(A) sites, APA events and poly(A) signals at the single-cell level. Currently, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bmibig.cn/scAPAdb&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;scAPAdb&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; collects APA information from &amp;gt; 360 scRNA-seq experiments, covering six species including human, mouse and several other plant species. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bmibig.cn/scAPAdb&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;scAPAdb&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; also provides batch download of data, and users can query the database through a variety of keywords such as gene identifier, gene function and accession number. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bmibig.cn/scAPAdb&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;scAPAdb&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; would be a valuable and extendable resource for the study of cell-to-cell heterogeneity in APA isoform usages and APA-mediated gene regulation at the single-cell level under diverse cell types, tissues and species.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spatiotemporal dissection of the cell cycle with single-cell proteogenomics</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33627808/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33627808/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The cell cycle, over which cells grow and divide, is a fundamental process of life. Its dysregulation has devastating consequences, including cancer. The cell cycle is driven by precise regulation of proteins in time and space, which creates variability between individual proliferating cells. To our knowledge, no systematic investigations of such cell-to-cell proteomic variability exist. Here we present a comprehensive, spatiotemporal map of human proteomic heterogeneity by integrating proteomics at subcellular resolution with single-cell transcriptomics and precise temporal measurements of individual cells in the cell cycle. We show that around one-fifth of the human proteome displays cell-to-cell variability, identify hundreds of proteins with previously unknown associations with mitosis and the cell cycle, and provide evidence that several of these proteins have oncogenic functions. Our results show that cell cycle progression explains less than half of all cell-to-cell variability, and that most cycling proteins are regulated post-translationally, rather than by transcriptomic cycling. These proteins are disproportionately phosphorylated by kinases that regulate cell fate, whereas non-cycling proteins that vary between cells are more likely to be modified by kinases that regulate metabolism. This spatially resolved proteomic map of the cell cycle is integrated into the Human Protein Atlas and will serve as a resource for accelerating molecular studies of the human cell cycle and cell proliferation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>scGMAI: a Gaussian mixture model for clustering single-cell RNA-Seq data based on deep autoencoder</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33300547/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33300547/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rapid development of single-cell RNA sequencing (scRNA-Seq) technology provides strong technical support for accurate and efficient analyzing single-cell gene expression data. However, the analysis of scRNA-Seq is accompanied by many obstacles, including dropout events and the curse of dimensionality. Here, we propose the scGMAI, which is a new single-cell Gaussian mixture clustering method based on autoencoder networks and the fast independent component analysis (FastICA). Specifically, scGMAI utilizes autoencoder networks to reconstruct gene expression values from scRNA-Seq data and FastICA is used to reduce the dimensions of reconstructed data. The integration of these computational techniques in scGMAI leads to outperforming results compared to existing tools, including Seurat, in clustering cells from 17 public scRNA-Seq datasets. In summary, scGMAI is an effective tool for accurately clustering and identifying cell types from scRNA-Seq data and shows the great potential of its applicative power in scRNA-Seq data analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A molecular cell atlas of the human lung from single-cell RNA sequencing</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33208946/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33208946/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although single-cell RNA sequencing studies have begun to provide compendia of cell expression profiles, it has been difficult to systematically identify and localize all molecular cell types in individual organs to create a full molecular cell atlas. Here, using droplet- and plate-based single-cell RNA sequencing of approximately 75,000 human cells across all lung tissue compartments and circulating blood, combined with a multi-pronged cell annotation approach, we create an extensive cell atlas of the human lung. We define the gene expression profiles and anatomical locations of 58 cell populations in the human lung, including 41 out of 45 previously known cell types and 14 previously unknown ones. This comprehensive molecular atlas identifies the biochemical functions of lung cells and the transcription factors and markers for making and monitoring them; defines the cell targets of circulating hormones and predicts local signalling interactions and immune cell homing; and identifies cell types that are directly affected by lung disease genes and respiratory viruses. By comparing human and mouse data, we identified 17 molecular cell types that have been gained or lost during lung evolution and others with substantially altered expression profiles, revealing extensive plasticity of cell types and cell-type-specific gene expression during organ evolution including expression switches between cell types. This atlas provides the molecular foundation for investigating how lung cell identities, functions and interactions are achieved in development and tissue engineering and altered in disease and evolution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mesenchymal stem cells alleviate LPS-induced acute lung injury by inhibiting the proinflammatory function of Ly6C&#43; CD8&#43; T cells</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33024074/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33024074/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Systemic inflammatory processes, including alveolar injury, cytokine induction, and neutrophil accumulation, play key roles in the pathophysiology of acute lung injury (ALI). The immunomodulatory effects of mesenchymal stem cells (MSCs) can contribute to the treatment of inflammatory disorders. In previous studies, the focus was on innate immune cells and the effects of MSCs on ALI through CD8&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T cells remain unclear. In the present study, lipopolysaccharide (LPS) was used to induce ALI in mice. ALI mice were treated with MSCs via intratracheal instillation. Survival rate, histopathological changes, protein levels, total cell count, cytokine levels, and chemokine levels in alveolar lavage fluid were used to determine the efficacy of MSCs. Mass cytometry and single-cell RNA sequencing (scRNA-seq) were used to characterize the CD8&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T cells in the lungs. Ly6C&lt;sup&gt;-&lt;/sup&gt; CD8&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T cells are prevalent in normal mice, whereas a specialized effector phenotype expressing a high level of Ly6C is predominant in advanced disease. MSCs significantly mitigated ALI and improved survival. MSCs decreased the infiltration of CD8&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T cells, especially Ly6C&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; CD8&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T cells into the lungs. Mass cytometry revealed that CD8&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T cells expressing high Ly6C and CXCR3 levels caused tissue damage in the lungs of ALI mice, which was alleviated by MSCs. The scRNA-seq showed that Ly6C&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; CD8&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T cells exhibited a more activated phenotype and decreased expression of proinflammatory factors that were enriched the most in immune chemotaxis after treatment with MSCs. We showed that CD8&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T cells play an important role in MSC-mediated ALI remission, and both infiltration quantity and proinflammatory function were inhibited by MSCs, indicating a potential mechanism for therapeutic intervention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Immunosuppressive effects of mesenchymal stem cells on lung B cell gene expression in LPS-induced acute lung injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32977837/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32977837/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Immune system disorders play important roles in acute lung injury (ALI), and mesenchymal stem cell (MSC) treatment can reduce inflammation during ALI. In this study, we compared the changes in lung B cells during MSC treatment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; We investigated the effects of MSCs on lung B cells in a mouse model of lipopolysaccharide (LPS)-induced ALI. MSCs were administered intratracheally 4 h after LPS. As vehicle-treated controls, mice were treated with phosphate-buffered saline (PBS) containing 2% C57BL/6 (PBS group). Histopathological changes, survival rate, inflammatory factor levels, and the number of neutrophils in bronchoalveolar lavage fluid (BALF) were determined. Single-cell RNA sequencing (scRNA-Seq) analysis was performed to evaluate the transcriptional changes in lung B cells between the PBS, LPS, and LPS/MSC groups on days 3 and 7.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; MSC treatment ameliorated LPS-induced ALI, as indicated by the reductions in mortality, the levels of chemokines and cytokines in BALF, and the severity of lung tissue histopathology in ALI mice. Lung B cells in the PBS group remained undifferentiated and had an inhibitory phenotype. Based on our scRNA-Seq results, the differentially expressed genes (DEGs) in lung B cells in both the PBS group and LPS group were involved in chemotaxis processes and some proinflammatory pathways. MSC treatment inhibited the expression of chemokine genes that were upregulated by LPS and were related to the recruitment of neutrophils into lung tissues. Immunoglobulin-related gene expression was decreased in lung B cells of mice treated with LPS/MSC for 7 days. The DEGs regulated by MSCs were enriched in biological processes, including humoral immune response and apoptotic signaling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; Lung B cells played an important role in the effects of treatment of ALI with MSCs. These observations provide new insights into the mechanisms underlying the effects of MSC treatment for ALI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deciphering human macrophage development at single-cell resolution</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32499656/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32499656/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Macrophages are the first cells of the nascent immune system to emerge during embryonic development. In mice, embryonic macrophages infiltrate developing organs, where they differentiate symbiotically into tissue-resident macrophages (TRMs). However, our understanding of the origins and specialization of macrophages in human embryos is limited. Here we isolated CD45&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; haematopoietic cells from human embryos at Carnegie stages 11 to 23 and subjected them to transcriptomic profiling by single-cell RNA sequencing, followed by functional characterization of a population of CD45&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt;CD34&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt;CD44&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; yolk sac-derived myeloid-biased progenitors (YSMPs) by single-cell culture. We also mapped macrophage heterogeneity across multiple anatomical sites and identified diverse subsets, including various types of embryonic TRM (in the head, liver, lung and skin). We further traced the specification trajectories of TRMs from either yolk sac-derived primitive macrophages or YSMP-derived embryonic liver monocytes using both transcriptomic and developmental staging information, with a focus on microglia. Finally, we evaluated the molecular similarities between embryonic TRMs and their adult counterparts. Our data represent a comprehensive characterization of the spatiotemporal dynamics of early macrophage development during human embryogenesis, providing a reference for future studies of the development and function of human TRMs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integrative differential expression and gene set enrichment analysis using summary statistics for scRNA-seq studies</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32221292/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32221292/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Differential expression (DE) analysis and gene set enrichment (GSE) analysis are commonly applied in single cell RNA sequencing (scRNA-seq) studies. Here, we develop an integrative and scalable computational method, iDEA, to perform joint DE and GSE analysis through a hierarchical Bayesian framework. By integrating DE and GSE analyses, iDEA can improve the power and consistency of DE analysis and the accuracy of GSE analysis. Importantly, iDEA uses only DE summary statistics as input, enabling effective data modeling through complementing and pairing with various existing DE methods. We illustrate the benefits of iDEA with extensive simulations. We also apply iDEA to analyze three scRNA-seq data sets, where iDEA achieves up to five-fold power gain over existing GSE methods and up to 64% power gain over existing DE methods. The power gain brought by iDEA allows us to identify many pathways that would not be identified by existing approaches in these data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Defining Epidermal Basal Cell States during Skin Homeostasis and Wound Healing Using Single-Cell Transcriptomics</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32187560/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32187560/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our knowledge of transcriptional heterogeneities in epithelial stem and progenitor cell compartments is limited. Epidermal basal cells sustain cutaneous tissue maintenance and drive wound healing. Previous studies have probed basal cell heterogeneity in stem and progenitor potential, but a comprehensive dissection of basal cell dynamics during differentiation is lacking. Using single-cell RNA sequencing coupled with RNAScope and fluorescence lifetime imaging, we identify three non-proliferative and one proliferative basal cell state in homeostatic skin that differ in metabolic preference and become spatially partitioned during wound re-epithelialization. Pseudotemporal trajectory and RNA velocity analyses predict a quasi-linear differentiation hierarchy where basal cells progress from Col17a1&lt;sup&gt;Hi&lt;/sup&gt;/Trp63&lt;sup&gt;Hi&lt;/sup&gt; state to early-response state, proliferate at the juncture of these two states, or become growth arrested before differentiating into spinous cells. Wound healing induces plasticity manifested by dynamic basal-spinous interconversions at multiple basal transcriptional states. Our study provides a systematic view of epidermal cellular dynamics, supporting a revised &amp;ldquo;hierarchical-lineage&amp;rdquo; model of homeostasis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SpatialDB: a database for spatially resolved transcriptomes</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/31713629/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/31713629/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spatially resolved transcriptomic techniques allow the characterization of spatial organization of cells in tissues, which revolutionize the studies of tissue function and disease pathology. New strategies for detecting spatial gene expression patterns are emerging, and spatially resolved transcriptomic data are accumulating rapidly. However, it is not convenient for biologists to exploit these data due to the diversity of strategies and complexity in data analysis. Here, we present &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.spatialomics.org/SpatialDB&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;SpatialDB&lt;/a&gt;, the first manually curated database for spatially resolved transcriptomic techniques and datasets. The current version of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.spatialomics.org/SpatialDB&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;SpatialDB&lt;/a&gt; contains 24 datasets (305 sub-datasets) from 5 species generated by 8 spatially resolved transcriptomic techniques. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.spatialomics.org/SpatialDB&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;SpatialDB&lt;/a&gt; provides a user-friendly web interface for visualization and comparison of spatially resolved transcriptomic data. To further explore these data, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.spatialomics.org/SpatialDB&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;SpatialDB&lt;/a&gt; also provides spatially variable genes and their functional enrichment annotation. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.spatialomics.org/SpatialDB&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;SpatialDB&lt;/a&gt; offers a repository for research community to investigate the spatial cellular structure of tissues, and may bring new insights into understanding the cellular microenvironment in disease.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Single-Cell Virus Sequencing of Influenza Infections That Trigger Innate Immunity</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/31068418/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/31068418/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Influenza virus-infected cells vary widely in their expression of viral genes and only occasionally activate innate immunity. Here, we develop a new method to assess how the genetic variation in viral populations contributes to this heterogeneity. We do this by determining the transcriptome and full-length sequences of all viral genes in single cells infected with a nominally &amp;ldquo;pure&amp;rdquo; stock of influenza virus. Most cells are infected by virions with defects, some of which increase the frequency of innate-immune activation. These immunostimulatory defects are diverse and include mutations that perturb the function of the viral polymerase protein PB1, large internal deletions in viral genes, and failure to express the virus&amp;rsquo;s interferon antagonist NS1. However, immune activation remains stochastic in cells infected by virions with these defects and occasionally is triggered even by virions that express unmutated copies of all genes. Our work shows that the diverse spectrum of defects in influenza virus populations contributes to-but does not completely explain-the heterogeneity in viral gene expression and immune activation in single infected cells.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Importance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because influenza virus has a high mutation rate, many cells are infected by mutated virions. But so far, it has been impossible to fully characterize the sequence of the virion infecting any given cell, since conventional techniques such as flow cytometry and single-cell transcriptome sequencing (scRNA-seq) only detect if a protein or transcript is present, not its sequence. Here we develop a new approach that uses long-read PacBio sequencing to determine the sequences of virions infecting single cells. We show that viral genetic variation explains some but not all of the cell-to-cell variability in viral gene expression and innate immune induction. Overall, our study provides the first complete picture of how viral mutations affect the course of infection in single cells.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PAGA: graph abstraction reconciles clustering with trajectory inference through a topology preserving map of single cells</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/30890159/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/30890159/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Single-cell RNA-seq quantifies biological heterogeneity across both discrete cell types and continuous cell transitions. &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/theislab/paga&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Partition-based graph abstraction (PAGA)&lt;/a&gt; provides an interpretable graph-like map of the arising data manifold, based on estimating connectivity of manifold partitions. &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/theislab/paga&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;PAGA&lt;/a&gt; maps preserve the global topology of data, allow analyzing data at different resolutions, and result in much higher computational efficiency of the typical exploratory data analysis workflow. We demonstrate the method by inferring structure-rich cell maps with consistent topology across four hematopoietic datasets, adult planaria and the zebrafish embryo and benchmark computational performance on one million neurons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Developmental Heterogeneity of Microglia and Brain Myeloid Cells Revealed by Deep Single-Cell RNA Sequencing</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/30606613/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/30606613/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Microglia are increasingly recognized for their major contributions during brain development and neurodegenerative disease. It is currently unknown whether these functions are carried out by subsets of microglia during different stages of development and adulthood or within specific brain regions. Here, we performed deep single-cell RNA sequencing (scRNA-seq) of microglia and related myeloid cells sorted from various regions of embryonic, early postnatal, and adult mouse brains. We found that the majority of adult microglia expressing homeostatic genes are remarkably similar in transcriptomes, regardless of brain region. By contrast, early postnatal microglia are more heterogeneous. We discovered a proliferative-region-associated microglia (PAM) subset, mainly found in developing white matter, that shares a characteristic gene signature with degenerative disease-associated microglia (DAM). Such PAM have amoeboid morphology, are metabolically active, and phagocytose newly formed oligodendrocytes. This scRNA-seq atlas will be a valuable resource for dissecting innate immune functions in health and disease.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-renewing resident cardiac macrophages limit adverse remodeling following myocardial infarction</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/30538339/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/30538339/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Erratum in:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Publisher Correction: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nature.com/articles/s41590-019-0363-8&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Self-renewing resident cardiac macrophages limit adverse remodeling following myocardial infarction&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Macrophages promote both injury and repair after myocardial infarction, but discriminating functions within mixed populations remains challenging. Here we used fate mapping, parabiosis and single-cell transcriptomics to demonstrate that at steady state, TIMD4&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt;LYVE1&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt;MHC-II&lt;sup&gt;lo&lt;/sup&gt;CCR2&lt;sup&gt;-&lt;/sup&gt; resident cardiac macrophages self-renew with negligible blood monocyte input. Monocytes partially replaced resident TIMD4&lt;sup&gt;-&lt;/sup&gt;LYVE1&lt;sup&gt;-&lt;/sup&gt;MHC-II&lt;sup&gt;hi&lt;/sup&gt;CCR2&lt;sup&gt;-&lt;/sup&gt; macrophages and fully replaced TIMD4&lt;sup&gt;-&lt;/sup&gt;LYVE1&lt;sup&gt;-&lt;/sup&gt;MHC-II&lt;sup&gt;hi&lt;/sup&gt;CCR2&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; macrophages, revealing a hierarchy of monocyte contribution to functionally distinct macrophage subsets. Ischemic injury reduced TIMD4&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; and TIMD4&lt;sup&gt;-&lt;/sup&gt; resident macrophage abundance, whereas CCR2&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; monocyte-derived macrophages adopted multiple cell fates within infarcted tissue, including those nearly indistinguishable from resident macrophages. Recruited macrophages did not express TIMD4, highlighting the ability of TIMD4 to track a subset of resident macrophages in the absence of fate mapping. Despite this similarity, inducible depletion of resident macrophages using a Cx3cr1-based system led to impaired cardiac function and promoted adverse remodeling primarily within the peri-infarct zone, revealing a nonredundant, cardioprotective role of resident cardiac macrophages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Single-cell transcriptomics of the mouse kidney reveals potential cellular targets of kidney disease</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/29622724/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/29622724/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Touring the kidney, cell by cell&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our kidneys play a critical role in keeping us healthy, a fact of which we are reminded several times each day. This organ&amp;rsquo;s cellular complexity has hindered progress in understanding the mechanisms underlying chronic kidney disease, which affects 10% of the world&amp;rsquo;s population. Using single-cell transcriptional profiling, Park et al. produced a comprehensive cell atlas of the healthy mouse kidney (see the Perspective by Humphreys). An unexpected cell type in the collecting duct appears to be a transitional state between two known cell types. The transition from one cell type to the other is regulated by the Notch signaling pathway and is associated with metabolic acidosis. The authors also find that genetically distinct kidney diseases with common clinical features share common cellular origins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our understanding of kidney disease pathogenesis is limited by an incomplete molecular characterization of the cell types responsible for the organ’s multiple homeostatic functions. To help fill this knowledge gap, we characterized 57,979 cells from healthy mouse kidneys by using unbiased single-cell RNA sequencing. On the basis of gene expression patterns, we infer that inherited kidney diseases that arise from distinct genetic mutations but share the same phenotypic manifestation originate from the same differentiated cell type. We also found that the collecting duct in kidneys of adult mice generates a spectrum of cell types through a newly identified transitional cell. Computational cell trajectory analysis and in vivo lineage tracing revealed that intercalated cells and principal cells undergo transitions mediated by the Notch signaling pathway. In mouse and human kidney disease, these transitions were shifted toward a principal cell fate and were associated with metabolic acidosis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reversed graph embedding resolves complex single-cell trajectories</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/28825705/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/28825705/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Single-cell trajectories can unveil how gene regulation governs cell fate decisions. However, learning the structure of complex trajectories with multiple branches remains a challenging computational problem. We present Monocle 2, an algorithm that uses reversed graph embedding to describe multiple fate decisions in a fully unsupervised manner. We applied Monocle 2 to two studies of blood development and found that mutations in the genes encoding key lineage transcription factors divert cells to alternative fates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Landscape of Infiltrating T Cells in Liver Cancer Revealed by Single-Cell Sequencing</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/28622514/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/28622514/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Systematic interrogation of tumor-infiltrating lymphocytes is key to the development of immunotherapies and the prediction of their clinical responses in cancers. Here, we perform deep single-cell RNA sequencing on 5,063 single T cells isolated from peripheral blood, tumor, and adjacent normal tissues from six hepatocellular carcinoma patients. The transcriptional profiles of these individual cells, coupled with assembled T cell receptor (TCR) sequences, enable us to identify 11 T cell subsets based on their molecular and functional properties and delineate their developmental trajectory. Specific subsets such as exhausted CD8+ T cells and Tregs are preferentially enriched and potentially clonally expanded in hepatocellular carcinoma (HCC), and we identified signature genes for each subset. One of the genes, layilin, is upregulated on activated CD8+ T cells and Tregs and represses the CD8+ T cell functions in vitro. This compendium of transcriptome data provides valuable insights and a rich resource for understanding the immune landscape in cancers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Single-cell mRNA quantification and differential analysis with Census</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/28114287/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/28114287/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Single-cell gene expression studies promise to reveal rare cell types and cryptic states, but the high variability of single-cell RNA-seq measurements frustrates efforts to assay transcriptional differences between cells. We introduce the Census algorithm to convert relative RNA-seq expression levels into relative transcript counts without the need for experimental spike-in controls. Analyzing changes in relative transcript counts led to dramatic improvements in accuracy compared to normalized read counts and enabled new statistical tests for identifying developmentally regulated genes. Census counts can be analyzed with widely used regression techniques to reveal changes in cell-fate-dependent gene expression, splicing patterns and allelic imbalances. We reanalyzed single-cell data from several developmental and disease studies, and demonstrate that Census enabled robust analysis at multiple layers of gene regulation. Census is freely available through our updated single-cell analysis toolkit, Monocle 2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The dynamics and regulators of cell fate decisions are revealed by pseudotemporal ordering of single cells</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/24658644/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/24658644/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Defining the transcriptional dynamics of a temporal process such as cell differentiation is challenging owing to the high variability in gene expression between individual cells. Time-series gene expression analyses of bulk cells have difficulty distinguishing early and late phases of a transcriptional cascade or identifying rare subpopulations of cells, and single-cell proteomic methods rely on a priori knowledge of key distinguishing markers. Here we describe Monocle, an unsupervised algorithm that increases the temporal resolution of transcriptome dynamics using single-cell RNA-Seq data collected at multiple time points. Applied to the differentiation of primary human myoblasts, Monocle revealed switch-like changes in expression of key regulatory factors, sequential waves of gene regulation, and expression of regulators that were not known to act in differentiation. We validated some of these predicted regulators in a loss-of function screen. Monocle can in principle be used to recover single-cell gene expression kinetics from a wide array of cellular processes, including differentiation, proliferation and oncogenic transformation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mesenchymal stem cell-mediated immunomodulation of recruited mononuclear phagocytes during acute lung injury: a high-dimensional analysis study</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33500722/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jun 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33500722/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rationale:&lt;/em&gt; Acute lung injury (ALI)-recruited mononuclear phagocytes play a pivotal role in lung injury and repair. This study investigated the types of recruited mononuclear phagocytes and the immunotherapeutic effects of allograft mesenchymal stem cells (MSCs) in a mouse model of lipopolysaccharide (LPS)-induced ALI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; C57BL/6 mice were orotracheally instilled with LPS (20 mg/kg). Compact bone-derived MSCs were administered orotracheally 4 h after LPS inhalation. Mononuclear phagocytes recruited in the lung tissues were characterized at different timepoints by high-dimensional analysis including flow cytometry, mass cytometry, and single-cell RNA sequencing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; Eight mononuclear phagocyte subsets recruited to LPS-challenged lungs were precisely identified. On day 3 after LPS administration, both Ly6C&lt;sup&gt;hi&lt;/sup&gt;CD38&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; and Ly6C&lt;sup&gt;low&lt;/sup&gt;CD38&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; monocytes were recruited into acutely injured lungs, which was associated with increased secretion of neutrophil chemokines. Ly6C&lt;sup&gt;hi&lt;/sup&gt;CD38&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; monocytes differentiated into M1 macrophages on day 3, and subsequently differentiated into CD38&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; monocyte-derived dendritic cells (mo-DCs) on day 7, while Ly6C&lt;sup&gt;low&lt;/sup&gt;CD38&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; monocytes differentiated into CD11b&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt;CD38&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; DCs on day 7. When ALI mice were treated with MSCs, the mortality significantly reduced. Notably, MSCs reduced the amount of M1 macrophages and reduced the secretion of neutrophil chemokines on day 3. Furthermore, MSCs reduced the number of CD38&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; mo-DCs and CD11b&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt;CD38&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; DCs on day 7, suppressing the antigen presentation process. Recruited mononuclear phagocyte subsets with a high level of CD38 exhibited an activated phenotype and could secrete higher levels of cytokines and chemokines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; This study characterized the dynamic functions and phenotypes of recruited mononuclear phagocytes in ALI mice and MSC-treated ALI mice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>scRNA-seq of gastric tumor shows complex intercellular interaction with an alternative T cell exhaustion trajectory</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35999201/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jun 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35999201/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tumor microenvironment (TME) in gastric cancer (GC) has been shown to be important for tumor control but the specific characteristics for GC are not fully appreciated. We generated an atlas of 166,533 cells from 10 GC patients with matched paratumor tissues and blood. Our results show tumor-associated stromal cells (TASCs) have upregulated activity of Wnt signaling and angiogenesis, and are negatively correlated with survival. Tumor-associated macrophages and LAMP3&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; DCs are involved in mediating T cell activity and form intercellular interaction hubs with TASCs. Clonotype and trajectory analysis demonstrates that Tc17 (IL-17&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt;CD8&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T cells) originate from tissue-resident memory T cells and can subsequently differentiate into exhausted T cells, suggesting an alternative pathway for T cell exhaustion. Our results indicate that IL17&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; cells may promote tumor progression through IL17, IL22, and IL26 signaling, highlighting the possibility of targeting IL17&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; cells and associated signaling pathways as a therapeutic strategy to treat GC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
