<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Notch | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/notch/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/notch/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Notch</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Notch</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/notch/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gut microbiota-stem cell niche crosstalk: A new territory for maintaining intestinal homeostasis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/imt2.54/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/imt2.54/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Intestinal stem cells (ISCs) are protected by their niche and are regulated by Wnt, bone morphogenetic protein, and Notch.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ISCs and their relationship with intestinal microbiota provide a feasible pathway to alleviate intestinal diseases.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Diverse bacteria-related postbiotics regulate ISCs and maintain their homeostasis.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Intestinal epithelium undergoes rapid cellular turnover, relying on the local niche, to support intestinal stem cells (ISCs) function and self-renewal. Research into the association between ISCs and disease continues to expand at a rapid rate. However, the detailed interaction of ISCs and gut microbes remains to be elucidated. Thus, this review witnessed major advances in the crosstalk between ISCs and gut microbes, delivering key insights into (1) construction of ISC niche and molecular mechanism of how to jointly govern epithelial homeostasis and protect against intestinal diseases with the participation of Wnt, bone morphogenetic protein, and Notch; (2) differentiation fate of ISCs affect the gut microbiota. Meanwhile, the presence of intestinal microbes also regulates ISC function; (3) microbiota regulation on ISCs by Wnt and Notch signals through pattern recognition receptors; (4) how do specific microbiota-related postbiotics influence ISCs to maintain intestinal epithelial regeneration and homeostasis that provide insights into a promising alternative therapeutic method for intestinal diseases. Considering the detailed interaction is still unclear, it is necessary to further explore the regulatory role of gut microbiota on ISCs to utilize microbes to alleviate gut disorders. Furthermore, these major advances collectively drive us ever closer to breakthroughs in regenerative medicine and cancer treatment by microbial transplantation in the clinic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Molecular Mechanism of Long Non-Coding RNA (LncRNA) Regulation of Notch Signaling in Glucose-Induced Apoptosis of Human Retinal Vascular Endothelial Cell</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35715905/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35715905/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Diabetes, a global health concern, affects the health of more than 500 million adults. The absence of Notch protein can cause an imbalance in the retinal vascular environment and cause retinal vascular disease. Long noncoding RNA (lncRNA) is known to be involved in the regulation of many signaling pathways. We hope to understand the specific mechanism of apoptosis in retinal vascular endothelial cells (RVECs) by exploring the regulatory effect of lncRNA on the Notch pathway. In this study, we found that RVECs treated with glucose showed increased levels of Notch transcript and protein expression. The lentiviral interference with Notch RNAi reversed this response. When Notch activity decreased, oxidative stress also decreased, accompanied by increased levels of Caspase-9 and Caspase-3 and an increased rate of apoptosis. Therefore, we believe that Notch is involved in the development of diabetic retinopathy and loss of expression promotes apoptosis of human RVECs. By inhibiting the Notch pathway, lncRNA promotes apoptosis of human RVECs in a high-glucose environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
