<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Notch | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/notch/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/notch/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Notch</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Notch</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/notch/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gut microbiota-stem cell niche crosstalk: A new territory for maintaining intestinal homeostasis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/imt2.54/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/imt2.54/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Intestinal stem cells (ISCs) are protected by their niche and are regulated by Wnt, bone morphogenetic protein, and Notch.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ISCs and their relationship with intestinal microbiota provide a feasible pathway to alleviate intestinal diseases.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Diverse bacteria-related postbiotics regulate ISCs and maintain their homeostasis.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Intestinal epithelium undergoes rapid cellular turnover, relying on the local niche, to support intestinal stem cells (ISCs) function and self-renewal. Research into the association between ISCs and disease continues to expand at a rapid rate. However, the detailed interaction of ISCs and gut microbes remains to be elucidated. Thus, this review witnessed major advances in the crosstalk between ISCs and gut microbes, delivering key insights into (1) construction of ISC niche and molecular mechanism of how to jointly govern epithelial homeostasis and protect against intestinal diseases with the participation of Wnt, bone morphogenetic protein, and Notch; (2) differentiation fate of ISCs affect the gut microbiota. Meanwhile, the presence of intestinal microbes also regulates ISC function; (3) microbiota regulation on ISCs by Wnt and Notch signals through pattern recognition receptors; (4) how do specific microbiota-related postbiotics influence ISCs to maintain intestinal epithelial regeneration and homeostasis that provide insights into a promising alternative therapeutic method for intestinal diseases. Considering the detailed interaction is still unclear, it is necessary to further explore the regulatory role of gut microbiota on ISCs to utilize microbes to alleviate gut disorders. Furthermore, these major advances collectively drive us ever closer to breakthroughs in regenerative medicine and cancer treatment by microbial transplantation in the clinic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Notch pathway attenuates burn-induced acute lung injury in rats by repressing reactive oxygen species</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35441079/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35441079/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This study demonstrated for the first time that the Notch pathway is activated in burn-induced ALI.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ROS production and cell apoptosis of PMVECs were closely associated with the Notch signaling pathway.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Activation of the Notch pathway downregulated the expression of ROS and attenuated excessive ROS-induced injury in PMVECs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Notch signaling regulated ROS production by modulating the expression of NOX4 rather than NOX2 and SOD1.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Acute lung injury (ALI) is a common complication following severe burns. The underlying mechanisms of ALI are incompletely understood; thus, available treatments are not sufficient to repair the lung tissue after ALI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; To investigate the relationship between the Notch pathway and burn-induced lung injury, we established a rat burn injury model by scalding and verified lung injury via lung injury evaluations, including hematoxylin and eosin (H&amp;amp;E) staining, lung injury scoring, bronchoalveolar lavage fluid and wet/dry ratio analyses, myeloperoxidase immunohistochemical staining and reactive oxygen species (ROS) accumulation analysis. To explore whether burn injury affects Notch1 expression, we detected the expression of Notch1 and Hes1 after burn injury. Then, we extracted pulmonary microvascular endothelial cells (PMVECs) and conducted Notch pathway inhibition and activation experiments, via a γ-secretase inhibitor (GSI) and OP9-DLL1 coculture, respectively, to verify the regulatory effect of the Notch pathway on ROS accumulation and apoptosis in burn-serum-stimulated PMVECs. To investigate the regulatory effect of the Notch pathway on ROS accumulation, we detected the expression of oxidative-stress-related molecules such as superoxide dismutase, nicotinamide adenine dinucleotide phosphate (NADPH) oxidase (NOX) 2, NOX4 and cleaved caspase-3. NOX4-specific small interfering RNA (siRNA) and the inhibitor GKT137831 were used to verify the regulatory effect of the Notch pathway on ROS via NOX4.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; We successfully established a burn model and revealed that lung injury, excessive ROS accumulation and an inflammatory response occurred. Notch1 detection showed that the expression of Notch1 was significantly increased after burn injury. In PMVECs challenged with burn serum, ROS and cell death were elevated. Moreover, when the Notch pathway was suppressed by GSI, ROS and cell apoptosis levels were significantly increased. Conversely, these parameters were reduced when the Notch pathway was activated by OP9-DLL1. Mechanistically, the inhibition of NOX4 by siRNA and GKT137831 showed that the Notch pathway reduced ROS production and cell apoptosis by downregulating the expression of NOX4 in PMVECs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; The Notch pathway reduced ROS production and apoptosis by downregulating the expression of NOX4 in burn-stimulated PMVECs. The Notch-NOX4 pathway may be a novel therapeutic target to treat burn-induced ALI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NEDD4 attenuates phosgene-induced acute lung injury through the inhibition of Notch1 activation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35355403/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35355403/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Phosgene gas leakage can cause life-threatening acute lung injury (ALI), which is characterized by inflammation, increased vascular permeability, pulmonary oedema and oxidative stress. Although the downregulation of neuronal precursor cell-expressed developmentally downregulated 4 (NEDD4) is known to be associated with inflammation and oxidative damage, its functions in phosgene-induced ALI remain unclear. In this study, rats with phosgene-induced ALI were intravenously injected with NEDD4-overexpressing lentiviruses to determine the functions of NEDD4 in this inflammatory condition. NEDD4 expression was decreased in the lung parenchyma of phosgene-exposed control rats, whereas its expression level was high in the NEDD4-overexpressing rats. Phosgene exposure increased the wet-to-dry lung weight ratio, but NEDD4 abrogated this effect. NEDD4 overexpression attenuated phosgene-induced lung inflammation, lowering the high lung injury score (based on total protein, inflammatory cells and inflammatory factors in bronchoalveolar lavage fluid) and also reduced phosgene-induced oxidative stress and cell apoptosis. Finally, NEDD4 was found to interact with Notch1, enhancing its ubiquitination and thereby its degradation, thus attenuating the inflammatory responses to ALI. Therefore, we demonstrated that NEDD4 plays a protective role in alleviating phosgene-induced ALI, suggesting that enhancing the effect of NEDD4 may be a new approach for treating phosgene-induced ALI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Molecular Mechanism of Long Non-Coding RNA (LncRNA) Regulation of Notch Signaling in Glucose-Induced Apoptosis of Human Retinal Vascular Endothelial Cell</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35715905/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35715905/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Diabetes, a global health concern, affects the health of more than 500 million adults. The absence of Notch protein can cause an imbalance in the retinal vascular environment and cause retinal vascular disease. Long noncoding RNA (lncRNA) is known to be involved in the regulation of many signaling pathways. We hope to understand the specific mechanism of apoptosis in retinal vascular endothelial cells (RVECs) by exploring the regulatory effect of lncRNA on the Notch pathway. In this study, we found that RVECs treated with glucose showed increased levels of Notch transcript and protein expression. The lentiviral interference with Notch RNAi reversed this response. When Notch activity decreased, oxidative stress also decreased, accompanied by increased levels of Caspase-9 and Caspase-3 and an increased rate of apoptosis. Therefore, we believe that Notch is involved in the development of diabetic retinopathy and loss of expression promotes apoptosis of human RVECs. By inhibiting the Notch pathway, lncRNA promotes apoptosis of human RVECs in a high-glucose environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Endothelial Shp2 deficiency controls alternative activation of macrophage preventing radiation-induced lung injury through notch signaling</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35243230/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35243230/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Phosphatase activity of endothelial Shp2 is elevated by irradiation &lt;em&gt;in vitro&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Radiation-induced Jag1 is blocked in Shp2-deficient endothelium&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Loss of Shp2 in endothelium relieves radiation-induced pulmonary injury&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Shp2-deficient endothelium restrains macrophage activation via Notch signaling&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Radiation-induced lung injury is a common late side effect of thoracic radiotherapy. Endothelial dysfunction following leukocytes infiltration is a prominent feature in this process. Here, we established a clinical-mimicking mouse model of radiation-induced lung injury and found the activity of phosphatase Shp2 was elevated in endothelium after injury. Endothelium-specific Shp2 deletion mice showed relieved collagen deposition along with disrupted radiation-induced Jag1 expression in the endothelium. Furthermore, endothelium-derived Jag1 activated the alternative activation of macrophages &lt;em&gt;in vitro&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt; by paracrine Notch signaling. Consistently, the Notch pathway was significantly activated by chest irradiation in the peripheral blood leukocytes of patients with cancer. Collectively, our work demonstrates that Shp2 participates in the radiation-induced endothelial dysfunction and subsequently inflammatory microenvironment producing during radiation-induced lung injury. Our findings indicate Shp2 as a potential target for radiation-induced lung injury and provide another way for endothelium to participate in the pathological process of radiation-induced lung injury.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
