<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Giant Virus | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/giant-virus/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/giant-virus/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Giant Virus</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Giant Virus</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/giant-virus/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Structural and Proteomic Characterization of the Initiation of Giant Virus Infection</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32392465/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32392465/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since their discovery, giant viruses have expanded our understanding of the principles of virology. Due to their gargantuan size and complexity, little is known about the life cycles of these viruses. To answer outstanding questions regarding giant virus infection mechanisms, we set out to determine biomolecular conditions that promote giant virus genome release. We generated four infection intermediates in Samba virus (Mimivirus genus, lineage A) as visualized by cryoelectron microscopy (cryo-EM), cryoelectron tomography (cryo-ET), and scanning electron microscopy (SEM). Each of these four intermediates reflects similar morphology to a stage that occurs in vivo. We show that these genome release stages are conserved in other mimiviruses. Finally, we identified proteins that are released from Samba and newly discovered Tupanvirus through differential mass spectrometry. Our work revealed the molecular forces that trigger infection are conserved among disparate giant viruses. This study is also the first to identify specific proteins released during the initial stages of giant virus infection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Giant virus diversity and host interactions through global metagenomics</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/31968354/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/31968354/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our current knowledge about nucleocytoplasmic large DNA viruses (NCLDVs) is largely derived from viral isolates that are co-cultivated with protists and algae. Here we reconstructed 2,074 NCLDV genomes from sampling sites across the globe by building on the rapidly increasing amount of publicly available metagenome data. This led to an 11-fold increase in phylogenetic diversity and a parallel 10-fold expansion in functional diversity. Analysis of 58,023 major capsid proteins from large and giant viruses using metagenomic data revealed the global distribution patterns and cosmopolitan nature of these viruses. The discovered viral genomes encoded a wide range of proteins with putative roles in photosynthesis and diverse substrate transport processes, indicating that host reprogramming is probably a common strategy in the NCLDVs. Furthermore, inferences of horizontal gene transfer connected viral lineages to diverse eukaryotic hosts. We anticipate that the global diversity of NCLDVs that we describe here will establish giant viruses-which are associated with most major eukaryotic lineages-as important players in ecosystems across Earth&amp;rsquo;s biomes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
