<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Bladder | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/bladder/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/bladder/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Bladder</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Bladder</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/bladder/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Proper wiring of newborn neurons to control bladder function after complete spinal cord injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36455486/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36455486/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Activation of endogenous neurogenesis by bioactive materials enables restoration of sensory/motor function after complete spinal cord injury (SCI) via formation of new relay neural circuits. The underlying wiring logic of newborn neurons in adult central nervous system (CNS) is unknown. Here, we report neurotrophin3-loaded chitosan biomaterial substantially recovered bladder function after SCI. Multiple neuro-circuitry tracing technologies using pseudorabies virus (PRV), rabies virus (RV), and anterograde adeno-associated virus (AAV), demonstrated that newborn neurons were integrated into the micturition neural circuits and reconnected higher brain centers and lower spinal cord centers to control voiding, and participated in the restoration of the lower urinary tract function, even in the absence of long-distance axonal regeneration. Opto- and chemo-genetic studies further supported the notion that the supraspinal control of the lower urinary tract function was partially recovered. Our data demonstrated that regenerated relay neurons could be properly integrated into disrupted long-range neural circuits to restore function of adult CNS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
