<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Exosomes | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/exosomes/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/exosomes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Exosomes</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Exosomes</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/exosomes/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hybrid exosomes, exosome-like nanovesicles and engineered exosomes for therapeutic applications</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/36528193/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/36528193/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Exosomes are endosome-derived nanovesicles involved in cellular communication. They are natural nanocarriers secreted by various cells, making them suitable candidates for diverse drug delivery and therapeutic applications from a material standpoint. They have a phospholipid bilayer decorated with functional molecules and an enclosed parental matrix, which has attracted interest in developing designer/hybrid engineered exosome nanocarriers. The structural versatility of exosomes allows the modification of their original configuration using various methods, including genetic engineering, chemical procedures, physical techniques, and microfluidic technology, to load exosomes with additional cargo for expanded biomedical applications. Exosomes show enormous potential for overcoming the limitations of conventional nanoparticle-based techniques in targeted therapy. This review highlights the exosome sources, characteristics, state of the art in the field of hybrid exosomes, exosome-like nanovesicles and engineered exosomes as potential cargo delivery vehicles for therapeutic applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exosomes as biomarkers and therapeutic delivery for autoimmune diseases: Opportunities and challenges</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/36565798/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/36565798/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Exosomes are spherical lipid bilayer vesicles composed of lipids, proteins and nucleic acids that deliver signaling molecules through a vesicular transport system to regulate the function and morphology of target cells, thereby involving in a variety of biological processes, such as cell apoptosis or proliferation, and cytokine production. In the past decades, there are emerging evidence that exosomes play pivotal roles in the pathological mechanisms of several autoimmune diseases (ADs), including rheumatoid arthritis (RA), systemic lupus erythematosus (SLE), type 1 diabetes mellitus (T1DM), Sjogren&amp;rsquo;s syndrome (SS), multiple sclerosis (MS), inflammatory bowel disease (IBD). systemic sclerosis (SSc), etc. Several publications have shown that exosomes are involved in the pathogenesis of ADs mainly through intercellular communication and by influencing the response of immune cells. The level of exosomes and the expression of nucleic acids can reflect the degree of disease progression and are excellent biomarkers for ADs. In addition, exosomes have the potential to be used as drug carriers thanks to their biocompatibility and stability. In this review, we briefly summarized the current researches regarding the biological functions of exosomes in ADs, and provided an insight into the potential of exosomes as biomarkers and therapeutic delivery for these diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resveratrol-loaded macrophage exosomes alleviate multiple sclerosis through targeting microglia</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36521687/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36521687/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite exosome promise as endogenous drug delivery vehicles, the current understanding of exosome may be insufficient to develop their various applications. Here we synthesized five sialic acid analogues with different length N-acyl side chains and screened out the optimal metabolic precursor for exosome labeling via bio-orthogonal click chemistry. In proof-of-principle labeling experiments, exosomes derived from macrophages (RAW-Exo) strongly co-localized with central nervous system (CNS) microglia. Inspired by this discovery, we developed a resveratrol-loaded RAW-Exo formulation (RSV&amp;amp;Exo) for multiple sclerosis (MS) treatment. Intranasal administration of RSV&amp;amp;Exo significantly inhibited inflammatory responses in the CNS and peripheral system in a mouse model of MS and effectively improved the clinical evolution of MS in vivo. These findings suggested the feasibility and efficacy of engineered RSV&amp;amp;Exo administration for MS, providing a potential therapeutic strategy for CNS diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exosomal noncoding RNAs in central nervous system diseases: biological functions and potential clinical applications</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/36438184/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/36438184/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Central nervous system (CNS) disease is a general term for a series of complex and diverse diseases, including Alzheimer&amp;rsquo;s disease (AD), Parkinson&amp;rsquo;s disease (PD), multiple sclerosis (MS), CNS tumors, stroke, epilepsy, and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS). Interneuron and neuron-glia cells communicate with each other through their homeostatic microenvironment. Exosomes in the microenvironment have crucial impacts on interneuron and neuron-glia cells by transferring their contents, such as proteins, lipids, and ncRNAs, constituting a novel form of cell-to-cell interaction and communication. Exosomal noncoding RNAs (ncRNAs), including microRNAs (miRNAs), long noncoding RNAs (lncRNAs), circular RNAs (circRNAs), and PIWI-interacting RNAs (piRNAs), regulate physiological functions and maintain CNS homeostasis. Exosomes are regarded as extracellular messengers that transfer ncRNAs between neurons and body fluids due to their ability to cross the blood-brain barrier. This review aims to summarize the current understanding of exosomal ncRNAs in CNS diseases, including prospective diagnostic biomarkers, pathological regulators, therapeutic strategies and clinical applications. We also provide an all-sided discussion of the comparison with some similar CNS diseases and the main limitations and challenges for exosomal ncRNAs in clinical applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Suppression of PD-L1 release from small extracellular vesicles promotes systemic anti-tumor immunity by targeting ORAI1 calcium channels</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36482876/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36482876/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blockade of immune checkpoints as a strategy of cancer cells to overcome the immune response has received ample attention in cancer research recently. In particular, expression of PD-L1 by various cancer cells has become a paradigm in this respect. Delivery of PD-L1 to its site of action occurs either by local diffusion, or else by transport via small extracellular vesicles (sEVs, commonly referred to as exosomes). Many steps of sEVs formation, their packaging with PD-L1 and their release into the extracellular space have been studied in detail. The likely dependence of release on Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt;-signaling, however, has received little attention. This is surprising, since the intracellular Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt;-concentration is known as a prominent regulator of many secretory processes. Here, we report on the roles of three Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt;-dependent proteins in regulating release of PD-L1-containing sEVs, as well as on the growth of tumors in mouse models. We show that sEVs release in cancer cell lines is Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt;-dependent and the knockdown of the gene coding the Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt;-channel protein ORAI1 reduces Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt;-signals and release of sEVs. Consequently, the T cell response is reinvigorated and tumor progression in mouse models is retarded. Furthermore, analysis of protein expression patterns in samples from human cancer tissue shows that the ORAI1 gene is significantly upregulated. Such upregulation is identified as an unfavorable prognostic factor for survival of patients with non-small-cell lung cancer. We show that reduced Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt;-signaling after knockdown of ORAI1 gene also compromises the activity of melanophilin and Synaptotagmin-like protein 2, two proteins, which are important for correct localization of secretory organelles within cancer cells and their transport to sites of exocytosis. Thus, the Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt;-channel ORAI1 and Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt;-dependent proteins of the secretion pathway emerge as important targets for understanding and manipulating immune checkpoint blockade by PD-L1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dendritic cell derived exosomes loaded neoantigens for personalized cancer immunotherapies</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36470333/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36470333/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therapeutics that discriminate between the genetic makeup of normal cells and tumour cells are valuable for treating and understanding cancer. Small molecules with oncogene-selective lethality may reveal novel functions of oncoproteins and enable the creation of more selective drugs. Here we describe the mechanism of action of the selective anti-tumour agent erastin, involving the RAS-RAF-MEK signalling pathway functioning in cell proliferation, differentiation and survival. Erastin exhibits greater lethality in human tumour cells harbouring mutations in the oncogenes HRAS, KRAS or BRAF. Using affinity purification and mass spectrometry, we discovered that erastin acts through mitochondrial voltage-dependent anion channels (VDACs)&amp;ndash;a novel target for anti-cancer drugs. We show that erastin treatment of cells harbouring oncogenic RAS causes the appearance of oxidative species and subsequent death through an oxidative, non-apoptotic mechanism. RNA-interference-mediated knockdown of VDAC2 or VDAC3 caused resistance to erastin, implicating these two VDAC isoforms in the mechanism of action of erastin. Moreover, using purified mitochondria expressing a single VDAC isoform, we found that erastin alters the permeability of the outer mitochondrial membrane. Finally, using a radiolabelled analogue and a filter-binding assay, we show that erastin binds directly to VDAC2. These results demonstrate that ligands to VDAC proteins can induce non-apoptotic cell death selectively in some tumour cells harbouring activating mutations in the RAS-RAF-MEK pathway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exosomes in sarcoma: Prospects for clinical applications</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/36481305/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/36481305/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sarcoma is a group of rare and heterogeneous mesenchymal tumors, prone to late diagnosis and poor prognosis. Exosomes are cell-derived small extracellular vesicles found in most body fluids and contain nucleic acids, proteins, lipids, and other molecules. Qualitative and quantitative changes of exosomes and the contents are associated with sarcoma progression, exhibiting their potential as biomarkers. Exosomes possess the capacity of evading immune responses, bioactivity for trafficking, tumor tropism, and lesion residence. Thus, exosomes could be engineered as tumor-specific vehicles in drugs and RNA delivery systems. Exosomes might also serve as therapeutic targets in targeted therapy and immunotherapy and be involved in chemotherapy resistance. Here, we provide a comprehensive summary of exosome applications in liquid biopsy-based diagnosis and explore their implications in the delivery system, targeted therapy, and chemotherapy resistance of sarcoma. Moreover, challenges in exosome clinical applications are raised and some future research directions are proposed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Injectable MMP1-sensitive microspheres with spatiotemporally controlled exosome release promote neovascularized bone healing</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36481504/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36481504/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bone marrow mesenchymal stromal cell-derived exosomes (BMSC-Exos) can recruit stem cells for bone repair, with neovessels serving as the main migratory channel for stem cells to the injury site. However, existing exosome (Exo) delivery strategies cannot reach the angiogenesis phase following bone injury. To that end, an enzyme-sensitive Exo delivery material that responds to neovessel formation during the angiogenesis phase was designed in the present study to achieve spatiotemporally controlled Exo release. Herein, matrix metalloproteinase-1 (MMP1) was found to be highly expressed in neovascularized bone; as a result, we proposed an injectable MMP1-sensitive hydrogel microspheres (KGE) made using a microfluidic chip prepared by mixing self-assembling peptide (KLDL-MMP1), GelMA, and BMSC-Exos. The results revealed that KGE microspheres had a uniform diameter of 50-70 μm, ideal for minimally invasive injection and could release exosomes in response to MMP1 expression. In vitro experiments demonstrated that KGE had less cytotoxicity and could promote the migration and osteodifferentiation of BMSCs. Furthermore, in vivo experiments confirmed that KGE could promote bone repair during angiogenesis by recruiting CD90+ stem cells via neovessels. Collectively, our results suggest that injectable enzyme-responsive KGE microspheres could be a promising Exo-secreting material for accelerating neovascularized bone healing. STATEMENT OF SIGNIFICANCE: Exosomes can spread through blood vessels and activate stem cells to participate in bone repair, but under normal circumstances, exosomes lacking sustained-release delivery materials cannot be maintained until the angiogenesis phase. In this study, we found that MMP1 was highly expressed in neovascularized bone, then we proposed an MMP1-sensitive injectable microsphere that carries exosomes and responds temporally and spatially to neovascularization, which maximizes the ability of exosomes to recruit stem cells. Different from previous strategies that focus on promoting angiogenesis to accelerate bone healing, this is a brand new delivery strategy that is stimuli-responsive to neovessel formation. In addition, the preparation of self-assembled peptide microspheres by a microfluidic chip is also proposed for the first time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CD44 promotes angiogenesis in myocardial infarction through regulating plasma exosome uptake and further enhancing FGFR2 signaling transduction</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36463112/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36463112/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since angiogenesis occurs as the pathological process following myocardial infarction to alleviate ischemia, therapeutic angiogenesis has been proposed to be a cardioprotective strategy. CD44 has been implicated in endothelial cell functions and its role has been well established in angiogenesis for years. Although recent studies indicate the close correlation between CD44 and exosome, as well as the two being implicated in myocardial ischemia pathological processes, the effect and the underlying mechanism of CD44 and its regulated plasma exosome in pathological angiogenesis post-myocardial infarction have not been fully elucidated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this study, we used CD44 knockout mice to study the in vivo impacts of CD44 on ischemic angiogenesis in myocardial infarction. Mouse cardiac function was measured by echocardiography, histological changes were observed by Evans Blue and TTC-double staining and Masson’s trichrome staining, and molecular changes were detected by immunofluorescence. In the in vitro study, CD44 knockout HUVECs were generated and CD44 inhibitor was used to study the mechanism of CD44 on angiogenesis. We performed the immunoprecipitation, proximity ligation assay, and super-resolution imaging to study the mechanistic regulation of FGFR2 signaling transduction by CD44. Importantly, we also isolated plasma exosomes from myocardial infarction model mice and studied the effect of plasma exosomes on the activation of the FGFR2 signaling pathway and the related phenotypic alterations, including exosomes uptake and angiogenic function in primary mouse microvascular endothelial cells, and further discovered the regulation mechanism of exosomal miRNAs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We observed that the expression of CD44 in the border zone of the infarcted heart was tightly related to pathological angiogenesis following myocardial ischemia. The depletion of CD44 impaired angiogenesis and impacts biogenesis and proangiogenic function of plasma exosomes. Subsequently, we found that CD44 mediated the activation of the FGFR2 signaling pathway as well as the caveolin 1-dependent uptake of exosomes in vascular endothelial cells. Most importantly, the proangiogenic therapeutic effect of plasma exosomal miRNAs depended upon the participation of CD44/FGFR2 signaling transduction in vascular endothelial cells.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CD44 and its regulated plasma exosomes have crucial potent angiogenic activity. Our studies elucidate that CD44 plays a key role in plasma exosomal miRNA-enhanced angiogenic FGFR2 singling transduction and ischemic angiogenesis in the early stage of myocardial infarction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extracellular signals regulate the biogenesis of extracellular vesicles</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/36435789/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/36435789/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Extracellular vesicles (EVs) are naturally released membrane vesicles that act as carriers of proteins and RNAs for intercellular communication. With various biomolecules and specific ligands, EV has represented a novel form of information transfer, which possesses extremely outstanding efficiency and specificity compared to the classical signal transduction. In addition, EV has extended the concept of signal transduction to intercellular aspect by working as the collection of extracellular information. Therefore, the functions of EVs have been extensively characterized and EVs exhibit an exciting prospect for clinical applications. However, the biogenesis of EVs and, in particular, the regulation of this process by extracellular signals, which are essential to conduct further studies and support optimal utility, remain unclear. Here, we review the current understanding of the biogenesis of EVs, focus on the regulation of this process by extracellular signals and discuss their therapeutic value.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A solution to the biophysical fractionation of extracellular vesicles: Acoustic Nanoscale Separation via Wave-pillar Excitation Resonance (ANSWER)</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36417505/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36417505/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therapeutics that discriminate between the genetic makeup of normal cells and tumour cells are valuable for treating and understanding cancer. Small molecules with oncogene-selective lethality may reveal novel functions of oncoproteins and enable the creation of more selective drugs. Here we describe the mechanism of action of the selective anti-tumour agent erastin, involving the RAS-RAF-MEK signalling pathway functioning in cell proliferation, differentiation and survival. Erastin exhibits greater lethality in human tumour cells harbouring mutations in the oncogenes HRAS, KRAS or BRAF. Using affinity purification and mass spectrometry, we discovered that erastin acts through mitochondrial voltage-dependent anion channels (VDACs)&amp;ndash;a novel target for anti-cancer drugs. We show that erastin treatment of cells harbouring oncogenic RAS causes the appearance of oxidative species and subsequent death through an oxidative, non-apoptotic mechanism. RNA-interference-mediated knockdown of VDAC2 or VDAC3 caused resistance to erastin, implicating these two VDAC isoforms in the mechanism of action of erastin. Moreover, using purified mitochondria expressing a single VDAC isoform, we found that erastin alters the permeability of the outer mitochondrial membrane. Finally, using a radiolabelled analogue and a filter-binding assay, we show that erastin binds directly to VDAC2. These results demonstrate that ligands to VDAC proteins can induce non-apoptotic cell death selectively in some tumour cells harbouring activating mutations in the RAS-RAF-MEK pathway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Renal Endothelial Cell-Targeted Extracellular Vesicles Protect the Kidney from Ischemic Injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36416304/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36416304/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Endothelial cell injury plays a critical part in ischemic acute kidney injury (AKI) and participates in the progression of AKI. Targeting renal endothelial cell therapy may ameliorate vascular injury and further improve the prognosis of ischemic AKI. Here, P-selectin as a biomarker of ischemic AKI in endothelial cells is identified and P-selectin binding peptide (PBP)-engineered extracellular vesicles (PBP-EVs) with imaging and therapeutic functions are developed. The results show that PBP-EVs exhibit a selective targeting tendency to injured kidneys, while providing spatiotemporal information for the early diagnosis of AKI by quantifying the expression of P-selectin in the kidneys by molecular imaging. Meanwhile, PBP-EVs reveal superior nephroprotective functions in the promotion of renal repair and inhibition of fibrosis by alleviating inflammatory infiltration, improving reparative angiogenesis, and ameliorating maladaptive repair of the renal parenchyma. In conclusion, PBP-EVs, as an ischemic AKI theranostic system that is designed in this study, provide a spatiotemporal diagnosis in the early stages of AKI to help guide personalized therapy and exhibit superior nephroprotective effects, offering proof-of-concept data to design EV-based theranostic strategies to promote renal recovery and further improve long-term outcomes following AKI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Do Extracellular Vesicles Play a Key Role in the Maintenance of Bone Homeostasis and Regeneration? A Comprehensive Review of Literature</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/36419718/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/36419718/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The maintenance of bone homeostasis includes both bone resorption by osteoclasts and bone formation by osteoblasts. These two processes are in dynamic balance to maintain a constant amount of bone for accomplishing its critical functions in daily life. Multiple cell type communications are involved in these two complex and continuous processes. In recent decades, an increasing number of studies have shown that osteogenic and osteoclastic extracellular vesicles play crucial roles in regulating bone homeostasis through paracrine, autosecretory and endocrine signaling. Elucidating the functional roles of extracellular vesicles in the maintenance of bone homeostasis may contribute to the design of new strategies for bone regeneration. Hence, we review the recent understandings of the classification, production process, extraction methods, structure, contents, functions and applications of extracellular vesicles in bone homeostasis. We highlight the contents of various bone-derived extracellular vesicles and their interactions with different cells in the bone microenvironment during bone homeostasis. We also summarize the recent advances in EV-loaded biomaterial scaffolds for bone regeneration and repair.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advances in Extracellular Vesicle Nanotechnology for Precision Theranostics</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/36373730/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/36373730/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Extracellular vesicles (EVs) have increasingly been recognized as important cell surrogates influencing many pathophysiological processes, including cellular homeostasis, cancer progression, neurologic disease, and infectious disease. These behaviors enable EVs broad application prospects for clinical application in disease diagnosis and treatment. Many studies suggest that EVs are superior to conventional synthetic carriers in terms of drug delivery and circulating biomarkers for early disease diagnosis, opening up new frontiers for modern theranostics. Despite these clinical potential, EVs containing diverse cellular components, such as nucleic acids, proteins, and metabolites are highly heterogeneous and small size. The limitation of preparatory, engineering and analytical technologies for EVs poses technical barriers to clinical translation. This article aims at present a critical overview of emerging technologies in EVs field for biomedical applications and challenges involved in their clinic translations. The current methods for isolation and identification of EVs are discussed. Additionally, engineering strategies developed to enhance scalable production and improved cargo loading as well as tumor targeting are presented. The superior clinical potential of EVs, particularly in terms of different cell origins and their application in the next generation of diagnostic and treatment platforms, are clarified.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exosomes─Nature&#39;s Lipid Nanoparticles, a Rising Star in Drug Delivery and Diagnostics</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/36354238/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/36354238/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Exosomes are a subgroup of nanosized extracellular vesicles enclosed by a lipid bilayer membrane and secreted by most eukaryotic cells. They represent a route of intercellular communication and participate in a wide variety of physiological and pathological processes. The biological roles of exosomes rely on their bioactive cargos, including proteins, nucleic acids, and lipids, which are delivered to target cells. Their distinctive properties─innate stability, low immunogenicity, biocompatibility, and good biomembrane penetration capacity─allow them to function as superior natural nanocarriers for efficient drug delivery. Another notably favorable clinical application of exosomes is in diagnostics. They hold various biomolecules from host cells, which are indicative of pathophysiological conditions; therefore, they are considered vital for biomarker discovery in clinical diagnostics. Here, we use data from the CAS Content Collection and provide a landscape overview of the current state and delineate trends in research advancement on exosome applications in therapeutics and diagnostics across time, geography, composition, cargo loading, and development pipelines. We discuss exosome composition and pathway, from their biogenesis and secretion from host cells to recipient cell uptake. We assess methods for exosome isolation and purification, their clinical applications in therapy and diagnostics, their development pipelines, the exploration goals of the companies, the assortment of diseases they aim to treat, development stages of their research, and publication trends. We hope this review will be useful for understanding the current knowledge in the field of medical applications of exosomes, in an effort to further solve the remaining challenges in fulfilling their potential.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exosome modification to better alleviates endoplasmic reticulum stress induced chondrocyte apoptosis and osteoarthritis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36370754/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36370754/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Osteoarthritis (OA) is characterized by cartilage matrix degeneration and chondrocyte apoptosis. Prolonged endoplasmic reticulum (ER) stress participates in chondrocyte apoptosis and cartilage degeneration in OA progression. miR-486-5p could suppress the apoptosis of nucleus pulposus cells and cardiomyocyte, yet whether miR-486-5p modified exosomes could modulate ER stress and apoptosis of chondrocytes remain unknown. We validated the increased inflammation and ER stress in OA synovium and cartilage, and the inhibition of ER stress could attenuate the IL-1β induced chondrocyte apoptosis. Administration of exogenous miR-486-5p could inhibit the ER stress, alleviate chondrocytes apoptosis and promote matrix regeneration. In comparison with direct administration of miR-486-5p and miR-486-5p overexpressing ADSCs, miR-486-5p modified exosomes indicated a better effect in modulating chondrocyte homeostasis. MiR-486-5p containing exosomes could also regulate macrophage polarization. Our IVIS imaging data validated that intraarticular injection of miR-486-5p containing exosomes could sustain for at least 7 days. MiR-486-5p containing exosomes showed a better effect on alleviating rats OA compared with direct administration of miR-486-5p and miR-486-5p overexpressing ADSCs. Our data demonstrated that miR-486-5p modified exosomes have a better effect on alleviating chondrocyte apoptosis and osteoarthritis. This study provides evidence of this efficient strategy of exosomal miRNA delivery and the miRNA-based therapy for OA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exosome biogenesis: machinery, regulation, and therapeutic implications in cancer</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/36320056/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/36320056/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Exosomes are well-known key mediators of intercellular communication and contribute to various physiological and pathological processes. Their biogenesis involves four key steps, including cargo sorting, MVB formation and maturation, transport of MVBs, and MVB fusion with the plasma membrane. Each process is modulated through the competition or coordination of multiple mechanisms, whereby diverse repertoires of molecular cargos are sorted into distinct subpopulations of exosomes, resulting in the high heterogeneity of exosomes. Intriguingly, cancer cells exploit various strategies, such as aberrant gene expression, posttranslational modifications, and altered signaling pathways, to regulate the biogenesis, composition, and eventually functions of exosomes to promote cancer progression. Therefore, exosome biogenesis-targeted therapy is being actively explored. In this review, we systematically summarize recent progress in understanding the machinery of exosome biogenesis and how it is regulated in the context of cancer. In particular, we highlight pharmacological targeting of exosome biogenesis as a promising cancer therapeutic strategy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A composite hydrogel containing resveratrol-laden nanoparticles and platelet-derived extracellular vesicles promotes wound healing in diabetic mice</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36309190/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36309190/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Diabetic wounds are difficult to heal because of persistent inflammation and limited angiogenesis. Resveratrol (RES) is an anti-inflammatory and antioxidant agent. Platelet-derived extracellular vesicles (PDEVs) are rich in growth factors and cytokines, which promote proliferation and angiogenesis. However, single drug treatment has limited efficacy and delivery efficiency. Bioengineering can improve the limited effect of single drugs by combining drugs and materials to obtain complementary or cooperative bioengineered drugs. In this study, gelatin methacrylate (GelMA) and silk fibroin glycidyl methacrylate (SFMA) were used to synthesize GelMA/SFMA composite hydrogels with suitable mechanical properties, swelling ratio and biodegradability. The composite hydrogel was used as a wound dressing for sustained drug release. RES was loaded into mesoporous silica nanoparticles (MSNs) to synthesize MSN-RES to enhance the release dynamic, and MSN-RES and PDEVs were combined with the composite hydrogels to form GelMA/SFMA/MSN-RES/PDEVs hydrogels. The GelMA/SFMA/MSN-RES/PDEVs had low cytotoxicity and good biocompatibility, inhibited macrophage iNOS expression, and promoted the tube formation by human umbilical vein endothelial cells (HUVECs) in vitro. In a diabetic mouse wound model, the GelMA/SFMA/MSN-RES/PDEVs hydrogels decreased the expression of pro-inflammatory factors TNF-α and iNOS, increased the expression of anti-inflammatory factors TGF-β1 and Arg-1, promoted angiogenesis, and accelerated wound healing. Interestingly, the GelMA/SFMA/MSN-RES/PDEVs hydrogels promoted the expression of extracellular purinergic signaling pathway-related CD73 and adenosine 2A receptor (A2A-R). Therefore, the GelMA/SFMA/MSN-RES/PDEVs hydrogels could be used as wound dressings to regulate the inflammation and angiogenesis of diabetic wounds and accelerate wound healing. STATEMENT OF SIGNIFICANCE: Drugs often fail to function because of a continuous oxidative stress microenvironment and inflammation. Here, a GelMA/SFMA hydrogel, with enhanced mechanical properties and liquid absorption ability, is proposed for sustained release of drugs. In addition to carrying platelet-derived extracellular vesicles (PDEVs) with pro-angiogenic effects, the hydrogels were also loaded with nanoparticle-encapsulated resveratrol with anti-inflammatory activities, aiming to reduce inflammation and oxidative stress in the wound microenvironment, such that the wound could receive proliferative repair signals to achieve sequential treatment and heal quickly. We also experimentally predicted that the regulatory mechanism of the GelMA/SFMA/MSN-RES/PDEVs in wound healing might be related to the extracellular purinergic signaling pathway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Novel Protein Encoded by Exosomal CircATG4B Induces Oxaliplatin Resistance in Colorectal Cancer by Promoting Autophagy</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36285810/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36285810/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oxaliplatin is commonly used in chemotherapeutic regimens for colorectal cancer (CRC) after surgical resection. However, acquired chemoresistance seriously affects the curative effect in CRC patients, and the mechanism is still unclear. Here, a circular RNA, circATG4B is identified, which plays an important role in oxaliplatin resistance in CRC. circATG4B expression is found to be increased in exosomes secreted by oxaliplatin-resistant CRC cells. In addition, the results suggest that circATG4B induces oxaliplatin resistance by promoting autophagy. Further in vivo and in vitro studies indicate that the effect of circATG4B is attributed to its potential to encode a novel protein, circATG4B-222aa. Next, circATG4B-222aa is found to function as a decoy to competitively interact with TMED10 and prevent TMED10 from binding to ATG4B, which leads to increased autophagy followed by induction of chemoresistance. Therefore, this study reveals that exosomal circATG4B participates in the decreased chemosensitivity of CRC cells, providing a new rationale for a potential therapeutic target for oxaliplatin resistance in CRC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>EV-ADD, a database for EV-associated DNA in human liquid biopsy samples</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36271888/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36271888/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Extracellular vesicles (EVs) play a key role in cellular communication both in physiological conditions and in pathologies such as cancer. Emerging evidence has shown that EVs are active carriers of molecular cargo (e.g. protein and nucleic acids) and a powerful source of biomarkers and targets. While recent studies on EV-associated DNA (EV-DNA) in human biofluids have generated a large amount of data, there is currently no database that catalogues information on EV-DNA. To fill this gap, we have manually curated a database of EV-DNA data derived from human biofluids (liquid biopsy) and in-vitro studies, called the &lt;a href=&#34;%28www.evdnadatabase.com%29&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Extracellular Vesicle-Associated DNA Database (EV-ADD)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. This database contains validated experimental details and data extracted from peer-reviewed published literature. It can be easily queried to search for EV isolation methods and characterization, EV-DNA isolation techniques, quality validation, DNA fragment size, volume of starting material, gene names and disease context. Currently, our database contains samples representing 23 diseases, with 13 different types of EV isolation techniques applied on eight different human biofluids (e.g. blood, saliva). In addition, &lt;a href=&#34;www.evdnadatabase.com&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EV-ADD&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; encompasses EV-DNA data both representing the whole genome and specifically including oncogenes, such as KRAS, EGFR, BRAF, MYC, and mitochondrial DNA (mtDNA). An &lt;a href=&#34;www.evdnadatabase.com&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EV-ADD&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; data metric system was also integrated to assign a compliancy score to the MISEV guidelines based on experimental parameters reported in each study. While currently available databases document the presence of proteins, lipids, RNA and metabolites in EVs (e.g. Vesiclepedia, ExoCarta, ExoBCD, EVpedia, and EV-TRACK), to the best of our knowledge, &lt;a href=&#34;www.evdnadatabase.com&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EV-ADD&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is the first of its kind to compile all available EV-DNA datasets derived from human biofluid samples. We believe that this database provides an important reference resource on EV-DNA-based liquid biopsy research, serving as a learning tool and to showcase the latest developments in the EV-DNA field. &lt;a href=&#34;www.evdnadatabase.com&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EV-ADD&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; will be updated yearly as newly published EV-DNA data becomes available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Study of immunomodulatory effects of mesenchymal stem cell-derived exosomes in a mouse model of LPS induced systemic inflammation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36150466/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36150466/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Sepsis is a debilitating systemic inflammation that resulted from infection or injury. Despite many advances in treatment, the resulting mortality rate has remained high due to increasing antibiotic resistance and aging communities. The present study investigated the effects of stem cell-derived exosomes in a mouse model of LPS-induced systemic inflammation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Materials and methods:&lt;/em&gt; To induce sepsis, the LPS model was used. Mice were divided into three groups: normal, patient group (LPS + PBS), and treatment group (LPS + exosome). The treatment group received an intravenous exosome 1 h after induction of the model. Patient and treatment groups were sacrificed at 4, 6, 24, and 48 h after induction of the model, and their tissues were isolated. Blood samples were taken from animal hearts to perform biochemical and immunological tests. The study results were analyzed using Graph Pad Prism software version 9.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; Mesenchymal stem cell-derived exosomes decreased serum levels of ALT and AST liver enzymes, decreased neutrophil to lymphocyte ratio (NLR), and improved kidney, liver, and lung tissue damage at 4, 6, and 24 h after model induction. At 24 h, the exosomes were able to reduce serum urea levels. This study revealed decreased levels of inflammatory cytokines such as IL-6, IL-1β, and TNF-α after exosome injection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/em&gt; Our findings suggest that treating mice with stem cell-derived exosomes can ameliorate the destructive effects of inflammation caused by sepsis by reducing inflammatory factors and tissue damage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exosome-mediated delivery of Cas9 ribonucleoprotein complexes for tissue-specific gene therapy of liver diseases</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36103526/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36103526/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CRISPR-Cas9 gene editing has emerged as a powerful therapeutic technology, but the lack of safe and efficient in vivo delivery systems, especially for tissue-specific vectors, limits its broad clinical applications. Delivery of Cas9 ribonucleoprotein (RNP) owns competitive advantages over other options; however, the large size of RNPs exceeds the loading capacity of currently available delivery vectors. Here, we report a previously unidentified genome editing delivery system, named exosome&lt;sup&gt;RNP&lt;/sup&gt;, in which Cas9 RNPs were loaded into purified exosomes isolated from hepatic stellate cells through electroporation. Exosome&lt;sup&gt;RNP&lt;/sup&gt; facilitated effective cytosolic delivery of RNP in vitro while specifically accumulated in the liver tissue in vivo. Exosome&lt;sup&gt;RNP&lt;/sup&gt; showed vigorous therapeutic potential in acute liver injury, chronic liver fibrosis, and hepatocellular carcinoma mouse models via targeting p53 up-regulated modulator of apoptosis (&lt;em&gt;PUMA&lt;/em&gt;), cyclin E1 (&lt;em&gt;CcnE1&lt;/em&gt;), and K (lysine) acetyltransferase 5 (&lt;em&gt;KAT5&lt;/em&gt;), respectively. The developed exosomeRNP provides a feasible platform for precise and tissue-specific gene therapies of liver diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hypoxia-induced exosomal circPDK1 promotes pancreatic cancer glycolysis via c-myc activation by modulating miR-628-3p/BPTF axis and degrading BIN1</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36068586/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36068586/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; circRNA has been established to play a pivotal role in tumorigenesis development in a variety of cancers; nevertheless, the biological functions and molecular mechanisms of hypoxia-induced exosomal circRNAs in pancreatic cancer remain largely unknown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; Differentially expressed circRNAs in exosomes between hypoxic exosomes and normoxic exosomes in PC cells were verified by RNA sequencing. The expression of circPDK1 in PC tumors and PC patients was evaluated by qRT-PCR and ISH, and the biological functions of circPDK1 in PC were verified through a series of in vitro and in vivo experiments. Using Western blotting, Co-IP, RNA pull-down, ChIP, RIP, dual-luciferase assays, and rescue experiments, the underlying mechanism of circPDK1 was verified.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; CircPDK1 was highly abundant in PC tumor tissues and serum exosomes and was associated with poor survival. Exosomal circPDK1 significantly promoted PC cell proliferation, migration, and glycolysis both in vitro and in vivo. Mechanistically, circPDK1 could be activated by HIF1A at the transcriptional level and sponges miR-628-3p to activate the BPTF/c-myc axis. In addition, circPDK1 serves as a scaffold that enhances the interaction between UBE2O and BIN1, inducing the UBE2O-mediated degradation of BIN1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; We found that circPDK1 was activated by HIF1A at the transcriptional level by modulating the miR-628-3p/BPTF axis and degrading BIN1. Exosomal circPDK1 is a promising biomarker for PC diagnosis and prognosis and represents a potential therapeutic target for PC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dental stem cell-derived extracellular vesicles transfer miR-330-5p to treat traumatic brain injury by regulating microglia polarization</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36064768/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36064768/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Traumatic brain injury (TBI) contributes to the key causative elements of neurological deficits. However, no effective therapeutics have been developed yet. In our previous work, extracellular vesicles (EVs) secreted by stem cells from human exfoliated deciduous teeth (SHED) offered new insights as potential strategies for functional recovery of TBI. The current study aims to elucidate the mechanism of action, providing novel therapeutic targets for future clinical interventions. With the miRNA array performed and Real-time PCR validated, we revealed the crucial function of miR-330-5p transferred by SHED-derived EVs (SHED-EVs) in regulating microglia, the critical immune modulator in central nervous system. MiR-330-5p targeted Ehmt2 and mediated the transcription of CXCL14 to promote M2 microglia polarization and inhibit M1 polarization. Identified in our in vivo data, SHED-EVs and their effector miR-330-5p alleviated the secretion of inflammatory cytokines and resumed the motor functional recovery of TBI rats. In summary, by transferring miR-330-5p, SHED-EVs favored anti-inflammatory microglia polarization through Ehmt2 mediated CXCL14 transcription in treating traumatic brain injury.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A shared, stochastic pathway mediates exosome protein budding along plasma and endosome membranes</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35988652/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35988652/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Exosomes are small extracellular vesicles of ∼30 to 150 nm that are secreted by all cells, abundant in all biofluids, and play important roles in health and disease. However, details about the mechanism of exosome biogenesis are unclear. Here, we carried out a cargo-based analysis of exosome cargo protein biogenesis in which we identified the most highly enriched exosomal cargo proteins and then followed their biogenesis, trafficking, and exosomal secretion to test different hypotheses for how cells make exosomes. We show that exosome cargo proteins bud from cells (i) in exosome-sized vesicles regardless of whether they are localized to plasma or endosome membranes, (ii) ∼5-fold more efficiently when localized to the plasma membrane, (iii) ∼5-fold less efficiently when targeted to the endosome membrane, (iv) by a stochastic process that leads to ∼100-fold differences in their abundance from one exosome to another, and (v) independently of small GTPase Rab27a, the ESCRT complex-associated protein Alix, or the cargo protein CD63. Taken together, our results demonstrate that cells use a shared, stochastic mechanism to bud exosome cargoes along the spectrum of plasma and endosome membranes and far more efficiently from the plasma membrane than the endosome. Our observations also indicate that the pronounced variation in content between different exosome-sized vesicles is an inevitable consequence of a stochastic mechanism of small vesicle biogenesis, that the origin membrane of exosome-sized extracellular vesicles simply cannot be determined, and that most of what we currently know about exosomes has likely come from studies of plasma membrane-derived vesicles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extracellular vesicles as an emerging drug delivery system for cancer treatment: Current strategies and recent advances</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/36076581/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/36076581/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cancer is one of the primary causes of death worldwide, and its morbidity and mortality rates are increasing rapidly. However, standard treatment modalities (surgery, radiotherapy, chemotherapy, and immunotherapy) often fail to achieve a satisfactory therapeutic effect. Extracellular vesicles (EVs) are natural nano-sized lipid bilayer vesicles secreted from cells. Owing to their advantages of low toxicity, high biocompatibility, low immunogenicity, and inherent targeting, EVs can be exploited as drug delivery vectors for cancer treatment. In this review, we summarize the research progress of EV-based drug delivery systems in cancer treatment by focusing on four aspects: sources, cargo types, cargo loading methods and modification strategies. Finally, current challenges and future perspectives are discussed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Activated Drp1 regulates p62-mediated autophagic flux and aggravates inflammation in cerebral ischemia-reperfusion via the ROS-RIP1/RIP3-exosome axis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35624495/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35624495/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Cerebral ischemia-reperfusion injury (CIRI) refers to a secondary brain injury that can occur when the blood supply to the ischemic brain tissue is restored. However, the mechanism underlying such injury remains elusive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; The 150 male C57 mice underwent middle cerebral artery occlusion (MCAO) for 1 h and reperfusion for 24 h, Among them, 50 MCAO mice were further treated with Mitochondrial division inhibitor 1 (Mdivi-1) and 50 MCAO mice were further treated with N-acetylcysteine (NAC). SH-SY5Y cells were cultured in a low-glucose culture medium for 4 h under hypoxic conditions and then transferred to normal conditions for 12 h. Then, cerebral blood flow, mitochondrial structure, mitochondrial DNA (mtDNA) copy number, intracellular and mitochondrial reactive oxygen species (ROS), autophagic flux, aggresome and exosome expression profiles, cardiac tissue structure, mitochondrial length and cristae density, mtDNA and ROS content, as well as the expression of Drp1-Ser616/Drp1, RIP1/RIP3, LC3 II/LC3 I, TNF-α, IL-1β, etc., were detected under normal or Drp1 interference conditions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; The mtDNA content, ROS levels, and Drp1-Ser616/Drp1 were elevated by 2.2, 1.7 and 2.7 times after CIRI (&lt;em&gt;P&lt;/em&gt; &amp;lt; 0.05). However, the high cytoplasmic LC3 II/I ratio and increased aggregation of p62 could be reversed by 44% and 88% by Drp1 short hairpin RNA (shRNA) (&lt;em&gt;P&lt;/em&gt; &amp;lt; 0.05). The low fluorescence intensity of autophagic flux and the increased phosphorylation of RIP3 induced by CIRI could be attenuated by ROS scavenger, NAC (&lt;em&gt;P&lt;/em&gt; &amp;lt; 0.05). RIP1/RIP3 inhibitor Necrostatin-1 (Nec-1) restored 75% to a low LC3 II/LC3 I ratio and enhanced 2 times to a high RFP-LC3 after Drp1 activation (&lt;em&gt;P&lt;/em&gt; &amp;lt; 0.05). In addition, although CIRI-induced ROS production caused no considerable accumulation of autophagosomes (&lt;em&gt;P&lt;/em&gt; &amp;gt; 0.05), it increased the packaging and extracellular secretion of exosomes containing p62 by 4 - 5 times, which could be decreased by Mdivi-1, Drp1 shRNA, and Nec-1 (&lt;em&gt;P&lt;/em&gt; &amp;lt; 0.05). Furthermore, TNF-α and IL-1β increased in CIRI-derived exosomes could increase RIP3 phosphorylation in normal or oxygen-glucose deprivation/reoxygenation (OGD/R) conditions (&lt;em&gt;P&lt;/em&gt; &amp;lt; 0.05).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; CIRI activated Drp1 and accelerated the p62-mediated formation of autophagosomes while inhibiting the transition of autophagosomes to autolysosomes via the RIP1/RIP3 pathway activation. Undegraded autophagosomes were secreted extracellularly in the form of exosomes, leading to inflammatory cascades that further damaged mitochondria, resulting in excessive ROS generation and the blockage of autophagosome degradation, triggering a vicious cycle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Challenges and directions in studying cell-cell communication by extracellular vesicles</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/35260831/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/35260831/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Extracellular vesicles (EVs) are increasingly recognized as important mediators of intercellular communication. They have important roles in numerous physiological and pathological processes, and show considerable promise as novel biomarkers of disease, as therapeutic agents and as drug delivery vehicles. Intriguingly, however, understanding of the cellular and molecular mechanisms that govern the many observed functions of EVs remains far from comprehensive, at least partly due to technical challenges in working with these small messengers. Here, we highlight areas of consensus as well as contentious issues in our understanding of the intracellular and intercellular journey of EVs: from biogenesis, release and dynamics in the extracellular space, to interaction with and uptake by recipient cells. We define knowledge gaps, identify key questions and challenges, and make recommendations on how to address these.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Specificities of exosome versus small ectosome secretion revealed by live intracellular tracking of CD63 and CD9</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34282141/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34282141/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite their roles in intercellular communications, the different populations of extracellular vesicles (EVs) and their secretion mechanisms are not fully characterized: how and to what extent EVs form as intraluminal vesicles of endocytic compartments (exosomes), or at the plasma membrane (PM) (ectosomes) remains unclear. Here we follow intracellular trafficking of the EV markers CD9 and CD63 from the endoplasmic reticulum to their residency compartment, respectively PM and late endosomes. We observe transient co-localization at both places, before they finally segregate. CD9 and a mutant CD63 stabilized at the PM are more abundantly released in EVs than CD63. Thus, in HeLa cells, ectosomes are more prominent than exosomes. By comparative proteomic analysis and differential response to neutralization of endosomal pH, we identify a few surface proteins likely specific of either exosomes (LAMP1) or ectosomes (BSG, SLC3A2). Our work sets the path for molecular and functional discrimination of exosomes and small ectosomes in any cell type.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hypoxia adipose stem cell-derived exosomes promote high-quality healing of diabetic wound involves activation of PI3K/Akt pathways</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34233694/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34233694/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Refractory diabetic wounds can cause persistent inflammation and delayed healing due to hypoxia. Currently, no optimal solution is available. Exosomes of adipose stem cells (ADSCs-exo) may promote skin wound healing, however, molecular mechanisms remains mysterious. We found significantly enhanced survival and proliferation of adipose stem cells after hypoxia induction compared to normoxia. Here, we aimed to investigate if hypoxic adipose stem cells exosomes (HypADSCs-exo) participate in hypoxia adaptability and accelerate diabetic wound healing. Based on high-throughput sequencing, 215 microRNAs (miRNAs) were upregulated and 369 miRNAs downregulated in HypADSCs-exo compared to ADSCs-exo. Up-regulated miR-21-3p, miR-126-5p, miR-31-5p whereas down-regulated gene miR-99b and miR-146-a correlated with wound healing. According to Gene Ontology (GO) and Kyoto Encyclopedia of Genes and Genomes (KEGG), miRNAs might regulate cell metabolism, differentiation and Transforming growth factor-β (TGF-β) function. Consistently, HpyADSCs-exo could promote diabetic wounds healing and inhibit inflammation through PI3K/AKT signaling pathway. Collectively, HpyADSCs-exo can promote diabetic wound healing as an alternative strategy to improve wound healing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A multi-omics investigation of the composition and function of extracellular vesicles along the temporal trajectory of COVID-19</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34158670/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34158670/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The type I interferon (IFN-I, IFN-α/β)-mediated immune response is the first line of host defense against invading viruses. IFN-α/β binds to IFN-α/β receptors (IFNARs) and triggers the expression of IFN-stimulated genes (ISGs). Thus, stabilization of IFNARs is important for prolonging antiviral activity. Here, we report the induction of an RNA-binding motif-containing protein, RBM47, upon viral infection or interferon stimulation. Using multiple virus infection models, we demonstrate that RBM47 has broad-spectrum antiviral activity in vitro and in vivo. RBM47 has no noticeable impact on IFN production, but significantly activates the IFN-stimulated response element (ISRE) and enhances the expression of interferon-stimulated genes (ISGs). Mechanistically, RBM47 binds to the 3&amp;rsquo;UTR of IFNAR1 mRNA, increases mRNA stability, and retards the degradation of IFNAR1. In summary, this study suggests that RBM47 is an interferon-inducible RNA-binding protein that plays an essential role in enhancing host IFN downstream signaling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Holistic Review of the State-of-the-Art Microfluidics for Exosome Separation: An Overview of the Current Status, Existing Obstacles, and Future Outlook</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/34047052/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/34047052/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Exosomes, a class of small extracellular vesicles (30-150 nm), are secreted by almost all types of cells into virtually all body fluids. These small vesicles are attracting increasing research attention owing to their potential for disease diagnosis and therapy. However, their inherent heterogeneity and the complexity of bio-fluids pose significant challenges for their isolation. Even the &amp;ldquo;gold standard,&amp;rdquo; differential centrifugation, suffers from poor yields and is time-consuming. In this context, recent developments in microfluidic technologies have provided an ideal system for exosome extraction and these devices exhibit some fascinating properties such as high speeds, good portability, and low sample volumes. In this review, the focus is on the state-of-the-art microfluidic technologies for exosome isolation and highlight potential directions for future research and development by analyzing the challenges faced by the current strategies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Delivering Antisense Oligonucleotides across the Blood-Brain Barrier by Tumor Cell-Derived Small Apoptotic Bodies</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34258157/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34258157/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The blood-brain barrier (BBB) is the most restrictive and complicated barrier that keeps most biomolecules and drugs from the brain. An efficient brain delivery strategy is urgently needed for the treatment of brain diseases. Based on the studies of brain-targeting extracellular vesicles (EVs), the potential of using small apoptotic bodies (sABs) from brain metastatic cancer cells for brain-targeting drug delivery is explored. It is found that anti-TNF-α antisense oligonucleotide (ASO) combined with cationic konjac glucomannan (cKGM) can be successfully loaded into sABs via a transfection/apoptosis induction process and that the sABs generated by B16F10 cells have an extraordinarily high brain delivery efficiency. Further studies suggest that ASO-loaded sABs (sCABs) are transcytosed by b. End3 (brain microvascular endothelial cells, BMECs) to penetrate the BBB, which is mediated by CD44v6, and eventually taken up by microglial cells in the brain. In a Parkinson&amp;rsquo;s disease (PD) mouse model, sCABs dramatically ameliorate PD symptoms via the anti-inflammatory effect of ASO. This study suggests that sABs from brain metastatic cancer cells are excellent carriers for brain-targeted delivery, as they have not only an extraordinary delivery efficiency but also a much higher scale-up production potential than other EVs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Targeted inhibition of SIRT6 via engineered exosomes impairs tumorigenesis and metastasis in prostate cancer</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33995674/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33995674/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The treatment for metastatic castration-resistant prostate cancer patients remains a great challenge in the clinic and continuously demands discoveries of new targets and therapies. Here, we assess the function and therapeutic value of SIRT6 in metastatic castration-resistant prostate cancer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The expression of SIRT6 was examined in prostate cancer tissue microarray by immunohistochemistry staining. The functions of SIRT6 and underlying mechanisms were elucidated by in vitro and in vivo experiments. We also developed an efficient method to silence SIRT6 by aptamer-modified exosomes carrying small interfering RNA and tested the therapeutic effect in the xenograft mice models.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SIRT6 expression is positively correlated with prostate cancer progression. Loss of SIRT6 significantly suppressed proliferation and metastasis of prostate cancer cell lines both in vitro and in vivo. SIRT6-driven prostate cancer displays activation of multiple cancer-related signaling pathways, especially the Notch pathway. Silencing SIRT6 by siRNA delivered through engineered exosomes inhibited tumor growth and metastasis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SIRT6 is identified as a driver and therapeutic target for metastatic prostate cancer in our findings, and inhibition of SIRT6 by engineered exosomes can serve as a promising therapeutic tool for clinical application.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>hnRNPA2B1 Associated with Recruitment of RNA into Exosomes Plays a Key Role in Herpes Simplex Virus 1 Release from Infected Cells</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32295924/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32295924/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;hnRNPA2B1, an abundant cellular protein, has been reported to recruit RNAs bearing a specific sequence (EXO motif) into exosomes. We characterized an exosome population averaging 100 ± 50 nm in diameter and containing a defined set of constitutive exosome markers. This population packages microRNAs (miRNAs) and can be directed to block targeted gene expression in a dose-dependent fashion. The objective of this study was to characterize the role of hnRNPA2B1 in the recruitment of miRNA. We report the following four key findings. (i) hnRNPA2B1 is not a component of exosomes produced in HEp-2 or HEK293T cells. Hence, hnRNPA2B1 carries its cargo, at most, to the site of exosome assembly, but it is not itself incorporated into exosomes. (ii) The accumulation of exosomes produced by cells in which the gene encoding hnRNPA2B1 has been knocked out (ΔhnRNPA2B1 cells) was reduced 3-fold. (iii) In uninfected HEp-2 cells, hnRNPA2B1 is localized in the nucleus. In cells infected with herpes simplex virus 1 (HSV-1), hnRNPA2B1 was quantitatively exported to the cytoplasm and at least a fraction of hnRNPA2B1 colocalized with a Golgi marker. (iv) Lastly, in ΔhnRNPA2B1 cells, there was a 2- to 3-fold reduction in virus yield but a significant (&amp;gt;10-fold) reduction in HSV-1 released through the apical surface into the extracellular environment. The absence of hnRNPA2B1 had no significant impact on the basolateral export of HSV-1 from infected to uninfected cells by direct cell-to-cell contact. The results suggest that hnRNPA2B1 plays a key role in the transport of enveloped virus from its site of assembly to the extracellular environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Importance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this report, we show that hnRNPA2B1 is not a component of exosomes produced in HEp-2 or HEK293T cells. In herpes simplex virus 1 (HSV-1)-infected cells, hnRNPA2B1 was quantitatively translocated from the nucleus into the cytoplasm. In infected ΔhnRNPA2B1 cells, Golgi-dependent transport of virus from the apical surface to the extracellular medium was significantly reduced. In essence, this report supports the hypothesis that hnRNPA2B1 plays a key role in the egress of exosomes and HSV-1 from infected cells.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exosome-based delivery of super-repressor IκBα relieves sepsis-associated organ damage and mortality</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32285005/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32285005/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As extracellular vesicles that play an active role in intercellular communication by transferring cellular materials to recipient cells, exosomes offer great potential as a natural therapeutic drug delivery vehicle. The inflammatory responses in various disease models can be attenuated through introduction of super-repressor IκB (srIκB), which is the dominant active form of IκBα and can inhibit translocation of nuclear factor κB into the nucleus. An optogenetically engineered exosome system (EXPLOR) that we previously developed was implemented for loading a large amount of srIκB into exosomes. We showed that intraperitoneal injection of purified srIκB-loaded exosomes (Exo-srIκBs) attenuates mortality and systemic inflammation in septic mouse models. In a biodistribution study, Exo-srIκBs were observed mainly in the neutrophils, and in monocytes to a lesser extent, in the spleens and livers of mice. Moreover, we found that Exo-srIκB alleviates inflammatory responses in monocytic THP-1 cells and human umbilical vein endothelial cells.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The biology, function, and biomedical applications of exosomes</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/32029601/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/32029601/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The study of extracellular vesicles (EVs) has the potential to identify unknown cellular and molecular mechanisms in intercellular communication and in organ homeostasis and disease. Exosomes, with an average diameter of ~100 nanometers, are a subset of EVs. The biogenesis of exosomes involves their origin in endosomes, and subsequent interactions with other intracellular vesicles and organelles generate the final content of the exosomes. Their diverse constituents include nucleic acids, proteins, lipids, amino acids, and metabolites, which can reflect their cell of origin. In various diseases, exosomes offer a window into altered cellular or tissue states, and their detection in biological fluids potentially offers a multicomponent diagnostic readout. The efficient exchange of cellular components through exosomes can inform their applied use in designing exosome-based therapeutics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
