<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Exosomes | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/exosomes/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/exosomes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Exosomes</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Exosomes</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/exosomes/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>A composite hydrogel containing resveratrol-laden nanoparticles and platelet-derived extracellular vesicles promotes wound healing in diabetic mice</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36309190/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36309190/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Diabetic wounds are difficult to heal because of persistent inflammation and limited angiogenesis. Resveratrol (RES) is an anti-inflammatory and antioxidant agent. Platelet-derived extracellular vesicles (PDEVs) are rich in growth factors and cytokines, which promote proliferation and angiogenesis. However, single drug treatment has limited efficacy and delivery efficiency. Bioengineering can improve the limited effect of single drugs by combining drugs and materials to obtain complementary or cooperative bioengineered drugs. In this study, gelatin methacrylate (GelMA) and silk fibroin glycidyl methacrylate (SFMA) were used to synthesize GelMA/SFMA composite hydrogels with suitable mechanical properties, swelling ratio and biodegradability. The composite hydrogel was used as a wound dressing for sustained drug release. RES was loaded into mesoporous silica nanoparticles (MSNs) to synthesize MSN-RES to enhance the release dynamic, and MSN-RES and PDEVs were combined with the composite hydrogels to form GelMA/SFMA/MSN-RES/PDEVs hydrogels. The GelMA/SFMA/MSN-RES/PDEVs had low cytotoxicity and good biocompatibility, inhibited macrophage iNOS expression, and promoted the tube formation by human umbilical vein endothelial cells (HUVECs) in vitro. In a diabetic mouse wound model, the GelMA/SFMA/MSN-RES/PDEVs hydrogels decreased the expression of pro-inflammatory factors TNF-α and iNOS, increased the expression of anti-inflammatory factors TGF-β1 and Arg-1, promoted angiogenesis, and accelerated wound healing. Interestingly, the GelMA/SFMA/MSN-RES/PDEVs hydrogels promoted the expression of extracellular purinergic signaling pathway-related CD73 and adenosine 2A receptor (A2A-R). Therefore, the GelMA/SFMA/MSN-RES/PDEVs hydrogels could be used as wound dressings to regulate the inflammation and angiogenesis of diabetic wounds and accelerate wound healing. STATEMENT OF SIGNIFICANCE: Drugs often fail to function because of a continuous oxidative stress microenvironment and inflammation. Here, a GelMA/SFMA hydrogel, with enhanced mechanical properties and liquid absorption ability, is proposed for sustained release of drugs. In addition to carrying platelet-derived extracellular vesicles (PDEVs) with pro-angiogenic effects, the hydrogels were also loaded with nanoparticle-encapsulated resveratrol with anti-inflammatory activities, aiming to reduce inflammation and oxidative stress in the wound microenvironment, such that the wound could receive proliferative repair signals to achieve sequential treatment and heal quickly. We also experimentally predicted that the regulatory mechanism of the GelMA/SFMA/MSN-RES/PDEVs in wound healing might be related to the extracellular purinergic signaling pathway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Novel Protein Encoded by Exosomal CircATG4B Induces Oxaliplatin Resistance in Colorectal Cancer by Promoting Autophagy</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36285810/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36285810/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oxaliplatin is commonly used in chemotherapeutic regimens for colorectal cancer (CRC) after surgical resection. However, acquired chemoresistance seriously affects the curative effect in CRC patients, and the mechanism is still unclear. Here, a circular RNA, circATG4B is identified, which plays an important role in oxaliplatin resistance in CRC. circATG4B expression is found to be increased in exosomes secreted by oxaliplatin-resistant CRC cells. In addition, the results suggest that circATG4B induces oxaliplatin resistance by promoting autophagy. Further in vivo and in vitro studies indicate that the effect of circATG4B is attributed to its potential to encode a novel protein, circATG4B-222aa. Next, circATG4B-222aa is found to function as a decoy to competitively interact with TMED10 and prevent TMED10 from binding to ATG4B, which leads to increased autophagy followed by induction of chemoresistance. Therefore, this study reveals that exosomal circATG4B participates in the decreased chemosensitivity of CRC cells, providing a new rationale for a potential therapeutic target for oxaliplatin resistance in CRC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>EV-ADD, a database for EV-associated DNA in human liquid biopsy samples</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36271888/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36271888/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Extracellular vesicles (EVs) play a key role in cellular communication both in physiological conditions and in pathologies such as cancer. Emerging evidence has shown that EVs are active carriers of molecular cargo (e.g. protein and nucleic acids) and a powerful source of biomarkers and targets. While recent studies on EV-associated DNA (EV-DNA) in human biofluids have generated a large amount of data, there is currently no database that catalogues information on EV-DNA. To fill this gap, we have manually curated a database of EV-DNA data derived from human biofluids (liquid biopsy) and in-vitro studies, called the &lt;a href=&#34;%28www.evdnadatabase.com%29&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Extracellular Vesicle-Associated DNA Database (EV-ADD)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. This database contains validated experimental details and data extracted from peer-reviewed published literature. It can be easily queried to search for EV isolation methods and characterization, EV-DNA isolation techniques, quality validation, DNA fragment size, volume of starting material, gene names and disease context. Currently, our database contains samples representing 23 diseases, with 13 different types of EV isolation techniques applied on eight different human biofluids (e.g. blood, saliva). In addition, &lt;a href=&#34;www.evdnadatabase.com&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EV-ADD&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; encompasses EV-DNA data both representing the whole genome and specifically including oncogenes, such as KRAS, EGFR, BRAF, MYC, and mitochondrial DNA (mtDNA). An &lt;a href=&#34;www.evdnadatabase.com&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EV-ADD&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; data metric system was also integrated to assign a compliancy score to the MISEV guidelines based on experimental parameters reported in each study. While currently available databases document the presence of proteins, lipids, RNA and metabolites in EVs (e.g. Vesiclepedia, ExoCarta, ExoBCD, EVpedia, and EV-TRACK), to the best of our knowledge, &lt;a href=&#34;www.evdnadatabase.com&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EV-ADD&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is the first of its kind to compile all available EV-DNA datasets derived from human biofluid samples. We believe that this database provides an important reference resource on EV-DNA-based liquid biopsy research, serving as a learning tool and to showcase the latest developments in the EV-DNA field. &lt;a href=&#34;www.evdnadatabase.com&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EV-ADD&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; will be updated yearly as newly published EV-DNA data becomes available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exosome-mediated delivery of Cas9 ribonucleoprotein complexes for tissue-specific gene therapy of liver diseases</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36103526/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36103526/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CRISPR-Cas9 gene editing has emerged as a powerful therapeutic technology, but the lack of safe and efficient in vivo delivery systems, especially for tissue-specific vectors, limits its broad clinical applications. Delivery of Cas9 ribonucleoprotein (RNP) owns competitive advantages over other options; however, the large size of RNPs exceeds the loading capacity of currently available delivery vectors. Here, we report a previously unidentified genome editing delivery system, named exosome&lt;sup&gt;RNP&lt;/sup&gt;, in which Cas9 RNPs were loaded into purified exosomes isolated from hepatic stellate cells through electroporation. Exosome&lt;sup&gt;RNP&lt;/sup&gt; facilitated effective cytosolic delivery of RNP in vitro while specifically accumulated in the liver tissue in vivo. Exosome&lt;sup&gt;RNP&lt;/sup&gt; showed vigorous therapeutic potential in acute liver injury, chronic liver fibrosis, and hepatocellular carcinoma mouse models via targeting p53 up-regulated modulator of apoptosis (&lt;em&gt;PUMA&lt;/em&gt;), cyclin E1 (&lt;em&gt;CcnE1&lt;/em&gt;), and K (lysine) acetyltransferase 5 (&lt;em&gt;KAT5&lt;/em&gt;), respectively. The developed exosomeRNP provides a feasible platform for precise and tissue-specific gene therapies of liver diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hypoxia-induced exosomal circPDK1 promotes pancreatic cancer glycolysis via c-myc activation by modulating miR-628-3p/BPTF axis and degrading BIN1</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36068586/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36068586/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; circRNA has been established to play a pivotal role in tumorigenesis development in a variety of cancers; nevertheless, the biological functions and molecular mechanisms of hypoxia-induced exosomal circRNAs in pancreatic cancer remain largely unknown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; Differentially expressed circRNAs in exosomes between hypoxic exosomes and normoxic exosomes in PC cells were verified by RNA sequencing. The expression of circPDK1 in PC tumors and PC patients was evaluated by qRT-PCR and ISH, and the biological functions of circPDK1 in PC were verified through a series of in vitro and in vivo experiments. Using Western blotting, Co-IP, RNA pull-down, ChIP, RIP, dual-luciferase assays, and rescue experiments, the underlying mechanism of circPDK1 was verified.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; CircPDK1 was highly abundant in PC tumor tissues and serum exosomes and was associated with poor survival. Exosomal circPDK1 significantly promoted PC cell proliferation, migration, and glycolysis both in vitro and in vivo. Mechanistically, circPDK1 could be activated by HIF1A at the transcriptional level and sponges miR-628-3p to activate the BPTF/c-myc axis. In addition, circPDK1 serves as a scaffold that enhances the interaction between UBE2O and BIN1, inducing the UBE2O-mediated degradation of BIN1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; We found that circPDK1 was activated by HIF1A at the transcriptional level by modulating the miR-628-3p/BPTF axis and degrading BIN1. Exosomal circPDK1 is a promising biomarker for PC diagnosis and prognosis and represents a potential therapeutic target for PC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dental stem cell-derived extracellular vesicles transfer miR-330-5p to treat traumatic brain injury by regulating microglia polarization</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36064768/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36064768/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Traumatic brain injury (TBI) contributes to the key causative elements of neurological deficits. However, no effective therapeutics have been developed yet. In our previous work, extracellular vesicles (EVs) secreted by stem cells from human exfoliated deciduous teeth (SHED) offered new insights as potential strategies for functional recovery of TBI. The current study aims to elucidate the mechanism of action, providing novel therapeutic targets for future clinical interventions. With the miRNA array performed and Real-time PCR validated, we revealed the crucial function of miR-330-5p transferred by SHED-derived EVs (SHED-EVs) in regulating microglia, the critical immune modulator in central nervous system. MiR-330-5p targeted Ehmt2 and mediated the transcription of CXCL14 to promote M2 microglia polarization and inhibit M1 polarization. Identified in our in vivo data, SHED-EVs and their effector miR-330-5p alleviated the secretion of inflammatory cytokines and resumed the motor functional recovery of TBI rats. In summary, by transferring miR-330-5p, SHED-EVs favored anti-inflammatory microglia polarization through Ehmt2 mediated CXCL14 transcription in treating traumatic brain injury.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A shared, stochastic pathway mediates exosome protein budding along plasma and endosome membranes</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35988652/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35988652/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Exosomes are small extracellular vesicles of ∼30 to 150 nm that are secreted by all cells, abundant in all biofluids, and play important roles in health and disease. However, details about the mechanism of exosome biogenesis are unclear. Here, we carried out a cargo-based analysis of exosome cargo protein biogenesis in which we identified the most highly enriched exosomal cargo proteins and then followed their biogenesis, trafficking, and exosomal secretion to test different hypotheses for how cells make exosomes. We show that exosome cargo proteins bud from cells (i) in exosome-sized vesicles regardless of whether they are localized to plasma or endosome membranes, (ii) ∼5-fold more efficiently when localized to the plasma membrane, (iii) ∼5-fold less efficiently when targeted to the endosome membrane, (iv) by a stochastic process that leads to ∼100-fold differences in their abundance from one exosome to another, and (v) independently of small GTPase Rab27a, the ESCRT complex-associated protein Alix, or the cargo protein CD63. Taken together, our results demonstrate that cells use a shared, stochastic mechanism to bud exosome cargoes along the spectrum of plasma and endosome membranes and far more efficiently from the plasma membrane than the endosome. Our observations also indicate that the pronounced variation in content between different exosome-sized vesicles is an inevitable consequence of a stochastic mechanism of small vesicle biogenesis, that the origin membrane of exosome-sized extracellular vesicles simply cannot be determined, and that most of what we currently know about exosomes has likely come from studies of plasma membrane-derived vesicles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Activated Drp1 regulates p62-mediated autophagic flux and aggravates inflammation in cerebral ischemia-reperfusion via the ROS-RIP1/RIP3-exosome axis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35624495/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35624495/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Cerebral ischemia-reperfusion injury (CIRI) refers to a secondary brain injury that can occur when the blood supply to the ischemic brain tissue is restored. However, the mechanism underlying such injury remains elusive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; The 150 male C57 mice underwent middle cerebral artery occlusion (MCAO) for 1 h and reperfusion for 24 h, Among them, 50 MCAO mice were further treated with Mitochondrial division inhibitor 1 (Mdivi-1) and 50 MCAO mice were further treated with N-acetylcysteine (NAC). SH-SY5Y cells were cultured in a low-glucose culture medium for 4 h under hypoxic conditions and then transferred to normal conditions for 12 h. Then, cerebral blood flow, mitochondrial structure, mitochondrial DNA (mtDNA) copy number, intracellular and mitochondrial reactive oxygen species (ROS), autophagic flux, aggresome and exosome expression profiles, cardiac tissue structure, mitochondrial length and cristae density, mtDNA and ROS content, as well as the expression of Drp1-Ser616/Drp1, RIP1/RIP3, LC3 II/LC3 I, TNF-α, IL-1β, etc., were detected under normal or Drp1 interference conditions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; The mtDNA content, ROS levels, and Drp1-Ser616/Drp1 were elevated by 2.2, 1.7 and 2.7 times after CIRI (&lt;em&gt;P&lt;/em&gt; &amp;lt; 0.05). However, the high cytoplasmic LC3 II/I ratio and increased aggregation of p62 could be reversed by 44% and 88% by Drp1 short hairpin RNA (shRNA) (&lt;em&gt;P&lt;/em&gt; &amp;lt; 0.05). The low fluorescence intensity of autophagic flux and the increased phosphorylation of RIP3 induced by CIRI could be attenuated by ROS scavenger, NAC (&lt;em&gt;P&lt;/em&gt; &amp;lt; 0.05). RIP1/RIP3 inhibitor Necrostatin-1 (Nec-1) restored 75% to a low LC3 II/LC3 I ratio and enhanced 2 times to a high RFP-LC3 after Drp1 activation (&lt;em&gt;P&lt;/em&gt; &amp;lt; 0.05). In addition, although CIRI-induced ROS production caused no considerable accumulation of autophagosomes (&lt;em&gt;P&lt;/em&gt; &amp;gt; 0.05), it increased the packaging and extracellular secretion of exosomes containing p62 by 4 - 5 times, which could be decreased by Mdivi-1, Drp1 shRNA, and Nec-1 (&lt;em&gt;P&lt;/em&gt; &amp;lt; 0.05). Furthermore, TNF-α and IL-1β increased in CIRI-derived exosomes could increase RIP3 phosphorylation in normal or oxygen-glucose deprivation/reoxygenation (OGD/R) conditions (&lt;em&gt;P&lt;/em&gt; &amp;lt; 0.05).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; CIRI activated Drp1 and accelerated the p62-mediated formation of autophagosomes while inhibiting the transition of autophagosomes to autolysosomes via the RIP1/RIP3 pathway activation. Undegraded autophagosomes were secreted extracellularly in the form of exosomes, leading to inflammatory cascades that further damaged mitochondria, resulting in excessive ROS generation and the blockage of autophagosome degradation, triggering a vicious cycle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Specificities of exosome versus small ectosome secretion revealed by live intracellular tracking of CD63 and CD9</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34282141/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34282141/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite their roles in intercellular communications, the different populations of extracellular vesicles (EVs) and their secretion mechanisms are not fully characterized: how and to what extent EVs form as intraluminal vesicles of endocytic compartments (exosomes), or at the plasma membrane (PM) (ectosomes) remains unclear. Here we follow intracellular trafficking of the EV markers CD9 and CD63 from the endoplasmic reticulum to their residency compartment, respectively PM and late endosomes. We observe transient co-localization at both places, before they finally segregate. CD9 and a mutant CD63 stabilized at the PM are more abundantly released in EVs than CD63. Thus, in HeLa cells, ectosomes are more prominent than exosomes. By comparative proteomic analysis and differential response to neutralization of endosomal pH, we identify a few surface proteins likely specific of either exosomes (LAMP1) or ectosomes (BSG, SLC3A2). Our work sets the path for molecular and functional discrimination of exosomes and small ectosomes in any cell type.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A multi-omics investigation of the composition and function of extracellular vesicles along the temporal trajectory of COVID-19</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34158670/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34158670/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The type I interferon (IFN-I, IFN-α/β)-mediated immune response is the first line of host defense against invading viruses. IFN-α/β binds to IFN-α/β receptors (IFNARs) and triggers the expression of IFN-stimulated genes (ISGs). Thus, stabilization of IFNARs is important for prolonging antiviral activity. Here, we report the induction of an RNA-binding motif-containing protein, RBM47, upon viral infection or interferon stimulation. Using multiple virus infection models, we demonstrate that RBM47 has broad-spectrum antiviral activity in vitro and in vivo. RBM47 has no noticeable impact on IFN production, but significantly activates the IFN-stimulated response element (ISRE) and enhances the expression of interferon-stimulated genes (ISGs). Mechanistically, RBM47 binds to the 3&amp;rsquo;UTR of IFNAR1 mRNA, increases mRNA stability, and retards the degradation of IFNAR1. In summary, this study suggests that RBM47 is an interferon-inducible RNA-binding protein that plays an essential role in enhancing host IFN downstream signaling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Targeted inhibition of SIRT6 via engineered exosomes impairs tumorigenesis and metastasis in prostate cancer</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33995674/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33995674/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The treatment for metastatic castration-resistant prostate cancer patients remains a great challenge in the clinic and continuously demands discoveries of new targets and therapies. Here, we assess the function and therapeutic value of SIRT6 in metastatic castration-resistant prostate cancer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The expression of SIRT6 was examined in prostate cancer tissue microarray by immunohistochemistry staining. The functions of SIRT6 and underlying mechanisms were elucidated by in vitro and in vivo experiments. We also developed an efficient method to silence SIRT6 by aptamer-modified exosomes carrying small interfering RNA and tested the therapeutic effect in the xenograft mice models.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SIRT6 expression is positively correlated with prostate cancer progression. Loss of SIRT6 significantly suppressed proliferation and metastasis of prostate cancer cell lines both in vitro and in vivo. SIRT6-driven prostate cancer displays activation of multiple cancer-related signaling pathways, especially the Notch pathway. Silencing SIRT6 by siRNA delivered through engineered exosomes inhibited tumor growth and metastasis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SIRT6 is identified as a driver and therapeutic target for metastatic prostate cancer in our findings, and inhibition of SIRT6 by engineered exosomes can serve as a promising therapeutic tool for clinical application.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>hnRNPA2B1 Associated with Recruitment of RNA into Exosomes Plays a Key Role in Herpes Simplex Virus 1 Release from Infected Cells</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32295924/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32295924/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;hnRNPA2B1, an abundant cellular protein, has been reported to recruit RNAs bearing a specific sequence (EXO motif) into exosomes. We characterized an exosome population averaging 100 ± 50 nm in diameter and containing a defined set of constitutive exosome markers. This population packages microRNAs (miRNAs) and can be directed to block targeted gene expression in a dose-dependent fashion. The objective of this study was to characterize the role of hnRNPA2B1 in the recruitment of miRNA. We report the following four key findings. (i) hnRNPA2B1 is not a component of exosomes produced in HEp-2 or HEK293T cells. Hence, hnRNPA2B1 carries its cargo, at most, to the site of exosome assembly, but it is not itself incorporated into exosomes. (ii) The accumulation of exosomes produced by cells in which the gene encoding hnRNPA2B1 has been knocked out (ΔhnRNPA2B1 cells) was reduced 3-fold. (iii) In uninfected HEp-2 cells, hnRNPA2B1 is localized in the nucleus. In cells infected with herpes simplex virus 1 (HSV-1), hnRNPA2B1 was quantitatively exported to the cytoplasm and at least a fraction of hnRNPA2B1 colocalized with a Golgi marker. (iv) Lastly, in ΔhnRNPA2B1 cells, there was a 2- to 3-fold reduction in virus yield but a significant (&amp;gt;10-fold) reduction in HSV-1 released through the apical surface into the extracellular environment. The absence of hnRNPA2B1 had no significant impact on the basolateral export of HSV-1 from infected to uninfected cells by direct cell-to-cell contact. The results suggest that hnRNPA2B1 plays a key role in the transport of enveloped virus from its site of assembly to the extracellular environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Importance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this report, we show that hnRNPA2B1 is not a component of exosomes produced in HEp-2 or HEK293T cells. In herpes simplex virus 1 (HSV-1)-infected cells, hnRNPA2B1 was quantitatively translocated from the nucleus into the cytoplasm. In infected ΔhnRNPA2B1 cells, Golgi-dependent transport of virus from the apical surface to the extracellular medium was significantly reduced. In essence, this report supports the hypothesis that hnRNPA2B1 plays a key role in the egress of exosomes and HSV-1 from infected cells.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exosome-based delivery of super-repressor IκBα relieves sepsis-associated organ damage and mortality</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32285005/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32285005/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As extracellular vesicles that play an active role in intercellular communication by transferring cellular materials to recipient cells, exosomes offer great potential as a natural therapeutic drug delivery vehicle. The inflammatory responses in various disease models can be attenuated through introduction of super-repressor IκB (srIκB), which is the dominant active form of IκBα and can inhibit translocation of nuclear factor κB into the nucleus. An optogenetically engineered exosome system (EXPLOR) that we previously developed was implemented for loading a large amount of srIκB into exosomes. We showed that intraperitoneal injection of purified srIκB-loaded exosomes (Exo-srIκBs) attenuates mortality and systemic inflammation in septic mouse models. In a biodistribution study, Exo-srIκBs were observed mainly in the neutrophils, and in monocytes to a lesser extent, in the spleens and livers of mice. Moreover, we found that Exo-srIκB alleviates inflammatory responses in monocytic THP-1 cells and human umbilical vein endothelial cells.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
