<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mitochondria | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/mitochondria/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/mitochondria/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Mitochondria</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Mitochondria</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/mitochondria/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mitochondria-localized lncRNA HITT inhibits fusion by attenuating formation of mitofusin-2 homo- or heterotypic complexes</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36567017/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36567017/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Long non-coding RNAs (lncRNAs) are emerging as essential players in multiple biological processes. Mitochondrial dynamics, comprising the continuous cycle of fission and fusion, are required for healthy mitochondria that function properly. Despite long-term recognition of its significance in cell-fate control, the mechanism underlying mitochondrial fusion is not completely understood, particularly regarding the involvement of lncRNAs. Here, we show that the lncRNA HITT (HIF-1α inhibitor at translation level), can specifically localize in mitochondria. Cells expressing higher levels of HITT contain fragmented mitochondria. Conversely, we show that HITT knockdown cells have more tubular mitochondria than is present in control cells. Mechanistically, we demonstrate HITT directly binds mitofusin-2 (MFN2), a core component that mediates mitochondrial outer membrane fusion, by the &lt;em&gt;in vitro&lt;/em&gt; RNA pull-down and UV-cross-linking RNA-IP (CLIP) assays. In doing so, we found HITT disturbs MFN2 homo- or heterotypic complex formation, attenuating mitochondrial fusion. Under stress conditions, such as ultraviolet radiation, we in addition show HITT stability increases as a consequence of MiR-205 downregulation, inhibiting MFN2-mediated fusion and leading to apoptosis. Overall, our data provide significant insights into the roles of organelle (mitochondria)-specific resident lncRNAs in regulating mitochondrial fusion, and also reveal how such a mechanism controls cellular sensitivity to UV radiation-induced apoptosis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dual roles of hexokinase 2 in shaping microglial function by gating glycolytic flux and mitochondrial activity</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36536134/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36536134/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Microglia continuously survey the brain parenchyma and actively shift status following stimulation. These processes demand a unique bioenergetic programme; however, little is known about the metabolic determinants in microglia. By mining large datasets and generating transgenic tools, here we show that hexokinase 2 (HK2), the most active isozyme associated with mitochondrial membrane, is selectively expressed in microglia in the brain. Genetic ablation of HK2 reduced microglial glycolytic flux and energy production, suppressed microglial repopulation, and attenuated microglial surveillance and damage-triggered migration in male mice. HK2 elevation is prominent in immune-challenged or disease-associated microglia. In ischaemic stroke models, however, HK2 deletion promoted neuroinflammation and potentiated cerebral damages. The enhanced inflammatory responses after HK2 ablation in microglia are associated with aberrant mitochondrial function and reactive oxygen species accumulation. Our study demonstrates that HK2 gates both glycolytic flux and mitochondrial activity to shape microglial functions, changes of which contribute to metabolic abnormalities and maladaptive inflammation in brain diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multi-color live-cell STED nanoscopy of mitochondria with a gentle inner membrane stain</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36534799/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36534799/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Capturing mitochondria&amp;rsquo;s intricate and dynamic structure poses a daunting challenge for optical nanoscopy. Different labeling strategies have been demonstrated for live-cell stimulated emission depletion (STED) microscopy of mitochondria, but orthogonal strategies are yet to be established, and image acquisition has suffered either from photodamage to the organelles or from rapid photobleaching. Therefore, live-cell nanoscopy of mitochondria has been largely restricted to two-dimensional (2D) single-color recordings of cancer cells. Here, by conjugation of cyclooctatetraene (COT) to a benzo-fused cyanine dye, we report a mitochondrial inner membrane (IM) fluorescent marker, PK Mito Orange (PKMO), featuring efficient STED at 775 nm, strong photostability, and markedly reduced phototoxicity. PKMO enables super-resolution (SR) recordings of IM dynamics for extended periods in immortalized mammalian cell lines, primary cells, and organoids. Photostability and reduced phototoxicity of PKMO open the door to live-cell three-dimensional (3D) STED nanoscopy of mitochondria for 3D analysis of the convoluted IM. PKMO is optically orthogonal with green and far-red markers, allowing multiplexed recordings of mitochondria using commercial STED microscopes. Using multi-color STED microscopy, we demonstrate that imaging with PKMO can capture interactions of mitochondria with different cellular components such as the endoplasmic reticulum (ER) or the cytoskeleton, Bcl-2-associated X protein (BAX)-induced apoptotic process, or crista phenotypes in genetically modified cells, all at sub-100 nm resolution. Thereby, this work offers a versatile tool for studying mitochondrial IM architecture and dynamics in a multiplexed manner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Endosomal lipid signaling reshapes the endoplasmic reticulum to control mitochondrial function</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36520888/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36520888/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;INTRODUCTION&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cells need to react appropriately to nutritional cues. Defects in the rewiring of metabolism in response to alterations in nutrient supply have been linked to human diseases ranging from diabetes to muscle atrophy. Starvation represses anabolic pathways and facilitates catabolic ones, such as the degradation of macromolecules by autophagy and endolysosomes. Starvation also promotes the β-oxidation of fatty acids in mitochondria to produce adenosine triphosphate (ATP). Within cells, organelles including lysosomes and mitochondria undergo changes in shape and dynamics. These processes are often regulated by phosphoinositide lipids. Phosphoinositides are also involved in the formation of membrane contacts between organelles and in the response of cells and tissues to growth and nutrient signals. How the adaptive changes that protect mammalian cells and tissues from starvation-induced damage are coordinated on a cell-wide scale is unknown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;RATIONALE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Endolysosomal membrane dynamics and function are controlled by phosphoinositide signaling lipids, most notably by the synthesis and turnover of phosphatidylinositol 3-phosphate [PI(3)P]. Patients carrying mutations in the gene encoding the lipid phosphatase MTM1, an enzyme that mediates endosomal PI(3)P turnover, suffer from X-linked centronuclear myopathy (XLCNM), a severe neuromuscular disease characterized by muscle atrophy, disorganization of mitochondria, and defects in the organization of the muscle endoplasmic reticulum (ER). Given that PI(3)P is a hallmark of endosomes, we hypothesized that the control of early endosomal PI(3)P by MTM1 might serve to orchestrate adaptive changes in the dynamics of the ER and mitochondria in response to altering nutrient supply.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;RESULTS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Working with XLCNM patient–derived myoblasts and engineered cell lines, we found that nutrient starvation (for example, lack of amino acids) induced the hydrolysis of PI(3)P by endosomal recruitment of MTM1. Concomitantly, tubular ER membranes were observed to be converted into ER sheets by live super-resolution light microscopy. Mechanistically, loss of early endosomal PI(3)P upon starvation was found to reduce membrane contacts between peripheral ER tubules and early endosomes. These contacts function as physical tethers that may transmit pulling forces from highly motile peripheral endosomes to the tubular ER. Using proximity labeling proteomic and functional cell biological experiments we demonstrated that the ER–endosome contacts were mediated by binding of the related ER membrane proteins RRBP1 and kinectin 1 to PI(3)P on endosomes. To study the role of starvation-induced reshaping of tubular ER membranes into sheets on mitochondrial form and function, we combined live imaging with three-dimensional focused ion beam milling scanning electron microscopy (FIB-SEM) and proteomic analysis. We found that starvation-induced ER reshaping by MTM1 reduced the rate of mitochondrial fission and promoted the formation of a hyperfused mitochondrial network. Genetic manipulations that resulted in ER sheet expansion caused the formation of an enlarged mitochondrial network even in fed cells. Conversely, impaired ER reshaping and reduced mitochondrial network formation were observed in starved myoblasts from XLCNM patients. Mitochondrial network formation appeared to be critical for the delivery of fatty acids from lipid droplets to mitochondria and for oxidative ATP production to sustain energy supply in nutrient-deprived cells.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CONCLUSION&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our data unravel a crucial role for early endosomal lipid signaling in controlling ER morphology and, thereby, mitochondrial form and function to orchestrate the adaptive response of cells to alterations in nutrient (e.g., amino acid) supply. This mechanism operates independent of autophagy, a cellular self-eating process typically induced by prolonged starvation. Rather, it resembles an organellar conveyor belt, in which the tubular ER serves as a membrane conduit that transmits nutrient-triggered changes in endosomal PI(3)P levels to metabolic organelles to enable metabolic rewiring. How early endosomal PI(3)P levels and MTM1 function are controlled by cellular nutrient status is currently unknown. Defects in ER shape, mitochondrial morphogenesis, and cellular ATP depletion caused by loss of MTM1 function can explain the observed myofiber hypotrophy and defective ER organization in animal models of XLCNM and in human patients who often appear undernourished. We therefore hypothesize that dysregulated organelle remodeling may underlie XLCNM caused by MTM1 mutations in humans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mitochondrial cristae architecture protects against mtDNA release and inflammation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36476853/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36476853/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A mitochondria-targeted sgRNA library for interrogating mitochondrial function&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mitochondrial regulators of type I interferon (IFN-I) response are identified&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cristae disorganization induces mtDNA release and STING-dependent IFN-I response&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Knockout of cristae regulator Metaxin-2 causes the IFN-I response in vivo&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mitochondrial damage causes mitochondrial DNA (mtDNA) release to activate the type I interferon (IFN-I) response via the cGAS-STING pathway. mtDNA-induced inflammation promotes autoimmune- and aging-related degenerative disorders. However, the global picture of inflammation-inducing mitochondrial damages remains obscure. Here, we have performed a mitochondria-targeted CRISPR knockout screen for regulators of the IFN-I response. Strikingly, our screen reveals dozens of hits enriched with key regulators of cristae architecture, including phospholipid cardiolipin and protein complexes such as OPA1, mitochondrial contact site and cristae organization (MICOS), sorting and assembly machinery (SAM), mitochondrial intermembrane space bridging (MIB), prohibitin (PHB), and the F&lt;sub&gt;1&lt;/sub&gt;F&lt;sub&gt;o&lt;/sub&gt;-ATP synthase. Disrupting these cristae organizers consistently induces mtDNA release and the STING-dependent IFN-I response. Furthermore, knocking out MTX2, a subunit of the SAM complex whose null mutations cause progeria in humans, induces a robust STING-dependent IFN-I response in mouse liver. Taken together, beyond revealing the central role of cristae architecture to prevent mtDNA release and inflammation, our results mechanistically link mitochondrial cristae disorganization and inflammation, two emerging hallmarks of aging and aging-related degenerative diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nuclear localization of mitochondrial TCA cycle enzymes modulates pluripotency via histone acetylation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36460681/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36460681/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pluripotent stem cells hold great promise in regenerative medicine and developmental biology studies. Mitochondrial metabolites, including tricarboxylic acid (TCA) cycle intermediates, have been reported to play critical roles in pluripotency. Here we show that TCA cycle enzymes including Pdha1, Pcb, Aco2, Cs, Idh3a, Ogdh, Sdha and Mdh2 are translocated to the nucleus during somatic cell reprogramming, primed-to-naive transition and totipotency acquisition. The nuclear-localized TCA cycle enzymes Pdha1, Pcb, Aco2, Cs, Idh3a promote somatic cell reprogramming and primed-to-naive transition. In addition, nuclear-localized TCA cycle enzymes, particularly nuclear-targeted Pdha1, facilitate the 2-cell program in pluripotent stem cells. Mechanistically, nuclear Pdha1 increases the acetyl-CoA and metabolite pool in the nucleus, leading to chromatin remodeling at pluripotency genes by enhancing histone H3 acetylation. Our results reveal an important role of mitochondrial TCA cycle enzymes in the epigenetic regulation of pluripotency that constitutes a mitochondria-to-nucleus retrograde signaling mode in different states of pluripotent acquisition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UBXD8 mediates mitochondria-associated degradation to restrain apoptosis and mitophagy</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35979733/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35979733/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The hexameric AAA-ATPase valosin-containing protein (VCP) is essential for mitochondrial protein quality control. How VCP is recruited to mammalian mitochondria remains obscure. Here we report that UBXD8, an ER- and lipid droplet-localized VCP adaptor, also localizes to mitochondria and locally recruits VCP. UBXD8 associates with mitochondrial and ER ubiquitin E3 ligases and targets their substrates for degradation. Remarkably, both mitochondria- and ER-localized UBXD8 can degrade mitochondrial and ER substrates in cis and in trans. UBXD8 also associates with the TOM complex but is dispensable for translocation-associated degradation. UBXD8 knockout impairs the degradation of the pro-survival protein Mcl1 but surprisingly sensitizes cells to apoptosis and mitochondrial stresses. UBXD8 knockout also hyperactivates mitophagy. We identify pro-apoptotic BH3-only proteins Noxa, Bik, and Bnip3 as novel UBXD8 substrates and determine that UBXD8 inhibits apoptosis via degrading Noxa and restrains mitophagy via degrading Bnip3. Collectively, our characterizations reveal UBXD8 as the major mitochondrial adaptor of VCP and unveil its role in apoptosis and mitophagy regulation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CircRNA Samd4 induces cardiac repair after myocardial infarction by blocking mitochondria-derived ROS output</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35791879/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35791879/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reactive oxygen species (ROS) derived from oxygen-dependent mitochondrial metabolism are the essential drivers of cardiomyocyte (CM) cell-cycle arrest in adulthood. Mitochondria-localized circular RNAs (circRNAs) play important roles in regulating mitochondria-derived ROS production, but their functions in cardiac regeneration are still unknown. Herein, we investigated the functions and underlying mechanism of mitochondria-localized circSamd4 in cardiac regeneration. We found that circSamd4 was selectively expressed in fetal and neonatal CMs. The transcription factor Nrf2 controlled circSamd4 expression by binding to the promoter of circSamd4 host gene. CircSamd4 overexpression reduced while circSamd4 silenced increased mitochondrial oxidative stress and subsequent oxidative DNA damage. Moreover, circSamd4 overexpression induced CM proliferation and prevented CM apoptosis, which reduced the size of the fibrotic area and improved cardiac function after myocardial infarction (MI). Mechanistically, circSamd4 reduced oxidative stress generation and maintained mitochondrial dynamics by inducing the mitochondrial translocation of the Vcp protein, which downregulated Vdac1 expression and prevented the mitochondrial permeability transition pore (mPTP) from opening. Our findings suggest that circSamd4 is a novel therapeutic target for heart failure after MI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>P4HB UFMylation regulates mitochondrial function and oxidative stress</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35753586/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35753586/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UFMylation is a ubiquitin-like modification which attaches the ubiquitin-fold modifier 1 to target proteins. To date, only a few UFMylation targets have been identified. In the current study, we demonstrated that P4HB is a new target protein for UFMylation and it can be UFMylated at three lysine residues in the form of mono-UFMylation. P4HB has oxidoreductase, chaperone and isomerase effects. It presents in the endoplasmic reticulum, mitochondria and cytosol. Next, we generated a stable HepG2 cell line, the hepatocellular cells, with defective P4HB UFMylation. Our data show that P4HB UFMylation defect promotes P4HB protein degradation via the ubiquitin-proteasome pathway. Defective P4HB UFMylation causes mitochondrial function damage, oxidative stress, and endoplasmic reticulum stress in HepG2 cells. These effects are more obvious when treating HepG2 cells with palmitic acid, which is frequently used as one of the cell models of non-alcoholic fatty liver disease (NAFLD). Our results identify UFMylation as a key post-translational modification for the maintenance of P4HB stability and biological functions in HepG2 cells, and point to P4HB UFMylation as a potential direction in the study of NAFLD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>STING signaling sensing of DRP1-dependent mtDNA release in kupffer cells contributes to lipopolysaccharide-induced liver injury in mice</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35724543/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35724543/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aberrant pro-inflammatory activation of Kupffer cells (KCs) is strongly involved in the pathogenesis of septic liver injury. Recent evidence indicates the crucial roles of excessive stimulator of interferon genes (STING) signaling activation during sepsis. However, the role of STING signaling in septic liver injury remains unclear. In this study, we demonstrated that STING signaling was markedly activated in KCs isolated from wild type mice after lipopolysaccharide (LPS) treatment. STING deficiency effectively protected liver function, attenuated systemic inflammatory response and decreased mortality in LPS-treated mice, which were aggravated by STING agonist (DMXAA). Importantly, STING signaling activation in KCs contributed to LPS-induced liver injury through promoting hepatocyte death. Mechanistically, STING signaling could be activated by release of mitochondrial DNA (mtDNA) through dynamin-related protein 1 (DRP1)-dependent mitochondrial fission in LPS-treated KCs. Additionally, LPS stimulation enhanced DRP1-dependent mitochondrial ROS production, which promoted the leak of mtDNA into the cytosol and subsequent STING signaling activation in KCs. The in vivo experiments showed that pharmacological inhibition of DRP1 with Mdivi-1 partially prevented the activation of STING signaling in KCs isolated from LPS-challenged mice, as well as alleviated liver injury and inhibited systemic inflammatory response. In summary, our study comprehensively confirmed that STING signaling senses the DRP1-dependent release of mtDNA in KCs and its activation might play a key role in LPS-induced liver injury, which offers new sights and therapeutic targets for management of septic liver injury.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Loss of Sam50 in hepatocytes induces cardiolipin-dependent mitochondrial membrane remodeling to trigger mtDNA release and liver injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35313046/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35313046/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background and aims:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sam50, a key component of the sorting and assembly machinery (SAM) complex, is also involved in bridging mitochondrial outer-membrane and inner-membrane contacts. However, the physiological and pathological functions of Sam50 remain largely unknown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Approach and results:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here we show that Sam50 interacts with MICOS (mitochondrial contact site and cristae organizing system) and ATAD3 (ATPase family AAA domain-containing protein 3) to form the Sam50-MICOS-ATAD3-mtDNA axis, which maintains mtDNA stability. Loss of Sam50 causes mitochondrial DNA (mtDNA) aggregation. Furthermore, Sam50 cooperates with Mic60 to bind to cardiolipin, maintaining the integrity of mitochondrial membranes. Sam50 depletion leads to cardiolipin externalization, which causes mitochondrial outer-membrane and inner-membrane (including crista membrane) remodeling, triggering Bax mitochondrial recruitment, mtDNA aggregation, and release. Physiologically, acetaminophen (an effective antipyretic and analgesic)-caused Sam50 reduction or Sam50 liver-specific knockout induces mtDNA release, leading to activation of the cGAS-STING pathway and liver inflammation in mice. Moreover, exogenous expression of Sam50 remarkably attenuates APAP-induced liver hepatoxicity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our findings uncover the critical role of Sam50 in maintaining mitochondrial membrane integrity and mtDNA stability in hepatocytes and reveal that Sam50 depletion-induced cardiolipin externalization is a signal of mtDNA release and controls mtDNA-dependent innate immunity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bacterial peptidoglycan muropeptides benefit mitochondrial homeostasis and animal physiology by acting as ATP synthase agonists</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35045336/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35045336/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The symbiotic relationship between commensal microbes and host animals predicts unidentified beneficial impacts of individual bacterial metabolites on animal physiology. Peptidoglycan fragments (muropeptides) from the bacterial cell wall are known for their roles in pathogenicity and for inducing host immune responses. However, the potential beneficial usage of muropeptides from commensal bacteria by the host needs exploration. We identified a striking role for muropeptides in supporting mitochondrial homeostasis, development, and behaviors in Caenorhabditis elegans. We determined that the beneficial molecules are disaccharide muropeptides containing a short AA chain, and they enter intestinal-cell mitochondria to repress oxidative stress. Further analyses indicate that muropeptides execute this role by binding to and promoting the activity of ATP synthase. Therefore, given the exceptional structural conservation of ATP synthase, the role of muropeptides as a rare agonist of the ATP synthase presents a major conceptual modification regarding the impact of bacterial cell metabolites on animal physiology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mitochondria shed their outer membrane in response to infection-induced stress</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35025629/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35025629/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;INTRODUCTION&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mitochondria are dynamic organelles that coordinate many cellular functions that are essential for life, including diverse metabolic processes, cell division and differentiation, and immune signaling.
To carry out these diverse functions, mitochondria must communicate with the cytosol, a task mediated by the outer mitochondrial membrane (OMM), the gateway between mitochondria and the rest of the cell. Thus, preserving the integrity of the OMM is essential for cellular homeostasis. Although responses to stress that is artificially induced by small molecules have been described, little is known of the mechanisms by which mammalian cells respond to naturally occurring stresses of the OMM.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;RATIONALE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Several intracellular microbes come in contact with the host OMM or release proteins that target the OMM. We reasoned that microbial infection would serve as a model with which to study cellular responses to natural OMM stress. To this end, we chose the human parasite Toxoplasma gondii because it tethers host mitochondria to its parasite vacuole; in an infected cell, areas of close membrane apposition form between the host OMM and the parasite vacuole membrane. To address how Toxoplasma affected the OMM, we performed live-cell imaging of infected mammalian cells stably expressing OMM-targeted green fluorescent protein (GFP). We found that mitochondria in contact with the Toxoplasma vacuole released large structures that were positive for OMM, which we termed “SPOTs.” Analysis of SPOTs in fixed and live cells revealed that SPOTs did not contain proteins of the mitochondrial matrix and inner mitochondrial membrane (IMM).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;RESULTS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having identified Toxoplasma infection as a natural stress that induced OMM remodeling and the shedding of SPOTs, we next dissected how these structures are formed. We found that the secreted effector protein TgMAF1 (Toxoplasma gondii mitochondrial association factor 1), which tethers the host OMM to the parasite vacuole membrane, was required for SPOT formation. TgMAF1 led to a decrease in the amount of mitochondrial proteins during infection. In particular, the OMM proteins mitofusin 1 and mitofusin 2 were degraded during infection. These proteins, which mediate a nutritional defense against Toxoplasma by promoting mitochondrial uptake of fatty acids, localized to SPOTs. The ability of TgMAF1 to induce SPOTs depended on its binding to the host OMM import receptor TOM70 (translocase of the outer membrane 70), whose import function TgMAF1 impaired. TOM70 was required for optimal parasite growth and enabled an interaction between TgMAF1 and the OMM translocase SAM50 (sorting assembly machinery 50 kDa subunit), which is a key component of the OMM-IMM mitochondrial intermembrane space bridging (MIB) complex. The genetic ablation of SAM50 and the overexpression of an OMM-targeted protein induced the formation of SPOT-like structures independently of infection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CONCLUSION&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because SAM50 is the only component of mitochondrial import machinery that bridges the OMM and IMM, it is in a position to translate OMM stress into the removal of compromised OMM. TgMAF1 behaves as a mitochondrial preprotein that uses the host receptor TOM70 to interact with SAM50. This enables Toxoplasma to hijack a cellular response to OMM stress—the formation of SPOTs—and drive the constitutive shedding of the OMM. Consequently, levels of mitochondrial proteins that restrict parasite growth are depleted, and import machinery that is required for mitochondrial biogenesis is sequestered on SPOTs. In an infection-independent context, however, we propose that SPOT-like structures could mitigate OMM stress by enabling the excision of dysfunctional OMM machinery, such as import receptors or translocases during defective import. Our finding that OMM remodeling occurs during infection and infection-independent scenarios sheds light on potential cellular mechanisms that safeguard OMM function.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quantitative high-confidence human mitochondrial proteome and its dynamics in cellular context</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34800366/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34800366/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mitochondria are key organelles for cellular energetics, metabolism, signaling, and quality control and have been linked to various diseases. Different views exist on the composition of the human mitochondrial proteome. We classified &amp;gt;8,000 proteins in mitochondrial preparations of human cells and defined a mitochondrial high-confidence proteome of &amp;gt;1,100 proteins (MitoCoP). We identified interactors of translocases, respiratory chain, and ATP synthase assembly factors. The abundance of MitoCoP proteins covers six orders of magnitude and amounts to 7% of the cellular proteome with the chaperones HSP60-HSP10 being the most abundant mitochondrial proteins. MitoCoP dynamics spans three orders of magnitudes, with half-lives from hours to months, and suggests a rapid regulation of biosynthesis and assembly processes. 460 MitoCoP genes are linked to human diseases with a strong prevalence for the central nervous system and metabolism. MitoCoP will provide a high-confidence resource for placing dynamics, functions, and dysfunctions of mitochondria into the cellular context.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ALKBH7-mediated demethylation regulates mitochondrial polycistronic RNA processing</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34253897/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34253897/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Members of the mammalian AlkB family are known to mediate nucleic acid demethylation. ALKBH7, a mammalian AlkB homologue, localizes in mitochondria and affects metabolism, but its function and mechanism of action are unknown. Here we report an approach to site-specifically detect N&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;-methyladenosine (m&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;A), N&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;-methylcytidine (m&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;C), N&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;-methylguanosine (m&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;G) and N&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;,N&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;-dimethylguanosine (m&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;G) modifications simultaneously within all cellular RNAs, and discovered that human ALKBH7 demethylates m&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;G and m&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;A within mitochondrial Ile and Leu1 pre-tRNA regions, respectively, in nascent polycistronic mitochondrial RNA. We further show that ALKBH7 regulates the processing and structural dynamics of polycistronic mitochondrial RNAs. Depletion of ALKBH7 leads to increased polycistronic mitochondrial RNA processing, reduced steady-state mitochondria-encoded tRNA levels and protein translation, and notably decreased mitochondrial activity. Thus, we identify ALKBH7 as an RNA demethylase that controls nascent mitochondrial RNA processing and mitochondrial activity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Structural insight into the molecular mechanism of p53-mediated mitochondrial apoptosis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33863900/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33863900/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tumor suppressor p53 is mutated in approximately half of all human cancers. p53 can induce apoptosis through mitochondrial membrane permeabilization by interacting with and antagonizing the anti-apoptotic proteins BCL-xL and BCL-2. However, the mechanisms by which p53 induces mitochondrial apoptosis remain elusive. Here, we report a 2.5 Å crystal structure of human p53/BCL-xL complex. In this structure, two p53 molecules interact as a homodimer, and bind one BCL-xL molecule to form a ternary complex with a 2:1 stoichiometry. Mutations at the p53 dimer interface or p53/BCL-xL interface disrupt p53/BCL-xL interaction and p53-mediated apoptosis. Overall, our current findings of the bona fide structure of p53/BCL-xL complex reveal the molecular basis of the interaction between p53 and BCL-xL, and provide insight into p53-mediated mitochondrial apoptosis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apaf-1 Pyroptosome Senses Mitochondrial Permeability Transition</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33308446/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33308446/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Caspase-4 is an intracellular sensor for cytosolic bacterial lipopolysaccharide (LPS) and underlies infection-elicited pyroptosis. It is unclear whether and how caspase-4 detects host-derived factors to trigger pyroptosis. Here we show that mitochondrial permeability transition (MPT) activates caspase-4 by promoting the assembly of a protein complex, which we term the Apaf-1 pyroptosome, for the execution of facilitated pyroptosis. MPT, when induced by bile acids, calcium overload, or an adenine nucleotide translocator 1 (ANT1) activator, triggers assembly of the pyroptosome comprised of Apaf-1 and caspase-4 with a stoichiometry ratio of 7:2. Unlike the direct cleavage of gasdermin D (GSDMD) by caspase-4 upon LPS ligation, caspase-4 activated in the Apaf-1 pyroptosome proceeds to cleave caspase-3 and thereby GSDME to induce pyroptosis. Caspase-4-initiated and GSDME-executed pyroptosis underlies cholestatic liver failure. These findings identify Apaf-1 pyroptosome as a pivotal machinery for cells sensing MPT signals and may shed light on understanding how cells execute intrinsic pyroptosis under sterile conditions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Autophagy regulates fatty acid availability for oxidative phosphorylation through mitochondria-endoplasmic reticulum contact sites</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32792483/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32792483/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Autophagy has been associated with oncogenesis with one of its emerging key functions being its contribution to the metabolism of tumors. Therefore, deciphering the mechanisms of how autophagy supports tumor cell metabolism is essential. Here, we demonstrate that the inhibition of autophagy induces an accumulation of lipid droplets (LD) due to a decrease in fatty acid β-oxidation, that leads to a reduction of oxidative phosphorylation (OxPHOS) in acute myeloid leukemia (AML), but not in normal cells. Thus, the autophagic process participates in lipid catabolism that supports OxPHOS in AML cells. Interestingly, the inhibition of OxPHOS leads to LD accumulation with the concomitant inhibition of autophagy. Mechanistically, we show that the disruption of mitochondria-endoplasmic reticulum (ER) contact sites (MERCs) phenocopies OxPHOS inhibition. Altogether, our data establish that mitochondria, through the regulation of MERCs, controls autophagy that, in turn finely tunes lipid degradation to fuel OxPHOS supporting proliferation and growth in leukemia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IL-1 induces mitochondrial translocation of IRAK2 to suppress oxidative metabolism in adipocytes</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32778760/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32778760/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chronic inflammation is a common feature of obesity, with elevated cytokines such as interleukin-1 (IL-1) in the circulation and tissues. Here, we report an unconventional IL-1R–MyD88–IRAK2–PHB/OPA1 signaling axis that reprograms mitochondrial metabolism in adipocytes to exacerbate obesity. IL-1 induced recruitment of IRAK2 Myddosome to mitochondria outer membranes via recognition by TOM20, followed by TIMM50-guided translocation of IRAK2 into mitochondria inner membranes, to suppress oxidative phosphorylation and fatty acid oxidation, thereby attenuating energy expenditure. Adipocyte-specific MyD88 or IRAK2 deficiency reduced high-fat-diet-induced weight gain, increased energy expenditure and ameliorated insulin resistance, associated with a smaller adipocyte size and increased cristae formation. IRAK2 kinase inactivation also reduced high-fat diet-induced metabolic diseases. Mechanistically, IRAK2 suppressed respiratory super-complex formation via interaction with PHB1 and OPA1 upon stimulation of IL-1. Taken together, our results suggest that the IRAK2 Myddosome functions as a critical link between inflammation and metabolism, representing a novel therapeutic target for patients with obesity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nuclear receptor PXR targets AKR1B7 to protect mitochondrial metabolism and renal function in AKI</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32404507/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32404507/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acute kidney injury (AKI) is a worldwide public health problem with no specific and satisfactory therapies in clinic. The nuclear pregnane X receptor (PXR) is involved in the progression of multiple diseases, including metabolic diseases, atherosclerosis, hypertension, liver injury, etc. However, its role in kidney injury remains to be understood. In this study, we have investigated the role of PXR in AKI and underlying mechanism(s) involved in its function. PXR was robustly down-regulated and negatively correlated with renal dysfunction in human and animal kidneys with AKI. Silencing PXR in rats enhanced cisplatin-induced AKI and induced severe mitochondrial abnormalities, whereas activating PXR protected against AKI. Using luciferase reporter assays, genomic manipulation, and proteomics data analysis on the kidneys of PXR&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt; rats, we determined that PXR targeted Aldo-keto reductase family 1, member B7 (AKR1B7) to improve mitochondrial function, thereby ameliorating AKI. We confirmed the protective role of PXR against kidney injury using genomic and pharmacologic approaches in an ischemia/reperfusion model of AKI. These findings demonstrate that disabling the PXR/AKR1B7/mitochondrial metabolism axis is an important factor that can contribute to AKI, whereas reestablishing this axis can be useful for treating AKI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A pathway coordinated by DELE1 relays mitochondrial stress to the cytosol</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32132706/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32132706/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mitochondrial fidelity is tightly linked to overall cellular homeostasis and is compromised in ageing and various pathologies. Mitochondrial malfunction needs to be relayed to the cytosol, where an integrated stress response is triggered by the phosphorylation of eukaryotic translation initiation factor 2α (eIF2α) in mammalian cells. eIF2α phosphorylation is mediated by the four eIF2α kinases GCN2, HRI, PERK and PKR, which are activated by diverse types of cellular stress. However, the machinery that communicates mitochondrial perturbation to the cytosol to trigger the integrated stress response remains unknown. Here we combine genome engineering and haploid genetics to unbiasedly identify genes that affect the induction of C/EBP homologous protein (CHOP), a key factor in the integrated stress response. We show that the mitochondrial protease OMA1 and the poorly characterized protein DELE1, together with HRI, constitute the missing pathway that is triggered by mitochondrial stress. Mechanistically, stress-induced activation of OMA1 causes DELE1 to be cleaved into a short form that accumulates in the cytosol, where it binds to and activates HRI via its C-terminal portion. Obstruction of this pathway can be beneficial or adverse depending on the type of mitochondrial perturbation. In addition to the core pathway components, our comparative genetic screening strategy identifies a suite of additional regulators. Together, these findings could be used to inform future strategies to modulate the cellular response to mitochondrial dysfunction in the context of human disease.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mitochondrial DNA stress triggers autophagy-dependent ferroptotic death</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32186434/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32186434/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pancreatic cancer tends to be highly resistant to current therapy and remains one of the great challenges in biomedicine with very low 5-year survival rates. Here, we report that zalcitabine, an antiviral drug for human immunodeficiency virus infection, can suppress the growth of primary and immortalized human pancreatic cancer cells through the induction of ferroptosis, an iron-dependent form of regulated cell death. Mechanically, this effect relies on zalcitabine-induced mitochondrial DNA stress, which activates the STING1/TMEM173-mediated DNA sensing pathway, leading to macroautophagy/autophagy-dependent ferroptotic cell death via lipid peroxidation, but not a type I interferon response. Consequently, the genetic and pharmacological inactivation of the autophagy-dependent ferroptosis pathway diminishes the anticancer effects of zalcitabine in cell culture and animal models. Together, these findings not only provide a new approach for pancreatic cancer therapy but also increase our understanding of the interplay between autophagy and DNA damage response in shaping cell death.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mitochondrial fragmentation limits NK cell-based tumor immunosurveillance</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/31636463/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/31636463/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Natural killer (NK) cells have crucial roles in tumor surveillance. We found that tumor-infiltrating NK cells in human liver cancers had small, fragmented mitochondria in their cytoplasm, whereas liver NK cells outside tumors, as well as peripheral NK cells, had normal large, tubular mitochondria. This fragmentation was correlated with reduced cytotoxicity and NK cell loss, resulting in tumor evasion of NK cell-mediated surveillance, which predicted poor survival in patients with liver cancer. The hypoxic tumor microenvironment drove the sustained activation of mechanistic target of rapamycin-GTPase dynamin-related protein 1 (mTOR-Drp1) in NK cells, resulting in excessive mitochondrial fission into fragments. Inhibition of mitochondrial fragmentation improved mitochondrial metabolism, survival and the antitumor capacity of NK cells. These data reveal a mechanism of immune escape that might be targetable and could invigorate NK cell-based cancer treatments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>S100a8/a9 Signaling Causes Mitochondrial Dysfunction and Cardiomyocyte Death in Response to Ischemic/Reperfusion Injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/31220942/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/31220942/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Myocardial ischemia-reperfusion (MI/R) injury is a significant clinical problem without effective therapy. Unbiased omics approaches may reveal key MI/R mediators to initiate MI/R injury.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; We used a dynamic transcriptome analysis of mouse heart exposed to various MI/R periods to identify S100a8/a9 as an early mediator. Using loss/gain-of-function approaches to understand the role of S100a8/a9 in MI/R injury, we explored the mechanisms through transcriptome and functional experiment. Dynamic serum S100a8/a9 levels were measured in patients with acute myocardial infarction before and after percutaneous coronary intervention. Patients were prospectively followed for the occurrence of major adverse cardiovascular events.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; S100a8/a9 was identified as the most significantly upregulated gene during the early reperfusion stage. Knockout of S100a9 markedly decreased cardiomyocyte death and improved heart function, whereas hematopoietic overexpression of S100a9 exacerbated MI/R injury. Transcriptome/functional studies revealed that S100a8/a9 caused mitochondrial respiratory dysfunction in cardiomyocytes. Mechanistically, S100a8/a9 downregulated NDUF gene expression with subsequent mitochondrial complex I inhibition via Toll-like receptor 4/Erk-mediated Pparg coactivator 1 alpha/nuclear respiratory factor 1 signaling suppression. Administration of S100a9 neutralizing antibody significantly reduced MI/R injury and improved cardiac function. Finally, we demonstrated that serum S100a8/a9 levels were significantly increased 1 day after percutaneous coronary intervention in patients with acute myocardial infarction, and elevated S100a8/a9 levels were associated with the incidence of major adverse cardiovascular events.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; Our study identified S100a8/a9 as a master regulator causing cardiomyocyte death in the early stage of MI/R injury via the suppression of mitochondrial function. Targeting S100a8/a9-intiated signaling may represent a novel therapeutic intervention against MI/R injury.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mitochondrial medicine in the omics era</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/29903433/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/29903433/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mitochondria are dynamic bioenergetic organelles whose maintenance requires around 1500 proteins from two genomes. Mutations in either the mitochondrial or nuclear genome can disrupt a plethora of cellular metabolic and homoeostatic functions. Mitochondrial diseases represent one of the most common and severe groups of inherited genetic disorders, characterised by clinical, biochemical, and genetic heterogeneity, diagnostic odysseys, and absence of disease-modifying curative therapies. This Review aims to discuss recent advances in mitochondrial biology and medicine arising from widespread use of high-throughput omics technologies, and also includes a broad discussion of emerging therapies for mitochondrial disease. New insights into both bioenergetic and biosynthetic mitochondrial functionalities have expedited the genetic diagnosis of primary mitochondrial disorders, and identified novel mitochondrial pathomechanisms and new targets for therapeutic intervention. As we enter this new era of mitochondrial medicine, underpinned by global unbiased approaches and multifaceted investigation of mitochondrial function, omics technologies will continue to shed light on unresolved mitochondrial questions, paving the way for improved outcomes for patients with mitochondrial diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
