<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mitochondria | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/mitochondria/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/mitochondria/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Mitochondria</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Mitochondria</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/mitochondria/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dopamine inhibits group 2 innate lymphoid cell-driven allergic lung inflammation by dampening mitochondrial activity</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36693372/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36693372/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The amounts of dopamine are negatively correlated with circulating ILC2 numbers in humans&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dopamine suppresses ILC2-driven allergic airway inflammation via DRD1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dopamine constrains ILC2 responses through inhibiting oxidative phosphorylation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Local administration of dopamine may represent a promising therapeutic regimen for asthma&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Neuronal signals have emerged as pivotal regulators of group 2 innate lymphoid cells (ILC2s) that regulate tissue homeostasis and allergic inflammation. The molecular pathways underlying the neuronal regulation of ILC2 responses in lungs remain to be fully elucidated. Here, we found that the abundance of neurotransmitter dopamine was negatively correlated with circulating ILC2 numbers and positively associated with pulmonary function in humans. Dopamine potently suppressed lung ILC2 responses in a DRD1-receptor-dependent manner. Genetic deletion of &lt;em&gt;Drd1&lt;/em&gt; or local ablation of dopaminergic neurons augmented ILC2 responses and allergic lung inflammation. Transcriptome and metabolic analyses revealed that dopamine impaired the mitochondrial oxidative phosphorylation (OXPHOS) pathway in ILC2s. Augmentation of OXPHOS activity with oltipraz antagonized the inhibitory effect of dopamine. Local administration of dopamine alleviated allergen-induced ILC2 responses and airway inflammation. These findings demonstrate that dopamine represents an inhibitory regulator of ILC2 responses in allergic airway inflammation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Formyl peptide receptor 2 activation by mitochondrial formyl peptides stimulates the neutrophil proinflammatory response via the ERK pathway and exacerbates ischemia-reperfusion injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36658472/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36658472/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Ischemia-reperfusion injury (IRI) is an inevitable process in renal transplantation that significantly increases the risk of delayed graft function, acute rejection, and even graft loss. Formyl peptide receptor 2 (FPR2) is an important receptor in multiple septic and aseptic injuries, but its functions in kidney IRI are still unclear. This study was designed to reveal the pathological role of FPR2 in kidney IRI and its functional mechanisms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; To explore the mechanism of FPR2 in kidney IRI, the model rats were sacrificed after IRI surgery. Immunofluorescence, enzyme-linked immunosorbent assays, and western blotting were used to detect differences in the expression of FPR2 and its ligands between the IRI and control groups. WRW4 (WRWWWW-NH2), a specific antagonist of FPR2, was administered to kidney IRI rats. Kidney function and pathological damage were detected to assess kidney injury and recovery. Flow cytometry was used to quantitatively compare neutrophil infiltration among the experimental groups. Mitochondrial formyl peptides (mtFPs) were synthesized and administered to primary rat neutrophils together with the specific FPR family antagonist WRW4 to verify our hypothesis in vitro. Western blotting and cell function assays were used to examine the functions and signaling pathways that FPR2 mediates in neutrophils.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; FPR2 was activated mainly by mtFPs during the acute phase of IRI, mediating neutrophil migration and reactive oxygen species production in the rat kidney through the ERK1/2 pathway. FPR2 blockade in the early phase protected rat kidneys from IRI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; mtFPs activated FPR2 during the acute phase of IRI and mediated rat kidney injury by activating the migration and reactive oxygen species generation of neutrophils through the ERK1/2 pathway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GATA6-AS1 regulates intestinal epithelial mitochondrial functions, and its reduced expression is linked to intestinal inflammation and less favorable disease course in ulcerative colitis (UC)</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36655602/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36655602/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background and aims:&lt;/em&gt; Widespread dysregulation of long non-coding RNAs (lncRNAs) including a reduction in GATA6-AS1 was noted in inflammatory bowel disease (IBD). We previously reported a prominent inhibition of epithelial mitochondrial functions in UC. However, the connection between reduction of GATA6-AS1 expression and attenuated epithelial mitochondrial functions was not yet defined.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; Mucosal transcriptomics was used to conform GATA6-AS1 reduction in several treatment naïve independent human cohorts (n=673). RNA pull-down followed by mass-spectrometry was used to determine GATA6-AS1 interactome. Metabolomics and mitochondrial respiration following GATA6-AS1 silencing in Caco-2, were used to elaborate on GATA6-AS1 functions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; GATA6-AS1 showed predominant expression in gut epithelia using single cell datasets. GATA6-AS1 levels were reduced in Crohn disease (CD) ileum and in ulcerative colitis (UC) rectum in independent cohorts. Reduced GATA6-AS1 lncRNA was further linked to more severe UC form, and to less favorable UC course. GATA6-AS1 interactome showed robust enrichment for mitochondrial proteins, and included TGM2, an autoantigen in celiac disease that is induced in UC, CD, and celiac, in contrast GATA6-AS1 reduction in these cohorts. GATA6-AS1 silencing resulted in induction of TGM2, and this was coupled with reduction in mitochondrial membrane potential and mitochondrial respiration, as well as in reduction of metabolites linked with aerobic respiration relevant to mucosal inflammation. TGM2 knockdown in GATA6-AS1 deficient cells rescued mitochondrial respiration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; GATA6-AS1 levels are reduced in UC, CD, and celiac, and in more severe UC forms. We highlight GATA6-AS1 as a target regulating epithelial mitochondrial functions, potentially through controlling TGM2 levels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>O-linked N-acetylglucosamine affects mitochondrial homeostasis by regulating Parkin-dependent mitophagy in hyperoxia-injured alveolar type II cells injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36647045/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36647045/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; The level of linked N-acetylglucosamine (O-GlcNAc) has been proved to be a sensor of cell state, but its relationship with hyperoxia-induced alveolar type 2 epithelial cells injure and bronchopulmonary dysplasia (BPD) has not been clarified. In this study, we evaluated if these effects ultimately led to functional damage in hyperoxia-induced alveolar cells.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; We treated RLE-6TN cells at 85% hyperoxia for 0, 24 and 48 h with Thiamet G (TG), an OGA inhibitor; OSMI-1 (OS), an OGT inhibitor; or with UDP-GlcNAc, which is involved in synthesis of O-GlcNAc as a donor. The metabolic rerouting, cell viability and apoptosis resulting from the changes in O-GlcNAc glycosyltransferase levels were evaluated in RLE-6TN cells after hyperoxia exposure. We constructed rat Park2 overexpression and knockdown plasmmids for in vitro verification and Co-immunoprecipitation corroborated the binding of Parkin and O-GlcNAc. Finally, we assessed morphological detection in neonatal BPD rats with TG and OS treatment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; We found a decrease in O-GlcNAc content and levels of its metabolic enzymes in RLE-6TN cells under hyperoxia. However, the inhibition of OGT function with OSMI-1 ameliorated hyperoxia-induced lung epithelial cell injury, enhanced cell metabolism and viability, reduced apoptosis, and accelerated the cell proliferation. Mitochondrial homeostasis was affected by O-GlcNAc and regulated Parkin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/em&gt; The results revealed that the decreased O-GlcNAc levels and increased O-GlcNAcylation of Parkin might cause hyperoxia-induced alveolar type II cells injurys.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mitochondrial stress and mitokines in aging</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/36642986/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/36642986/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mitokines are signaling molecules that enable communication of local mitochondrial stress to other mitochondria in distant cells and tissues. Among those molecules are FGF21, GDF15 (both expressed in the nucleus) and several mitochondrial-derived peptides, including humanin. Their responsiveness to mitochondrial stress induces mitokine-signaling in response for example to exercise, following mitochondrial challenges in skeletal muscle. Such signaling is emerging as an important mediator of exercise-derived and dietary strategy-related molecular and systemic health benefits, including healthy aging. A compensatory increase in mitokine synthesis and secretion could preserve mitochondrial function and overall cellular vitality. Conversely, resistance against mitokine actions may also develop. Alterations of mitokine-levels, and therefore of mitokine-related inter-tissue cross talk, are associated with general aging processes and could influence the development of age-related chronic metabolic, cardiovascular and neurological diseases; whether these changes contribute to aging or represent &amp;ldquo;rescue factors&amp;rdquo; remains to be conclusively shown. The aim of the present review is to summarize the expanding knowledge on mitokines, the potential to modulate them by lifestyle and their involvement in aging and age-related diseases. We highlight the importance of well-balanced mitokine-levels, the preventive and therapeutic properties of maintaining mitokine homeostasis and sensitivity of mitokine signaling but also the risks arising from the dysregulation of mitokines. While reduced mitokine levels may impair inter-organ crosstalk, also excessive mitokine concentrations can have deleterious consequences and are associated with conditions such as cancer and heart failure. Preservation of healthy mitokine signaling levels can be achieved by regular exercise and is associated with an increased lifespan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Small molecule agonist of mitochondrial fusion repairs mitochondrial dysfunction</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36635564/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36635564/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Membrane dynamics are important to the integrity and function of mitochondria. Defective mitochondrial fusion underlies the pathogenesis of multiple diseases. The ability to target fusion highlights the potential to fight life-threatening conditions. Here we report a small molecule agonist, S89, that specifically promotes mitochondrial fusion by targeting endogenous MFN1. S89 interacts directly with a loop region in the helix bundle 2 domain of MFN1 to stimulate GTP hydrolysis and vesicle fusion. GTP loading or competition by S89 dislodges the loop from the GTPase domain and unlocks the molecule. S89 restores mitochondrial and cellular defects caused by mitochondrial DNA mutations, oxidative stress inducer paraquat, ferroptosis inducer RSL3 or CMT2A-causing mutations by boosting endogenous MFN1. Strikingly, S89 effectively eliminates ischemia/reperfusion (I/R)-induced mitochondrial damage and protects mouse heart from I/R injury. These results reveal the priming mechanism for MFNs and provide a therapeutic strategy for mitochondrial diseases when additional mitochondrial fusion is beneficial.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LONP1 targets HMGCS2 to protect mitochondrial function and attenuate chronic kidney disease</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36629048/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36629048/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mitochondria comprise the central metabolic hub of cells and their imbalance plays a pathogenic role in chronic kidney disease (CKD). Here, we studied Lon protease 1 (LONP1), a major mitochondrial protease, as its role in CKD pathogenesis is unclear. LONP1 expression was decreased in human patients and mice with CKD, and tubular-specific Lonp1 overexpression mitigated renal injury and mitochondrial dysfunction in two different models of CKD, but these outcomes were aggravated by Lonp1 deletion. These results were confirmed in renal tubular epithelial cells in vitro. Mechanistically, LONP1 downregulation caused mitochondrial accumulation of the LONP1 substrate, 3-hydroxy-3-methylglutaryl-CoA synthase 2 (HMGCS2), which disrupted mitochondrial function and further accelerated CKD progression. Finally, computer-aided virtual screening was performed, which identified a novel LONP1 activator. Pharmacologically, the LONP1 activator attenuated renal fibrosis and mitochondrial dysfunction. Collectively, these results imply that LONP1 is a promising therapeutic target for treating CKD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>microRNA-33 deficiency in macrophages enhances autophagy, improves mitochondrial homeostasis, and protects against lung fibrosis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36626225/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36626225/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis (IPF) is a progressive and ultimately fatal disease. Recent findings have shown a marked metabolic reprogramming associated with changes in mitochondrial homeostasis and autophagy during pulmonary fibrosis. The microRNA-33 (miR-33) family of microRNAs (miRNAs) encoded within the introns of SREBP (sterol regulatory element binding protein) genes are master regulators of sterol and fatty acid (FA) metabolism. miR-33 controls macrophage immuno-metabolic response and enhances mitochondrial biogenesis, FA oxidation, and cholesterol efflux. Here, we show that miR-33 levels are increased in Broncho Alveolar Lavage (BAL) cells isolated from IPF patients compared to healthy controls. We demonstrate that specific genetic ablation of miR-33 in macrophages protects against bleomycin-induced pulmonary fibrosis. The absence of miR-33 in macrophages improves mitochondrial homeostasis and increases autophagy while decreasing inflammatory response after bleomycin injury. Notably, pharmacological inhibition of miR-33 in macrophages via administration of anti-miR-33 Peptide Nucleic Acids (PNA-33) attenuates fibrosis in different &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;ex vivo&lt;/em&gt; mice and human models of pulmonary fibrosis. Together, these studies elucidate a major role of miR-33 in macrophages in the regulation of pulmonary fibrosis and uncover a novel therapeutic approach to treat this disease.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inter-tissue communication of mitochondrial stress and metabolic health</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/lifemeta.load001/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/lifemeta.load001/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mitochondria function as a hub of the cellular metabolic network. Mitochondrial stress is closely associated with aging and a variety of diseases, including neurodegeneration and cancer. Cells autonomously elicit specific stress responses to cope with mitochondrial stress to maintain mitochondrial homeostasis. Interestingly, mitochondrial stress responses may also be induced in a non-autonomous manner in cells or tissues that are not directly experiencing such stress. Such non-autonomous mitochondrial stress responses are mediated by secreted molecules called mitokines. Due to their significant translational potential in improving human metabolic health, there has been a surge in mitokine-focused research. In this review, we summarize the findings regarding inter-tissue communication of mitochondrial stress in animal models. In addition, we discuss the possibility of mitokine-mediated intercellular mitochondrial communication originating from bacterial quorum sensing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TMBIM6 prevents VDAC1 multimerization and improves mitochondrial quality control to reduce sepsis-related myocardial injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36603706/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36603706/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The regulatory mechanisms involved in mitochondrial quality control (MQC) dysfunction during septic cardiomyopathy (SCM) remain incompletely characterized. Transmembrane BAX inhibitor motif containing 6 (TMBIM6) is an endoplasmic reticulum protein with Ca2+ leak activity that modulates cellular responses to various cellular stressors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this study, we evaluated the role of TMBIM6 in SCM using cardiomyocyte-specific TMBIM6 knockout (TMBIM6CKO) and TMBIM6 transgenic (TMBIM6TG) mice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Myocardial TMBIM6 transcription and expression were significantly downregulated in wild-type mice upon LPS exposure, along with characteristic alterations in myocardial systolic/diastolic function, cardiac inflammation, and cardiomyocyte death. Notably, these alterations were further exacerbated in LPS-treated TMBIM6CKO mice, and largely absent in TMBIM6TG mice. In LPS-treated primary cardiomyocytes, TMBIM6 deficiency further impaired mitochondrial respiration and ATP production, while defective MQC was suggested by enhanced mitochondrial fission, impaired mitophagy, and disrupted mitochondrial biogenesis. Structural protein analysis, Co-IP, mutant TMBIM6 plasmid transfection, and molecular docking assays subsequently indicated that TMBIM6 exerts cardioprotection against LPS-induced sepsis by interacting with and preventing the oligomerization of voltage-dependent anion channel-1 (VDAC1), the major route of mitochondrial Ca2+ uptake.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We conclude that the TMBIM6-VDAC1 interaction prevents VDAC1 oligomerization and thus sustains mitochondrial Ca2+ homeostasis as well as MQC, contributing to improved myocardial function in SCM.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lycopene Attenuates Di(2-ethylhexyl) Phthalate-Induced Mitochondrial Damage and Inflammation in Kidney via cGAS-STING Signaling</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36583613/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36583613/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Di(2-ethylhexyl) phthalate (DEHP) is a highly harmful and persistent environmental pollutant. Due to its unique chemical composition, it frequently dissolves and enters the environment to endanger human and animal health. Lycopene is a natural bioactive component that can potentially reduce the risk of environmental factor-induced chronic diseases. The present study sought to explore the role and underlying mechanism of lycopene (LYC) on DEHP-induced renal inflammatory response and apoptosis. In this study, mice were orally treated with LYC (5 mg/kg BW/day) and/or DEHP (500 or 1000 mg/kg BW/day) for 28 days. Our results indicated that LYC prevented DEHP-induced histopathological alterations and ultrastructural injuries, including decreased mitochondrial membrane potential (ΔΨm), PINK1/Parkin pathway-mediated mitophagy, and mitochondrial energetic deficit. When damaged mitochondria release mitochondrial DNA (mtDNA) into cytosol, LYC can alleviate inflammation and apoptosis caused by DEHP exposure by activating the cyclic GMP-AMP synthase-stimulator of interferon gene (cGAS-STING) signal pathway. Collectively, our data demonstrate that LYC can reduce mitophagy caused by DEHP exposure by activating the PINK1/Parkin pathway and then reduce renal inflammation and apoptosis through the cGAS-STING pathway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optogenetic rejuvenation of mitochondrial membrane potential extends C. elegans lifespan</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/s43587-022-00340-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/s43587-022-00340-7/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mitochondrial dysfunction plays a central role in aging but the exact biological causes are still being determined. Here, we show that optogenetically increasing mitochondrial membrane potential during adulthood using a light-activated proton pump improves age-associated phenotypes and extends lifespan in &lt;em&gt;Caenorhabditis elegans&lt;/em&gt;. Our findings provide direct causal evidence that rescuing the age-related decline in mitochondrial membrane potential is sufficient to slow the rate of aging and extend healthspan and lifespan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mitochondrial Genome-Encoded Long Noncoding RNA and Mitochondrial Stability in Diabetic Retinopathy</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36563021/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36563021/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mitochondria experience genomic and functional instability in diabetes, and mitochondrial dysfunction has a critical role in the development of diabetic retinopathy. Diabetes also alters expressions of many long non-coding RNAs (LncRNAs), the RNAs with &amp;gt;200 nucleotides and no open reading frame. LncRNAs are mainly encoded by nuclear genome, but mtDNA also encodes three LncRNAs. Our goal was to investigate the effect of hyperglycemia on mtDNA-encoded LncRNA Cytochrome B (LncCytB) in mtDNA stability in diabetic retinopathy. Retinal endothelial cells, transfected with LncCytB- overexpressing plasmids or siRNA, incubated in 5mmols/L (NG) or 20mmols/L (HG) D-glucose for four days, were analyzed for LncCytB expression by strand-specific PCR, and its mitochondrial localization by RNA-FISH. Damage sensitive mtDNA regions were examined by micrococcal nuclease digestion-sequencing, and LncCytB occupancy at mtDNA by chromatin isolation by RNA purification. Protective nucleoids in mtDNA were analyzed by SYBR green-MitoTracker Red staining, and confirmed in isolated mitochondria by flow cytometry. Compared to NG, HG downregulated LncCytB by &amp;gt;50%, but had no significant effect on the other mtDNAencoded LncRNAs. mtDNA packaging was impaired and MNase sensitivity was increased, and LncCytB occupancy at mtDNA was decreased. While LncCytB overexpression ameliorated mtDNA damage and decrease in nucleoids and copy numbers, LncCytB-siRNA exacerbated damage and further reduced nucleoids. Retinal microvessels from streptozotocin-induced diabetic mice and human donors with diabetic retinopathy presented similar decrease in LncCytB and mtDNA nucleoids. Thus, LncCytB has a major role in maintaining mitochondrial genomic stability, and its downregulation in hyperglycemic milieu contributes to increased vulnerability of mtDNA to damage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mitochondria-localized lncRNA HITT inhibits fusion by attenuating formation of mitofusin-2 homo- or heterotypic complexes</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36567017/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36567017/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Long non-coding RNAs (lncRNAs) are emerging as essential players in multiple biological processes. Mitochondrial dynamics, comprising the continuous cycle of fission and fusion, are required for healthy mitochondria that function properly. Despite long-term recognition of its significance in cell-fate control, the mechanism underlying mitochondrial fusion is not completely understood, particularly regarding the involvement of lncRNAs. Here, we show that the lncRNA HITT (HIF-1α inhibitor at translation level), can specifically localize in mitochondria. Cells expressing higher levels of HITT contain fragmented mitochondria. Conversely, we show that HITT knockdown cells have more tubular mitochondria than is present in control cells. Mechanistically, we demonstrate HITT directly binds mitofusin-2 (MFN2), a core component that mediates mitochondrial outer membrane fusion, by the &lt;em&gt;in vitro&lt;/em&gt; RNA pull-down and UV-cross-linking RNA-IP (CLIP) assays. In doing so, we found HITT disturbs MFN2 homo- or heterotypic complex formation, attenuating mitochondrial fusion. Under stress conditions, such as ultraviolet radiation, we in addition show HITT stability increases as a consequence of MiR-205 downregulation, inhibiting MFN2-mediated fusion and leading to apoptosis. Overall, our data provide significant insights into the roles of organelle (mitochondria)-specific resident lncRNAs in regulating mitochondrial fusion, and also reveal how such a mechanism controls cellular sensitivity to UV radiation-induced apoptosis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dual roles of hexokinase 2 in shaping microglial function by gating glycolytic flux and mitochondrial activity</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36536134/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36536134/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Microglia continuously survey the brain parenchyma and actively shift status following stimulation. These processes demand a unique bioenergetic programme; however, little is known about the metabolic determinants in microglia. By mining large datasets and generating transgenic tools, here we show that hexokinase 2 (HK2), the most active isozyme associated with mitochondrial membrane, is selectively expressed in microglia in the brain. Genetic ablation of HK2 reduced microglial glycolytic flux and energy production, suppressed microglial repopulation, and attenuated microglial surveillance and damage-triggered migration in male mice. HK2 elevation is prominent in immune-challenged or disease-associated microglia. In ischaemic stroke models, however, HK2 deletion promoted neuroinflammation and potentiated cerebral damages. The enhanced inflammatory responses after HK2 ablation in microglia are associated with aberrant mitochondrial function and reactive oxygen species accumulation. Our study demonstrates that HK2 gates both glycolytic flux and mitochondrial activity to shape microglial functions, changes of which contribute to metabolic abnormalities and maladaptive inflammation in brain diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multi-color live-cell STED nanoscopy of mitochondria with a gentle inner membrane stain</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36534799/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36534799/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Capturing mitochondria&amp;rsquo;s intricate and dynamic structure poses a daunting challenge for optical nanoscopy. Different labeling strategies have been demonstrated for live-cell stimulated emission depletion (STED) microscopy of mitochondria, but orthogonal strategies are yet to be established, and image acquisition has suffered either from photodamage to the organelles or from rapid photobleaching. Therefore, live-cell nanoscopy of mitochondria has been largely restricted to two-dimensional (2D) single-color recordings of cancer cells. Here, by conjugation of cyclooctatetraene (COT) to a benzo-fused cyanine dye, we report a mitochondrial inner membrane (IM) fluorescent marker, PK Mito Orange (PKMO), featuring efficient STED at 775 nm, strong photostability, and markedly reduced phototoxicity. PKMO enables super-resolution (SR) recordings of IM dynamics for extended periods in immortalized mammalian cell lines, primary cells, and organoids. Photostability and reduced phototoxicity of PKMO open the door to live-cell three-dimensional (3D) STED nanoscopy of mitochondria for 3D analysis of the convoluted IM. PKMO is optically orthogonal with green and far-red markers, allowing multiplexed recordings of mitochondria using commercial STED microscopes. Using multi-color STED microscopy, we demonstrate that imaging with PKMO can capture interactions of mitochondria with different cellular components such as the endoplasmic reticulum (ER) or the cytoskeleton, Bcl-2-associated X protein (BAX)-induced apoptotic process, or crista phenotypes in genetically modified cells, all at sub-100 nm resolution. Thereby, this work offers a versatile tool for studying mitochondrial IM architecture and dynamics in a multiplexed manner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crosstalk between mitophagy and innate immunity in viral infection</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/36590405/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/36590405/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mitochondria are important organelles involved in cell metabolism and programmed cell death in eukaryotic cells and are closely related to the innate immunity of host cells against viruses. Mitophagy is a process in which phagosomes selectively phagocytize damaged or dysfunctional mitochondria to form autophagosomes and is degraded by lysosomes, which control mitochondrial mass and maintain mitochondrial dynamics and cellular homeostasis. Innate immunity is an important part of the immune system and plays a vital role in eliminating viruses. Viral infection causes many physiological and pathological alterations in host cells, including mitophagy and innate immune pathways. Accumulating evidence suggests that some virus promote self-replication through regulating mitophagy-mediated innate immunity. Clarifying the regulatory relationships among mitochondria, mitophagy, innate immunity, and viral infection will shed new insight for pathogenic mechanisms and antiviral strategies. This review systemically summarizes the activation pathways of mitophagy and the relationship between mitochondria and innate immune signaling pathways, and then discusses the mechanisms of viruses on mitophagy and innate immunity and how viruses promote self-replication by regulating mitophagy-mediated innate immunity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Endosomal lipid signaling reshapes the endoplasmic reticulum to control mitochondrial function</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36520888/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36520888/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;INTRODUCTION&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cells need to react appropriately to nutritional cues. Defects in the rewiring of metabolism in response to alterations in nutrient supply have been linked to human diseases ranging from diabetes to muscle atrophy. Starvation represses anabolic pathways and facilitates catabolic ones, such as the degradation of macromolecules by autophagy and endolysosomes. Starvation also promotes the β-oxidation of fatty acids in mitochondria to produce adenosine triphosphate (ATP). Within cells, organelles including lysosomes and mitochondria undergo changes in shape and dynamics. These processes are often regulated by phosphoinositide lipids. Phosphoinositides are also involved in the formation of membrane contacts between organelles and in the response of cells and tissues to growth and nutrient signals. How the adaptive changes that protect mammalian cells and tissues from starvation-induced damage are coordinated on a cell-wide scale is unknown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;RATIONALE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Endolysosomal membrane dynamics and function are controlled by phosphoinositide signaling lipids, most notably by the synthesis and turnover of phosphatidylinositol 3-phosphate [PI(3)P]. Patients carrying mutations in the gene encoding the lipid phosphatase MTM1, an enzyme that mediates endosomal PI(3)P turnover, suffer from X-linked centronuclear myopathy (XLCNM), a severe neuromuscular disease characterized by muscle atrophy, disorganization of mitochondria, and defects in the organization of the muscle endoplasmic reticulum (ER). Given that PI(3)P is a hallmark of endosomes, we hypothesized that the control of early endosomal PI(3)P by MTM1 might serve to orchestrate adaptive changes in the dynamics of the ER and mitochondria in response to altering nutrient supply.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;RESULTS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Working with XLCNM patient–derived myoblasts and engineered cell lines, we found that nutrient starvation (for example, lack of amino acids) induced the hydrolysis of PI(3)P by endosomal recruitment of MTM1. Concomitantly, tubular ER membranes were observed to be converted into ER sheets by live super-resolution light microscopy. Mechanistically, loss of early endosomal PI(3)P upon starvation was found to reduce membrane contacts between peripheral ER tubules and early endosomes. These contacts function as physical tethers that may transmit pulling forces from highly motile peripheral endosomes to the tubular ER. Using proximity labeling proteomic and functional cell biological experiments we demonstrated that the ER–endosome contacts were mediated by binding of the related ER membrane proteins RRBP1 and kinectin 1 to PI(3)P on endosomes. To study the role of starvation-induced reshaping of tubular ER membranes into sheets on mitochondrial form and function, we combined live imaging with three-dimensional focused ion beam milling scanning electron microscopy (FIB-SEM) and proteomic analysis. We found that starvation-induced ER reshaping by MTM1 reduced the rate of mitochondrial fission and promoted the formation of a hyperfused mitochondrial network. Genetic manipulations that resulted in ER sheet expansion caused the formation of an enlarged mitochondrial network even in fed cells. Conversely, impaired ER reshaping and reduced mitochondrial network formation were observed in starved myoblasts from XLCNM patients. Mitochondrial network formation appeared to be critical for the delivery of fatty acids from lipid droplets to mitochondria and for oxidative ATP production to sustain energy supply in nutrient-deprived cells.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CONCLUSION&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our data unravel a crucial role for early endosomal lipid signaling in controlling ER morphology and, thereby, mitochondrial form and function to orchestrate the adaptive response of cells to alterations in nutrient (e.g., amino acid) supply. This mechanism operates independent of autophagy, a cellular self-eating process typically induced by prolonged starvation. Rather, it resembles an organellar conveyor belt, in which the tubular ER serves as a membrane conduit that transmits nutrient-triggered changes in endosomal PI(3)P levels to metabolic organelles to enable metabolic rewiring. How early endosomal PI(3)P levels and MTM1 function are controlled by cellular nutrient status is currently unknown. Defects in ER shape, mitochondrial morphogenesis, and cellular ATP depletion caused by loss of MTM1 function can explain the observed myofiber hypotrophy and defective ER organization in animal models of XLCNM and in human patients who often appear undernourished. We therefore hypothesize that dysregulated organelle remodeling may underlie XLCNM caused by MTM1 mutations in humans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mitochondrial cristae architecture protects against mtDNA release and inflammation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36476853/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36476853/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A mitochondria-targeted sgRNA library for interrogating mitochondrial function&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mitochondrial regulators of type I interferon (IFN-I) response are identified&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cristae disorganization induces mtDNA release and STING-dependent IFN-I response&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Knockout of cristae regulator Metaxin-2 causes the IFN-I response in vivo&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mitochondrial damage causes mitochondrial DNA (mtDNA) release to activate the type I interferon (IFN-I) response via the cGAS-STING pathway. mtDNA-induced inflammation promotes autoimmune- and aging-related degenerative disorders. However, the global picture of inflammation-inducing mitochondrial damages remains obscure. Here, we have performed a mitochondria-targeted CRISPR knockout screen for regulators of the IFN-I response. Strikingly, our screen reveals dozens of hits enriched with key regulators of cristae architecture, including phospholipid cardiolipin and protein complexes such as OPA1, mitochondrial contact site and cristae organization (MICOS), sorting and assembly machinery (SAM), mitochondrial intermembrane space bridging (MIB), prohibitin (PHB), and the F&lt;sub&gt;1&lt;/sub&gt;F&lt;sub&gt;o&lt;/sub&gt;-ATP synthase. Disrupting these cristae organizers consistently induces mtDNA release and the STING-dependent IFN-I response. Furthermore, knocking out MTX2, a subunit of the SAM complex whose null mutations cause progeria in humans, induces a robust STING-dependent IFN-I response in mouse liver. Taken together, beyond revealing the central role of cristae architecture to prevent mtDNA release and inflammation, our results mechanistically link mitochondrial cristae disorganization and inflammation, two emerging hallmarks of aging and aging-related degenerative diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FUNDC1 protects against doxorubicin-induced cardiomyocyte PANoptosis through stabilizing mtDNA via interaction with TUFM</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36470869/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36470869/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Doxorubicin (DOX) is an effective anthracycline chemotherapeutic anticancer drug with its life-threatening cardiotoxicity severely limiting its clinical application. Mitochondrial damage-induced cardiomyocyte death is considered an essential cue for DOX cardiotoxicity. FUN14 domain containing 1 (FUNDC1) is a mitochondrial membrane protein participating in the regulation of mitochondrial integrity in multiple diseases although its role in DOX cardiomyopathy remains elusive. Here, we examined whether PANoptosis, a novel type of programmed cell death closely associated with mitochondrial damage, was involved in DOX-induced heart injury, and FUNDC1-mediated regulation of cardiomyocyte PANoptosis, if any. FUNDC1 was downregulated in heart tissues in patients with dilated cardiomyopathy (DCM) and DOX-challenged mice. FUNDC1 deficiency aggravated DOX-induced cardiac dysfunction, mitochondrial injury, and cardiomyocyte PANoptosis. Further examination revealed that FUNDC1 countered cytoplasmic release of mitochondrial DNA (mtDNA) and activation of PANoptosome through interaction with mitochondrial Tu translation elongation factor (TUFM), a key factor in the translational expression and repair of mitochondrial DNA, via its 96-133 amino acid domain. TUFM intervention reversed FUNDC1-elicited protection against DOX-induced mtDNA cytosolic release and cardiomyocyte PANoptosis. Our findings shed light toward a beneficial role of FUNDC1 in DOX cardiotoxicity and cardiomyocyte PANoptosis, thus offering therapeutic promises in DOX-induced cardiotoxicity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nuclear localization of mitochondrial TCA cycle enzymes modulates pluripotency via histone acetylation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36460681/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36460681/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pluripotent stem cells hold great promise in regenerative medicine and developmental biology studies. Mitochondrial metabolites, including tricarboxylic acid (TCA) cycle intermediates, have been reported to play critical roles in pluripotency. Here we show that TCA cycle enzymes including Pdha1, Pcb, Aco2, Cs, Idh3a, Ogdh, Sdha and Mdh2 are translocated to the nucleus during somatic cell reprogramming, primed-to-naive transition and totipotency acquisition. The nuclear-localized TCA cycle enzymes Pdha1, Pcb, Aco2, Cs, Idh3a promote somatic cell reprogramming and primed-to-naive transition. In addition, nuclear-localized TCA cycle enzymes, particularly nuclear-targeted Pdha1, facilitate the 2-cell program in pluripotent stem cells. Mechanistically, nuclear Pdha1 increases the acetyl-CoA and metabolite pool in the nucleus, leading to chromatin remodeling at pluripotency genes by enhancing histone H3 acetylation. Our results reveal an important role of mitochondrial TCA cycle enzymes in the epigenetic regulation of pluripotency that constitutes a mitochondria-to-nucleus retrograde signaling mode in different states of pluripotent acquisition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amorphous silica nanoparticles caused lung injury through the induction of epithelial apoptosis via ROS/Ca2&#43;/DRP1-mediated mitochondrial fission signaling</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36441139/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36441139/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The adverse effects of amorphous silica nanoparticles (SiNPs) exposure on the respiratory system were increasingly recognized, however, its potential pathogenesis still remains not fully elucidated. So, this study aimed to explore its effects on pulmonary injury, and to investigate related mechanisms. Histological investigations illustrated SiNPs triggered the lung injury, mainly manifested as alveolar structure destruction, collagen deposition, and mitochondrial ultrastructural injury. In particular, SiNPs greatly enhanced pulmonary ROS and TUNEL positive rate in lungs, both of which were positively correlated with lung impairments. Further, the underlying mechanisms were investigated in cultured human bronchial epithelial cells (16HBE). Consistent with the &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt; findings, SiNPs caused the impairments on mitochondrial structure, as well as the activation of ROS generation and oxidative injury. Upon SiNPs stimuli, mitochondrial respiration was greatly inhibited, while Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt; overload in cytosol and mitochondria owing to ER calcium release was noticed, resulting in mitochondrial-dependent epithelial apoptosis. More importantly, mitochondrial dynamics was imbalanced toward a fission type, as evidenced by upregulated DRP1 and its phosphorylation at Ser616 (DRP1&lt;sup&gt;s616&lt;/sup&gt;), while downregulated DRP1&lt;sup&gt;s637&lt;/sup&gt;, and also MFN1, MFN2. Mechanistic investigations revealed that the activation of ROS/Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt; signaling promoted DRP1-mediated mitochondrial fission by SiNPs, forming a vicious cycle, and ultimately contributing to apoptosis in 16HBE. In summary, our results disclosed SiNPs caused pulmonary injury through the induction of epithelial apoptosis via a ROS/Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt;/DRP1-mediated mitochondrial fission axis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mitochondrial citrate accumulation drives alveolar epithelial cell necroptosis in lipopolysaccharide-induced acute lung injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36443565/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36443565/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Necroptosis is the major cause of death in alveolar epithelial cells (AECs) during acute lung injury (ALI). Here, we report a previously unrecognized mechanism for necroptosis. We found an accumulation of mitochondrial citrate (citratemt) in lipopolysaccharide (LPS)-treated AECs because of the downregulation of Idh3α and citrate carrier (CIC, also known as Slc25a1). shRNA- or inhibitor-mediated inhibition of Idh3α and Slc25a1 induced citratemt accumulation and necroptosis in vitro. Mice with AEC-specific Idh3α and Slc25a1 deficiency exhibited exacerbated lung injury and AEC necroptosis. Interestingly, the overexpression of Idh3α and Slc25a1 decreased citratemt levels and rescued AECs from necroptosis. Mechanistically, citratemt accumulation induced mitochondrial fission and excessive mitophagy in AECs. Furthermore, citratemt directly interacted with FUN14 domain-containing protein 1 (FUNDC1) and promoted the interaction of FUNDC1 with dynamin-related protein 1 (DRP1), leading to excessive mitophagy-mediated necroptosis and thereby initiating and promoting ALI. Importantly, necroptosis induced by citratemt accumulation was inhibited in FUNDC1-knockout AECs. We show that citratemt accumulation is a novel target for protection against ALI involving necroptosis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sirt3 mitigates LPS-induced mitochondrial damage in renal tubular epithelial cells by deacetylating YME1L1</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36433732/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36433732/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acute kidney injury (AKI) is often secondary to sepsis. Increasing evidence suggests that mitochondrial dysfunction contributes to the pathological process of AKI. In this study, we aimed to examine the regulatory roles of Sirt3 in Lipopolysaccharide (LPS)-induced mitochondrial damage in renal tubular epithelial cells (TECs). Sirt3 knockout mice were intraperitoneally injected with LPS, and cultured TECs were stimulated with LPS to evaluate the effects of Sirt3 on mitochondrial structure and function in TECs. Electron microscopy was used to assess mitochondrial morphology. Immunofluorescence staining was performed to detect protein expression and examine mitochondrial morphology. Western blotting was used to quantify protein expression. We observed that LPS increased apoptosis, induced disturbances in mitochondrial function and dynamics, and downregulated Sirt3 expression in a sepsis-induced AKI mouse model and human proximal tubular (HK-2) cells in vitro. Sirt3 deficiency further exacerbated LPS-induced renal pathological damage, apoptosis and disturbances in mitochondrial function and dynamics. On the contrary, Sirt3 overexpression in HK-2 cells alleviated these lesions. Functional studies revealed that Sirt3 overexpression alleviated LPS-induced mitochondrial damage and apoptosis in TECs by promoting OPA1-mediated mitochondrial fusion through the deacetylation of i-AAA protease (YME1L1), an upstream regulatory molecule of OPA1. Our study has identified Sirt3 as a vital factor that protects against LPS-induced mitochondrial damage and apoptosis in TECs via the YME1L1-OPA1 signaling pathway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Xuanfei Baidu formula alleviates impaired mitochondrial dynamics and activated NLRP3 inflammasome by repressing NF-κB and MAPK pathways in LPS-induced ALI and inflammation models</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36423572/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36423572/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Xuanfei Baidu Formula (XBF) is an effective traditional Chinese medicine (TCM) remedy for treating coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) in China. This herbal medicine has shown effects in reducing clinical symptoms and shortening the average length of hospital stay for COVID-19 patients. Previous studies have demonstrated that XBF alleviates acute lung injury (ALI) by regulating macrophage-mediated immune inflammation, but the mechanisms of action remain elusive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Purpose&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This study aimed to evaluate the lung-protective and anti-inflammatory effects of XBF and its underlying mechanisms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here, XBF&amp;rsquo;s effects were investigated in an ALI mouse model induced by inhalation of atomized lipopolysaccharide (LPS). Besides, the LPS-induced inflammation model in RAW264.7 cells was used to clarify the underlying mechanisms of XBF against ALI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our results showed that XBF treatment alleviated LPS-induced lung injury, as evidenced by reduced histopathological changes, pulmonary alveoli permeability, fibrosis, and apoptosis in the lung tissues. In addition, inflammation was alleviated as shown by decreased levels of tumor necrosis factor (TNF)-α, interleukin (IL)-6, IL-1β in serum and bronchoalveolar lavage fluid (BALF), and reduced white blood cell (WBC) count in BALF. Furthermore, consistent with the in vivo assay, XBF inhibited LPS-induced inflammatory cytokines release and pro-inflammatory polarization in RAW264.7 cells. Mechanistically, XBF increased mitochondrial fusion by upregulating Mfn1 and attenuated NLRP3 inflammasome activation by repressing Casp11, respectively, to inhibit NF-κB and MAPK pathways, thus repressing pro-inflammatory macrophage polarization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this study, we demonstrate that XBF exerts anti-ALI and -inflammatory effects by recovering mitochondrial dynamics and reducing inflammasome activation, providing a biological illustration of the clinical efficacy of XBF in treating COVID-19 patients.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CLIC4 localizes to mitochondrial-associated membranes and mediates cardioprotection</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36269835/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36269835/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mitochondrial-associated membranes (MAMs) are known to modulate organellar and cellular functions and can subsequently affect pathophysiology including myocardial ischemia-reperfusion (IR) injury. Thus, identifying molecular targets in MAMs that regulate the outcome of IR injury will hold a key to efficient therapeutics. Here, we found chloride intracellular channel protein (CLIC4) presence in MAMs of cardiomyocytes and demonstrate its role in modulating ER and mitochondrial calcium homeostasis under physiological and pathological conditions. In a murine model, loss of CLIC4 increased myocardial infarction and substantially reduced cardiac function after IR injury. CLIC4 null cardiomyocytes showed increased apoptosis and mitochondrial dysfunction upon hypoxia-reoxygenation injury in comparison to wild-type cardiomyocytes. Overall, our results indicate that MAM-CLIC4 is a key mediator of cellular response to IR injury and therefore may have a potential implication on other pathophysiological processes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gallic, ellagic acids and their oral combined administration induce kidney, lung, and heart injury after acute exposure in Wistar rats</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36272503/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36272503/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gallic (GA) and ellagic (EA) acids are present in foods, medicinal plants, teas, and dietary supplements. An acute toxicological study was conducted by oral administration of both compounds alone (200, 1000, and 2000 mg/kg) and combined (2000 mg/kg) and their effects on the electron transport chain (ETC) and the ROS production in kidney mitochondria further evaluated. All treatments induced a dose-dependent heart, lung, and kidney injury. However, the intensity of these effects varied according to the substance, with greater cardiac and renal toxicity for EA and pulmonary injury for GA, while the combination attenuated the toxicity of the isolated molecules. All substances inhibited the activity of complexes II, III, and IV of the ETC from renal mitochondria. However, no changes were observed regarding mitochondrial ROS production. These compounds have a non-negligible inherent deleterious potential, so their uncontrolled use at high doses (≥200 mg/kg) could cause undesirable effects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oxaloacetate acid ameliorates paraquat-induced acute lung injury by alleviating oxidative stress and mitochondrial dysfunction</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36313362/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36313362/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acute lung injury (ALI) is the primary cause of death among patients with acute paraquat (PQ) poisoning, whereby peroxidative damage is an important mechanism underlying PQ-induced lung injury. There is a lack of effective interventional drugs for patients with PQ poisoning. Oxaloacetic acid (OAA) participates in multiple &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt; metabolic processes, whereby it facilitates the clearance of reactive oxygen species (ROS) and improves mitochondrial function. The study aimed to assess the protective effects of OAA on PQ-induced ALI and elucidate the underlying molecular mechanism. Our data demonstrated that OAA treatment significantly alleviated PQ-induced ALI and improved the survival rate of PQ-poisoned mice, and also alleviated PQ-induced cellular oxidative stress and mitochondrial dysfunction. OAA-mediated alleviation of PQ-induced mitochondrial dysfunction depends on the following mechanisms which may explain the above findings: 1) OAA effectively cleared intracellular ROS, inhibited ROS accumulation, and mitochondrial depolarization; 2) OAA inhibited the downregulation of L-OPA1 and MFN2 caused by PQ and promoted a dynamic balance of mitochondrial fusion and fission, and 3) the expression of PGC-1α, TFAM, COX2, and COX4I1, increased significantly following OAA intervention which improved mitochondrial respiratory functions and promoted its biogenesis and energy metabolism in damaged cells. In conclusion, OAA effectively cleared ROS and improved mitochondrial dysfunction, thereby significantly improving ALI caused by PQ poisoning and the animal survival rate. Therefore, OAA may be a potential drug for the treatment of PQ poisoning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A-Kinase Anchor Protein 1 deficiency causes mitochondrial dysfunction in mouse model of hyperoxia induced acute lung injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36263130/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36263130/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Critically ill patients on supplemental oxygen therapy eventually develop acute lung injury (ALI). Reactive oxygen species (ROS) produced during ALI perturbs the mitochondrial dynamics resulting in cellular damage. Genetic deletion of the mitochondrial A-kinase anchoring protein 1 (Akap1) in mice resulted in mitochondrial damage, Endoplasmic reticulum (ER) stress, increased expression of mitophagy proteins and pro-inflammatory cytokines, exacerbating hyperoxia-induced Acute Lung Injury (HALI).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Objective:&lt;/em&gt; Despite a strong causal link between mitochondrial dysfunction and HALI, the mechanisms governing the disease progression at the transcriptome level is unknown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; In this study, RNA sequencing (RNA-seq) analysis was carried out using the lungs of Akap1 knockout (&lt;em&gt;Akap1&lt;sup&gt;−/−&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt;) mice exposed to normoxia or 48 h of hyperoxia followed by quantitative real time PCR and Ingenuity pathway analysis (IPA). Western blot analysis assessed mitochondrial dysfunction, OXPHOS complex (I-V), apoptosis and antioxidant proteins. Mitochondrial enzymatic assays was used to measure the aconitase, fumarase, citrate synthase activities in isolated mitochondria from &lt;em&gt;Akap1&lt;sup&gt;−/−&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; vs. Wt mice exposed to hyperoxia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; Transcriptome analysis of &lt;em&gt;Akap1&lt;sup&gt;−/−&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; exposed to hyperoxia reveals increases in transcripts encoding electron transport chain (ETC) and tricarboxylic acid cycle (TCA) proteins. Ingenuity pathway analysis (IPA) shows enrichment of mitochondrial dysfunction and oxidative phosphorylation in &lt;em&gt;Akap1&lt;sup&gt;−/−&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; mice. Loss of AKAP1, coupled with oxidant injury, significantly decreases the activities of TCA enzymes. Mechanistically, a significant loss of dynamin-related protein 1 (Drp1) phosphorylation at the protein kinase A (PKA) site Serine 637 (Ser637), decreases in Akt phosphorylation at Serine 437 (Ser47) and increase in the expression of pro-apoptotic protein Bax indicate mitochondrial dysfunction. Heme oxygenase-1 (HO-1) levels significantly increased in CD68 positive alveolar macrophages in &lt;em&gt;Akap1&lt;sup&gt;−/−&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; lungs, suggesting a strong antioxidant response to hyperoxia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/em&gt; Overall these results suggest that AKAP1 overexpression and modulation of Drp1 phosphorylation at Ser637 is an important therapeutic strategy for acute lung injury.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CGG repeat expansion in NOTCH2NLC causes mitochondrial dysfunction and progressive neurodegeneration in Drosophila model</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36191230/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36191230/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Significance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CGG repeat expansion in the 5′ untranslated region of the &lt;em&gt;NOTCH2NLC&lt;/em&gt; gene was reported to be associated with a neuromuscular/neurodegenerative disease, neuronal intranuclear inclusion disease (NIID). Here, we developed a fly model of CGG repeat expansion in &lt;em&gt;NOTCH2NLC&lt;/em&gt;, recapitulated key pathological and clinical features of NIID, and characterized the mitochondrial dysfunction in these model organisms, human samples, and cellular models. Moreover, idebenone treatment restored mitochondrial function and alleviated neurodegenerative phenotypes in transgenic flies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Neuronal intranuclear inclusion disease (NIID) is a neuromuscular/neurodegenerative disease caused by the expansion of CGG repeats in the 5&amp;rsquo; untranslated region (UTR) of the &lt;em&gt;NOTCH2NLC&lt;/em&gt; gene. These repeats can be translated into a polyglycine-containing protein, uN2CpolyG, which forms protein inclusions and is toxic in cell models, albeit through an unknown mechanism. Here, we established a transgenic Drosophila model expressing uN2CpolyG in multiple systems, which resulted in progressive neuronal cell loss, locomotor deficiency, and shortened lifespan. Interestingly, electron microscopy revealed mitochondrial swelling both in transgenic flies and in muscle biopsies of individuals with NIID. Immunofluorescence and immunoelectron microscopy showed colocalization of uN2CpolyG with mitochondria in cell and patient samples, while biochemical analysis revealed that uN2CpolyG interacted with a mitochondrial RNA binding protein, LRPPRC (leucine-rich pentatricopeptide repeat motif-containing protein). Furthermore, RNA sequencing (RNA-seq) analysis and functional assays showed down-regulated mitochondrial oxidative phosphorylation in uN2CpolyG-expressing flies and NIID muscle biopsies. Finally, idebenone treatment restored mitochondrial function and alleviated neurodegenerative phenotypes in transgenic flies. Overall, these results indicate that transgenic flies expressing uN2CpolyG recapitulate key features of NIID and that reversing mitochondrial dysfunction might provide a potential therapeutic approach for this disorder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The mitochondrial calcium uniporter of pulmonary type 2 cells determines severity of acute lung injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36192486/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36192486/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acute Lung Injury (ALI) due to inhaled pathogens causes high mortality. Underlying mechanisms are inadequately understood. Here, by optical imaging of live mouse lungs we show that a key mechanism is the viability of cytosolic Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt; buffering by the mitochondrial Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt; uniporter (MCU) in the lung&amp;rsquo;s surfactant-secreting, alveolar type 2 cells (AT2). The buffering increased mitochondrial Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt; and induced surfactant secretion in wild-type mice, but not in mice with AT2-specific MCU knockout. In the knockout mice, ALI due to intranasal LPS instillation caused severe pulmonary edema and mortality, which were mitigated by surfactant replenishment prior to LPS instillation, indicating surfactant&amp;rsquo;s protective effect against alveolar edema. In wild-type mice, intranasal LPS, or &lt;em&gt;Pseudomonas aeruginosa&lt;/em&gt; decreased AT2 MCU. Loss of MCU abrogated buffering. The resulting mortality was reduced by spontaneous recovery of MCU expression, or by MCU replenishment. Enhancement of AT2 mitochondrial buffering, hence endogenous surfactant secretion, through MCU replenishment might be a therapy against ALI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TraB family proteins are components of ER-mitochondrial contact sites and regulate ER-mitochondrial interactions and mitophagy</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36163196/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36163196/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ER-mitochondrial contact sites (EMCSs) are important for mitochondrial function. Here, we have identified a EMCS complex, comprising a family of uncharacterised mitochondrial outer membrane proteins, TRB1, TRB2, and the ER protein, VAP27-1. In Arabidopsis, there are three TraB family isoforms and the trb1/trb2 double mutant exhibits abnormal mitochondrial morphology, strong starch accumulation, and impaired energy metabolism, indicating that these proteins are essential for normal mitochondrial function. Moreover, TRB1 and TRB2 proteins also interact with ATG8 in order to regulate mitochondrial degradation (mitophagy). The turnover of depolarised mitochondria is significantly reduced in both trb1/trb2 and VAP27 mutants (vap27-1,3,4,6) under mitochondrial stress conditions, with an increased population of dysfunctional mitochondria present in the cytoplasm. Consequently, plant recovery after stress is significantly perturbed, suggesting that TRB1-regulated mitophagy and ER-mitochondrial interaction are two closely related processes. Taken together, we ascribe a dual role to TraB family proteins which are component of the EMCS complex in eukaryotes, regulating both interaction of the mitochondria to the ER and mitophagy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Molecular Mechanisms of Ferroptosis and Relevance to Cardiovascular Disease</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/36078133/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/36078133/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ferroptosis has recently been demonstrated to be a novel regulated non-apoptotic cell death characterized by iron-dependence and the accumulation of lipid peroxidation that results in membrane damage. Excessive iron induces ferroptosis by promoting the generation of both soluble and lipid ROS via an iron-dependent Fenton reaction and lipoxygenase (LOX) enzyme activity. Cytosolic glutathione peroxidase 4 (cGPX4) pairing with ferroptosis suppressor protein 1 (FSP1) and mitochondrial glutathione peroxidase 4 (mGPX4) pairing with dihydroorotate dehydrogenase (DHODH) serve as two separate defense systems to detoxify lipid peroxidation in the cytoplasmic as well as the mitochondrial membrane, thereby defending against ferroptosis in cells under normal conditions. However, disruption of these defense systems may cause ferroptosis. Emerging evidence has revealed that ferroptosis plays an essential role in the development of diverse cardiovascular diseases (CVDs), such as hemochromatosis-associated cardiomyopathy, doxorubicin-induced cardiotoxicity, ischemia/reperfusion (I/R) injury, heart failure (HF), atherosclerosis, and COVID-19-related arrhythmias. Iron chelators, antioxidants, ferroptosis inhibitors, and genetic manipulations may alleviate the aforementioned CVDs by blocking ferroptosis pathways. In conclusion, ferroptosis plays a critical role in the pathogenesis of various CVDs and suppression of cardiac ferroptosis is expected to become a potential therapeutic option. Here, we provide a comprehensive review on the molecular mechanisms involved in ferroptosis and its implications in cardiovascular disease.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blocking CHOP-dependent TXNIP shuttling to mitochondria attenuates albuminuria and mitigates kidney injury in nephrotic syndrome</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35994650/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35994650/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Significance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Albuminuria is the hallmark of nephrotic syndrome (NS), a leading cause of chronic kidney disease affecting 500 million people worldwide. Thus, there is a clear need to discover novel drug targets to treat proteinuric kidney disease. We demonstrate that thioredoxin-interacting protein (TXNIP), a redox protein that forms the complex with antioxidant oxidoreductase thioredoxin (Trx), relocates from nucleus to mitochondria when C/EBP homologous protein (CHOP), a major endoplasmic reticulum (ER) stress-associated transcription factor, is induced by albuminuria. TXNIP shuttling to mitochondria is essential for mitochondrial reactive oxygen species (ROS) production, which oxidizes mitochondrial-specific Trx2 and disrupts the association between Trx2-TXNIP and Trx2-ASK1 in mitochondria, leading to NLRP3 inflammasome activation and mitochondria-dependent apoptosis. Thus, TXNIP is a potential target to treat NS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Albuminuria is a hallmark of glomerular disease of various etiologies. It is not only a symptom of glomerular disease but also a cause leading to glomerulosclerosis, interstitial fibrosis, and eventually, a decline in kidney function. The molecular mechanism underlying albuminuria-induced kidney injury remains poorly defined. In our genetic model of nephrotic syndrome (NS), we have identified CHOP (C/EBP homologous protein)-TXNIP (thioredoxin-interacting protein) as critical molecular linkers between albuminuria-induced ER dysfunction and mitochondria dyshomeostasis. TXNIP is a ubiquitously expressed redox protein that binds to and inhibits antioxidant enzyme, cytosolic thioredoxin 1 (Trx1), and mitochondrial Trx2. However, very little is known about the regulation and function of TXNIP in NS. By utilizing &lt;em&gt;Chop&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Txnip&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; mice as well as &lt;sup&gt;68&lt;/sup&gt;Ga-Galuminox, our molecular imaging probe for detection of mitochondrial reactive oxygen species (ROS) in vivo, we demonstrate that CHOP up-regulation induced by albuminuria drives TXNIP shuttling from nucleus to mitochondria, where it is required for the induction of mitochondrial ROS. The increased ROS accumulation in mitochondria oxidizes Trx2, thus liberating TXNIP to associate with mitochondrial nod-like receptor protein 3 (NLRP3) to activate inflammasome, as well as releasing mitochondrial apoptosis signal-regulating kinase 1 (ASK1) to induce mitochondria-dependent apoptosis. Importantly, inhibition of TXNIP translocation and mitochondrial ROS overproduction by CHOP deletion suppresses NLRP3 inflammasome activation and p-ASK1-dependent mitochondria apoptosis in NS. Thus, targeting TXNIP represents a promising therapeutic strategy for the treatment of NS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Targeting Myocardial Mitochondria-STING-Polyamine Axis Prevents Cardiac Hypertrophy in Chronic Kidney Disease</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36061341/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36061341/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HIGHLIGHTS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mitochondrial damage is early and prominent in cardiomyocytes under CKD milieu.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mitochondrial damage stimulates myocardial STING-NFκB pathway to drive hypertrophy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;NFκB transactivates ODC1-PUT metabolic flux in cardiomyocytes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ODC1-PUT metabolic flux is required for STING/NFκB-driven cardiac hypertrophy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Targeting mitochondria-STING-ODC1 axis prevents cardiac hypertrophy in CKD.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chronic kidney disease (CKD) is well recognized as a distinct contributor to cardiac hypertrophy, while the underlying mechanism remains incompletely understood. Here, the authors show that myocardial mitochondrial oxidative damage is early and prominent in CKD and distinctively stimulates the STING-NFκB pathway by releasing mitochondrial DNA to drive cardiac hypertrophy. Furthermore, the authors reveal that ornithine decarboxylase (ODC1)-putrescine metabolic flux is transactivated by NFκB and is required for the STING-NFκB pathway to drive cardiac hypertrophy. Finally, genetic or pharmacologic inhibition of the myocardial mitochondria-STING-NFκB-ODC1 axis significantly prevents CKD-associated cardiac hypertrophy. Therefore, targeting the myocardial mitochoandria-STING-NFκB-ODC1 axis is a promising therapeutic strategy for cardiac hypertrophy in patients with CKD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UBXD8 mediates mitochondria-associated degradation to restrain apoptosis and mitophagy</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35979733/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35979733/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The hexameric AAA-ATPase valosin-containing protein (VCP) is essential for mitochondrial protein quality control. How VCP is recruited to mammalian mitochondria remains obscure. Here we report that UBXD8, an ER- and lipid droplet-localized VCP adaptor, also localizes to mitochondria and locally recruits VCP. UBXD8 associates with mitochondrial and ER ubiquitin E3 ligases and targets their substrates for degradation. Remarkably, both mitochondria- and ER-localized UBXD8 can degrade mitochondrial and ER substrates in cis and in trans. UBXD8 also associates with the TOM complex but is dispensable for translocation-associated degradation. UBXD8 knockout impairs the degradation of the pro-survival protein Mcl1 but surprisingly sensitizes cells to apoptosis and mitochondrial stresses. UBXD8 knockout also hyperactivates mitophagy. We identify pro-apoptotic BH3-only proteins Noxa, Bik, and Bnip3 as novel UBXD8 substrates and determine that UBXD8 inhibits apoptosis via degrading Noxa and restrains mitophagy via degrading Bnip3. Collectively, our characterizations reveal UBXD8 as the major mitochondrial adaptor of VCP and unveil its role in apoptosis and mitophagy regulation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SHMT2-mediated mitochondrial serine metabolism drives 5-FU resistance by fueling nucleotide biosynthesis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35977477/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35977477/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Serine metabolism is a key driver of 5-FU acquired resistance in CRC&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Affecting serine availability impairs DNA damage response in 5-FU-resistant cells&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mitochondrial compartmentalization of serine metabolism sustains 5-FU resistance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Targeting mitochondrial serine metabolism is effective in overcoming 5-FU resistance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;5-Fluorouracil (5-FU) is a key component of chemotherapy for colorectal cancer (CRC). 5-FU efficacy is established by intracellular levels of folate cofactors and DNA damage repair strategies. However, drug resistance still represents a major challenge. Here, we report that alterations in serine metabolism affect 5-FU sensitivity in in vitro and in vivo CRC models. In particular, 5-FU-resistant CRC cells display a strong serine dependency achieved either by upregulating endogenous serine synthesis or increasing exogenous serine uptake. Importantly, regardless of the serine feeder strategy, serine hydroxymethyltransferase-2 (SHMT2)-driven compartmentalization of one-carbon metabolism inside the mitochondria represents a specific adaptation of resistant cells to support purine biosynthesis and potentiate DNA damage response. Interfering with serine availability or affecting its mitochondrial metabolism revert 5-FU resistance. These data disclose a relevant mechanism of mitochondrial serine use supporting 5-FU resistance in CRC and provide perspectives for therapeutic approaches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>lncRNA CYTOR promotes aberrant glycolysis and mitochondrial respiration via HNRNPC-mediated ZEB1 stabilization in oral squamous cell carcinoma</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35963855/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35963855/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oral squamous cell carcinoma (OSCC), the most common malignancy of the oral and maxillofacial region, severely affects human health. However, current treatments for OSCC commonly show only a ~60% 5-year survival rate of patients with distant metastases, indicating an urgent need for targeted treatments for patients with advanced metastases. Here, we report a survival-related long non-coding RNA, CYTOR, which is highly expressed in the lesions of oral cancer patients. We found that CYTOR can promote both migration and invasion in oral cancer cells as well as the epithelial-mesenchymal transition (EMT). RNA-sequencing of CYTOR-knockdown oral cancer cells revealed that CYTOR can regulate mitochondrial respiration and RNA splicing. Mechanistically, we found that nuclear-localized CYTOR interacts with HNRNPC, resulting in stabilization of ZEB1 mRNAs by inhibiting the nondegradative ubiquitination of HNRNPC. By synthesizing CYTOR-targeting small interfering RNAs (siRNAs) encapsulated in Nanoscale Metal Organic Frameworks (NMOFs), we demonstrate the targeted suppression of CYTOR to inhibit invasion and metastasis of oral cancer cells in a nude mouse model. Cumulatively, this study reveals the potential role of the CYTOR-HNRNPC-ZEB1 axis in regulating mitochondrial metabolism and glycolysis of oral cancer cells, and illustrates the effective use of lncRNA targeting in anti-metastatic cancer therapies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ischemia-Selective Cardioprotection by Malonate for Ischemia/Reperfusion Injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35959683/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35959683/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Inhibiting SDH (succinate dehydrogenase), with the competitive inhibitor malonate, has shown promise in ameliorating ischemia/reperfusion injury. However, key for translation to the clinic is understanding the mechanism of malonate entry into cells to enable inhibition of SDH, its mitochondrial target, as malonate itself poorly permeates cellular membranes. The possibility of malonate selectively entering the at-risk heart tissue on reperfusion, however, remains unexplored.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; C57BL/6J mice, C2C12 and H9c2 myoblasts, and HeLa cells were used to elucidate the mechanism of selective malonate uptake into the ischemic heart upon reperfusion. Cells were treated with malonate while varying pH or together with transport inhibitors. Mouse hearts were either perfused ex vivo (Langendorff) or subjected to in vivo left anterior descending coronary artery ligation as models of ischemia/reperfusion injury. Succinate and malonate levels were assessed by liquid chromatography-tandem mass spectrometry LC-MS/MS, in vivo by mass spectrometry imaging, and infarct size by TTC (2,3,5-triphenyl-2H-tetrazolium chloride) staining.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; Malonate was robustly protective against cardiac ischemia/reperfusion injury, but only if administered at reperfusion and not when infused before ischemia. The extent of malonate uptake into the heart was proportional to the duration of ischemia. Malonate entry into cardiomyocytes in vivo and in vitro was dramatically increased at the low pH (≈6.5) associated with ischemia. This increased uptake of malonate was blocked by selective inhibition of MCT1 (monocarboxylate transporter 1). Reperfusion of the ischemic heart region with malonate led to selective SDH inhibition in the at-risk region. Acid-formulation greatly enhances the cardioprotective potency of malonate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; Cardioprotection by malonate is dependent on its entry into cardiomyocytes. This is facilitated by the local decrease in pH that occurs during ischemia, leading to its selective uptake upon reperfusion into the at-risk tissue, via MCT1. Thus, malonate&amp;rsquo;s preferential uptake in reperfused tissue means it is an at-risk tissue-selective drug that protects against cardiac ischemia/reperfusion injury.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mitochondrial quality control in cardiac ischemia/reperfusion injury: new insights into mechanisms and implications</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/35951200/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/35951200/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The current effective method for the treatment of myocardial infarction is timely restoration of the blood supply to the ischemic area of the heart. Although reperfusion is essential for reestablishing oxygen and nutrient supplies, it often leads to additional myocardial damage, creating an important clinical dilemma. Reports from long-term studies have confirmed that mitochondrial damage is the critical mechanism in cardiac ischemia/reperfusion (I/R) injury. Mitochondria are dynamic and possess a quality control system that targets mitochondrial quantity and quality by modifying mitochondrial fusion, fission, mitophagy, and biogenesis and protein homeostasis to maintain a healthy mitochondrial network. The system of mitochondrial quality control involves complex molecular machinery that is highly interconnected and associated with pathological changes such as oxidative stress, calcium overload, and endoplasmic reticulum (ER) stress. Because of the critical role of the mitochondrial quality control systems, many reports have suggested that defects in this system are among the molecular mechanisms underlying myocardial reperfusion injury. In this review, we briefly summarize the important role of the mitochondrial quality control in cardiomyocyte function and focus on the current understanding of the regulatory mechanisms and molecular pathways involved in mitochondrial quality control in cardiac I/R damage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Structural integrity is essential for the protective effect of mitochondrial transplantation against UV-induced cell death</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35905626/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35905626/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mitochondrial transplantation exhibits protective effect on UV-induced cell death.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The mitochondrial components, such as ATP and mtDNA, are not the key factors of mitochondrial transplantation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mitochondria structural integrity is crucial in the radiation resistance of mitochondrial transplantation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mitochondrial transplantation (MT) is a new technology developed in recent years, which injects healthy mitochondria directly into damaged tissues or blood vessels to play a therapeutic role. This technology has been studied in many animal models of various diseases including myocardial ischemia, cerebral stroke, liver and lung injury, and even has been successfully used in the treatment of childhood heart disease. MT can quickly improve tissue function within a few minutes after injection. The speed with which MT improves tissue function is frequently questioned, for it is hard to understand how the whole mitochondrion transports to the damaged sites, enters cells and functions within such a short period of time. Are there small molecules of mitochondrial component responsible for the function of MT? To test this hypothesis, we established an ultra-violet (UV)-irradiated HeLa cell model. The results of colony formation, sulforhodamine B (SRB), and Hoechst 33342/PI double staining assay strongly indicated that MT exhibited a significant protective effect against UV irradiation damage. The UV irradiation-induced cell cycle arresting at S phase, apoptosis, mitochondrial membrane potential (MMP) decreasing, and the related apoptosis signaling factors p-IKKα, p-p65, I-κB and the activation of caspase3 were all reversed by MT treatments to some extent. The mechanisms of MT were evaluated through comparing the effect of thermal inactivation, ultrasonic crushing, and repeated freezing and thawing treatments on MT function. These results denied the above hypothesis that mitochondrial component may be responsible for MT, excluded the function of ATP, mtDNA and other small molecules, and indicated that the mitochondria structural integrity is essential. We also evaluated the effect of Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt; concentrations (1 and 1.8 mM) on MT, and the results showed no effect was found in this UV-irradiated HeLa cell model. Our data support a potent anti-UV irradiation effect of MT, and that structural integrity of the mitochondria is critical for its function.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mitochondrial PKM2 deacetylation by procyanidin B2-induced SIRT3 upregulation alleviates lung ischemia/reperfusion injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35821123/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35821123/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apoptosis is a critical event in the pathogenesis of lung ischemia/reperfusion (I/R) injury. Sirtuin 3 (SIRT3), an important deacetylase predominantly localized in mitochondria, regulates diverse physiological processes, including apoptosis. However, the detailed mechanisms by which SIRT3 regulates lung I/R injury remain unclear. Many polyphenols strongly regulate the sirtuin family. In this study, we found that a polyphenol compound, procyanidin B2 (PCB2), activated SIRT3 in mouse lungs. Due to this effect, PCB2 administration attenuated histological lesions, relieved pulmonary dysfunction, and improved the survival rate of the murine model of lung I/R injury. Additionally, this treatment inhibited hypoxia/reoxygenation (H/R)-induced A549 cell apoptosis and rescued Bcl-2 expression. Using Sirt3-knockout mice and specific SIRT3 knockdown in vitro, we further found that SIRT3 strongly protects against lung I/R injury. Sirt3 deficiency or enzymatic inactivation substantially aggravated lung I/R-induced pulmonary lesions, promoted apoptosis, and abolished PCB2-mediated protection. Mitochondrial pyruvate kinase M2 (PKM2) inhibits apoptosis by stabilizing Bcl-2. Here, we found that PKM2 accumulates and is hyperacetylated in mitochondria upon lung I/R injury. By screening the potential sites of PKM2 acetylation, we found that SIRT3 deacetylates the K433 residue of PKM2 in A549 cells. Transfection with a deacetylated mimic plasmid of PKM2 noticeably reduced apoptosis, while acetylated mimic transfection abolished the protective effect of PKM2. Furthermore, PKM2 knockdown or inhibition in vivo significantly abrogated the antiapoptotic effects of SIRT3 upregulation. Collectively, this study provides the first evidence that the SIRT3/PKM2 pathway is a protective target for the suppression of apoptosis in lung I/R injury. Moreover, this study identifies K433 deacetylation of PKM2 as a novel modification that regulates its anti-apoptotic activity. In addition, PCB2-mediated modulation of the SIRT3/PKM2 pathway may significantly protect against lung I/R injury, suggesting a novel prophylactic strategy for lung I/R injury.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CircRNA Samd4 induces cardiac repair after myocardial infarction by blocking mitochondria-derived ROS output</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35791879/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35791879/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reactive oxygen species (ROS) derived from oxygen-dependent mitochondrial metabolism are the essential drivers of cardiomyocyte (CM) cell-cycle arrest in adulthood. Mitochondria-localized circular RNAs (circRNAs) play important roles in regulating mitochondria-derived ROS production, but their functions in cardiac regeneration are still unknown. Herein, we investigated the functions and underlying mechanism of mitochondria-localized circSamd4 in cardiac regeneration. We found that circSamd4 was selectively expressed in fetal and neonatal CMs. The transcription factor Nrf2 controlled circSamd4 expression by binding to the promoter of circSamd4 host gene. CircSamd4 overexpression reduced while circSamd4 silenced increased mitochondrial oxidative stress and subsequent oxidative DNA damage. Moreover, circSamd4 overexpression induced CM proliferation and prevented CM apoptosis, which reduced the size of the fibrotic area and improved cardiac function after myocardial infarction (MI). Mechanistically, circSamd4 reduced oxidative stress generation and maintained mitochondrial dynamics by inducing the mitochondrial translocation of the Vcp protein, which downregulated Vdac1 expression and prevented the mitochondrial permeability transition pore (mPTP) from opening. Our findings suggest that circSamd4 is a novel therapeutic target for heart failure after MI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TLR4-SIRT3 Mechanism Modulates Mitochondrial and Redox Homeostasis and Promotes EPCs Recruitment and Survival</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35832490/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35832490/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The low survival rate of endothelial progenitor cells (EPCs) &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt; which are susceptible to adverse microenvironments including inflammation and oxidative stress has become one primary challenge of EPCs transplantation for regenerative therapy. Recent studies reported functional expression of toll-like receptor (TLR) 4 on EPCs and dose-dependent effects of lipopolysaccharide (LPS) on cellular oxidative stress and angiogenic properties. However, the involved mechanism has not yet been elucidated well, and the influence of TLR4 signaling on EPCs survival and function &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt; is unknown. In the present study, we observed the effects of LPS and TLR4/SIRT3 on EPCs mitochondrial permeability and intracellular mitochondrial superoxide. We employed the monocrotaline-induced pulmonary arteriolar injury model to observe the effects of TLR4/SIRT3 on the recruitment and survival of transplanted EPCs. We found the destructive effects of 10 μg/mL LPS on mitochondrial homeostasis, and cellular viability was mediated by TLR4/SIRT3 signals at least partially, and the TLR4 mediates the early-stage recruitment of transplanted EPCs in pulmonary arteriolar inflammation injury; however, SIRT3 has more contribution to the survival of incorporated EPCs and ameliorated arteriolar remodeling in lung vascular tissue. The study provides insights for the critical role of TLR4/SIRT3 in LPS-induced oxidative stress and mitochondrial disorder in EPCs &lt;em&gt;in vitro&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt;. The TLR4/SIRT3 signaling is important for EPCs resistance against inflammation and oxidative stress and may represent a new manipulating target for developing efficient cell therapy strategy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A circular RNA derived from the insulin receptor locus protects against doxorubicin-induced cardiotoxicity</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35758064/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35758064/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Aims:&lt;/em&gt; Cardiotoxicity leading to heart failure (HF) is a growing problem in many cancer survivors. As specific treatment strategies are not available, RNA discovery pipelines were employed and a new and powerful circular RNA (circRNA)-based therapy was developed for the treatment of doxorubicin-induced HF.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods and results:&lt;/em&gt; The circRNA sequencing was applied and the highly species-conserved circRNA insulin receptor (Circ-INSR) was identified, which participates in HF processes, including those provoked by cardiotoxic anti-cancer treatments. Chemotherapy-provoked cardiotoxicity leads to the down-regulation of Circ-INSR in rodents and patients, which mechanistically contributes to cardiomyocyte cell death, cardiac dysfunction, and mitochondrial damage. In contrast, Circ-INSR overexpression prevented doxorubicin-mediated cardiotoxicity in both rodent and human cardiomyocytes in vitro and in a mouse model of chronic doxorubicin cardiotoxicity. Breast cancer type 1 susceptibility protein (Brca1) was identified as a regulator of Circ-INSR expression. Detailed transcriptomic and proteomic analyses revealed that Circ-INSR regulates apoptotic and metabolic pathways in cardiomyocytes. Circ-INSR physically interacts with the single-stranded DNA-binding protein (SSBP1) mediating its cardioprotective effects under doxorubicin stress. Importantly, in vitro transcribed and circularized Circ-INSR mimics also protected against doxorubicin-induced cardiotoxicity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/em&gt; Circ-INSR is a highly conserved non-coding RNA which is down-regulated during cardiotoxicity and cardiac remodelling. Adeno-associated virus and circRNA mimics-based Circ-INSR overexpression prevent and reverse doxorubicin-mediated cardiomyocyte death and improve cardiac function. The results of this study highlight a novel and translationally important Circ-INSR-based therapeutic approach for doxorubicin-induced cardiac dysfunction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>P4HB UFMylation regulates mitochondrial function and oxidative stress</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35753586/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35753586/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UFMylation is a ubiquitin-like modification which attaches the ubiquitin-fold modifier 1 to target proteins. To date, only a few UFMylation targets have been identified. In the current study, we demonstrated that P4HB is a new target protein for UFMylation and it can be UFMylated at three lysine residues in the form of mono-UFMylation. P4HB has oxidoreductase, chaperone and isomerase effects. It presents in the endoplasmic reticulum, mitochondria and cytosol. Next, we generated a stable HepG2 cell line, the hepatocellular cells, with defective P4HB UFMylation. Our data show that P4HB UFMylation defect promotes P4HB protein degradation via the ubiquitin-proteasome pathway. Defective P4HB UFMylation causes mitochondrial function damage, oxidative stress, and endoplasmic reticulum stress in HepG2 cells. These effects are more obvious when treating HepG2 cells with palmitic acid, which is frequently used as one of the cell models of non-alcoholic fatty liver disease (NAFLD). Our results identify UFMylation as a key post-translational modification for the maintenance of P4HB stability and biological functions in HepG2 cells, and point to P4HB UFMylation as a potential direction in the study of NAFLD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mitochondrial cyclophilin D promotes disease tolerance by licensing NK cell development and IL-22 production against influenza virus</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35732121/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35732121/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mitochondrial CypD is required to protect against severe influenza infection&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CypD expression promotes NK cell lymphopoiesis and maturation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;NK cell-derived IL-22 enhances disease tolerance during influenza infection&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Transfer of WT NK cells confers protection in &lt;em&gt;CypD&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; mice to influenza infection&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Severity of pulmonary viral infections, including influenza A virus (IAV), is linked to excessive immunopathology, which impairs lung function. Thus, the same immune responses that limit viral replication can concomitantly cause lung damage that must be countered by largely uncharacterized disease tolerance mechanisms. Here, we show that mitochondrial cyclophilin D (CypD) protects against IAV via disease tolerance. &lt;em&gt;CypD&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; mice are significantly more susceptible to IAV infection despite comparable antiviral immunity. This susceptibility results from damage to the lung epithelial barrier caused by a reduction in interleukin-22 (IL-22)-producing natural killer (NK) cells. Transcriptomic and functional data reveal that &lt;em&gt;CypD&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; NK cells are immature and have altered cellular metabolism and impaired IL-22 production, correlating with dysregulated bone marrow lymphopoiesis. Administration of recombinant IL-22 or transfer of wild-type (WT) NK cells abrogates pulmonary damage and protects &lt;em&gt;CypD&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; mice after IAV infection. Collectively, these results demonstrate a key role for CypD in NK cell-mediated disease tolerance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>STING signaling sensing of DRP1-dependent mtDNA release in kupffer cells contributes to lipopolysaccharide-induced liver injury in mice</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35724543/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35724543/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aberrant pro-inflammatory activation of Kupffer cells (KCs) is strongly involved in the pathogenesis of septic liver injury. Recent evidence indicates the crucial roles of excessive stimulator of interferon genes (STING) signaling activation during sepsis. However, the role of STING signaling in septic liver injury remains unclear. In this study, we demonstrated that STING signaling was markedly activated in KCs isolated from wild type mice after lipopolysaccharide (LPS) treatment. STING deficiency effectively protected liver function, attenuated systemic inflammatory response and decreased mortality in LPS-treated mice, which were aggravated by STING agonist (DMXAA). Importantly, STING signaling activation in KCs contributed to LPS-induced liver injury through promoting hepatocyte death. Mechanistically, STING signaling could be activated by release of mitochondrial DNA (mtDNA) through dynamin-related protein 1 (DRP1)-dependent mitochondrial fission in LPS-treated KCs. Additionally, LPS stimulation enhanced DRP1-dependent mitochondrial ROS production, which promoted the leak of mtDNA into the cytosol and subsequent STING signaling activation in KCs. The in vivo experiments showed that pharmacological inhibition of DRP1 with Mdivi-1 partially prevented the activation of STING signaling in KCs isolated from LPS-challenged mice, as well as alleviated liver injury and inhibited systemic inflammatory response. In summary, our study comprehensively confirmed that STING signaling senses the DRP1-dependent release of mtDNA in KCs and its activation might play a key role in LPS-induced liver injury, which offers new sights and therapeutic targets for management of septic liver injury.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arsenic induces ferroptosis and acute lung injury through mtROS-mediated mitochondria-associated endoplasmic reticulum membrane dysfunction</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35525119/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35525119/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Acute As exposure induced pulmonary function decline and ALI in mice.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Acute As exposure caused ferroptosis, MAMs dysfunction and mitochondrial stress in mice lungs and pulmonary epithelial cells.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pretreatment with ferrostatin-1 alleviated As-induced pulmonary function decline and ALI.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PERK inhibitor and Mfn-2-overexpression inhibited As-evoked ferroptosis in pulmonary epithelial cells.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MitoQ neutralized As-mediated MAMs dysfunction, mtROS production and ferroptosis in pulmonary epithelial cells.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MitoQ abolished As-induced decline of the interaction between PERK and Mfn-2 in pulmonary epithelial cells.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MitoQ attenuated As-caused ferroptosis and ALI in mice.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The goal of this study was to analyze whether mitochondria-associated endoplasmic reticulum membrane (MAMs) dysfunction mediated arsenic (As)-evoked pulmonary ferroptosis and acute lung injury (ALI). As exposure led to alveolar structure damage, inflammatory cell infiltration and pulmonary function decline in mice. Ferritin, the marker of iron overload, was increased, GPX4, the index of lipid peroxidation, was decreased in As-exposed lungs and pulmonary epithelial cells (MLE-12). Pretreatment with ferrostatin-1 (Fer-1), the inhibitor of ferroptosis, alleviated As-evoked ALI. In addition, As-induced non-heme iron deposition was inhibited in Fer-1 pretreated-mice. Moreover, As-triggered mitochondria damage and ferroptosis were mitigated in Fer-1 pretreated-MLE-12 cells. Mechanistically, PERK phosphorylation and mitofusin-2 (Mfn-2) reduction was observed in As-exposed MLE-12 cells and mice lungs. Additionally, the interaction between PERK and Mfn-2 was downregulated and MAMs dysfunction was observed in As-exposed MLE-12 cells. Intriguingly, PERK inhibitor and Mfn-2-overexpression all mitigated As-induced ferroptosis in MLE-12 cells. Additionally, CLPP and mtHSP70, the markers of mitochondrial stress, were upregulated, mitochondrial ROS (mtROS) was elevated, mitochondrial membrane potential (MMP) and ATP were decreased in As-exposed MLE-12 cells. Mitoquinone mesylate (MitoQ), a novel mitochondrial-targeted antioxidant, alleviated As-induced excess mtROS, mitochondrial stress, MAMs dysfunction in pulmonary epithelial cells. Similarly, in vivo experiments indicated that MitoQ pretreatment countered As-induced pulmonary ferroptosis and ALI. These data indicated that mtROS-initiated MAMs dysfunction is, at least partially, implicated in As-evoked ferroptosis and ALI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>L-OPA1 deficiency aggravates necroptosis of alveolar epithelial cells through impairing mitochondrial function during acute lung injury in mice</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35478455/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35478455/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Necroptosis, a recently described form of programmed cell death, is the main way of alveolar epithelial cells (AECs) death in acute lung injury (ALI). While the mechanism of how to trigger necroptosis in AECs during ALI has been rarely evaluated. Long optic atrophy protein 1 (L-OPA1) is a crucial mitochondrial inner membrane fusion protein, and its deficiency impairs mitochondrial function. This study aimed to investigate the role of L-OPA1 deficiency-mediated mitochondrial dysfunction in AECs necroptosis. We comprehensively investigated the detailed contribution and molecular mechanism of L-OPA1 deficiency in AECs necroptosis by inhibiting or activating L-OPA1. First, our data showed that L-OPA1 expression was downregulated in the lungs and AECs under the lipopolysaccharide (LPS) challenge. Furthermore, inhibition of L-OPA1 aggravated the pathological injury, inflammatory response, and necroptosis in the lungs of LPS-induced ALI mice. In vitro, inhibition of L-OPA1 induced necroptosis of AECs, while activation of L-OPA1 alleviated necroptosis of AECs under the LPS challenge. Mechanistically, inhibition of L-OPA1 aggravated necroptosis of AECs by inducing mitochondrial fragmentation and reducing mitochondrial membrane potential. While activation of L-OPA1 had the opposite effects. In summary, these findings indicate for the first time that L-OPA1 deficiency mediates mitochondrial fragmentation, induces necroptosis of AECs, and exacerbates ALI in mice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SARS-CoV-2 infection of human-induced pluripotent stem cells-derived lung lineage cells evokes inflammatory and chemosensory responses by targeting mitochondrial pathways</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35460571/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35460571/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The COVID-19 disease caused by severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 (SARS-CoV-2) primarily affects the lung, particularly the proximal airway and distal alveolar cells. NKX2.1+ primordial lung progenitors of the foregut (anterior) endoderm are the developmental precursors to all adult lung epithelial lineages and are postulated to play an important role in viral tropism. Here, we show that SARS-CoV-2 readily infected and replicated in human-induced pluripotent stem cell-derived proximal airway cells, distal alveolar cells, and lung progenitors. In addition to the upregulation of antiviral defense and immune responses, transcriptomics data uncovered a robust epithelial cell-specific response, including perturbation of metabolic processes and disruption in the alveolar maturation program. We also identified spatiotemporal dysregulation of mitochondrial heme oxygenase 1 (HMOX1), which is associated with defense against antioxidant-induced lung injury. Cytokines, such as TNF-α, INF-γ, IL-6, and IL-13, were upregulated in infected cells sparking mitochondrial ROS production and change in electron transport chain complexes. Increased mitochondrial ROS then activated additional proinflammatory cytokines leading to an aberrant cell cycle resulting in apoptosis. Notably, we are the first to report a chemosensory response resulting from SARS-CoV-2 infection similar to that seen in COVID-19 patients. Some of our key findings were validated using COVID-19-affected postmortem lung tissue sections. These results suggest that our in vitro system could serve as a suitable model to investigate the pathogenetic mechanisms of SARS-CoV-2 infection and to discover and test therapeutic drugs against COVID-19 or its consequences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reticulon-1A mediates diabetic kidney disease progression through endoplasmic reticulum-mitochondrial contacts in tubular epithelial cells</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35469894/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35469894/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recent epidemiological studies suggest that some patients with diabetes progress to kidney failure without significant albuminuria and glomerular injury, suggesting a critical role of kidney tubular epithelial cell (TEC) injury in diabetic kidney disease (DKD) progression. However, the major risk factors contributing to TEC injury and progression in DKD remain unclear. We previously showed that expression of endoplasmic reticulum-resident protein Reticulon-1A (RTN1A) increased in human DKD, and the increased RTN1A expression promoted TEC injury through endoplasmic reticulum (ER) stress response. Here, we show that TEC-specific RTN1A overexpression worsened DKD in mice, evidenced by enhanced tubular injury, tubulointerstitial fibrosis, and kidney function decline. But RTN1A overexpression did not exacerbate diabetes-induced glomerular injury or albuminuria. Notably, RTN1A overexpression worsened both ER stress and mitochondrial dysfunction in TECs under diabetic conditions by regulation of ER-mitochondria contacts. Mechanistically, ER-bound RTN1A interacted with mitochondrial hexokinase-1 and the voltage-dependent anion channel-1 (VDAC1), interfering with their association. This disengagement of VDAC1 from hexokinase-1 resulted in activation of apoptotic and inflammasome pathways, leading to TEC injury and loss. Thus, our observations highlight the importance of ER-mitochondrial crosstalk in TEC injury and the salient role of RTN1A-mediated ER-mitochondrial contact regulation in DKD progression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Impairment of Mitochondrial ATP Synthesis Induces RIPK3-dependent Necroptosis in Lung Epithelial Cells During Lung Injury by Lung Inflammation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35573150/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35573150/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dysfunction of mitochondrial metabolism is implicated in cellular injury and cell death. While mitochondrial dysfunction is associated with lung injury by lung inflammation, the mechanism by which the impairment of mitochondrial ATP synthesis regulates necroptosis during acute lung injury (ALI) by lung inflammation is unclear. Here, we showed that the impairment of mitochondrial ATP synthesis induces receptor interacting serine/threonine kinase 3 (RIPK3)-dependent necroptosis during lung injury by lung inflammation. We found that the impairment of mitochondrial ATP synthesis by oligomycin, an inhibitor of ATP synthase, resulted in increased lung injury and RIPK3 levels in lung tissues during lung inflammation by LPS in mice. The elevated RIPK3 and RIPK3 phosphorylation levels by oligomycin resulted in high mixed lineage kinase domain-like (MLKL) phosphorylation, the terminal molecule in necroptotic cell death pathway, in lung epithelial cells during lung inflammation. Moreover, the levels of protein in bronchoalveolar lavage fluid (BALF) were increased by the activation of necroptosis via oligomycin during lung inflammation. Furthermore, the levels of ATP5A, a catalytic subunit of the mitochondrial ATP synthase complex for ATP synthesis, were reduced in lung epithelial cells of lung tissues from patients with acute respiratory distress syndrome (ARDS), the most severe form of ALI. The levels of RIPK3, RIPK3 phosphorylation and MLKL phosphorylation were elevated in lung epithelial cells in patients with ARDS. Our results suggest that the impairment of mitochondrial ATP synthesis induces RIPK3-dependent necroptosis in lung epithelial cells during lung injury by lung inflammation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cGAS modulates cytokine secretion and bacterial burdens by altering the release of mitochondrial DNA in pseudomonas pulmonary infection</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35420160/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35420160/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cyclic GMP-AMP synthase (cGAS) is essential for fighting against viruses and bacteria, but how cGAS is involved in host immune response remains largely elusive. Here, we uncover the crucial role of cGAS in host immunity based on a &lt;em&gt;Pseudomonas aeruginosa&lt;/em&gt; pulmonary infection model. &lt;em&gt;cGAS&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; mice showed more heavy bacterial burdens and serious lung injury accompanied with exorbitant proinflammatory cytokines than wild-type mice. cGAS deficiency caused an accumulation of mitochondrial DNA in the cytoplasm, which, in turn, induced excessive secretion of proinflammatory factors by activating inflammasome and TLR9 signalling. Mechanistically, cGAS deficiency inhibited the recruitment of LC3 by reducing the binding capacity of TBK-1 to p62, leading to impaired mitophagy and augmented release of mitochondrial DNA. Importantly, cytoplasmic mitochondrial DNA also acted as a feedback signal that induced the activation of cGAS. Altogether, these findings identify protective and homeostasis functions of cGAS against &lt;em&gt;Pseudomonas aeruginosa&lt;/em&gt; infection, adding significant insight into the pathogenesis of bacterial infectious diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The inhibition of TRIM35-mediated TIGAR ubiquitination enhances mitochondrial fusion and alleviates renal ischemia-reperfusion injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35421414/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35421414/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tripartite motif 35 (TRIM35) is a member of the tripartite motif protein family and has been recognized to play a key role in immune-inflammatory diseases. However, the role of TRIM35 in renal ischemia-reperfusion injury (IRI) remains unclear. Our study proved that knockdown of TRIM35 alleviates kidney IRI by inhibiting oxidative stress and enhancing mitochondrial fusion. In addition, our experimental results found that TRIM35 interacts with TP53-induced glycolysis and apoptosis regulator (TIGAR) and promotes the polyubiquitination of TIGAR and induces its degradation in the proteasome pathway. Furthermore, TIGAR knockdown significantly inhibited mitochondrial fusion. These results indicate that TRIM35 is a potential therapeutic target for renal IRI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Loss of Sam50 in hepatocytes induces cardiolipin-dependent mitochondrial membrane remodeling to trigger mtDNA release and liver injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35313046/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35313046/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background and aims:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sam50, a key component of the sorting and assembly machinery (SAM) complex, is also involved in bridging mitochondrial outer-membrane and inner-membrane contacts. However, the physiological and pathological functions of Sam50 remain largely unknown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Approach and results:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here we show that Sam50 interacts with MICOS (mitochondrial contact site and cristae organizing system) and ATAD3 (ATPase family AAA domain-containing protein 3) to form the Sam50-MICOS-ATAD3-mtDNA axis, which maintains mtDNA stability. Loss of Sam50 causes mitochondrial DNA (mtDNA) aggregation. Furthermore, Sam50 cooperates with Mic60 to bind to cardiolipin, maintaining the integrity of mitochondrial membranes. Sam50 depletion leads to cardiolipin externalization, which causes mitochondrial outer-membrane and inner-membrane (including crista membrane) remodeling, triggering Bax mitochondrial recruitment, mtDNA aggregation, and release. Physiologically, acetaminophen (an effective antipyretic and analgesic)-caused Sam50 reduction or Sam50 liver-specific knockout induces mtDNA release, leading to activation of the cGAS-STING pathway and liver inflammation in mice. Moreover, exogenous expression of Sam50 remarkably attenuates APAP-induced liver hepatoxicity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our findings uncover the critical role of Sam50 in maintaining mitochondrial membrane integrity and mtDNA stability in hepatocytes and reveal that Sam50 depletion-induced cardiolipin externalization is a signal of mtDNA release and controls mtDNA-dependent innate immunity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mitochondria bridge HIF signaling and ferroptosis blockage in acute kidney injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/35387983/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/35387983/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ferroptosis, a form of regulated cell death, plays an important role in acute kidney injury (AKI). Previous studies have shown that prolyl hydroxylase domain protein (PHD) inhibitors that activate HIF signaling provide strong protection against AKI, which is characterized by marked cell death. However, the relationship between PHD inhibition/HIF signaling and ferroptosis in AKI has not been elucidated. Here, we review recent studies to explore the issue. First, we will review the literature concerning the functions of HIF in promoting mitophagy, suppressing mitochondrial respiration and modulating redox homeostasis. Second, we will describe the current understanding of ferroptosis and its role in AKI, particularly from the perspective of mitochondrial dysfunction. Finally, we will discuss the possibility that mitochondria link PHD inhibition/HIF signaling and ferroptosis in AKI. In conclusion, we propose that HIF may protect renal cells against ferroptosis in AKI by reducing mitochondrial oxidative stress and damage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Facts&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ferroptosis plays an important role in the development of AKI.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Activation of HIF signaling provides protection against AKI.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mitochondrial ROS facilitate ferroptosis in many cases.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;HIF signaling regulates multiple mitochondrial activities, including mitochondrial oxidative capacity, redox homeostasis and autophagy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Open questions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Can HIF signaling alleviate ferroptosis in AKI with different etiologies?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is mitochondrial pathway decisive for HIF-offered protection in situations like AKI, given that HIF signaling has extensive downstream effects?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Would PHD inhibitors be effective in AKI prevention and treatment clinically?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meldonium Ameliorates Hypoxia-Induced Lung Injury and Oxidative Stress by Regulating Platelet-Type Phosphofructokinase-Mediated Glycolysis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35450040/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35450040/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hypoxic environments at high altitudes influence the long-term non-altitude health of residents, by inducing changes in metabolism and the mitochondria, severe lung injury, and endangering life. This study was aimed to determine whether meldonium can ameliorate hypoxia-induced lung injury and investigate its possible molecular mechanisms. We used Swiss mice and exposed type Ⅱ alveolar epithelial cell to hypobaric hypoxic conditions to induce lung injury and found that meldonium has significant preventive effect, which was associated with the regulation of glycolysis. We found using human proteome microarrays assay, molecular docking, immunofluorescence and pull-down assay that the target protein of meldonium is a platelet-type phosphofructokinase (PFKP), which is a rate-limiting enzyme of glycolysis. Also, meldonium promotes the transfer of nuclear factor erythroid 2-related factor 2 (Nrf2) from the cytoplasm to the nucleus, which mitigates oxidative stress and mitochondrial damage under hypoxic condition. Mechanistically, meldonium ameliorates lung injury by targeting PFKP to regulate glycolysis, which promotes Nrf2 translocation from the cytoplasm to the nucleus to alleviate oxidative stress and mitochondrial damage under hypoxic condition. Our study provides a novel potential prevention and treatment strategy against hypoxia-induced lung injury.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chrysin Ameliorates Influenza Virus Infection in the Upper Airways by Repressing Virus-Induced Cell Cycle Arrest and Mitochondria-Dependent Apoptosis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35432374/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35432374/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chrysin has been proven to possess antiviral properties, but the precise underlying anti-influenza mechanism and its anti-influenza efficacy in vivo are largely unclear. In this study, we investigated the involvement of chrysin in the blockade of cell cycle and apoptosis in distinct cell lines subjected to two H1N1 influenza A virus (IAV) strains, as well as its anti-IAV activity in vivo. Here, we found an early unidentified finding that chrysin strongly impeded IAV replication through a mechanism that was autonomous of innate antiviral immune activation and viral protein interaction. Surprisingly, chrysin can suppress IAV-induced cell cycle arrest in the G0/G1 phase by downregulating the expression levels of P53 and P21 while promoting Cyclin D1/CDK4 and Cyclin E1/CDK2 activation. Furthermore, chrysin dramatically inhibited the IAV-triggered mitochondrial apoptotic pathway by altering the balance of Bax/Bcl-xl and reducing caspase-9 and caspase-3 activation. Accumulated reactive oxygen species (ROS) reduction may contribute to the inhibitory role of chrysin in cell cycle arrest and apoptosis following IAV infection. Notably, chrysin preferably inhibited IAV replication in the upper respiratory tract, indicating that it might be a promising drug for restraining the spread of respiratory viruses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AdMSC-derived exosomes alleviate acute lung injury via transferring mitochondrial component to improve homeostasis of alveolar macrophages</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35401830/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35401830/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rationale:&lt;/em&gt; Aberrant activation of macrophages with mitochondria dismiss was proved to be associated with pathogenesis of ALI (acute lung injury). Exosomes from adipose-derived mesenchymal stem cells (AdMSC-Exos) have been distinguished by their low immunogenicity, lack of tumorigenicity, and high clinical safety, but their role in treating ALI and the mechanism involved need to be defined. In this study, we sought to investigate whether the mitochondrial donation from AdMSC-Exos provides profound protection against LPS-induced ALI in mice, accompanied by improvement of macrophage mitochondrial function.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; C57BL/6 mice were orotracheally instilled with LPS (1 mg/kg). AdMSC-Exos were administered via the tail vein 4 h after LPS inhalation. Flow cytometry, H&amp;amp;E, Quantitative Real-Time PCR, immunofluorescence (IF), confocal microscopy imaging was conducted to investigate lung tissue inflammation and macrophage mitochondrial function. And further observe the transfer of exosomes and the effect on mitochondrial function of MH-S cells through &lt;em&gt;in vitro&lt;/em&gt; experiments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; AdMSC-Exos can transfer the stem cell-derived mitochondria components to alveolar macrophages in a dose-dependent manner. Likely through complementing the damaged mitochondria, AdMSC-Exos exhibited the ability to elevate the level of mtDNA, mitochondrial membrane potential (MMP), OXPHOS activity and ATP generation, while reliving mROS stress in LPS-challenged macrophages. Restoring mitochondrial integrity via AdMSC-Exos treatment enabled macrophages shifting to anti-inflammatory phenotype, as featured with the down-regulation of IL-1β, TNF-α and iNOS secretion and increase in production of anti-inflammatory cytokines IL-10 and Arg-1. As we depleted alveolar macrophages using clodronate liposomes, the protective role for AdMSC-Exos was largely abrogated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; AdMSC-Exos can effectively donate mitochondria component improved macrophages mitochondrial integrity and oxidative phosphorylation level, leading to the resumption of metabolic and immune homeostasis of airway macrophages and mitigating lung inflammatory pathology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DNA-PKcs interacts with and phosphorylates Fis1 to induce mitochondrial fragmentation in tubular cells during acute kidney injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35290083/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35290083/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The catalytic subunit of DNA-dependent protein kinase (DNA-PKcs) regulates cell death. We sought to determine whether DNA-PKcs played a role in the tubular damage that occurs during acute kidney injury (AKI) induced by LPS injection (to mimic sepsis), cisplatin administration, or renal ischemia/reperfusion injury. Although DNA-PKcs normally localizes to the nucleus, we detected cytoplasmic DNA-PKcs in mouse kidney tissues and urinary sediments of human patients with septic AKI. Increased cytoplasmic amounts of DNA-PKcs correlated with renal dysfunction. Tubule cell-specific &lt;em&gt;DNA-PKcs&lt;/em&gt; deletion attenuated AKI-mediated tubular cell death and changes in the abundance of various proteins with mitochondrial functions or roles in apoptotic pathways. DNA-PKcs interacted with Fis1 and phosphorylated it at Thr&lt;sup&gt;34&lt;/sup&gt; in its TQ motif, which increased the affinity of Fis1 for Drp1 and induced mitochondrial fragmentation. Knockin mice expressing a nonphosphorylatable T34A mutant exhibited improved renal function and histological features and reduced mitochondrial fragmentation upon induction of AKI. Phosphorylation of Thr&lt;sup&gt;34&lt;/sup&gt; in Fis1 was detectable in urinary sediments of human patients with septic AKI and correlated with renal dysfunction. Our findings provide insight into the role of cytoplasmic DNA-PKcs and phosphorylated Fis1 in AKI development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mitochondrial Protein Akap 1 Deletion Exacerbates Endoplasmic Reticulum Stress in Mice Exposed to Hyperoxia</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35370705/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35370705/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acute lung injury (ALI) and its severe manifestation, acute respiratory distress syndrome (ARDS), are treated with high concentrations of supplementary oxygen. However, prolonged exposure to high oxygen concentrations stimulates the production of reactive oxygen species (ROS), which damages the mitochondria and accumulates misfolded proteins in the endoplasmic reticulum (ER). The mitochondrial protein A-kinase anchoring protein 1 (&lt;em&gt;Akap1&lt;/em&gt;) is critical for mitochondrial homeostasis. It is known that &lt;em&gt;Akap1&lt;/em&gt; deficiency results in heart damage, neuronal development impairment, and mitochondrial malfunction in preclinical studies. Our laboratory recently revealed that deleting &lt;em&gt;Akap1&lt;/em&gt; increases the severity of hyperoxia-induced ALI in mice. To assess the role of &lt;em&gt;Akap1&lt;/em&gt; deletion in ER stress in lung injury, wild-type and &lt;em&gt;Akap1&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; mice were exposed to hyperoxia for 48 h. This study indicates that &lt;em&gt;Akap1&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; mice exposed to hyperoxia undergo ER stress, which is associated with an increased expression of BiP, JNK phosphorylation, eIF2α phosphorylation, ER stress-induced cell death, and autophagy. This work demonstrates that deleting &lt;em&gt;Akap1&lt;/em&gt; results in increased ER stress in the lungs of mice and that hyperoxia exacerbates ER stress-related consequences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Age-associated decline of MondoA drives cellular senescence through impaired autophagy and mitochondrial homeostasis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35235784/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35235784/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The transcription factor MondoA is identified as a regulator of cellular senescence&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MondoA counteracts senescence by activating autophagy via the suppression of Rubicon&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MondoA delays senescence by maintaining mitochondrial function through Prdx3&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Decrease of MondoA in the nucleus is correlated with senescence in human aging&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Accumulation of senescent cells affects organismal aging and the prevalence of age-associated disease. Emerging evidence suggests that activation of autophagy protects against age-associated diseases and promotes longevity, but the roles and regulatory mechanisms of autophagy in cellular senescence are not well understood. Here, we identify the transcription factor, MondoA, as a regulator of cellular senescence, autophagy, and mitochondrial homeostasis. MondoA protects against cellular senescence by activating autophagy partly through the suppression of an autophagy-negative regulator, Rubicon. In addition, we identify peroxiredoxin 3 (Prdx3) as another downstream regulator of MondoA essential for mitochondrial homeostasis and autophagy. Rubicon and Prdx3 work independently to regulate senescence. Furthermore, we find that MondoA knockout mice have exacerbated senescence during ischemic acute kidney injury (AKI), and a decrease of MondoA in the nucleus is correlated with human aging and ischemic AKI. Our results suggest that decline of MondoA worsens senescence and age-associated disease.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chicoric Acid Attenuated Renal Tubular Injury in HFD-Induced Chronic Kidney Disease Mice through the Promotion of Mitophagy via the Nrf2/PINK/Parkin Pathway</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35195395/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35195395/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the main factor in the pathogenesis of chronic kidney disease (CKD), the excessive apoptosis of renal tubular epithelial cells (RTECs) and its underlying mechanism of action are worth further investigation. Chicoric acid (CA), a major active constituent of the Uyghur folk medicine chicory, was recorded to possess a renal protective effect. The precise effect of CA on renal tubular injury in obesity-related CKD remains unknown. In the current study, CA was proven to ameliorate metabolic disorders including overweight, hyperglycemia, hyperlipidemia, and hyperuricemia in high fat diet (HFD)-fed mice. Furthermore, the reverse effect of CA on renal histological changes and functional damage was confirmed. &lt;em&gt;In vitro&lt;/em&gt;, the alleviation of lipid accumulation and cell apoptosis was observed in palmitic acid (PA)-exposed HK2 cells. Treatment with CA reduced mitochondrial damage and oxidative stress in the renal tubule of HFD-fed mice and PA-treated HK2 cells. Finally, CA was observed to activate the Nrf2 pathway; increase PINK and Parkin expression; and regulate LC3, SQSTM1, Mfn2, and FIS1 expression; therefore, it would improve mitochondrial dynamics and mitophagy to alleviate mitochondrial damage in RTECs of obesity-related CKD. These results may provide fresh insights into the promotion of mitophagy in the prevention and alleviation of obesity-related CKD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NR4A1 Promotes LPS-Induced Acute Lung Injury through Inhibition of Opa1-Mediated Mitochondrial Fusion and Activation of PGAM5-Related Necroptosis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35222801/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35222801/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mitochondrial dysfunction and necroptosis have been perceived as the primary molecular mechanisms underscoring acute lung injury. Meanwhile, nuclear receptor subfamily 4 group A member 1 (NR4A1) is considered a regulator of inflammation-related endothelial injury in lung tissue although the downstream molecular events remain elusive. In this study, we employed NR4A1-/- mice to decipher the role of NR4A1 in the onset and progression of acute lung injury with a focus on mitochondrial damage and necroptosis. Our results demonstrated that NR4A1 was significantly upregulated in lipopolysaccharide- (LPS-) treated lung tissues. Knockout of NR4A1 overtly improved lung tissue morphology, inhibited inflammation, and reduced oxidative stress in LPS-treated lung tissue. A cell signaling study suggested that NR4A1 deletion repressed levels of PGAM5 and attenuated LPS-mediated necroptosis in primary murine alveolar epithelial type II (ATII) cells, the effects of which were mitigated by PGAM5 overexpression. Moreover, LPS-mediated mitochondrial injury including mitochondrial membrane potential collapse and mitochondrial oxidative stress was drastically improved by NR4A1 deletion. Furthermore, NR4A1 deletion preserved mitochondrial homeostasis through activation of Opa1-related mitochondrial fusion. Silencing of Opa1 triggered mitochondrial dysfunction in NR4A1-deleted ATII cells. Taken together, our data identified NR4A1 as a novel regulator of LPS-related acute lung injury through regulation of mitochondrial fusion and necroptosis, indicating therapeutic promises of targeting NR4A1 in the treatment of acute lung injury in clinical practice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Repression of hypoxia-inducible factor-1 contributes to increased mitochondrial reactive oxygen species production in diabetes</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35164902/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35164902/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Excessive production of mitochondrial reactive oxygen species (ROS) is a central mechanism for the development of diabetes complications. Recently, hypoxia has been identified to play an additional pathogenic role in diabetes. In this study, we hypothesized that ROS overproduction was secondary to the impaired responses to hypoxia due to the inhibition of hypoxia-inducible factor-1 (HIF-1) by hyperglycemia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; The ROS levels were analyzed in the blood of healthy subjects and individuals with type 1 diabetes after exposure to hypoxia. The relation between HIF-1, glucose levels, ROS production and its functional consequences were analyzed in renal mIMCD-3 cells and in kidneys of mouse models of diabetes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; Exposure to hypoxia increased circulating ROS in subjects with diabetes, but not in subjects without diabetes. High glucose concentrations repressed HIF-1 both in hypoxic cells and in kidneys of animals with diabetes, through a HIF prolyl-hydroxylase (PHD)-dependent mechanism. The impaired HIF-1 signaling contributed to excess production of mitochondrial ROS through increased mitochondrial respiration that was mediated by Pyruvate dehydrogenase kinase 1 (PDK1). The restoration of HIF-1 function attenuated ROS overproduction despite persistent hyperglycemia, and conferred protection against apoptosis and renal injury in diabetes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; We conclude that the repression of HIF-1 plays a central role in mitochondrial ROS overproduction in diabetes and is a potential therapeutic target for diabetic complications. These findings are timely since the first PHD inhibitor that can activate HIF-1 has been newly approved for clinical use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mitochondrial and metabolic dysfunction in ageing and age-related diseases</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/35145250/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/35145250/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Organismal ageing is accompanied by progressive loss of cellular function and systemic deterioration of multiple tissues, leading to impaired function and increased vulnerability to death. Mitochondria have become recognized not merely as being energy suppliers but also as having an essential role in the development of diseases associated with ageing, such as neurodegenerative and cardiovascular diseases. A growing body of evidence suggests that ageing and age-related diseases are tightly related to an energy supply and demand imbalance, which might be alleviated by a variety of interventions, including physical activity and calorie restriction, as well as naturally occurring molecules targeting conserved longevity pathways. Here, we review key historical advances and progress from the past few years in our understanding of the role of mitochondria in ageing and age-related metabolic diseases. We also highlight emerging scientific innovations using mitochondria-targeted therapeutic approaches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PACS-2 Ameliorates Tubular Injury by Facilitating Endoplasmic Reticulum-Mitochondria Contact and Mitophagy in Diabetic Nephropathy</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35133431/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35133431/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mitochondria-associated endoplasmic reticulum membrane (MAM) may have a role in tubular injury in diabetic nephropathy (DN), but the precise mechanism remains unclear. Here, we demonstrate that the expression of phosphofurin acidic cluster sorting protein 2 (PACS-2), a critical regulator of MAM formation, is significantly decreased in renal tubules of patients with DN, and PACS-2 expression is positively correlated with renal function and negatively correlated with degrees of tubulointerstitial lesions. Conditional deletion of Pacs-2 in proximal tubules (PTs) aggravates albuminuria and tubular injury in a streptozotocin-induced mouse model of diabetes. Mitochondrial fragmentation, MAM disruption, and defective mitophagy accompanied by altered expression of mitochondrial dynamics and mitophagic proteins, including Drp1 and Becn1, are observed in tubules of diabetic mice; these changes are more pronounced in PT-specific Pacs-2 knockout mice. In vitro, overexpression of PACS-2 in HK-2 cells alleviates excessive mitochondrial fission induced by high glucose concentrations through blocking mitochondrial recruitment of DRP1 and subsequently restores MAM integrity and enhances mitophagy. Mechanistically, PACS-2 binds to BECN1 and mediates the relocalization of BECN1 to MAM, where it promotes the formation of mitophagosome. Together, these data highlight an important but previously unrecognized role of PACS-2 in ameliorating tubular injury in DN by facilitating MAM formation and mitophagy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OTUD7B deubiquitinates SQSTM1/p62 and promotes IRF3 degradation to regulate antiviral immunity</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35100065/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35100065/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Deubiquitination plays an important role in the regulation of the crosstalk between macroautophagy/autophagy and innate immune signaling, yet its regulatory mechanisms are not fully understood. Here we identify the deubiquitinase OTUD7B as a negative regulator of antiviral immunity by targeting IRF3 (interferon regulatory factor 3) for selective autophagic degradation. Mechanistically, OTUD7B interacts with IRF3, and activates IRF3-associated cargo receptor SQSTM1/p62 (sequestosome 1) by removing its K63-linked poly-ubiquitin chains at lysine 7 (K7) to enhance SQSTM1 oligomerization. Moreover, viral infection increased the expression of OTUD7B, which forms a negative feedback loop by promoting IRF3 degradation to balance type I interferon (IFN) signaling. Taken together, our study reveals a specific role of OTUD7B in mediating the activation of cargo receptors in a substrate-dependent manner, which could be a potential target against excessive immune responses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bacterial peptidoglycan muropeptides benefit mitochondrial homeostasis and animal physiology by acting as ATP synthase agonists</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35045336/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35045336/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The symbiotic relationship between commensal microbes and host animals predicts unidentified beneficial impacts of individual bacterial metabolites on animal physiology. Peptidoglycan fragments (muropeptides) from the bacterial cell wall are known for their roles in pathogenicity and for inducing host immune responses. However, the potential beneficial usage of muropeptides from commensal bacteria by the host needs exploration. We identified a striking role for muropeptides in supporting mitochondrial homeostasis, development, and behaviors in Caenorhabditis elegans. We determined that the beneficial molecules are disaccharide muropeptides containing a short AA chain, and they enter intestinal-cell mitochondria to repress oxidative stress. Further analyses indicate that muropeptides execute this role by binding to and promoting the activity of ATP synthase. Therefore, given the exceptional structural conservation of ATP synthase, the role of muropeptides as a rare agonist of the ATP synthase presents a major conceptual modification regarding the impact of bacterial cell metabolites on animal physiology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mitochondria shed their outer membrane in response to infection-induced stress</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35025629/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35025629/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;INTRODUCTION&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mitochondria are dynamic organelles that coordinate many cellular functions that are essential for life, including diverse metabolic processes, cell division and differentiation, and immune signaling.
To carry out these diverse functions, mitochondria must communicate with the cytosol, a task mediated by the outer mitochondrial membrane (OMM), the gateway between mitochondria and the rest of the cell. Thus, preserving the integrity of the OMM is essential for cellular homeostasis. Although responses to stress that is artificially induced by small molecules have been described, little is known of the mechanisms by which mammalian cells respond to naturally occurring stresses of the OMM.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;RATIONALE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Several intracellular microbes come in contact with the host OMM or release proteins that target the OMM. We reasoned that microbial infection would serve as a model with which to study cellular responses to natural OMM stress. To this end, we chose the human parasite Toxoplasma gondii because it tethers host mitochondria to its parasite vacuole; in an infected cell, areas of close membrane apposition form between the host OMM and the parasite vacuole membrane. To address how Toxoplasma affected the OMM, we performed live-cell imaging of infected mammalian cells stably expressing OMM-targeted green fluorescent protein (GFP). We found that mitochondria in contact with the Toxoplasma vacuole released large structures that were positive for OMM, which we termed “SPOTs.” Analysis of SPOTs in fixed and live cells revealed that SPOTs did not contain proteins of the mitochondrial matrix and inner mitochondrial membrane (IMM).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;RESULTS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having identified Toxoplasma infection as a natural stress that induced OMM remodeling and the shedding of SPOTs, we next dissected how these structures are formed. We found that the secreted effector protein TgMAF1 (Toxoplasma gondii mitochondrial association factor 1), which tethers the host OMM to the parasite vacuole membrane, was required for SPOT formation. TgMAF1 led to a decrease in the amount of mitochondrial proteins during infection. In particular, the OMM proteins mitofusin 1 and mitofusin 2 were degraded during infection. These proteins, which mediate a nutritional defense against Toxoplasma by promoting mitochondrial uptake of fatty acids, localized to SPOTs. The ability of TgMAF1 to induce SPOTs depended on its binding to the host OMM import receptor TOM70 (translocase of the outer membrane 70), whose import function TgMAF1 impaired. TOM70 was required for optimal parasite growth and enabled an interaction between TgMAF1 and the OMM translocase SAM50 (sorting assembly machinery 50 kDa subunit), which is a key component of the OMM-IMM mitochondrial intermembrane space bridging (MIB) complex. The genetic ablation of SAM50 and the overexpression of an OMM-targeted protein induced the formation of SPOT-like structures independently of infection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CONCLUSION&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because SAM50 is the only component of mitochondrial import machinery that bridges the OMM and IMM, it is in a position to translate OMM stress into the removal of compromised OMM. TgMAF1 behaves as a mitochondrial preprotein that uses the host receptor TOM70 to interact with SAM50. This enables Toxoplasma to hijack a cellular response to OMM stress—the formation of SPOTs—and drive the constitutive shedding of the OMM. Consequently, levels of mitochondrial proteins that restrict parasite growth are depleted, and import machinery that is required for mitochondrial biogenesis is sequestered on SPOTs. In an infection-independent context, however, we propose that SPOT-like structures could mitigate OMM stress by enabling the excision of dysfunctional OMM machinery, such as import receptors or translocases during defective import. Our finding that OMM remodeling occurs during infection and infection-independent scenarios sheds light on potential cellular mechanisms that safeguard OMM function.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quantitative high-confidence human mitochondrial proteome and its dynamics in cellular context</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34800366/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34800366/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mitochondria are key organelles for cellular energetics, metabolism, signaling, and quality control and have been linked to various diseases. Different views exist on the composition of the human mitochondrial proteome. We classified &amp;gt;8,000 proteins in mitochondrial preparations of human cells and defined a mitochondrial high-confidence proteome of &amp;gt;1,100 proteins (MitoCoP). We identified interactors of translocases, respiratory chain, and ATP synthase assembly factors. The abundance of MitoCoP proteins covers six orders of magnitude and amounts to 7% of the cellular proteome with the chaperones HSP60-HSP10 being the most abundant mitochondrial proteins. MitoCoP dynamics spans three orders of magnitudes, with half-lives from hours to months, and suggests a rapid regulation of biosynthesis and assembly processes. 460 MitoCoP genes are linked to human diseases with a strong prevalence for the central nervous system and metabolism. MitoCoP will provide a high-confidence resource for placing dynamics, functions, and dysfunctions of mitochondria into the cellular context.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crosstalk between autophagy inhibitors and endosome-related secretory pathways: a challenge for autophagy-based treatment of solid cancers</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/34706732/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/34706732/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Autophagy is best known for its role in organelle and protein turnover, cell quality control, and metabolism. The autophagic machinery has, however, also adapted to enable protein trafficking and unconventional secretory pathways so that organelles (such as autophagosomes and multivesicular bodies) delivering cargo to lysosomes for degradation can change their mission from fusion with lysosomes to fusion with the plasma membrane, followed by secretion of the cargo from the cell. Some factors with key signalling functions do not enter the conventional secretory pathway but can be secreted in an autophagy-mediated manner.Positive clinical results of some autophagy inhibitors are encouraging. Nevertheless, it is becoming clear that autophagy inhibition, even within the same cancer type, can affect cancer progression differently. Even next-generation inhibitors of autophagy can have significant non-specific effects, such as impacts on endosome-related secretory pathways and secretion of extracellular vesicles (EVs). Many studies suggest that cancer cells release higher amounts of EVs compared to non-malignant cells, which makes the effect of autophagy inhibitors on EVs secretion highly important and attractive for anticancer therapy. In this review article, we discuss how different inhibitors of autophagy may influence the secretion of EVs and summarize the non-specific effects of autophagy inhibitors with a focus on endosome-related secretory pathways. Modulation of autophagy significantly impacts not only the quantity of EVs but also their content, which can have a deep impact on the resulting pro-tumourigenic or anticancer effect of autophagy inhibitors used in the antineoplastic treatment of solid cancers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The assembly, regulation and function of the mitochondrial respiratory chain</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/34621061/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/34621061/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The mitochondrial oxidative phosphorylation system is central to cellular metabolism. It comprises five enzymatic complexes and two mobile electron carriers that work in a mitochondrial respiratory chain. By coupling the oxidation of reducing equivalents coming into mitochondria to the generation and subsequent dissipation of a proton gradient across the inner mitochondrial membrane, this electron transport chain drives the production of ATP, which is then used as a primary energy carrier in virtually all cellular processes. Minimal perturbations of the respiratory chain activity are linked to diseases; therefore, it is necessary to understand how these complexes are assembled and regulated and how they function. In this Review, we outline the latest assembly models for each individual complex, and we also highlight the recent discoveries indicating that the formation of larger assemblies, known as respiratory supercomplexes, originates from the association of the intermediates of individual complexes. We then discuss how recent cryo-electron microscopy structures have been key to answering open questions on the function of the electron transport chain in mitochondrial respiration and how supercomplexes and other factors, including metabolites, can regulate the activity of the single complexes. When relevant, we discuss how these mechanisms contribute to physiology and outline their deregulation in human diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Machinery, regulation and pathophysiological implications of autophagosome maturation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/34302147/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/34302147/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Autophagy is a versatile degradation system for maintaining cellular homeostasis whereby cytosolic materials are sequestered in a double-membrane autophagosome and subsequently delivered to lysosomes, where they are broken down. In multicellular organisms, newly formed autophagosomes undergo a process called &amp;lsquo;maturation&amp;rsquo;, in which they fuse with vesicles originating from endolysosomal compartments, including early/late endosomes and lysosomes, to form amphisomes, which eventually become degradative autolysosomes. This fusion process requires the concerted actions of multiple regulators of membrane dynamics, including SNAREs, tethering proteins and RAB GTPases, and also transport of autophagosomes and late endosomes/lysosomes towards each other. Multiple mechanisms modulate autophagosome maturation, including post-translational modification of key components, spatial distribution of phosphoinositide lipid species on membranes, RAB protein dynamics, and biogenesis and function of lysosomes. Nutrient status and various stresses integrate into the autophagosome maturation machinery to coordinate the progression of autophagic flux. Impaired autophagosome maturation is linked to the pathogenesis of various human diseases, including neurodegenerative disorders, cancer and myopathies. Furthermore, invading pathogens exploit various strategies to block autophagosome maturation, thus evading destruction and even subverting autophagic vacuoles (autophagosomes, amphisomes and autolysosomes) for survival, growth and/or release. Here, we discuss the recent progress in our understanding of the machinery and regulation of autophagosome maturation, the relevance of these mechanisms to human pathophysiology and how they are harnessed by pathogens for their benefit. We also provide perspectives on targeting autophagosome maturation therapeutically.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ALKBH7-mediated demethylation regulates mitochondrial polycistronic RNA processing</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34253897/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34253897/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Members of the mammalian AlkB family are known to mediate nucleic acid demethylation. ALKBH7, a mammalian AlkB homologue, localizes in mitochondria and affects metabolism, but its function and mechanism of action are unknown. Here we report an approach to site-specifically detect N&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;-methyladenosine (m&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;A), N&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;-methylcytidine (m&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;C), N&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;-methylguanosine (m&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;G) and N&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;,N&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;-dimethylguanosine (m&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;G) modifications simultaneously within all cellular RNAs, and discovered that human ALKBH7 demethylates m&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;G and m&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;A within mitochondrial Ile and Leu1 pre-tRNA regions, respectively, in nascent polycistronic mitochondrial RNA. We further show that ALKBH7 regulates the processing and structural dynamics of polycistronic mitochondrial RNAs. Depletion of ALKBH7 leads to increased polycistronic mitochondrial RNA processing, reduced steady-state mitochondria-encoded tRNA levels and protein translation, and notably decreased mitochondrial activity. Thus, we identify ALKBH7 as an RNA demethylase that controls nascent mitochondrial RNA processing and mitochondrial activity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Suppression of mitochondrial ROS by prohibitin drives glioblastoma progression and therapeutic resistance</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34140524/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34140524/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Low levels of reactive oxygen species (ROS) are crucial for maintaining cancer stem cells (CSCs) and their ability to resist therapy, but the ROS regulatory mechanisms in CSCs remains to be explored. Here, we discover that prohibitin (PHB) specifically regulates mitochondrial ROS production in glioma stem-like cells (GSCs) and facilitates GSC radiotherapeutic resistance. We find that PHB is upregulated in GSCs and is associated with malignant gliomas progression and poor prognosis. PHB binds to peroxiredoxin3 (PRDX3), a mitochondrion-specific peroxidase, and stabilizes PRDX3 protein through the ubiquitin-proteasome pathway. Knockout of PHB dramatically elevates ROS levels, thereby inhibiting GSC self-renewal. Importantly, deletion or pharmacological inhibition of PHB potently slows tumor growth and sensitizes tumors to radiotherapy, thus providing significant survival benefits in GSC-derived orthotopic tumors and glioblastoma patient-derived xenografts. These results reveal a selective role of PHB in mitochondrial ROS regulation in GSCs and suggest that targeting PHB improves radiotherapeutic efficacy in glioblastoma.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mitocytosis, a migrasome-mediated mitochondrial quality-control process</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34048705/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34048705/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mild mitochondrial stress triggers disposal of damaged mitochondria by migrasomes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In this process (mitocytosis), motor proteins selectively bind damaged mitochondria&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Damaged mitochondria become localized at the cell periphery to facilitate mitocytosis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mitocytosis maintains mitochondrial quality and viability in neutrophils &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Damaged mitochondria need to be cleared to maintain the quality of the mitochondrial pool. Here, we report mitocytosis, a migrasome-mediated mitochondrial quality-control process. We found that, upon exposure to mild mitochondrial stresses, damaged mitochondria are transported into migrasomes and subsequently disposed of from migrating cells. Mechanistically, mitocytosis requires positioning of damaged mitochondria at the cell periphery, which occurs because damaged mitochondria avoid binding to inward motor proteins. Functionally, mitocytosis plays an important role in maintaining mitochondrial quality. Enhanced mitocytosis protects cells from mitochondrial stressor-induced loss of mitochondrial membrane potential (MMP) and mitochondrial respiration; conversely, blocking mitocytosis causes loss of MMP and mitochondrial respiration under normal conditions. Physiologically, we demonstrate that mitocytosis is required for maintaining MMP and viability in neutrophils &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt;. We propose that mitocytosis is an important mitochondrial quality-control process in migrating cells, which couples mitochondrial homeostasis with cell migration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Structural insight into the molecular mechanism of p53-mediated mitochondrial apoptosis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33863900/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33863900/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tumor suppressor p53 is mutated in approximately half of all human cancers. p53 can induce apoptosis through mitochondrial membrane permeabilization by interacting with and antagonizing the anti-apoptotic proteins BCL-xL and BCL-2. However, the mechanisms by which p53 induces mitochondrial apoptosis remain elusive. Here, we report a 2.5 Å crystal structure of human p53/BCL-xL complex. In this structure, two p53 molecules interact as a homodimer, and bind one BCL-xL molecule to form a ternary complex with a 2:1 stoichiometry. Mutations at the p53 dimer interface or p53/BCL-xL interface disrupt p53/BCL-xL interaction and p53-mediated apoptosis. Overall, our current findings of the bona fide structure of p53/BCL-xL complex reveal the molecular basis of the interaction between p53 and BCL-xL, and provide insight into p53-mediated mitochondrial apoptosis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apaf-1 Pyroptosome Senses Mitochondrial Permeability Transition</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33308446/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33308446/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Caspase-4 is an intracellular sensor for cytosolic bacterial lipopolysaccharide (LPS) and underlies infection-elicited pyroptosis. It is unclear whether and how caspase-4 detects host-derived factors to trigger pyroptosis. Here we show that mitochondrial permeability transition (MPT) activates caspase-4 by promoting the assembly of a protein complex, which we term the Apaf-1 pyroptosome, for the execution of facilitated pyroptosis. MPT, when induced by bile acids, calcium overload, or an adenine nucleotide translocator 1 (ANT1) activator, triggers assembly of the pyroptosome comprised of Apaf-1 and caspase-4 with a stoichiometry ratio of 7:2. Unlike the direct cleavage of gasdermin D (GSDMD) by caspase-4 upon LPS ligation, caspase-4 activated in the Apaf-1 pyroptosome proceeds to cleave caspase-3 and thereby GSDME to induce pyroptosis. Caspase-4-initiated and GSDME-executed pyroptosis underlies cholestatic liver failure. These findings identify Apaf-1 pyroptosome as a pivotal machinery for cells sensing MPT signals and may shed light on understanding how cells execute intrinsic pyroptosis under sterile conditions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mitochondrial Fusion: The Machineries In and Out</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/33092941/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/33092941/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Crystal structures of truncated mitofusin (MFN)1 and MFN2, the dynamin-like fusogens of the outer mitochondrial membrane, reveal their structural kinship to bacterial dynamin-like protein (BDLP). Human MFN1 and MFN2 bear subtle differences that govern the distinct biochemical properties.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GTP-dependent dimerization and conformational changes are key features of MFNs in driving outer membrane fusion.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Short optic atrophy 1/short mitochondria genome maintenance 1 (s-OPA1/s-Mgm1) resembles fission dynamins in 3D architecture, highlighting a mechanism of inner mitochondrial membrane (IMM) merging distinct from that of other known types of homotypic fusion.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;OPA1/Mgm1 uses multiple intermolecular assemblies to achieve either IMM fusion or cristae shaping.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Structures of the mitochondrial fusion machinery provide important rules for comparing fusion DLPs with fission DLPs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mitochondria are highly dynamic organelles that constantly undergo fission and fusion. Disruption of mitochondrial dynamics undermines their function and causes several human diseases. The fusion of the outer (OMM) and inner mitochondrial membranes (IMM) is mediated by two classes of dynamin-like protein (DLP): mitofusin (MFN)/fuzzy onions 1 (Fzo1) and optic atrophy 1/mitochondria genome maintenance 1 (OPA1/Mgm1). Given the lack of structural information on these fusogens, the molecular mechanisms underlying mitochondrial fusion remain unclear, even after 20 years. Here, we review recent advances in structural studies of the mitochondrial fusion machinery, discuss their implication for DLPs, and summarize the pathogenic mechanisms of disease-causing mutations in mitochondrial fusion DLPs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Autophagy regulates fatty acid availability for oxidative phosphorylation through mitochondria-endoplasmic reticulum contact sites</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32792483/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32792483/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Autophagy has been associated with oncogenesis with one of its emerging key functions being its contribution to the metabolism of tumors. Therefore, deciphering the mechanisms of how autophagy supports tumor cell metabolism is essential. Here, we demonstrate that the inhibition of autophagy induces an accumulation of lipid droplets (LD) due to a decrease in fatty acid β-oxidation, that leads to a reduction of oxidative phosphorylation (OxPHOS) in acute myeloid leukemia (AML), but not in normal cells. Thus, the autophagic process participates in lipid catabolism that supports OxPHOS in AML cells. Interestingly, the inhibition of OxPHOS leads to LD accumulation with the concomitant inhibition of autophagy. Mechanistically, we show that the disruption of mitochondria-endoplasmic reticulum (ER) contact sites (MERCs) phenocopies OxPHOS inhibition. Altogether, our data establish that mitochondria, through the regulation of MERCs, controls autophagy that, in turn finely tunes lipid degradation to fuel OxPHOS supporting proliferation and growth in leukemia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IL-1 induces mitochondrial translocation of IRAK2 to suppress oxidative metabolism in adipocytes</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32778760/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32778760/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chronic inflammation is a common feature of obesity, with elevated cytokines such as interleukin-1 (IL-1) in the circulation and tissues. Here, we report an unconventional IL-1R–MyD88–IRAK2–PHB/OPA1 signaling axis that reprograms mitochondrial metabolism in adipocytes to exacerbate obesity. IL-1 induced recruitment of IRAK2 Myddosome to mitochondria outer membranes via recognition by TOM20, followed by TIMM50-guided translocation of IRAK2 into mitochondria inner membranes, to suppress oxidative phosphorylation and fatty acid oxidation, thereby attenuating energy expenditure. Adipocyte-specific MyD88 or IRAK2 deficiency reduced high-fat-diet-induced weight gain, increased energy expenditure and ameliorated insulin resistance, associated with a smaller adipocyte size and increased cristae formation. IRAK2 kinase inactivation also reduced high-fat diet-induced metabolic diseases. Mechanistically, IRAK2 suppressed respiratory super-complex formation via interaction with PHB1 and OPA1 upon stimulation of IL-1. Taken together, our results suggest that the IRAK2 Myddosome functions as a critical link between inflammation and metabolism, representing a novel therapeutic target for patients with obesity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nuclear receptor PXR targets AKR1B7 to protect mitochondrial metabolism and renal function in AKI</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32404507/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32404507/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acute kidney injury (AKI) is a worldwide public health problem with no specific and satisfactory therapies in clinic. The nuclear pregnane X receptor (PXR) is involved in the progression of multiple diseases, including metabolic diseases, atherosclerosis, hypertension, liver injury, etc. However, its role in kidney injury remains to be understood. In this study, we have investigated the role of PXR in AKI and underlying mechanism(s) involved in its function. PXR was robustly down-regulated and negatively correlated with renal dysfunction in human and animal kidneys with AKI. Silencing PXR in rats enhanced cisplatin-induced AKI and induced severe mitochondrial abnormalities, whereas activating PXR protected against AKI. Using luciferase reporter assays, genomic manipulation, and proteomics data analysis on the kidneys of PXR&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt; rats, we determined that PXR targeted Aldo-keto reductase family 1, member B7 (AKR1B7) to improve mitochondrial function, thereby ameliorating AKI. We confirmed the protective role of PXR against kidney injury using genomic and pharmacologic approaches in an ischemia/reperfusion model of AKI. These findings demonstrate that disabling the PXR/AKR1B7/mitochondrial metabolism axis is an important factor that can contribute to AKI, whereas reestablishing this axis can be useful for treating AKI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A pathway coordinated by DELE1 relays mitochondrial stress to the cytosol</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32132706/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32132706/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mitochondrial fidelity is tightly linked to overall cellular homeostasis and is compromised in ageing and various pathologies. Mitochondrial malfunction needs to be relayed to the cytosol, where an integrated stress response is triggered by the phosphorylation of eukaryotic translation initiation factor 2α (eIF2α) in mammalian cells. eIF2α phosphorylation is mediated by the four eIF2α kinases GCN2, HRI, PERK and PKR, which are activated by diverse types of cellular stress. However, the machinery that communicates mitochondrial perturbation to the cytosol to trigger the integrated stress response remains unknown. Here we combine genome engineering and haploid genetics to unbiasedly identify genes that affect the induction of C/EBP homologous protein (CHOP), a key factor in the integrated stress response. We show that the mitochondrial protease OMA1 and the poorly characterized protein DELE1, together with HRI, constitute the missing pathway that is triggered by mitochondrial stress. Mechanistically, stress-induced activation of OMA1 causes DELE1 to be cleaved into a short form that accumulates in the cytosol, where it binds to and activates HRI via its C-terminal portion. Obstruction of this pathway can be beneficial or adverse depending on the type of mitochondrial perturbation. In addition to the core pathway components, our comparative genetic screening strategy identifies a suite of additional regulators. Together, these findings could be used to inform future strategies to modulate the cellular response to mitochondrial dysfunction in the context of human disease.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mitochondrial DNA stress triggers autophagy-dependent ferroptotic death</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32186434/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32186434/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pancreatic cancer tends to be highly resistant to current therapy and remains one of the great challenges in biomedicine with very low 5-year survival rates. Here, we report that zalcitabine, an antiviral drug for human immunodeficiency virus infection, can suppress the growth of primary and immortalized human pancreatic cancer cells through the induction of ferroptosis, an iron-dependent form of regulated cell death. Mechanically, this effect relies on zalcitabine-induced mitochondrial DNA stress, which activates the STING1/TMEM173-mediated DNA sensing pathway, leading to macroautophagy/autophagy-dependent ferroptotic cell death via lipid peroxidation, but not a type I interferon response. Consequently, the genetic and pharmacological inactivation of the autophagy-dependent ferroptosis pathway diminishes the anticancer effects of zalcitabine in cell culture and animal models. Together, these findings not only provide a new approach for pancreatic cancer therapy but also increase our understanding of the interplay between autophagy and DNA damage response in shaping cell death.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mitochondrial fragmentation limits NK cell-based tumor immunosurveillance</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/31636463/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/31636463/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Natural killer (NK) cells have crucial roles in tumor surveillance. We found that tumor-infiltrating NK cells in human liver cancers had small, fragmented mitochondria in their cytoplasm, whereas liver NK cells outside tumors, as well as peripheral NK cells, had normal large, tubular mitochondria. This fragmentation was correlated with reduced cytotoxicity and NK cell loss, resulting in tumor evasion of NK cell-mediated surveillance, which predicted poor survival in patients with liver cancer. The hypoxic tumor microenvironment drove the sustained activation of mechanistic target of rapamycin-GTPase dynamin-related protein 1 (mTOR-Drp1) in NK cells, resulting in excessive mitochondrial fission into fragments. Inhibition of mitochondrial fragmentation improved mitochondrial metabolism, survival and the antitumor capacity of NK cells. These data reveal a mechanism of immune escape that might be targetable and could invigorate NK cell-based cancer treatments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>S100a8/a9 Signaling Causes Mitochondrial Dysfunction and Cardiomyocyte Death in Response to Ischemic/Reperfusion Injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/31220942/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/31220942/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Myocardial ischemia-reperfusion (MI/R) injury is a significant clinical problem without effective therapy. Unbiased omics approaches may reveal key MI/R mediators to initiate MI/R injury.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; We used a dynamic transcriptome analysis of mouse heart exposed to various MI/R periods to identify S100a8/a9 as an early mediator. Using loss/gain-of-function approaches to understand the role of S100a8/a9 in MI/R injury, we explored the mechanisms through transcriptome and functional experiment. Dynamic serum S100a8/a9 levels were measured in patients with acute myocardial infarction before and after percutaneous coronary intervention. Patients were prospectively followed for the occurrence of major adverse cardiovascular events.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; S100a8/a9 was identified as the most significantly upregulated gene during the early reperfusion stage. Knockout of S100a9 markedly decreased cardiomyocyte death and improved heart function, whereas hematopoietic overexpression of S100a9 exacerbated MI/R injury. Transcriptome/functional studies revealed that S100a8/a9 caused mitochondrial respiratory dysfunction in cardiomyocytes. Mechanistically, S100a8/a9 downregulated NDUF gene expression with subsequent mitochondrial complex I inhibition via Toll-like receptor 4/Erk-mediated Pparg coactivator 1 alpha/nuclear respiratory factor 1 signaling suppression. Administration of S100a9 neutralizing antibody significantly reduced MI/R injury and improved cardiac function. Finally, we demonstrated that serum S100a8/a9 levels were significantly increased 1 day after percutaneous coronary intervention in patients with acute myocardial infarction, and elevated S100a8/a9 levels were associated with the incidence of major adverse cardiovascular events.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; Our study identified S100a8/a9 as a master regulator causing cardiomyocyte death in the early stage of MI/R injury via the suppression of mitochondrial function. Targeting S100a8/a9-intiated signaling may represent a novel therapeutic intervention against MI/R injury.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mitochondrial medicine in the omics era</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/29903433/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/29903433/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mitochondria are dynamic bioenergetic organelles whose maintenance requires around 1500 proteins from two genomes. Mutations in either the mitochondrial or nuclear genome can disrupt a plethora of cellular metabolic and homoeostatic functions. Mitochondrial diseases represent one of the most common and severe groups of inherited genetic disorders, characterised by clinical, biochemical, and genetic heterogeneity, diagnostic odysseys, and absence of disease-modifying curative therapies. This Review aims to discuss recent advances in mitochondrial biology and medicine arising from widespread use of high-throughput omics technologies, and also includes a broad discussion of emerging therapies for mitochondrial disease. New insights into both bioenergetic and biosynthetic mitochondrial functionalities have expedited the genetic diagnosis of primary mitochondrial disorders, and identified novel mitochondrial pathomechanisms and new targets for therapeutic intervention. As we enter this new era of mitochondrial medicine, underpinned by global unbiased approaches and multifaceted investigation of mitochondrial function, omics technologies will continue to shed light on unresolved mitochondrial questions, paving the way for improved outcomes for patients with mitochondrial diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
