<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ubiquitination | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/ubiquitination/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/ubiquitination/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Ubiquitination</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Ubiquitination</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/ubiquitination/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Genetic code expansion reveals aminoacylated lysine ubiquitination mediated by UBE2W</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36593310/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36593310/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Protein post-translational modification (PTM) regulates nearly every aspect of cellular processes in eukaryotes. However, the identification of new protein PTMs is very challenging. Here, using genetically encoded unnatural amino acids as chemical probes, we report the identification and validation of a previously unreported form of protein PTM, aminoacylated lysine ubiquitination, in which the modification occurs on the α-amine group of aminoacylated lysine. We identify more than 2,000 ubiquitination sites on all 20 aminoacylated lysines in two human cell lines. The modifications can mediate rapid protein degradation, complementing the canonical lysine ubiquitination-mediated proteome degradation. Furthermore, we demonstrate that the ubiquitin-conjugating enzyme UBE2W acts as a writer of aminoacylated lysine ubiquitination and facilitates the ubiquitination event on proteins. More broadly, the discovery and validation of aminoacylated lysine ubiquitination paves the way for the identification and verification of new protein PTMs with the genetic code expansion strategy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UBE2J1 inhibits colorectal cancer progression by promoting ubiquitination and degradation of RPS3</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36567344/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36567344/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ubiquitin-conjugating enzyme E2 J1 (UBE2J1) has been proven to participate in the ubiquitination of multiple substrate proteins. However, the underlying mechanisms of UBE2J1 as a ubiquitin-conjugating enzyme participating in cancer development and progression remain largely unknown. Here, we identified that UBE2J1 is downregulated in colorectal cancer (CRC) tissues and cell lines which are mediated by DNA hypermethylation of its promoter, and decreased UBE2J1 is associated with poor prognosis. Functionally, UBE2J1 serving as a suppressor gene inhibits the proliferation and metastasis of CRC cells. Mechanistically, UBE2J1-TRIM25, forming an E2-E3 complex, physically interacts with and targets RPS3 for ubiquitination and degradation at the K214 residue. The downregulated RPS3 caused by UBE2J1 overexpression restrains NF-κB translocation into the nucleus and therefore inactivates the NF-κB signaling pathway. Our study revealed a novel role of UBE2J1-mediated RPS3 poly-ubiquitination and degradation in disrupting the NF-κB signaling pathway, which may serve as a novel and promising biomarker and therapeutic target for CRC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MYC multimers shield stalled replication forks from RNA polymerase</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36424410/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36424410/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oncoproteins of the MYC family drive the development of numerous human tumours. In unperturbed cells, MYC proteins bind to nearly all active promoters and control transcription by RNA polymerase II. MYC proteins can also coordinate transcription with DNA replication and promote the repair of transcription-associated DNA damage, but how they exert these mechanistically diverse functions is unknown. Here we show that MYC dissociates from many of its binding sites in active promoters and forms multimeric, often sphere-like structures in response to perturbation of transcription elongation, mRNA splicing or inhibition of the proteasome. Multimerization is accompanied by a global change in the MYC interactome towards proteins involved in transcription termination and RNA processing. MYC multimers accumulate on chromatin immediately adjacent to stalled replication forks and surround FANCD2, ATR and BRCA1 proteins, which are located at stalled forks. MYC multimerization is triggered in a HUWE1 and ubiquitylation-dependent manner. At active promoters, MYC multimers block antisense transcription and stabilize FANCD2 association with chromatin. This limits DNA double strand break formation during S-phase, suggesting that the multimerization of MYC enables tumour cells to proliferate under stressful conditions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>USP15 promotes cGAS activation through deubiquitylation and liquid condensation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36243958/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36243958/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Double-stranded DNA (dsDNA) is recognized as a danger signal by cyclic GMP-AMP synthase (cGAS), which triggers innate immune responses. cGAS activity must be properly regulated to maintain immune homeostasis. However, the mechanism by which cGAS activation is controlled remains to be better understood. In this study, we identified USP15 as a cGAS-interacting partner. USP15 promoted DNA-induced cGAS activation and downstream innate immune responses through a positive feedback mechanism. Specifically, USP15 deubiquitylated cGAS and promoted its activation. In the absence of DNA, USP15 drove cGAS dimerization and liquid condensation through the USP15 intrinsic disordered region (IDR), which prepared cGAS for a rapid response to DNA. Upon DNA stimulation, USP15 was induced to express and boost cGAS activation, functioning as an efficient amplifier in innate immune signal transduction. In summary, the positive role played by USP15-mediated cGAS activation may be a novel regulatory mechanism in the fine-tuning of innate immunity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NLRC5 restricts dengue virus infection by promoting the autophagic degradation of viral NS3 through E3 ligase CUL2 (cullin 2)</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36126167/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36126167/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NLRC5 has been reported to be involved in antiviral immunity; however, the underlying mechanism remains poorly understood. Here, we investigated the functional role of NLRC5 in the infection of a flavivirus, dengue virus (DENV). We found that the expression of NLRC5 was strongly induced by virus infection and IFNB or IFNG stimulation in different cell lines. Overexpression of NLRC5 remarkably suppressed DENV infection, whereas knockout of NLRC5 led to a significant increase in DENV infection. Mechanistic study revealed that NLRC5 interacted with the viral nonstructural protein 3 (NS3) protease domain and mediated degradation of NS3 through a ubiquitin-dependent selective macroautophagy/autophagy pathway. We demonstrated that NLRC5 recruited the E3 ubiquitin ligase CUL2 (cullin 2) to catalyze K48-linked poly-ubiquitination of the NS3 protease domain, which subsequently served as a recognition signal for cargo receptor TOLLIP-mediated selective autophagic degradation. Together, we have demonstrated that NLRC5 exerted an antiviral effect by mediating the degradation of a multifunctional protein of DENV, providing a novel antiviral signal axis of NLRC5-CUL2-NS3-TOLLIP. This study expands our understanding of the regulatory network of NLRC5 in the host defense against virus infection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PSMD12-Mediated M1 Ubiquitination of Influenza A Virus at K102 Regulates Viral Replication</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35861516/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35861516/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The M1 of influenza A virus (IAV) is important for the virus life cycle, especially for the assembly and budding of viruses, which is a multistep process that requires host factors. Identifying novel host proteins that interact with M1 and understanding their functions in IAV replication are of great interest in antiviral drug development. In this study, we identified 19 host proteins in DF1 cells suspected to interact with the M1 protein of an H5N6 virus through immunoprecipitation (IP)/mass spectrometry. Among them, PSMD12, a 26S proteasome regulatory subunit, was shown to interact with influenza M1, acting as a positive host factor in IAV replication in avian and human cells. The data showed that PSMD12 promoted K63-linked ubiquitination of M1 at the K102 site. H5N6 and PR8 with an M1-K102 site mutant displayed a significantly weaker replication ability than the wild-type viruses. Mechanistically, PSMD12 promoted M1-M2 virus-like particle (VLP) release, and an M1-K102 mutation disrupted the formation of supernatant M1-M2 VLPs. An H5N6 M1-K102 site mutation or knockdown PSMD12 disrupted the budding release of the virus in chicken embryo fibroblast (CEF) cells, which was confirmed by transmission electron microscopy. Further study confirmed that M1-K102 site mutation significantly affected the virulence of H5N6 and PR8 viruses in mice. In conclusion, we report the novel host factor PSMD12 which affects the replication of influenza virus by mediating K63-linked ubiquitination of M1 at K102. These findings provide novel insight into the interactions between IAV and host cells, while suggesting an important target for anti-influenza virus drug research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Importance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;M1 is proposed to play multiple biologically important roles in the life cycle of IAV, which relies largely on host factors. This study is the first one to identify that PSMD12 interacts with M1, mediates K63-linked ubiquitination of M1 at the K102 site, and thus positively regulates influenza virus proliferation. PSMD12 promoted M1-M2 VLP egress, and an M1-K102 mutation affected the M1-M2 VLP formation. Furthermore, we demonstrate the importance of this site to the morphology and budding of influenza viruses by obtaining mutant viruses, and the M1 ubiquitination regulator PSMD12 has a similar function to the M1 K102 mutation in regulating virus release and virus morphology. Additionally, we confirm the reduced virulence of H5N6 and PR8 (H1N1) viruses carrying the M1-K102 site mutation in mice. These findings provide novel insights into IAV interactions with host cells and suggest a valid and highly conserved candidate target for antiviral drug development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pellino2 accelerate inflammation and pyroptosis via the ubiquitination and activation of NLRP3 inflammation in model of pediatric pneumonia</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35809381/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35809381/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pellino2 accelerated lung injury in mice of pediatric pneumonia.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pellino2 accelerate inflammation and pyroptosis in model of pediatric pneumonia by NLRP3.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pellino2 may serve as a potential approach for the treatment of pediatric pneumonia and other inflammatory diseases.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Mycoplasma pneumoniae pneumonia (MPP) is a common and frequently-occurring disease in pediatrics. This study aims to via unveiling the novel effects and mechanisms of Pellino2 in model of pediatric pneumonia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Materials and methods:&lt;/em&gt; Male infancy C57BL/6 mice were injected with 2 mg/kg of LPS (Sigma-Aldrich Merck KGaA). THP-1 cells were induced with LPS and ATP.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; The expression of Pellino2 mRNA and protein in patients with pediatric pneumonia or mice with pediatric pneumonia were reduced. Pellino2 accelerated lung injury and expanded inflammation and pyroptosis in lung tissue of pediatric pneumonia in vivo and vitro model. Furthermore, the inhibition of Pellino2 reduced lung injury and weakened inflammation and pyroptosis in lung tissue of pediatric pneumonia in vivo and vitro model. Pellino2 protein catenated NLRP3 protein, and Pellino2 promoted ubiquitination and activation of NLRP3 inflammation in model of pediatric pneumonia. Pellino2 accelerate inflammation and pyroptosis in model of pediatric pneumonia by NLRP3.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; These results suggest that Pellino2 accelerate inflammation and pyroptosis via the induction of ubiquitination and activation of NLRP3 inflammation in model of pediatric pneumonia, Pellino2 may serve as a potential approach for the treatment of pediatric pneumonia and other inflammatory diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>P4HB UFMylation regulates mitochondrial function and oxidative stress</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35753586/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35753586/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UFMylation is a ubiquitin-like modification which attaches the ubiquitin-fold modifier 1 to target proteins. To date, only a few UFMylation targets have been identified. In the current study, we demonstrated that P4HB is a new target protein for UFMylation and it can be UFMylated at three lysine residues in the form of mono-UFMylation. P4HB has oxidoreductase, chaperone and isomerase effects. It presents in the endoplasmic reticulum, mitochondria and cytosol. Next, we generated a stable HepG2 cell line, the hepatocellular cells, with defective P4HB UFMylation. Our data show that P4HB UFMylation defect promotes P4HB protein degradation via the ubiquitin-proteasome pathway. Defective P4HB UFMylation causes mitochondrial function damage, oxidative stress, and endoplasmic reticulum stress in HepG2 cells. These effects are more obvious when treating HepG2 cells with palmitic acid, which is frequently used as one of the cell models of non-alcoholic fatty liver disease (NAFLD). Our results identify UFMylation as a key post-translational modification for the maintenance of P4HB stability and biological functions in HepG2 cells, and point to P4HB UFMylation as a potential direction in the study of NAFLD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LINC01194 recruits NUMA1 to promote ubiquitination of RYR2 to enhance malignant progression in triple-negative breast cancer</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35750275/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35750275/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;LINC01194 was highly expressed in TNBC.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;LINC01194 recruited NUMA1 to stabilize UBE2C mRNA, thereby promoting RYR2 ubiquitination and degradation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;LINC01194/NUMA1/UBE2C/RYR2/Wnt/β-catenin signaling pathway might provide an effective therapeutic strategy for TNBC.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Long intergenic nonprotein coding RNA 1194 (LINC01194) has been reported as an oncogene in several cancer types, but its expression and potential role in triple-negative breast cancer (TNBC) are still unclear. We found that LINC01194 was significantly highly expressed in TNBC based on The Cancer Genome Atlas (TCGA) database. Data from in vitro experiments and in vivo assays demonstrated that LINC01194 promoted TNBC progression. Through bioinformatics prediction, mass spectrometry, and mechanical experiments, we found that LINC01194 could recruit nuclear mitotic apparatus protein 1 (NUMA1) to bind to the untranslated region (3&amp;rsquo;UTR) of ubiquitin-conjugating enzyme E2 C (UBE2C) 3&amp;rsquo; and stabilize UBE2C mRNA. Moreover, we found that UBE2C acted as an ubiquitin ligase to promote the ubiquitination and degradation of ryanodine receptor type 2 (RYR2) that inhibited the progression of TNBC by inhibiting the Wnt/β-catenin signaling pathway. In summary, LINC01194 activate the Wnt/β-catenin signaling pathway and accelerates the malignant progression of TNBC by recruiting NUMA1 to stabilize UBE2C mRNA and thus promotes RYR2 ubiquitination and degradation. These findings might provide a more effective therapeutic strategy for TNBC patients.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tankyrases inhibit innate antiviral response by PARylating VISA/MAVS and priming it for RNF146-mediated ubiquitination and degradation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35733260/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35733260/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During viral infection, sensing of viral RNA by retinoic acid-inducible gene-I-like receptors (RLRs) initiates an antiviral innate immune response, which is mediated by the mitochondrial adaptor protein VISA (virus-induced signal adaptor; also known as mitochondrial antiviral signaling protein [MAVS]). VISA is regulated by various posttranslational modifications (PTMs), such as polyubiquitination, phosphorylation, O-linked β-d-N-acetylglucosaminylation (O-GlcNAcylation), and monomethylation. However, whether other forms of PTMs regulate VISA-mediated innate immune signaling remains elusive. Here, we report that Poly(ADP-ribosyl)ation (PARylation) is a PTM of VISA, which attenuates innate immune response to RNA viruses. Using a biochemical purification approach, we identified tankyrase 1 (TNKS1) as a VISA-associated protein. Viral infection led to the induction of TNKS1 and its homolog TNKS2, which translocated from cytosol to mitochondria and interacted with VISA. TNKS1 and TNKS2 catalyze the PARylation of VISA at Glu137 residue, thereby priming it for K48-linked polyubiquitination by the E3 ligase Ring figure protein 146 (RNF146) and subsequent degradation. Consistently, TNKS1, TNKS2, or RNF146 deficiency increased the RNA virus-triggered induction of downstream effector genes and impaired the replication of the virus. Moreover, TNKS1- or TNKS2-deficient mice produced higher levels of type I interferons (IFNs) and proinflammatory cytokines after virus infection and markedly reduced virus loads in the brains and lungs. Together, our findings uncover an essential role of PARylation of VISA in virus-triggered innate immune signaling, which represents a mechanism to avoid excessive harmful immune response.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LncNSPL facilitates influenza A viral immune escape by restricting TRIM25-mediated K63-linked RIG-I ubiquitination</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35800772/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35800772/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;NS1 protein of Influenza A virus (IAV) promotes lncNSPL expression&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deficiency of lncNSPL specifically enhances retinoic acid-inducible gene I (RIG-I) initiated IFN production&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;lncNSPL competes with tripartite interaction motif 25 (TRIM25) for binding RIG-I and inhibits its K63 ubiquitination&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;lncNSPL inhibits innate antiviral immune responses and enhances viral replication&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Long noncoding RNAs (lncRNAs) participate in host antiviral responses; however, how viruses exploit host lncRNAs for immune evasion remains largely unexplored. Functional screening of differentially expressed lncRNA profile in patients infected with influenza A virus (IAV) revealed that lncNSPL (Gene Symbol: LOC105370355) was highly expressed in monocytes. Deregulated lncNSPL expression in infected monocytes significantly increased type I interferon (IFN-I) production and inhibited IAV replication. Moreover, lncNSPL overexpression in mice increased the susceptibility to IAV infection and impaired IFN-I production. LncNSPL directly bound to retinoic acid-inducible gene I (RIG-I) and blocked the interaction between RIG-I and E3 ligase tripartite interaction motif 25 (TRIM25), reducing TRIM25-mediated lysine 63 (K63)-linked RIG-I ubiquitination and limiting the downstream production of antiviral mediators during the late stage of IAV infection. Our findings provide mechanistic insights into the means by which lncNSPL promotes IAV replication and immune escape via restricting the TRIM25-mediated RIG-I K63-linked ubiquitination. Thus, lncNSPL may represent a promising pharmaceutical target for anti-IAV therapy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MG53 Inhibits Necroptosis Through Ubiquitination-Dependent RIPK1 Degradation for Cardiac Protection Following Ischemia/Reperfusion Injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35711363/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35711363/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rationale:&lt;/em&gt; While reactive oxygen species (ROS) has been recognized as one of the main causes of cardiac injury following myocardial infarction, the clinical application of antioxidants has shown limited effects on protecting hearts against ischemia-reperfusion (I/R) injury. Thus, the precise role of ROS following cardiac injury remains to be fully elucidated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Objective:&lt;/em&gt; We investigated the role of mitsugumin 53 (MG53) in regulating necroptosis following I/R injury to the hearts and the involvement of ROS in MG53-mediated cardioprotection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods and results:&lt;/em&gt; Antioxidants were used to test the role of ROS in MG53-mediated cardioprotection in the mouse model of I/R injury and induced human pluripotent stem cells (hiPSCs)-derived cardiomyocytes subjected to hypoxia or re-oxygenation (H/R) injury. Western blotting and co-immunoprecipitation were used to identify potential cell death pathways that MG53 was involved in. CRISPR/Cas 9-mediated genome editing and mutagenesis assays were performed to further identify specific interaction amino acids between MG53 and its ubiquitin E3 ligase substrate. We found that MG53 could protect myocardial injury via inhibiting the necroptosis pathway. Upon injury, the generation of ROS in the infarct zone of the hearts promoted interaction between MG53 and receptor-interacting protein kinase 1 (RIPK1). As an E3 ubiquitin ligase, MG53 added multiple ubiquitin chains to RIPK1 at the sites of K316, K604, and K627 for proteasome-mediated RIPK1 degradation and inhibited necroptosis. The application of N-acetyl cysteine (NAC) disrupted the interaction between MG53 and RIPK1 and abolished MG53-mediated cardioprotective effects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; Taken together, this study provided a molecular mechanism of a potential beneficial role of ROS following acute myocardial infarction. Thus, fine-tuning ROS levels might be critical for cardioprotection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MARCH8 attenuates cGAS-mediated innate immune responses through ubiquitylation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35503863/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35503863/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cyclic GMP-AMP synthase (cGAS) binds to microbial and self-DNA in the cytosol and synthesizes cyclic GMP-AMP (cGAMP), which activates stimulator of interferon genes (STING) and downstream mediators to elicit an innate immune response. Regulation of cGAS activity is essential for immune homeostasis. Here, we identified the E3 ubiquitin ligase MARCH8 (also known as MARCHF8, c-MIR, and RNF178) as a negative regulator of cGAS-mediated signaling. The immune response to double-stranded DNA was attenuated by overexpression of MARCH8 and enhanced by knockdown or knockout of MARCH8. MARCH8 interacted with the enzymatically active core of cGAS through its conserved RING-CH domain and catalyzed the lysine-63 (K63)-linked polyubiquitylation of cGAS at Lys411. This polyubiquitylation event inhibited the DNA binding ability of cGAS, impaired cGAMP production, and attenuated the downstream innate immune response. Furthermore, March8-deficient mice were less susceptible than their wild-type counterparts to herpes simplex virus 1 (HSV-1) infection. Together, our findings reveal a mechanism underlying the functional regulation of cGAS and the fine-tuning of the innate immune response.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cul3-KLHL20 E3 ubiquitin ligase plays a key role in the arms race between HIV-1 Nef and host SERINC5 restriction</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35474067/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35474067/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;HIV-1 must counteract various host restrictions to establish productive infection. SERINC5 is a potent restriction factor that blocks HIV-1 entry from virions, but its activity is counteracted by Nef. The SERINC5 and Nef activities are both initiated from the plasma membrane, where SERINC5 is packaged into virions for viral inhibition or downregulated by Nef via lysosomal degradation. However, it is still unclear how SERINC5 is localized to and how its expression is regulated on the plasma membrane. We now report that Cullin 3-KLHL20, a &lt;em&gt;trans&lt;/em&gt;-Golgi network (TGN)-localized E3 ubiquitin ligase, polyubiquitinates SERINC5 at lysine 130 via K33/K48-linked ubiquitination. The K33-linked polyubiquitination determines SERINC5 expression on the plasma membrane, and the K48-linked polyubiquitination contributes to SERINC5 downregulation from the cell surface. Our study reveals an important role of K130 polyubiquitination and K33/K48-linked ubiquitin chains in HIV-1 infection by regulating SERINC5 post-Golgi trafficking and degradation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NRIP1 aggravates lung injury caused by Pseudomonas aeruginosa in mice by increasing PIAS1 ubiquitination</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35460552/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35460552/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently, evidence has shown that nuclear receptor interacting protein 1 (NRIP1) is involved in acute lung injury (ALI) progression, but the specific mechanism remains unclear. Pseudomonas aeruginosa (PA)-treated TC-1 cells were transfected with pcDNA-NRIP1 or si-NRIP1, and we found that overexpression of NRIP1 inhibited cell viability and promoted cell apoptosis and secretion of inflammatory factors, and transfection of si-NRIP1 reversed these effects. Furthermore, online bioinformatics analysis and co-immunoprecipitation assay results indicated that NRIP1 could bind to Ubiquitin Conjugating Enzyme E2I (UBE2I), and promoted UBE2I expression. Next, the PA-treated TC-1 cells were transfected with si-NRIP1 alone or together with pcDNA-UBE2I, and we observed that transfection with si-NRIP1 inhibited UBE2I expression, promoted cell viability, and reduced cell apoptosis and inflammatory factor secretion, which could be reversed by UBE2I overexpression. Moreover, UBE2I could bind to protein inhibitor of activated signal transducer and activators of transcription 1 (PIAS1). Overexpression of NRIP1 promoted UBE2I expression and inhibited PIAS1 expression, and NRIP1 promoted PIAS1 ubiquitination and degradation by UBE2I. The PA-treated TC-1 cells were transfected with si-UBE2I alone or together with si-PIAS1, and the results indicated that transfection of si-UBE2I had the same effect as transfection of si-NRIP1. Finally, our in vivo findings indicated that the expression of NRIP1 and UBE2I was decreased, and PIAS1 expression was increased, in the lung tissues of mice with NRIP1 knocked-down, and the inflammatory infiltration in the lung tissue was reduced. In conclusion, our study demonstrates that NRIP1 aggravates PA-induced lung injury in mice by promoting PIAS1 ubiquitination.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The inhibition of TRIM35-mediated TIGAR ubiquitination enhances mitochondrial fusion and alleviates renal ischemia-reperfusion injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35421414/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35421414/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tripartite motif 35 (TRIM35) is a member of the tripartite motif protein family and has been recognized to play a key role in immune-inflammatory diseases. However, the role of TRIM35 in renal ischemia-reperfusion injury (IRI) remains unclear. Our study proved that knockdown of TRIM35 alleviates kidney IRI by inhibiting oxidative stress and enhancing mitochondrial fusion. In addition, our experimental results found that TRIM35 interacts with TP53-induced glycolysis and apoptosis regulator (TIGAR) and promotes the polyubiquitination of TIGAR and induces its degradation in the proteasome pathway. Furthermore, TIGAR knockdown significantly inhibited mitochondrial fusion. These results indicate that TRIM35 is a potential therapeutic target for renal IRI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OTUD7B deubiquitinates SQSTM1/p62 and promotes IRF3 degradation to regulate antiviral immunity</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35100065/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35100065/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Deubiquitination plays an important role in the regulation of the crosstalk between macroautophagy/autophagy and innate immune signaling, yet its regulatory mechanisms are not fully understood. Here we identify the deubiquitinase OTUD7B as a negative regulator of antiviral immunity by targeting IRF3 (interferon regulatory factor 3) for selective autophagic degradation. Mechanistically, OTUD7B interacts with IRF3, and activates IRF3-associated cargo receptor SQSTM1/p62 (sequestosome 1) by removing its K63-linked poly-ubiquitin chains at lysine 7 (K7) to enhance SQSTM1 oligomerization. Moreover, viral infection increased the expression of OTUD7B, which forms a negative feedback loop by promoting IRF3 degradation to balance type I interferon (IFN) signaling. Taken together, our study reveals a specific role of OTUD7B in mediating the activation of cargo receptors in a substrate-dependent manner, which could be a potential target against excessive immune responses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The chemokine CCL1 triggers an AMFR-SPRY1 pathway that promotes differentiation of lung fibroblasts into myofibroblasts and drives pulmonary fibrosis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34407391/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34407391/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Erratum in:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cell.com/immunity/fulltext/S1074-7613%2821%2900394-0&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The chemokine CCL1 triggers an AMFR-SPRY1 pathway that promotes differentiation of lung fibroblasts into myofibroblasts and drives pulmonary fibrosis&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CCL1 expression positively correlates with the development of lung fibrosis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CCL1 exerts its fibrogenic activity by signaling through AMFR on fibroblasts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CCL1-AMFR interaction relieves Spry1-repressed Ras-ERK-p70S6K activity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Suppression of the CCL1-AMFR-Ras-ERK-p70S6K axis reduces lung fibrosis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recruitment of immune cells to the site of inflammation by the chemokine CCL1 is important in the pathology of inflammatory diseases. Here, we examined the role of CCL1 in pulmonary fibrosis (PF). Bronchoalveolar lavage fluid from PF mouse models contained high amounts of CCL1, as did lung biopsies from PF patients. Immunofluorescence analyses revealed that alveolar macrophages and CD4+ T cells were major producers of CCL1 and targeted deletion of Ccl1 in these cells blunted pathology. Deletion of the CCL1 receptor Ccr8 in fibroblasts limited migration, but not activation, in response to CCL1. Mass spectrometry analyses of CCL1 complexes identified AMFR as a CCL1 receptor, and deletion of Amfr impaired fibroblast activation. Mechanistically, CCL1 binding triggered ubiquitination of the ERK inhibitor Spry1 by AMFR, thus activating Ras-mediated profibrotic protein synthesis. Antibody blockade of CCL1 ameliorated PF pathology, supporting the therapeutic potential of targeting this pathway for treating fibroproliferative lung diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MARCH8 inhibits influenza A virus infection by targeting viral M2 protein for ubiquitination-dependent degradation in lysosomes</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34285233/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34285233/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The membrane-associated RING-CH (MARCH) proteins are E3 ligases that regulate the stability of various cellular membrane proteins. MARCH8 has been reported to inhibit the infection of HIV-1 and a few other viruses, thus plays an important role in host antiviral defense. However, the antiviral spectrum and the underlying mechanisms of MARCH8 are incompletely defined. Here, we demonstrate that MARCH8 profoundly inhibits influenza A virus (IAV) replication both in vitro and in mice. Mechanistically, MARCH8 suppresses IAV release through redirecting viral M2 protein from the plasma membrane to lysosomes for degradation. Specifically, MARCH8 catalyzes the K63-linked polyubiquitination of M2 at lysine residue 78 (K78). A recombinant A/Puerto Rico/8/34 virus carrying the K78R M2 protein shows greater replication and more severe pathogenicity in cells and mice. More importantly, we found that the M2 protein of the H1N1 IAV has evolved to acquire non-lysine amino acids at positions 78/79 to resist MARCH8-mediated ubiquitination and degradation. Together, our data support the important role of MARCH8 in host anti-IAV intrinsic immune defense by targeting M2, and suggest the inhibitory pressure of MARCH8 on H1N1 IAV transmission in the human population.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Regulation of Wnt/PCP signaling through p97/VCP-KBTBD7-mediated Vangl ubiquitination and endoplasmic reticulum-associated degradation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33990333/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33990333/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The four-pass transmembrane proteins Vangl1 and Vangl2 are dedicated core components of Wnt/planar cell polarity (Wnt/PCP) signaling that critically regulate polarized cell behaviors in many morphological and physiological processes. Here, we found that the abundance of Vangl proteins is tightly controlled by the ubiquitin-proteasome system through endoplasmic reticulum-associated degradation (ERAD). The key ERAD component p97/VCP directly binds to Vangl at a highly conserved VCP-interacting motif and recruits the E3 ligase KBTBD7 via its UBA-UBX adaptors to promote Vangl ubiquitination and ERAD. We found that Wnt5a/CK1 prevents Vangl ubiquitination and ERAD by inducing Vangl phosphorylation, which facilitates Vangl export from the ER to the plasma membrane. We also provide in vivo evidence that KBTBD7 regulates convergent extension during zebrafish gastrulation and functions as a tumor suppressor in breast cancer by promoting Vangl degradation. Our findings reveal a previously unknown regulatory mechanism of Wnt/PCP signaling through the p97/VCP-KBTBD7-mediated ERAD pathway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>YAP promotes the activation of NLRP3 inflammasome via blocking K27-linked polyubiquitination of NLRP3</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33976226/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33976226/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The transcription coactivator YAP plays a vital role in Hippo pathway for organ-size control and tissue homeostasis. Recent studies have demonstrated YAP is closely related to immune disorders and inflammatory diseases, but the underlying mechanisms remain less defined. Here, we find that YAP promotes the activation of NLRP3 inflammasome, an intracellular multi-protein complex that orchestrates host immune responses to infections or sterile injuries. YAP deficiency in myeloid cells significantly attenuates LPS-induced systemic inflammation and monosodium urate (MSU) crystals-induced peritonitis. Mechanistically, YAP physically interacts with NLRP3 and maintains the stability of NLRP3 through blocking the association between NLRP3 and the E3 ligase β-TrCP1, the latter increases the proteasomal degradation of NLRP3 via K27-linked ubiquitination at lys380. Together, these findings establish a role of YAP in the activation of NLRP3 inflammasome, and provide potential therapeutic target to treat the NLRP3 inflammasome-related diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>E3 ligase TRIM25 ubiquitinates RIP3 to inhibit TNF induced cell necrosis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33953350/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33953350/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Receptor interacting protein kinase 3 (RIP3 or RIPK3), the critical executor of cell programmed necrosis, plays essential roles in maintaining immune responses and appropriate tissue homeostasis. Although the E3 ligases CHIP and PELI1 are reported to promote RIP3 degradation, however, how post-translational modification regulates RIP3 activity and stability is poorly understood. Here, we identify the tripartite motif protein TRIM25 as a negative regulator of RIP3-dependent necrosis. TRIM25 directly interacts with RIP3 through its SPRY domain and mediates the K48-linked polyubiquitination of RIP3 on residue K501. The RING domain of TRIM25 facilitates the polyubiquitination chain on RIP3, thereby promoting proteasomal degradation of RIP3. Also, TRIM25 deficiency inhibited the ubiquitination of RIP3, thus promoting TNF-induced cell necrosis. Our current finding reveals the regulating mechanism of polyubiquitination on RIP3, which might be a potential therapeutic target for the intervention of RIP3-dependent necrosis-related diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Excessive deubiquitination of NLRP3-R779C variant contributes to very-early-onset inflammatory bowel disease development</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32941940/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32941940/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Very-early-onset inflammatory bowel disease (VEOIBD) is a chronic inflammatory disease of the gastrointestinal tract occurring during infancy or early childhood. NOD-like receptor family, pyrin domain containing 3 (NLRP3) inflammasome has emerged as a crucial regulator of intestinal homeostasis; however, whether NLRP3 variants may modify VEOIBD risk is unknown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Objective:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We sought to investigate whether and how a rare NLRP3 variant, found in 3 patients with gastrointestinal symptoms, contributes to VEOIBD development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whole-exome sequencing and bioinformatic analysis were performed to screen disease-associated NLRP3 variants from a cohort of children with VEOIBD. Inflammasome activation was determined in reconstituted HEK293T human embryonic kidney cells with NLRP3 inflammasome components, doxycycline-inducible NLRP3 macrophages, as well as PBMCs and biopsies from patients with NLRP3 variants. Pathogenesis of the variants was determined using a dextran sulfate sodium-induced acute colitis model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We identified a dominant gain-of-function missense variant of NLRP3, encoded by rs772009059 (R779C), in 3 patients with gastrointestinal symptoms. Functional analysis revealed that R779C increased NLRP3 inflammasome activation and pyroptosis in macrophages. This was mediated by enhanced deubiquitination of NLRP3 via binding with deubiquitinases BRCC3 and JOSD2, which are highly expressed in myeloid cells. In a dextran sulfate sodium-induced acute colitis model, NLRP3-R779C in hematopoietic cells resulted in more severe colitis, which can be ameliorated via knockdown of BRCC3 or JOSD2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BRCC3 and JOSD2 mediate NLRP3-R779C deubiquitination, which promotes NLRP3 inflammasome activation and the risk of developing VEOIBD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UFMylation maintains tumour suppressor p53 stability by antagonizing its ubiquitination</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32807901/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32807901/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;p53 is the most intensively studied tumour suppressor. The regulation of p53 homeostasis is essential for its tumour-suppressive function. Although p53 is regulated by an array of post-translational modifications, both during normal homeostasis and in stress-induced responses, how p53 maintains its homeostasis remains unclear. UFMylation is a recently identified ubiquitin-like modification with essential biological functions. Deficiency in this modification leads to embryonic lethality in mice and disease in humans. Here, we report that p53 can be covalently modified by UFM1 and that this modification stabilizes p53 by antagonizing its ubiquitination and proteasome degradation. Mechanistically, UFL1, the UFM1 ligase, competes with MDM2 to bind to p53 for its stabilization. Depletion of UFL1 or DDRGK1, the critical regulator of UFMylation6,13, decreases p53 stability and in turn promotes cell growth and tumour formation in vivo. Clinically, UFL1 and DDRGK1 expression are downregulated and positively correlated with levels of p53 in a high percentage of renal cell carcinomas. Our results identify UFMylation as a crucial post-translational modification for maintenance of p53 stability and tumour-suppressive function, and point to UFMylation as a promising therapeutic target in cancer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TRIM24 facilitates antiviral immunity through mediating K63-linked TRAF3 ubiquitination</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32324863/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32324863/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ubiquitination is an essential mechanism in the control of antiviral immunity upon virus infection. Here, we identify a series of ubiquitination-modulating enzymes that are modulated by vesicular stomatitis virus (VSV). Notably, TRIM24 is down-regulated through direct transcriptional suppression induced by VSV-activated IRF3. Reducing or ablating TRIM24 compromises type I IFN (IFN-I) induction upon RNA virus infection and thus renders mice more sensitive to VSV infection. Mechanistically, VSV infection induces abundant TRIM24 translocation to mitochondria, where TRIM24 binds with TRAF3 and directly mediates K63-linked TRAF3 ubiquitination at K429/K436. This modification of TRAF3 enables its association with MAVS and TBK1, which consequently activates downstream antiviral signaling. Together, these findings establish TRIM24 as a critical positive regulator in controlling the activation of antiviral signaling and describe a previously unknown mechanism of TRIM24 function.The predicted 80 open reading frames (ORFs) of herpes simplex virus 1 (HSV-1) have been intensively studied for decades. Here, we unravel the complete viral transcriptome and translatome during lytic infection with base-pair resolution by computational integration of multi-omics data. We identify a total of 201 transcripts and 284 ORFs including all known and 46 novel large ORFs. This includes a so far unknown ORF in the locus deleted in the FDA-approved oncolytic virus Imlygic. Multiple transcript isoforms expressed from individual gene loci explain translation of the vast majority of ORFs as well as N-terminal extensions (NTEs) and truncations. We show that NTEs with non-canonical start codons govern the subcellular protein localization and packaging of key viral regulators and structural proteins. We extend the current nomenclature to include all viral gene products and provide a genome browser that visualizes all the obtained data from whole genome to single-nucleotide resolution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A novel selective autophagy receptor, CCDC50, delivers K63 polyubiquitination-activated RIG-I/MDA5 for degradation during viral infection</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32612200/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32612200/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Autophagy is a conserved process that delivers cytosolic substances to the lysosome for degradation, but its direct role in the regulation of antiviral innate immunity remains poorly understood. Here, through high-throughput screening, we discovered that CCDC50 functions as a previously unknown autophagy receptor that negatively regulates the type I interferon (IFN) signaling pathway initiated by RIG-I-like receptors (RLRs), the sensors for RNA viruses. The expression of CCDC50 is enhanced by viral infection, and CCDC50 specifically recognizes K63-polyubiquitinated RLRs, thus delivering the activated RIG-I/MDA5 for autophagic degradation. The association of CCDC50 with phagophore membrane protein LC3 is confirmed by crystal structure analysis. In contrast to other known autophagic cargo receptors that associate with either the LIR-docking site (LDS) or the UIM-docking site (UDS) of LC3, CCDC50 can bind to both LDS and UDS, representing a new type of cargo receptor. In mouse models with RNA virus infection, CCDC50 deficiency reduces the autophagic degradation of RIG-I/MDA5 and promotes type I IFN responses, resulting in enhanced viral resistance and improved survival rates. These results reveal a new link between autophagy and antiviral innate immune responses and provide additional insights into the regulatory mechanisms of RLR-mediated antiviral signaling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ubiquitination of RIPK1 suppresses programmed cell death by regulating RIPK1 kinase activation during embryogenesis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/31519886/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/31519886/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ubiquitination status of RIPK1 is considered to be critical for cell fate determination. However, the in vivo role for RIPK1 ubiquitination remains undefined. Here we show that mice expressing RIPK1&lt;sup&gt;K376R&lt;/sup&gt; which is defective in RIPK1 ubiquitination die during embryogenesis. This lethality is fully rescued by concomitant deletion of &lt;em&gt;Fadd&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Ripk3&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;Mlkl&lt;/em&gt;. Mechanistically, cells expressing RIPK1K376R are more susceptible to TNF-α induced apoptosis and necroptosis with more complex II formation and increased RIPK1 activation, which is consistent with the observation that &lt;em&gt;Ripk1&lt;sup&gt;K376R/K376R&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; lethality is effectively prevented by treatment of RIPK1 kinase inhibitor and is rescued by deletion of Tnfr1. However, &lt;em&gt;Tnfr1&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt; Ripk1&lt;sup&gt;K376R/K376R&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; mice display systemic inflammation and die within 2 weeks. Significantly, this lethal inflammation is rescued by deletion of &lt;em&gt;Ripk3&lt;/em&gt;. Taken together, these findings reveal a critical role of Lys376-mediated ubiquitination of RIPK1 in suppressing RIPK1 kinase activity-dependent lethal pathways during embryogenesis and RIPK3-dependent inflammation postnatally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LZTR1 is a regulator of RAS ubiquitination and signaling</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/30442766/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/30442766/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In genetic screens aimed at understanding drug resistance mechanisms in chronic myeloid leukemia cells, inactivation of the cullin 3 adapter protein-encoding leucine zipper-like transcription regulator 1 (&lt;em&gt;LZTR1&lt;/em&gt;) gene led to enhanced mitogen-activated protein kinase (MAPK) pathway activity and reduced sensitivity to tyrosine kinase inhibitors. Knockdown of the &lt;em&gt;Drosophila LZTR1&lt;/em&gt; ortholog &lt;em&gt;CG3711&lt;/em&gt; resulted in a Ras-dependent gain-of-function phenotype. Endogenous human LZTR1 associates with the main RAS isoforms. Inactivation of &lt;em&gt;LZTR1&lt;/em&gt; led to decreased ubiquitination and enhanced plasma membrane localization of endogenous KRAS (V-Ki-ras2 Kirsten rat sarcoma viral oncogene homolog). We propose that LZTR1 acts as a conserved regulator of RAS ubiquitination and MAPK pathway activation. Because &lt;em&gt;LZTR1&lt;/em&gt; disease mutations failed to revert loss-of-function phenotypes, our findings provide a molecular rationale for &lt;em&gt;LZTR1&lt;/em&gt; involvement in a variety of inherited and acquired human disorders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Proteomic and Biochemical Analyses Reveal a Novel Mechanism for Promoting Protein Ubiquitination and Degradation by UFBP1, a Key Component of Ufmylation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/29533670/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/29533670/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Protein post-translational modification by ubiquitin-fold modifier 1, UFM1, regulates many biological processes such as response to endoplasmic reticulum stress and regulation of tumor progression. A recent study has indicated that the UFM1-binding and PCI domain-containing protein 1 (UFBP1) is required for the conjugation of UFM1 to a substrate. However, other biological functions of UFBP1 have not been explored. Here, we use immunoprecipitation and label-free quantitative proteomics to identify UFBP1-interacting proteins in a mammalian cell line. About 80 potential interacting proteins are obtained from MS analyses of three biological replicates. Bioinformatics analyses of these proteins suggest that UFBP1 may participate in the regulation of protein folding, stability, and trafficking. Biochemical experiments discover that UFBP1 expression downregulates the protein level and reduces the stability of several of its interacting proteins, while UFBP1 knockdown increases their protein levels. Protein synthesis inhibition and proteasomal inhibition experiments reveal that UFBP1 promotes their ubiquitination and degradation. Experiments using a model UFBP1-interacting protein ANT3 demonstrate that UFBP1 enhances the interaction between ANT3 and its E3 ligase and thus promotes its ubiquitination and degradation. Our work elucidates a novel molecular mechanism by which UFBP1 regulates protein ubiquitination and degradation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
