<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ubiquitination | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/ubiquitination/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/ubiquitination/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Ubiquitination</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Ubiquitination</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/ubiquitination/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Genetic code expansion reveals aminoacylated lysine ubiquitination mediated by UBE2W</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/23-01-03-08-21/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/23-01-03-08-21/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Protein post-translational modification (PTM) regulates nearly every aspect of cellular processes in eukaryotes. However, the identification of new protein PTMs is very challenging. Here, using genetically encoded unnatural amino acids as chemical probes, we report the identification and validation of a previously unreported form of protein PTM, aminoacylated lysine ubiquitination, in which the modification occurs on the α-amine group of aminoacylated lysine. We identify more than 2,000 ubiquitination sites on all 20 aminoacylated lysines in two human cell lines. The modifications can mediate rapid protein degradation, complementing the canonical lysine ubiquitination-mediated proteome degradation. Furthermore, we demonstrate that the ubiquitin-conjugating enzyme UBE2W acts as a writer of aminoacylated lysine ubiquitination and facilitates the ubiquitination event on proteins. More broadly, the discovery and validation of aminoacylated lysine ubiquitination paves the way for the identification and verification of new protein PTMs with the genetic code expansion strategy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ubiquitination of RIPK1 suppresses programmed cell death by regulating RIPK1 kinase activation during embryogenesis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/31519886/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/31519886/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ubiquitination status of RIPK1 is considered to be critical for cell fate determination. However, the in vivo role for RIPK1 ubiquitination remains undefined. Here we show that mice expressing RIPK1&lt;sup&gt;K376R&lt;/sup&gt; which is defective in RIPK1 ubiquitination die during embryogenesis. This lethality is fully rescued by concomitant deletion of &lt;em&gt;Fadd&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Ripk3&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;Mlkl&lt;/em&gt;. Mechanistically, cells expressing RIPK1K376R are more susceptible to TNF-α induced apoptosis and necroptosis with more complex II formation and increased RIPK1 activation, which is consistent with the observation that &lt;em&gt;Ripk1&lt;sup&gt;K376R/K376R&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; lethality is effectively prevented by treatment of RIPK1 kinase inhibitor and is rescued by deletion of Tnfr1. However, &lt;em&gt;Tnfr1&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt; Ripk1&lt;sup&gt;K376R/K376R&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; mice display systemic inflammation and die within 2 weeks. Significantly, this lethal inflammation is rescued by deletion of &lt;em&gt;Ripk3&lt;/em&gt;. Taken together, these findings reveal a critical role of Lys376-mediated ubiquitination of RIPK1 in suppressing RIPK1 kinase activity-dependent lethal pathways during embryogenesis and RIPK3-dependent inflammation postnatally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LZTR1 is a regulator of RAS ubiquitination and signaling</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/30442766/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/30442766/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In genetic screens aimed at understanding drug resistance mechanisms in chronic myeloid leukemia cells, inactivation of the cullin 3 adapter protein-encoding leucine zipper-like transcription regulator 1 (&lt;em&gt;LZTR1&lt;/em&gt;) gene led to enhanced mitogen-activated protein kinase (MAPK) pathway activity and reduced sensitivity to tyrosine kinase inhibitors. Knockdown of the &lt;em&gt;Drosophila LZTR1&lt;/em&gt; ortholog &lt;em&gt;CG3711&lt;/em&gt; resulted in a Ras-dependent gain-of-function phenotype. Endogenous human LZTR1 associates with the main RAS isoforms. Inactivation of &lt;em&gt;LZTR1&lt;/em&gt; led to decreased ubiquitination and enhanced plasma membrane localization of endogenous KRAS (V-Ki-ras2 Kirsten rat sarcoma viral oncogene homolog). We propose that LZTR1 acts as a conserved regulator of RAS ubiquitination and MAPK pathway activation. Because &lt;em&gt;LZTR1&lt;/em&gt; disease mutations failed to revert loss-of-function phenotypes, our findings provide a molecular rationale for &lt;em&gt;LZTR1&lt;/em&gt; involvement in a variety of inherited and acquired human disorders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Proteomic and Biochemical Analyses Reveal a Novel Mechanism for Promoting Protein Ubiquitination and Degradation by UFBP1, a Key Component of Ufmylation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/29533670/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/29533670/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Protein post-translational modification by ubiquitin-fold modifier 1, UFM1, regulates many biological processes such as response to endoplasmic reticulum stress and regulation of tumor progression. A recent study has indicated that the UFM1-binding and PCI domain-containing protein 1 (UFBP1) is required for the conjugation of UFM1 to a substrate. However, other biological functions of UFBP1 have not been explored. Here, we use immunoprecipitation and label-free quantitative proteomics to identify UFBP1-interacting proteins in a mammalian cell line. About 80 potential interacting proteins are obtained from MS analyses of three biological replicates. Bioinformatics analyses of these proteins suggest that UFBP1 may participate in the regulation of protein folding, stability, and trafficking. Biochemical experiments discover that UFBP1 expression downregulates the protein level and reduces the stability of several of its interacting proteins, while UFBP1 knockdown increases their protein levels. Protein synthesis inhibition and proteasomal inhibition experiments reveal that UFBP1 promotes their ubiquitination and degradation. Experiments using a model UFBP1-interacting protein ANT3 demonstrate that UFBP1 enhances the interaction between ANT3 and its E3 ligase and thus promotes its ubiquitination and degradation. Our work elucidates a novel molecular mechanism by which UFBP1 regulates protein ubiquitination and degradation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
