<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Influenza Virus | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/influenza-virus/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/influenza-virus/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Influenza Virus</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Influenza Virus</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/influenza-virus/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interactomics: dozens of viruses, co-evolving with humans, including the influenza A virus, may actively distort human ageing</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36649176/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36649176/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some viruses (e.g. HIV-1, SARS-CoV-2) have been experimentally proposed to accelerate features of human ageing and of cellular senescence. These observations, along with evolutionary considerations on viral fitness, raised the more general puzzling hypothesis that, beyond documented sources in human genetics, ageing in our species may also depend on virally-encoded interactions distorting our ageing to the benefits of diverse viruses. Accordingly, we designed systematic network-based analyses of the human and viral protein interactomes, which unraveled dozens of viruses encoding proteins experimentally demonstrated to interact with proteins from pathways associated with human ageing, including cellular senescence. We further corroborated our predictions that specific viruses interfere with human ageing using published experimental evidence and transcriptomic data; identifying influenza A virus (subtype H1N1) as a major candidate age-distorter, notably through manipulation of cellular senescence. By providing original evidence that viruses may convergently contribute to the evolution of numerous age-associated pathways through co-evolution, our network- and bipartite network-based methodology supports an ecosystemic study of ageing, also searching for genetic causes of ageing outside a focal ageing species. Our findings, predicting age-distorters and targets for anti-ageing therapies amongst human viruses, could have fundamental and practical implications for evolutionary biology, ageing study, virology, medicine and demography.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Antiviral Approaches against Influenza Virus</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/36645300/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/36645300/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Preventing and controlling influenza virus infection remains a global public health challenge, as it causes seasonal epidemics to unexpected pandemics. These infections are responsible for high morbidity, mortality, and substantial economic impact. Vaccines are the prophylaxis mainstay in the fight against influenza. However, vaccination fails to confer complete protection due to inadequate vaccination coverages, vaccine shortages, and mismatches with circulating strains. Antivirals represent an important prophylactic and therapeutic measure to reduce influenza-associated morbidity and mortality, particularly in high-risk populations. Here, we review current FDA-approved influenza antivirals with their mechanisms of action, and different viral- and host-directed influenza antiviral approaches, including immunomodulatory interventions in clinical development. Furthermore, we also illustrate the potential utility of machine learning in developing next-generation antivirals against influenza.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Severe respiratory viral infections: T-cell functions diverging from immunity to inflammation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/36635162/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/36635162/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Upon respiratory viral infection, a robust innate immune response can efficiently drive adaptive immunity whereby virus-specific T cells are activated. Meanwhile, memory T cells nonspecific to the virus can also be primed by proinflammatory cytokines and complement proteins, a process termed ‘bystander activation’.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Exaggerated production of proinflammatory cytokines from prolonged infection can skew the balance from virus-specific T-cell activation to nonspecific bystander T-cell activation which can significantly contribute to unresolved inflammation and cause tissue damage and severe disease.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Preventive and therapeutic strategies that suppress viral replication or inhibit proinflammatory signals can reinstate the balance of virus-specific activation and bystander activation of T cells. Prevention of T-cell-mediated pathology and tissue damage will support efficient immunity and recovery.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Respiratory viral infections such as severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 (SARS-CoV-2) and influenza A virus (IAV) trigger distinct clinical outcomes defined by immunity-based viral clearance or disease associated with exaggerated and prolonged inflammation. The important role of T cells in shaping both antiviral immunity and inflammation has revived interest in understanding the host-pathogen interactions that lead to the diverse functions of T cells in respiratory viral infections. Inborn deficiencies and acquired insufficiency in immunity can prolong infection and shift the immune response towards exacerbated inflammation, which results from persistent innate immune activation and bystander T-cell activation that is nonspecific to the pathogen but is often driven by cytokines. This review discusses how virus variants, exposure doses, routes of infection, host genetics, and immune history can modulate the activation and function of T cells, thus influencing clinical outcomes. Knowledge of virus-host interaction can inform strategies to prevent immune dysfunction in respiratory viral infection and help in the treatment of associated diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The nucleoprotein of influenza A virus inhibits the innate immune response by inducing mitophagy</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36588386/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36588386/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mitophagy is a form of autophagy that plays a key role in maintaining the homeostasis of functional mitochondria in the cell. Viruses have evolved various strategies to manipulate mitophagy to escape host immune responses and promote virus replication. In this study, the nucleoprotein (NP) of H1N1 virus (PR8 strain) was identified as a regulator of mitophagy. We revealed that NP-mediated mitophagy leads to the degradation of the mitochondria-anchored protein MAVS, thereby blocking MAVS-mediated antiviral signaling and promoting virus replication. The NP-mediated mitophagy is dependent on the interaction of NP with MAVS and the cargo receptor TOLLIP. Moreover, Y313 of NP is a key residue for the MAVS-NP interaction and NP-mediated mitophagy. The NPY313F mutation significantly attenuates the virus-induced mitophagy and the virus replication in vitro and in vivo. Taken together, our findings uncover a novel mechanism by which the NP of influenza virus induces mitophagy to attenuate innate immunity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PI3K/AKT-mediated autophagy inhibition facilitates mast cell activation to enhance severe inflammatory lung injury in influenza A virus- and secondary Staphylococcus aureus-infected mice</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36549394/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36549394/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Influenza A virus infection causes considerable morbidity and mortality each year globally, and secondary bacterial infection further exacerbates the severity and fatality of the initial viral infection. Mast cells have substantial roles in protecting the respiratory tract mucosa, while their role in viral and bacterial co-infection remains unclear. The present study revealed that secondary Staphylococcus aureus infection significantly aggravated the activation of mast cells during the initial H1N1 infection both in vivo and in vitro, which was closely related to the increased inflammatory lung injury and mortality. Meanwhile, the secondary S. aureus infection suppressed autophagy and promoted inflammatory mediators released by mast cells through activating the PI3K/Akt signaling pathway. Blocking PI3K/Akt pathway by LY294002, an inhibitor of Akt phosphorylation, could rescue autophagy and inhibit the release of inflammatory mediators. Furthermore, based on the influenza A viral and secondary bacterial infected mice model, we showed that the combination of LY294002 and antiviral drug oseltamivir could effectively reduce the inflammatory damage and pro-inflammatory cytokines releasing in lungs, recovering body weight loss and improving the survival rate from the co-infections. In conclusion, secondary bacterial infection can inhibit autophagy and stimulate mast cell activation through the PI3K/Akt pathway, which might explain why secondary bacterial infection would cause severe and fatal consequences following an initial influenza A viral infection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Polystyrene microplastics significantly facilitate influenza A virus infection of host cells</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36623344/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36623344/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Microplastics (MPs) are emerging pollutants which exist in various environments and pose a potential threat to human health. However, the effect of MP on respiratory pathogens-infected organisms is unknown. In order to explore the effect of MP on respiratory pathogen infection, we studied the effect of polystyrene microplastics (PS) on influenza A virus (IAV)-infected A549 cells. Western blot, qPCR, and viral plaque assay demonstrated that PS could promote IAV infection. Further study by bioluminescence imaging showed that a large number of IAV could be enriched on PS and entered cells through endocytosis. Meanwhile, the expression of IFITM3 in cells was significantly reduced. In addition, our results showed that PS down-regulated IRF3 and its active form P-IRF3 by down-regulating RIG-I and inhibiting TBK1 phosphorylation activation, which then significantly reduced IFN-β expression and affected the cellular innate antiviral immune system. Taken together, our results indicate the potential threat of MPs to respiratory diseases caused by IAV and provide new insights into human health protection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alveolar macrophages instruct CD8&#43; T cell expansion by antigen cross-presentation in lung</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36516765/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36516765/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lung CD8&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; memory T cells play central roles in protective immunity to respiratory viruses, such as influenza A virus (IAV). Here, we find that alveolar macrophages (AMs) function as antigen-presenting cells that support the expansion of lung CD8&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; memory T cells. Intranasal antigen administration to mice subcutaneously immunized with antigen results in a rapid expansion of antigen-specific CD8&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T cells in the lung, which is dependent on antigen cross-presentation by AMs. AMs highly express interleukin-18 (IL-18), which mediates subsequent formation of CD103&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt;CD8&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; resident memory T (T&lt;sub&gt;RM&lt;/sub&gt;) cells in the lung. In a mouse model of IAV infection, AMs are required for expansion of virus-specific CD8&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T cells and CD103&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt;CD8&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T&lt;sub&gt;RM&lt;/sub&gt; cells and inhibiting virus replication in the lungs during secondary infection. These results suggest that AMs instruct a rapid expansion of antigen-specific CD8&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T cells in lung, which protect the host from respiratory virus infection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A multivalent nucleoside-modified mRNA vaccine against all known influenza virus subtypes</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36423275/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36423275/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seasonal influenza vaccines offer little protection against pandemic influenza virus strains. It is difficult to create effective prepandemic vaccines because it is uncertain which influenza virus subtype will cause the next pandemic. In this work, we developed a nucleoside-modified messenger RNA (mRNA)-lipid nanoparticle vaccine encoding hemagglutinin antigens from all 20 known influenza A virus subtypes and influenza B virus lineages. This multivalent vaccine elicited high levels of cross-reactive and subtype-specific antibodies in mice and ferrets that reacted to all 20 encoded antigens. Vaccination protected mice and ferrets challenged with matched and mismatched viral strains, and this protection was at least partially dependent on antibodies. Our studies indicate that mRNA vaccines can provide protection against antigenically variable viruses by simultaneously inducing antibodies against multiple antigens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Melatonin Suppresses Macrophage M1 Polarization and ROS-Mediated Pyroptosis via Activating ApoE/LDLR Pathway in Influenza A-Induced Acute Lung Injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36425057/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36425057/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Influenza virus infection is one of the strongest pathogenic factors for the development of acute lung injury (ALI)/ acute respiratory distress syndrome (ARDS). However, the underlying cellular and molecular mechanisms have not been clarified. In this study, we aim to investigate whether melatonin modulates macrophage polarization, oxidative stress, and pyroptosis via activating Apolipoprotein E/low-density lipoprotein receptor (ApoE/LDLR) pathway in influenza A-induced ALI. Here, wild-type (WT) and ApoE&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt; mice were instilled intratracheally with influenza A (H3N2) and injected intraperitoneally with melatonin for 7 consecutive days. In vitro, WT and ApoE&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt; murine bone marrow-derived macrophages (BMDMs) were pretreated with melatonin before H3N2 stimulation. The results showed that melatonin administration significantly attenuated H3N2-induced pulmonary damage, leukocyte infiltration, and edema; decreased the expression of proinflammatory M1 markers; enhanced anti-inflammatory M2 markers; and switched the polarization of alveolar macrophages (AMs) from M1 to M2 phenotype. Additionally, melatonin inhibited reactive oxygen species- (ROS-) mediated pyroptosis shown by downregulation of malonaldehyde (MDA) and ROS levels as well as inhibition of the NLRP3/GSDMD pathway and lactate dehydrogenase (LDH) release. Strikingly, the ApoE/LDLR pathway was activated when melatonin was applied in H3N2-infected macrophages and mice. ApoE knockout mostly abrogated the protective impacts of melatonin on H3N2-induced ALI and its regulatory ability on macrophage polarization, oxidative stress, and pyroptosis. Furthermore, recombinant ApoE3 (re-ApoE3) inhibited H3N2-induced M1 polarization of BMDMs with upregulation of MT1 and MT2 expression, but re-ApoE2 and re-ApoE4 failed to do this. Melatonin combined with re-ApoE3 played more beneficial protective effects on modulating macrophage polarization, oxidative stress, and pyroptosis in H3N2-infected ApoE&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt; BMDMs. Our study indicated that melatonin attenuated influenza A- (H3N2-) induced ALI by inhibiting the M1 polarization of pulmonary macrophages and ROS-mediated pyroptosis via activating the ApoE/LDLR pathway. This study suggested that melatonin-ApoE/LDLR axis may serve as a novel therapeutic strategy for influenza virus-induced ALI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cellular glycan modification by B3GAT1 broadly restricts influenza virus infection</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36309510/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36309510/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Communicable respiratory viral infections pose both epidemic and pandemic threats and broad-spectrum antiviral strategies could improve preparedness for these events. To discover host antiviral restriction factors that may act as suitable targets for the development of host-directed antiviral therapies, we here conduct a whole-genome CRISPR activation screen with influenza B virus (IBV). A top hit from our screen, beta-1,3-glucuronyltransferase 1 (B3GAT1), effectively blocks IBV infection. Subsequent studies reveal that B3GAT1 activity prevents cell surface sialic acid expression. Due to this mechanism of action, B3GAT1 expression broadly restricts infection with viruses that require sialic acid for entry, including Victoria and Yamagata lineage IBVs, H1N1/H3N2 influenza A viruses (IAVs), and the unrelated enterovirus D68. To understand the potential utility of B3GAT1 induction as an antiviral strategy in vivo, we specifically express B3GAT1 in the murine respiratory epithelium and find that overexpression is not only well-tolerated, but also protects female mice from a lethal viral challenge with multiple influenza viruses, including a pandemic-like H1N1 IAV. Thus, B3GAT1 may represent a host-directed broad-spectrum antiviral target with utility against clinically relevant respiratory viruses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The influenza virus PB2 protein evades antiviral innate immunity by inhibiting JAK1/STAT signalling</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36271046/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36271046/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Influenza A virus (IAV) polymerase protein PB2 has been shown to partially inhibit the host immune response by blocking the induction of interferons (IFNs). However, the IAV PB2 protein that regulates the downstream signaling pathway of IFNs is not well characterized. Here, we report that IAV PB2 protein reduces cellular sensitivity to IFNs, suppressing the activation of STAT1/STAT2 and ISGs. Furthermore, IAV PB2 protein targets mammalian JAK1 at lysine 859 and 860 for ubiquitination and degradation. Notably, the H5 subtype of highly pathogenic avian influenza virus with I283M/K526R mutations on PB2 increases the ability to degrade mammalian JAK1 and exhibits higher replicate efficiency in mammalian (but not avian) cells and mouse lung tissues, and causes greater mortality in infected mice. Altogether, these data describe a negative regulatory mechanism involving PB2-JAK1 and provide insights into an evasion strategy from host antiviral immunity employed by IAV.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SRSF5-Mediated Alternative Splicing of M Gene is Essential for Influenza A Virus Replication: A Host-Directed Target Against Influenza Virus</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36257906/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36257906/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Splicing of influenza A virus (IAV) RNA is an essential process in the viral life cycle that involves the co-opting of host factors. Here, it is demonstrated that induction of host serine and arginine-rich splicing factor 5 (SRSF5) by IAV facilitated viral replication by enhancing viral M mRNA splicing. Mechanistically, SRSF5 with its RRM2 domain directly bounds M mRNA at conserved sites (M mRNA position 163, 709, and 712), and interacts with U1 small nuclear ribonucleoprotein (snRNP) to promote M mRNA splicing and M2 production. Mutations introduced to the three binding sites, without changing amino acid code, significantly attenuates virus replication and pathogenesis in vivo. Likewise, SRSF5 conditional knockout in the lung protects mice against lethal IAV challenge. Furthermore, anidulafungin, an approved antifungal drug, is identified as an inhibitor of SRSF5 that effectively blocks IAV replication in vitro and in vivo. In conclusion, SRSF5 as an activator of M mRNA splicing promotes IAV replication and is a host-derived antiviral target.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Common and species-specific molecular signatures, networks, and regulators of influenza virus infection in mice, ferrets, and humans</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36197970/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36197970/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Molecular responses to influenza A virus (IAV) infections vary between mammalian species. To identify conserved and species-specific molecular responses, we perform a comparative study of transcriptomic data derived from blood cells, primary epithelial cells, and lung tissues collected from IAV-infected humans, ferrets, and mice. The molecular responses in the human host have unique functions such as antigen processing that are not observed in mice or ferrets. Highly conserved gene coexpression modules across the three species are enriched for IAV infection-induced pathways including cell cycle and interferon (IFN) signaling. TDRD7 is predicted as an IFN-inducible host factor that is up-regulated upon IAV infection in the three species. TDRD7 is required for antiviral IFN response, potentially modulating IFN signaling via the JAK/STAT/IRF9 pathway. Identification of the common and species-specific molecular signatures, networks, and regulators of IAV infection provides insights into host-defense mechanisms and will facilitate the development of novel therapeutic interventions against IAV infection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Distinct roles of ORAI1 in T cell-mediated allergic airway inflammation and immunity to influenza A virus infection</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36206339/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36206339/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;T cell activation and function depend on Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt; signals mediated by store-operated Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt; entry (SOCE) through Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt; release-activated Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt; (CRAC) channels formed by ORAI1 proteins. We here investigated how SOCE controls T cell function in pulmonary inflammation during a T helper 1 (T&lt;sub&gt;H&lt;/sub&gt;1) cell-mediated response to influenza A virus (IAV) infection and T&lt;sub&gt;H&lt;/sub&gt;2 cell-mediated allergic airway inflammation. T cell-specific deletion of &lt;em&gt;Orai1&lt;/em&gt; did not exacerbate pulmonary inflammation and viral burdens following IAV infection but protected mice from house dust mite-induced allergic airway inflammation. ORAI1 controlled the expression of genes including p53 and E2F transcription factors that regulate the cell cycle in T&lt;sub&gt;H&lt;/sub&gt;2 cells in response to allergen stimulation and the expression of transcription factors and cytokines that regulate T&lt;sub&gt;H&lt;/sub&gt;2 cell function. Systemic application of a CRAC channel blocker suppressed allergic airway inflammation without compromising immunity to IAV infection, suggesting that inhibition of SOCE is a potential treatment for allergic airway disease.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Influenza A virus infection instructs hematopoiesis to megakaryocyte-lineage output</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36198277/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36198277/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IAV infection transiently activates CD41+ HSCs, while EPCR+ CD41− HSCs remain quiescent&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CD41+ HSCs produce megakaryocytes in IAV-induced emergency megakaryopoiesis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Platelets generated by IAV-induced emergency megakaryopoiesis are pro-coagulant&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IAV-induced emergency megakaryopoiesis is attenuated in IL1R1-deficient mice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Respiratory tract infections are among the deadliest communicable diseases worldwide. Severe cases of viral lung infections are often associated with a cytokine storm and alternating platelet numbers. We report that hematopoietic stem and progenitor cells (HSPCs) sense a non-systemic influenza A virus (IAV) infection via inflammatory cytokines. Irrespective of antiviral treatment or vaccination, at a certain threshold of IAV titer in the lung, CD41-positive hematopoietic stem cells (HSCs) enter the cell cycle while endothelial protein C receptor-positive CD41-negative HSCs remain quiescent. Active CD41-positive HSCs represent the source of megakaryocytes, while their multi-lineage reconstitution potential is reduced. This emergency megakaryopoiesis is thrombopoietin independent and attenuated in IAV-infected interleukin-1 receptor-deficient mice. Newly produced platelets during IAV infection are immature and hyper-reactive. After viral clearance, HSC quiescence is re-established. Our study reveals that non-systemic viral respiratory infection has an acute impact on HSCs via inflammatory cytokines to counteract IAV-induced thrombocytopenia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Orthogonally-tunable and ER-targeting fluorophores detect avian influenza virus early infection</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36192426/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36192426/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cell-based assays can monitor virus infection at a single-cell level with high sensitivity and cost-efficiency. For this purpose, it is crucial to develop molecular probes that respond selectively to physiological changes in live cells. We report stimuli-responsive light-emitters built on a T-shaped benzimidazole platform, and consecutive borylation reactions to produce a library of homologs displaying systematic changes in fluorescence quantum yield and environmental sensitivity. We find that certain fluorophores localize selectively at the endoplasmic reticulum, and interact with proteins involved in the stress signaling pathways. Notably, the mono-borylated compound responds selectively to the stress conditions by enhancing fluorescence, and detects avian influenza virus infection at the single-cell level. Our findings demonstrate the unprecedented practical utility of the stress-responsive molecular probes to differentiate cellular states for early diagnosis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Single cell analysis of PANoptosome cell death complexes through an expansion microscopy method</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36169732/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36169732/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In response to infection or sterile insults, inflammatory programmed cell death is an essential component of the innate immune response to remove infected or damaged cells. PANoptosis is a unique innate immune inflammatory cell death pathway regulated by multifaceted macromolecular complexes called PANoptosomes, which integrate components from other cell death pathways. Growing evidence shows that PANoptosis can be triggered in many physiological conditions, including viral and bacterial infections, cytokine storms, and cancers. However, PANoptosomes at the single cell level have not yet been fully characterized. Initial investigations have suggested that key pyroptotic, apoptotic, and necroptotic molecules including the inflammasome adaptor protein ASC, apoptotic caspase-8 (CASP8), and necroptotic RIPK3 are conserved components of PANoptosomes. Here, we optimized an immunofluorescence procedure to probe the highly dynamic multiprotein PANoptosome complexes across various innate immune cell death-inducing conditions. We first identified and validated antibodies to stain endogenous mouse ASC, CASP8, and RIPK3, without residual staining in the respective knockout cells. We then assessed the formation of PANoptosomes across innate immune cell death-inducing conditions by monitoring the colocalization of ASC with CASP8 and/or RIPK3. Finally, we established an expansion microscopy procedure using these validated antibodies to image the organization of ASC, CASP8, and RIPK3 within the PANoptosome. This optimized protocol, which can be easily adapted to study other multiprotein complexes and other cell death triggers, provides confirmation of PANoptosome assembly in individual cells and forms the foundation for a deeper molecular understanding of the PANoptosome complex and PANoptosis to facilitate therapeutic targeting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apolipoprotein E mediates cell resistance to influenza virus infection</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36129973/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36129973/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Viruses exploit host cell machinery to support their replication. Defining the cellular proteins and processes required for a virus during infection is crucial to understanding the mechanisms of virally induced disease and designing host-directed therapeutics. Here, we perform a genome-wide CRISPR-Cas9-based screening in lung epithelial cells infected with the PR/8/NS1-GFP virus and use GFPhi cell as a unique screening marker to identify host factors that inhibit influenza A virus (IAV) infection. We discovered that APOE affects influenza virus infection both in vitro and in vivo. Cell deficiency in APOE conferred substantially increased susceptibility to IAV; mice deficient in APOE manifested more severe lung pathology, increased virus load, and decreased survival rate. Mechanistically, lack of cell-produced APOE results in impaired cell cholesterol homeostasis, enhancing influenza virus attachment. Thus, we identified a previously unrecognized role of APOE in restraining IAV infection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IFN-γ transforms the transcriptomic landscape and triggers myeloid cell hyperresponsiveness to cause lethal lung injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36203588/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36203588/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acute Respiratory Distress Syndrome (ARDS) is an inflammatory disease that is associated with high mortality but no specific treatment. Our understanding of initial events that trigger ARDS pathogenesis is limited. We have developed a mouse model of inflammatory lung injury by influenza and methicillin-resistant &lt;em&gt;Staphylococcus aureus&lt;/em&gt; (MRSA) coinfection plus daily antibiotic therapy. Using this pneumonic ARDS model, here we show that IFN-γ receptor signaling drives inflammatory cytokine storm and lung tissue damage. By single-cell RNA sequencing (scRNA-seq) analysis, we demonstrate that IFN-γ signaling induces a transcriptional shift in airway immune cells, particularly by upregulating macrophage and monocyte expression of genes associated with inflammatory diseases. Further evidence from conditional knockout mouse models reveals that IFN-γ receptor signaling in myeloid cells, particularly CD11c&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; mononuclear phagocytes, directly promotes TNF-α hyperproduction and inflammatory lung damage. Collectively, the findings from this study, ranging from cell-intrinsic gene expression to overall disease outcome, demonstrate that influenza-induced IFN-γ triggers myeloid cell hyperresponsiveness to MRSA, thereby leading to excessive inflammatory response and lethal lung damage during coinfection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>H1N1 influenza virus dose dependent induction of dysregulated innate immune responses and STAT1/3 activation are associated with pulmonary immunopathological damage</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36082929/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36082929/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Influenza A virus (IAV) infection poses a substantial challenge and causes high morbidity and mortality. Exacerbated pulmonary inflammatory responses are the major causes of extensive diffuse alveolar immunopathological damage. However, the relationship between the extent of cytokine storm, neutrophils/macrophages infiltration, and different IAV infection dose and time still needs to be further elucidated, and it is still unclear whether the signal transduction and transcriptional activator 1/3 (STAT1/3) signalling pathway plays a beneficial or detrimental role. Here, we established a mouse model of high- and low-dose pH1N1 infection. We found that pH1N1 infection induced robust and early pathological damage and cytokine storm in an infection dose- and time-dependent manner. High-dose pH1N1 infection induced massive and sustained recruitment of neutrophils as well as a higher ratio of M1:M2, which may contribute to severe lung immunopathological damage. pH1N1 infection activated dose- and time-dependent STAT1 and STAT3. Inhibition of STAT1 and/or STAT3 aggravated low-dose pH1N1 infection, induced lung damage, and decreased survival rate. Appropriate activation of STAT1/3 provided survival benefits and pathological improvement during low-dose pH1N1 infection. These results demonstrate that high-dose pH1N1 infection induces robust and sustained neutrophil infiltration, imbalanced macrophage polarization, excessive and earlier cytokine storm, and STAT1/3 activation, which are associated with pulmonary dysregulated proinflammatory responses and progress of acute lung injury. The severe innate immune responses may be the threshold at which protective functions give way to immunopathology, and assessing the magnitude of host innate immune responses is necessary in adjunctive immunomodulatory therapy for alleviating influenza-induced pneumonia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transient RNA structures cause aberrant influenza virus replication and innate immune activation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36083899/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36083899/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During infection, the influenza A virus RNA polymerase produces both full-length and aberrant RNA molecules, such as defective viral genomes (DVGs) and mini viral RNAs (mvRNAs). Subsequent innate immune activation involves the binding of host pathogen receptor retinoic acid-inducible gene I (RIG-I) to viral RNAs. However, it is not clear what factors determine which influenza A virus RNAs are RIG-I agonists. Here, we provide evidence that RNA structures, called template loops (t-loops), stall the viral RNA polymerase and contribute to innate immune activation by mvRNAs during influenza A virus infection. Impairment of replication by t-loops depends on the formation of an RNA duplex near the template entry and exit channels of the RNA polymerase, and this effect is enhanced by mutation of the template exit path from the RNA polymerase active site. Overall, these findings are suggestive of a mechanism involving polymerase stalling that links aberrant viral replication to the activation of the innate immune response.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Injury-induced pulmonary tuft cells are heterogenous, arise independent of key Type 2 cytokines, and are dispensable for dysplastic repair</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36073526/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36073526/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the lung bears significant regenerative capacity, severe viral pneumonia can chronically impair lung function by triggering dysplastic remodeling. The connection between these enduring changes and chronic disease remains poorly understood. We recently described the emergence of tuft cells within Krt5+ dysplastic regions after influenza injury. Using bulk and single-cell transcriptomics, we characterized and delineated multiple distinct tuft cell populations that arise following influenza clearance. Distinct from intestinal tuft cells which rely on Type 2 immune signals for their expansion, neither IL-25 nor IL-4ra signaling are required to drive tuft cell development in dysplastic/injured lungs. In addition, tuft cell expansion occurred independently of type I or type III interferon signaling. Furthermore, tuft cells were also observed upon bleomycin injury, suggesting that their development may be a general response to severe lung injury. While intestinal tuft cells promote growth and differentiation of surrounding epithelial cells, in the lungs of tuft cell deficient mice, Krt5+ dysplasia still occurs, goblet cell production is unchanged, and there remains no appreciable contribution of Krt5+ cells into more regionally appropriate alveolar Type 2 cells. Together, these findings highlight unexpected differences in signals necessary for murine lung tuft cell amplification and establish a framework for future elucidation of tuft cell functions in pulmonary health and disease.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intestinal microbiota metabolizing Houttuynia cordata polysaccharides in H1N1 induced pneumonia mice contributed to Th17/Treg rebalance in gut-lung axis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36084869/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36084869/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Influenza A virus is intricately linked to dysregulation of gut microbiota and host immunity. Previous study revealed that Houttuynia cordata polysaccharides (HCP) exert the therapeutic effect on influenza A virus inducing lung and intestine damage via regulating pulmonary and intestinal mucosal immunity. However, whether this result was due to the regulation of gut microbiota in the gut-lung axis remains unclear. Here, we firstly found that the elimination of gut microbiota using antibiotic cocktails led to both loss of the protective effect of HCP on intestine and lung injury, and reduction of the efficacy on regulating Th17/Treg balance in gut-lung axis. Fecal microbiota transplantation study confirmed that the gut microbiota fermented with HCP under pathological conditions (H1N1 infection) was responsible for reducing pulmonary and intestinal injury. Moreover, the interaction of HCP and gut microbiota under pathological conditions exhibited not only much more abundant gut microbial diversity, but also higher content of the acetate. Our results demonstrated that the underlying mechanism to ameliorate viral pneumonia in mice involving Th17/Treg rebalance via the gut microbiota and HCP metabolite (acetate) metabolized in pneumonia mice. Our results provided a new insight for macromolecular polysaccharides through targeting intestinal microenvironment reducing distant pulmonary infection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Influenza A virus use of BinCARD1 to facilitate the binding of viral NP to importin α7 is counteracted by TBK1-p62 axis-mediated autophagy</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36056146/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36056146/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a major component of the viral ribonucleoprotein (vRNP) complex in influenza A virus (IAV), nucleoprotein (NP) interacts with isoforms of importin α family members, leading to the import of itself and vRNP complex into the nucleus, a process pivotal in the replication cycle of IAV. In this study, we found that BinCARD1, an isoform of Bcl10-interacting protein with CARD (BinCARD), was leveraged by IAV for efficient viral replication. BinCARD1 promoted the nuclear import of the vRNP complex and newly synthesized NP and thus enhanced vRNP complex activity. Moreover, we found that BinCARD1 interacted with NP to promote NP binding to importin α7, an adaptor in the host nuclear import pathway. However, we also found that BinCARD1 promoted RIG-I-mediated innate immune signaling by mediating Lys63-linked polyubiquitination of TRAF3, and that TBK1 appeared to degrade BinCARD1. We showed that BinCARD1 was polyubiquitinated at residue K103 through a Lys63 linkage, which was recognized by the TBK1-p62 axis for autophagic degradation. Overall, our data demonstrate that IAV leverages BinCARD1 as an important host factor that promotes viral replication, and two mechanisms in the host defense system are triggered-innate immune signaling and autophagic degradation-to mitigate the promoting effect of BinCARD1 on the life cycle of IAV.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Novel Requirement for Staphylococcal Cell Wall-Anchored Protein SasD in Pulmonary Infection</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36040164/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36040164/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Staphylococcus aureus&lt;/em&gt; can complicate preceding viral infections, including influenza virus. A bacterial infection combined with a preceding viral infection, known as superinfection, leads to worse outcomes than a single infection. Most of the pulmonary infection literature focuses on the changes in immune responses to bacteria between homeostatic and virally infected lungs. However, it is unclear how much of an influence bacterial virulence factors have in single or superinfection. Staphylococcal species express a broad range of cell wall-anchored proteins (CWAs) that have roles in host adhesion, nutrient acquisition, and immune evasion. We screened the importance of these CWAs using mutants lacking individual CWAs in vivo in both bacterial pneumonia and influenza superinfection. In bacterial pneumonia, the lack of individual CWAs leads to various decreases in bacterial burden, lung damage, and immune infiltration into the lung. However, the presence of a preceding influenza infection partially abrogates the requirement for CWAs. In the screen, we found that the uncharacterized CWA &lt;em&gt;S. aureus&lt;/em&gt; surface protein D (SasD) induced changes in both inflammatory and homeostatic lung markers. We further characterized a SasD mutant (sasD A50.1) in the context of pneumonia. Mice infected with sasD A50.1 have decreased bacterial burden, inflammatory responses, and mortality compared to wild-type &lt;em&gt;S. aureus&lt;/em&gt;. Mice also have reduced levels of interleukin-1β (IL-1β), likely derived from macrophages. Reductions in IL-1β transcript levels as well as increased macrophage viability point at differences in cell death pathways. These data identify a novel virulence factor for &lt;em&gt;S. aureus&lt;/em&gt; that influences inflammatory signaling within the lung.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Importance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Staphylococcus aureus&lt;/em&gt; is a common commensal bacterium that can cause severe infections, such as pneumonia. In the lung, viral infections increase the risk of staphylococcal pneumonia, leading to combined infections known as superinfections. The most common virus associated with &lt;em&gt;S. aureus&lt;/em&gt; pneumonia is influenza, and superinfections lead to worse patient outcomes than either infection alone. While there is much known about how the immune system differs between healthy and virally infected lungs, the role of bacterial virulence factors in single and superinfection is less understood. The significance of our research is identifying bacterial components that play a role in the initiation of lung injury, which could lead to future therapies to prevent pulmonary single or superinfection with &lt;em&gt;S. aureus&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Influenza virus causes lung immunopathology through down-regulating PPARγ activity in macrophages</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36091002/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36091002/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fatal influenza (flu) virus infection often activates excessive inflammatory signals, leading to multi-organ failure and death, also referred to as cytokine storm. PPARγ (Peroxisome proliferator-activated receptor gamma) agonists are well-known candidates for cytokine storm modulation. The present study identified that influenza infection reduced PPARγ expression and decreased PPARγ transcription activity in human alveolar macrophages (AMs) from different donors. Treatment with PPARγ agonist Troglitazone ameliorated virus-induced proinflammatory cytokine secretion but did not interfere with the IFN-induced antiviral pathway in human AMs. In contrast, PPARγ antagonist and knockdown of PPARγ in human AMs further enhanced virus-stimulated proinflammatory response. In a mouse model of influenza infection, flu virus dose-dependently reduced PPARγ transcriptional activity and decreased expression of PPARγ. Moreover, PPARγ agonist troglitazone significantly reduced high doses of influenza infection-induced lung pathology. In addition, flu infection reduced PPARγ expression in all mouse macrophages, including AMs, interstitial macrophages, and bone-marrow-derived macrophages but not in alveolar epithelial cells. Our results indicate that the influenza virus specifically targets the PPARγ pathway in macrophages to cause acute injury to the lung.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Long noncoding RNA CHROMR regulates antiviral immunity in humans</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36001732/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36001732/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Significance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An effective innate immune response to virus infection requires the induction of type I interferons and up-regulation of hundreds of interferon-stimulated genes (ISGs) that instruct antiviral functions and immune regulation. Deciphering the regulatory mechanisms that direct expression of the ISG network is critical for understanding the fundamental organization of the innate immune response and the development of antiviral therapies. We define a regulatory role for the primate-specific long noncoding RNA &lt;em&gt;CHROMR&lt;/em&gt; in coordinating ISG transcription. &lt;em&gt;CHROMR&lt;/em&gt; sequesters the interferon regulatory factor (IRF)-2/IRF2BP2 complex that restrains ISG transcription and thus is required to restrict influenza virus replication. These data identify a novel regulator of the antiviral gene program in humans and provide insights into the multilayered regulatory network that controls the innate immune response.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Long noncoding RNAs (lncRNAs) have emerged as critical regulators of gene expression, yet their contribution to immune regulation in humans remains poorly understood. Here, we report that the primate-specific lncRNA &lt;em&gt;CHROMR&lt;/em&gt; is induced by influenza A virus and SARS-CoV-2 infection and coordinates the expression of interferon-stimulated genes (ISGs) that execute antiviral responses. &lt;em&gt;CHROMR&lt;/em&gt; depletion in human macrophages reduces histone acetylation at regulatory regions of ISG loci and attenuates ISG expression in response to microbial stimuli. Mechanistically, we show that &lt;em&gt;CHROMR&lt;/em&gt; sequesters the interferon regulatory factor (IRF)-2-dependent transcriptional corepressor IRF2BP2, thereby licensing IRF-dependent signaling and transcription of the ISG network. Consequently, &lt;em&gt;CHROMR&lt;/em&gt; expression is essential to restrict viral infection of macrophages. Our findings identify &lt;em&gt;CHROMR&lt;/em&gt; as a key arbitrator of antiviral innate immune signaling in humans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tumor Progression Locus 2 Protects against Acute Respiratory Distress Syndrome in Influenza A Virus-Infected Mice</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35980186/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35980186/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Excessive inflammation in patients with severe influenza disease may lead to acute lung injury that results in acute respiratory distress syndrome (ARDS). ARDS is associated with alveolar damage and pulmonary edema that severely impair gas exchange, leading to hypoxia. With no existing FDA-approved treatment for ARDS, it is important to understand the factors that lead to virus-induced ARDS development to improve prevention, diagnosis, and treatment. We have previously shown that mice deficient in the serine-threonine mitogen-activated protein kinase, Tpl2 (MAP3K8 or COT), succumb to infection with a typically low-pathogenicity strain of influenza A virus (IAV; HKX31, H3N2 [x31]). The goal of the current study was to evaluate influenza A virus-infected &lt;em&gt;Tpl2&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; mice clinically and histopathologically to gain insight into the disease mechanism. We hypothesized that &lt;em&gt;Tpl2&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; mice succumb to IAV infection due to development of ARDS-like disease and pulmonary dysfunction. We observed prominent signs of alveolar septal necrosis, hyaline membranes, pleuritis, edema, and higher lactate dehydrogenase (LDH) levels in the lungs of IAV-infected &lt;em&gt;Tpl2&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; mice compared to wild-type (WT) mice from 7 to 9 days postinfection (dpi). Notably, WT mice showed signs of regenerating epithelium, indicative of repair and recovery, that were reduced in &lt;em&gt;Tpl2&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; mice. Furthermore, biomarkers associated with human ARDS cases were upregulated in &lt;em&gt;Tpl2&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; mice at 7 dpi, demonstrating an ARDS-like phenotype in &lt;em&gt;Tpl2&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; mice in response to IAV infection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Importance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This study demonstrates the protective role of the serine-threonine mitogen-activated protein kinase, Tpl2, in influenza virus pathogenesis and reveals that host Tpl2 deficiency is sufficient to convert a low-pathogenicity influenza A virus infection into severe influenza disease that resembles ARDS, both histopathologically and transcriptionally. The IAV-infected &lt;em&gt;Tpl2&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; mouse thereby represents a novel murine model for studying ARDS-like disease that could improve our understanding of this aggressive disease and assist in the design of better diagnostics and treatments.
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cangma Huadu granules attenuate H1N1 virus-induced severe lung injury correlated with repressed apoptosis and altered gut microbiome</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36090063/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36090063/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Severe influenza A virus infection leads to overwhelming inflammatory responses and cellular apoptosis, which causes lung injury and contributes to high mortality and morbidity. The gut microbiome altered in response to the infection might influence the disease progression and the treatment outcome. Cangma Huadu (CMHD) granules, an in-hospital preparation of traditional Chinese medicine, have been shown to be favorable in the clinical treatment of influenza. However, the effects and mechanisms of CMHD granules on severe influenza pneumonia and its mechanisms are not well-known. In this study, a lethal influenza A (H1N1) A/Puerto Rico/8/34 virus (PR8)-infected mice model was established, and the 16S ribosomal RNA (16S rRNA) V3-V4 region sequencing of the intestinal microbiome was conducted. We revealed that the oral administration of CMHD granules protects mice against higher mortality, enhanced weight loss, overwhelmed interferon-γ concentration, lung viral titers, and severe lung pathological injury in PR8-infected mice. CMHD granules&amp;rsquo; administration downregulated the levels of interleukin (IL)-1β, tumor necrosis factor-α, and malondialdehyde, while it upregulated the levels of IL-10, superoxide dismutase, and glutathione peroxidase. Subsequently, it decreased the protein ratio of B-cell lymphoma-2/Bcl-2-associated X and the expression of cleaved caspase-3. The diversity and compositions of the gut microbes were altered profoundly after the administration of CMHD granules in PR8-infected mice. A higher abundance of &lt;em&gt;Bifidobacterium&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Parasutterella&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Bacteroides&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Faecalibaculum&lt;/em&gt; was observed in the CMHD group, and a higher abundance of &lt;em&gt;Lactobacillus&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Turicibacter&lt;/em&gt; was observed in the positive drug Ribavirin group. The linear discriminant analysis effect size also revealed a higher proportion of &lt;em&gt;Bacteroides&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Bifidobacterium_pseudolongum&lt;/em&gt; characterized in the CMHD group. These results demonstrated that CMHD granules are a promising strategy for managing severe influenza and attenuating severe lung damage via reducing viral titer, inflammatory responses, and oxidative stress. The mechanisms are involved in repressed Bcl-2-regulated apoptosis and altered composition and diversity of the gut microbiome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PEtOxylated Interferon-α2a Bioconjugates Addressing H1N1 Influenza A Virus Infection</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35904477/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35904477/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Influenza A viruses (IAV), including the pandemic 2009 (pdm09) H1N1 or avian influenza H5N1 virus, may advance into more pathogenic, potentially antiviral drug-resistant strains (including loss of susceptibility against oseltamivir). Such IAV strains fuel the risk of future global outbreaks, to which this study responds by re-engineering Interferon-α2a (IFN-α2a) bioconjugates into influenza therapeutics. Type-I interferons such as IFN-α2a play an essential role in influenza infection and may prevent serious disease courses. We site-specifically conjugated a genetically engineered IFN-α2a mutant to poly(2-ethyl-2-oxazoline)s (PEtOx) of different molecular weights by strain-promoted azide-alkyne cyclo-addition. The promising pharmacokinetic profile of the 25 kDa PEtOx bioconjugate in mice echoed an efficacy in IAV-infected ferrets. One intraperitoneal administration of this bioconjugate, but not the marketed IFN-α2a bioconjugate, changed the disease course similar to oseltamivir, given orally twice every study day. PEtOxylated IFN-α2a bioconjugates may expand our therapeutic arsenal against future influenza pandemics, particularly in light of rising first-line antiviral drug resistance to IAV.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PSMD12-Mediated M1 Ubiquitination of Influenza A Virus at K102 Regulates Viral Replication</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35861516/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35861516/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The M1 of influenza A virus (IAV) is important for the virus life cycle, especially for the assembly and budding of viruses, which is a multistep process that requires host factors. Identifying novel host proteins that interact with M1 and understanding their functions in IAV replication are of great interest in antiviral drug development. In this study, we identified 19 host proteins in DF1 cells suspected to interact with the M1 protein of an H5N6 virus through immunoprecipitation (IP)/mass spectrometry. Among them, PSMD12, a 26S proteasome regulatory subunit, was shown to interact with influenza M1, acting as a positive host factor in IAV replication in avian and human cells. The data showed that PSMD12 promoted K63-linked ubiquitination of M1 at the K102 site. H5N6 and PR8 with an M1-K102 site mutant displayed a significantly weaker replication ability than the wild-type viruses. Mechanistically, PSMD12 promoted M1-M2 virus-like particle (VLP) release, and an M1-K102 mutation disrupted the formation of supernatant M1-M2 VLPs. An H5N6 M1-K102 site mutation or knockdown PSMD12 disrupted the budding release of the virus in chicken embryo fibroblast (CEF) cells, which was confirmed by transmission electron microscopy. Further study confirmed that M1-K102 site mutation significantly affected the virulence of H5N6 and PR8 viruses in mice. In conclusion, we report the novel host factor PSMD12 which affects the replication of influenza virus by mediating K63-linked ubiquitination of M1 at K102. These findings provide novel insight into the interactions between IAV and host cells, while suggesting an important target for anti-influenza virus drug research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Importance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;M1 is proposed to play multiple biologically important roles in the life cycle of IAV, which relies largely on host factors. This study is the first one to identify that PSMD12 interacts with M1, mediates K63-linked ubiquitination of M1 at the K102 site, and thus positively regulates influenza virus proliferation. PSMD12 promoted M1-M2 VLP egress, and an M1-K102 mutation affected the M1-M2 VLP formation. Furthermore, we demonstrate the importance of this site to the morphology and budding of influenza viruses by obtaining mutant viruses, and the M1 ubiquitination regulator PSMD12 has a similar function to the M1 K102 mutation in regulating virus release and virus morphology. Additionally, we confirm the reduced virulence of H5N6 and PR8 (H1N1) viruses carrying the M1-K102 site mutation in mice. These findings provide novel insights into IAV interactions with host cells and suggest a valid and highly conserved candidate target for antiviral drug development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Human-type sialic acid receptors contribute to avian influenza A virus binding and entry by hetero-multivalent interactions</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35831293/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35831293/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Establishment of zoonotic viruses, causing pandemics like the Spanish flu and Covid-19, requires adaptation to human receptors. Pandemic influenza A viruses (IAV) that crossed the avian-human species barrier switched from binding avian-type α2-3-linked sialic acid (2-3Sia) to human-type 2-6Sia receptors. Here, we show that this specificity switch is however less dichotomous as generally assumed. Binding and entry specificity were compared using mixed synthetic glycan gradients of 2-3Sia and 2-6Sia and by employing a genetically remodeled Sia repertoire on the surface of a Sia-free cell line and on a sialoglycoprotein secreted from these cells. Expression of a range of (mixed) 2-3Sia and 2-6Sia densities shows that non-binding human-type receptors efficiently enhanced avian IAV binding and entry provided the presence of a low density of high affinity avian-type receptors, and vice versa. Considering the heterogeneity of sialoglycan receptors encountered in vivo, hetero-multivalent binding is physiologically relevant and will impact evolutionary pathways leading to host adaptation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recapitulating influenza virus infection and facilitating antiviral and neuroprotective screening in tractable brain organoids</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35910807/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35910807/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Human pluripotent stem cell derived brain organoids offer an unprecedented opportunity for various applications as &lt;em&gt;in vitro&lt;/em&gt; model. Currently, human brain organoids as models have been used to understand virus-induced neurotoxicity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; The brain organoids were separately challenged by multiple viruses including influenza viruses (H1N1-WSN and H3N2-HKT68), Enteroviruses (EV68 and EV71) and Severe Fever with Thrombocytopenia Syndrome Virus (SFTSV) to investigate the impaired effect of these viruses on human brain development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; The brain organoids challenged by influenza viruses had decreased overall organoid size, while enteroviruses infected brain organoids displayed the opposite result. Then, we found WSN preferentially infected MAP2+ neurons compared to SOX2+ neural stem cells (NSCs) and GFAP+ astrocytes in brain organoids, and induced apoptosis of NSCs and neurons, and released inflammatory factors (TNF-α, INF-γ, and IL-6), facilitating brain damage. Furthermore, transcriptional profiling revealed several co-upregulated genes (&lt;em&gt;CSAG3&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;OAS2&lt;/em&gt;) and co-downregulated genes (&lt;em&gt;CDC20B&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;KCNJ13&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;OTX2-AS1&lt;/em&gt;) after WSN infection for 24 hpi and 96 hpi, implicating target for antiviral drugs development. Finally, we explored compound PYC-12 could significantly suppress virus infection, apoptosis, and inflammatory responses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; Collectively, we established a tractable experimental model to investigate the impact and mechanism of virus infection on human brain development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lactiplantibacillus plantarum 0111 Protects Against Influenza Virus by Modulating Intestinal Microbial-Mediated Immune Responses</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35847111/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35847111/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are some limitations of traditional influenza vaccines concerning novel mutant strains. Therefore, it is particularly important to develop preventive means for antigen-unrelated types of influenza viruses. Recent studies have shown that probiotics can modulate the immune system and reduce the severity of viral infections. In this study, we investigated the potential of &lt;em&gt;Lactiplantibacillus plantarum&lt;/em&gt; 0111 against influenza virus H9N2. Challenge experiments showed that &lt;em&gt;L. plantarum&lt;/em&gt; 0111 pretreatments could effectively improve mice&amp;rsquo;s survival rate and weight loss and reduce the inflammatory cytokines IL-6 and TNF-α in the lungs and bronchoalveolar lavage fluid (BALF) along with the degree of lung and intestinal injury. FMT experiment demonstrates that the protective effect produced by &lt;em&gt;L. plantarum&lt;/em&gt; 0111 is associated with gut microorganisms. In addition, 16S high-throughput sequencing of the mouse intestinal microbiota showed that &lt;em&gt;L. plantarum&lt;/em&gt; 0111 remodeled the intestinal microbiota after H9N2 infection and maintained the gut microbiota balance. In a mouse model, the oral administration of &lt;em&gt;L. plantarum&lt;/em&gt; 0111 increased IFN-β expression in the serum and BALF. At the same time, the transcript levels of IFN-β and related ISGs in the intestine and lungs of mice were also increased. In addition, the activation and polarization of T cells in mesenteric lymph nodes (MLNs) and the spleen were detected by flow cytometry, and the results showed that &lt;em&gt;L. plantarum&lt;/em&gt; 0111 modulated cytokines in T cells and increased IgA expression in B cells in the MLNs and spleen. Thus, &lt;em&gt;L. plantarum&lt;/em&gt; 0111 may improve gut microbiota-mediated immune responses and thus, resist infection by the influenza virus, and it could be used as an effective preventive measure against the influenza virus.
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mitochondrial cyclophilin D promotes disease tolerance by licensing NK cell development and IL-22 production against influenza virus</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35732121/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35732121/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mitochondrial CypD is required to protect against severe influenza infection&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CypD expression promotes NK cell lymphopoiesis and maturation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;NK cell-derived IL-22 enhances disease tolerance during influenza infection&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Transfer of WT NK cells confers protection in &lt;em&gt;CypD&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; mice to influenza infection&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Severity of pulmonary viral infections, including influenza A virus (IAV), is linked to excessive immunopathology, which impairs lung function. Thus, the same immune responses that limit viral replication can concomitantly cause lung damage that must be countered by largely uncharacterized disease tolerance mechanisms. Here, we show that mitochondrial cyclophilin D (CypD) protects against IAV via disease tolerance. &lt;em&gt;CypD&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; mice are significantly more susceptible to IAV infection despite comparable antiviral immunity. This susceptibility results from damage to the lung epithelial barrier caused by a reduction in interleukin-22 (IL-22)-producing natural killer (NK) cells. Transcriptomic and functional data reveal that &lt;em&gt;CypD&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; NK cells are immature and have altered cellular metabolism and impaired IL-22 production, correlating with dysregulated bone marrow lymphopoiesis. Administration of recombinant IL-22 or transfer of wild-type (WT) NK cells abrogates pulmonary damage and protects &lt;em&gt;CypD&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; mice after IAV infection. Collectively, these results demonstrate a key role for CypD in NK cell-mediated disease tolerance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SATB1 ensures appropriate transcriptional programs within naïve CD8&#43; T cells</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35713361/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35713361/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Special AT-binding protein 1 (SATB1) is a chromatin-binding protein that has been shown to be a key regulator of T-cell development and CD4&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T-cell fate decisions and function. The underlying function for SATB1 in peripheral CD8&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T-cell differentiation processes is largely unknown. To address this, we examined SATB1-binding patterns in naïve and effector CD8&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T cells demonstrating that SATB1 binds to noncoding regulatory elements linked to T-cell lineage-specific gene programs, particularly in naïve CD8&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T cells. We then assessed SATB1 function using N-ethyl-N-nitrosourea-mutant mice that exhibit a point mutation in the SATB1 DNA-binding domain (termed Satb1m1Anu/m1Anu ). Satb1m1Anu/m1Anu mice exhibit diminished SATB1-binding, naïve, Satb1m1Anu/m1Anu CD8&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T cells exhibiting transcriptional and phenotypic characteristics reminiscent of effector T cells. Upon activation, the transcriptional signatures of Satb1m1Anu/m1Anu and wild-type effector CD8&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T cells converged. While there were no overt differences, primary respiratory infection of Satb1m1Anu/m1Anu mice with influenza A virus (IAV) resulted in a decreased proportion and number of IAV-specific CD8&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; effector T cells recruited to the infected lung when compared with wild-type mice. Together, these data suggest that SATB1 has a major role in an appropriate transcriptional state within naïve CD8&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T cells and ensures appropriate CD8&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T-cell effector gene expression upon activation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The protective effect of Tilia amurensis honey on influenza A virus infection through stimulation of interferon-mediated IFITM3 signaling</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35717782/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35717782/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;TH inhibit infection of influenza A virus in murine macrophages.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;TH activates the type-1 interferon related pathway including TBK-STAT signaling.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;TH increases expression of IFN-stimulating genes (ISG’s) and IFN-inducible transmembrane 3 (IFITM3)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;TH could be a potential preventive and therapeutic agents for influenza A virus by modulating the regulates innate immune response.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently, attention has focused on the prevention and treatment of respiratory viruses including influenza viruses. We evaluated the antiviral effect of &lt;em&gt;Tilia amurensis&lt;/em&gt; honey (TH) against influenza A virus in murine macrophages. Influenza A virus infection was reduced following pretreatment with TH. Pretreatment of murine macrophages with TH increased the production and secretion of type-1 interferon (IFN) and proinflammatory cytokines and increased phosphorylation of the type-1 IFN-related proteins, TANK-binding kinase (TBK), and STAT. Moreover, TH increased the expression of IFN-stimulating genes and increased the expression of IFN-inducible transmembrane (IFITM3), a protein that interferes with virus replication and entry. Taken together, these findings suggest that TH suppresses influenza A virus infection by regulating the innate immune response in macrophages. This supports the development of preventive and therapeutic agents for influenza A virus and enhances the economic value of TH.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LncNSPL facilitates influenza A viral immune escape by restricting TRIM25-mediated K63-linked RIG-I ubiquitination</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35800772/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35800772/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;NS1 protein of Influenza A virus (IAV) promotes lncNSPL expression&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deficiency of lncNSPL specifically enhances retinoic acid-inducible gene I (RIG-I) initiated IFN production&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;lncNSPL competes with tripartite interaction motif 25 (TRIM25) for binding RIG-I and inhibits its K63 ubiquitination&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;lncNSPL inhibits innate antiviral immune responses and enhances viral replication&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Long noncoding RNAs (lncRNAs) participate in host antiviral responses; however, how viruses exploit host lncRNAs for immune evasion remains largely unexplored. Functional screening of differentially expressed lncRNA profile in patients infected with influenza A virus (IAV) revealed that lncNSPL (Gene Symbol: LOC105370355) was highly expressed in monocytes. Deregulated lncNSPL expression in infected monocytes significantly increased type I interferon (IFN-I) production and inhibited IAV replication. Moreover, lncNSPL overexpression in mice increased the susceptibility to IAV infection and impaired IFN-I production. LncNSPL directly bound to retinoic acid-inducible gene I (RIG-I) and blocked the interaction between RIG-I and E3 ligase tripartite interaction motif 25 (TRIM25), reducing TRIM25-mediated lysine 63 (K63)-linked RIG-I ubiquitination and limiting the downstream production of antiviral mediators during the late stage of IAV infection. Our findings provide mechanistic insights into the means by which lncNSPL promotes IAV replication and immune escape via restricting the TRIM25-mediated RIG-I K63-linked ubiquitination. Thus, lncNSPL may represent a promising pharmaceutical target for anti-IAV therapy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Influenza A virus undergoes compartmentalized replication in vivo dominated by stochastic bottlenecks</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35701424/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35701424/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Transmission of influenza A viruses (IAV) between hosts is subject to numerous physical and biological barriers that impose genetic bottlenecks, constraining viral diversity and adaptation. The bottlenecks within hosts and their potential impacts on evolutionary pathways taken during infection are poorly understood. To address this, we created highly diverse IAV libraries bearing molecular barcodes on two gene segments, enabling high-resolution tracking and quantification of unique virus lineages within hosts. Here we show that IAV infection in lungs is characterized by multiple within-host bottlenecks that result in &amp;ldquo;islands&amp;rdquo; of infection in lung lobes, each with genetically distinct populations. We perform site-specific inoculation of barcoded IAV in the upper respiratory tract of ferrets and track viral diversity as infection spreads to the trachea and lungs. We detect extensive compartmentalization of discrete populations within lung lobes. Bottleneck events and localized replication stochastically sample individual viruses from the upper respiratory tract or the trachea that become the dominant genotype in a particular lobe. These populations are shaped strongly by founder effects, with limited evidence for positive selection. The segregated sites of replication highlight the jackpot-style events that contribute to within-host influenza virus evolution and may account for low rates of intrahost adaptation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Electronic cigarette vapor exposure exaggerates the pro-inflammatory response during influenza A viral infection in human distal airway epithelium</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35672461/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35672461/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Electronic cigarettes or vaping products have been marketed as a safer alternative to smoking, but very little is known about the health effects in the human lung, particularly in the distal airways, a key site of airway obstruction and destruction in chronic obstructive pulmonary disease that is often exacerbated by viral infections. The aim of this study was to investigate the effects of electronic cigarette vapor (e-vapor) on human distal airway epithelial responses to influenza A virus (IAV) infection. We isolated primary small airway epithelial cells (SAECs) from donor lungs free of lung disease, and cultured them at air-liquid interface (ALI). To measure markers of epithelial injury such as integrity of epithelial barrier structure and function, we selected a regimen of non-toxic, barrier preserving e-vapor exposure of cultured cells to 15 puffs of e-vapor from a commercially available e-cigarette once per day for 3 days, prior to IAV infection. After 72 h of infection, media and cell lysates were collected to measure cytokines involved in inflammatory and antiviral responses. Pre-exposure to e-vapor with IAV infection, compared to IAV infection alone, significantly increased inflammatory and antiviral mediators including IL-8, CXCL10, IFN-beta, and MX1. Our results suggest that e-vapor exposure amplifies human distal airway pro-inflammatory response to IAV infection, independently of the severity of cell injury during viral infection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The C-terminal LCAR of host ANP32 proteins interacts with the influenza A virus nucleoprotein to promote the replication of the viral RNA genome</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35639917/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35639917/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The segmented negative-sense RNA genome of influenza A virus is assembled into ribonucleoprotein complexes (RNP) with viral RNA-dependent RNA polymerase and nucleoprotein (NP). It is in the context of these RNPs that the polymerase transcribes and replicates viral RNA (vRNA). Host acidic nuclear phosphoprotein 32 (ANP32) family proteins play an essential role in vRNA replication by mediating the dimerization of the viral polymerase via their N-terminal leucine-rich repeat (LRR) domain. However, whether the C-terminal low-complexity acidic region (LCAR) plays a role in RNA synthesis remains unknown. Here, we report that the LCAR is required for viral genome replication during infection. Specifically, we show that the LCAR directly interacts with NP and this interaction is mutually exclusive with RNA. Furthermore, we show that the replication of a short vRNA-like template that can be replicated in the absence of NP is less sensitive to LCAR truncations compared with the replication of full-length vRNA segments which is NP-dependent. We propose a model in which the LCAR interacts with NP to promote NP recruitment to nascent RNA during influenza virus replication, ensuring the co-replicative assembly of RNA into RNPs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Disrupting the HDAC6-ubiquitin interaction impairs infection by influenza and Zika virus and cellular stress pathways</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35476995/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35476995/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A small synthetic protein (DARPin) blocks interaction between HDAC6 and ubiquitin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This DARPin impairs infection by influenza and Zika virus at the uncoating step&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Both viruses contain ubiquitin associated with their capsid&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The DARPin also impacts the formation of aggresomes and stress granules&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The deacetylase HDAC6 has tandem catalytic domains and a zinc finger domain (ZnF) binding ubiquitin (Ub). While the catalytic domain has an antiviral effect, the ZnF facilitates influenza A virus (IAV) infection and cellular stress responses. By recruiting Ub via the ZnF, HDAC6 promotes the formation of aggresomes and stress granules (SGs), dynamic structures associated with pathologies such as neurodegeneration. IAV subverts the aggresome/HDAC6 pathway to facilitate capsid uncoating during early infection. To target this pathway, we generate designed ankyrin repeat proteins (DARPins) binding the ZnF; one of these prevents interaction with Ub in vitro and in cells. Crystallographic analysis shows that it blocks the ZnF pocket where Ub engages. Conditional expression of this DARPin reversibly impairs infection by IAV and Zika virus; moreover, SGs and aggresomes are downregulated. These results validate the HDAC6 ZnF as an attractive target for drug discovery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Methodology to Detect Biological Particles Using a Biosensing Surface Integrated in Resistive Pulse Sensing</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35446533/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35446533/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Resistive pulse sensing (RPS) is an analytical method that can be used to individually count particles from a small sample. RPS simply monitors the physical characteristics of particles, such as size, shape, and charge density, and the integration of RPS with biosensing is an attractive theme to detect biological particles such as virus and bacteria. In this report, a methodology of biosensing on RPS was investigated. Polydopamine (PD), an adhesive component of mussels, was used as the base material to create a sensing surface. PD adheres to most materials, such as noble metals, metal oxides, semiconductors, and polymers; as a result, PD is a versatile intermediate layer for the fabrication of a biosensing surface. As an example of a biological particle, human influenza A virus (H1N1 subtype) was used to monitor translocation of particles through the pore membrane. When virus-specific ligands (6&amp;rsquo;-sialyllactose) were immobilized on the pore surface, the translocation time of the virus particles was considerably extended. The detailed translocation data suggest that the viral particles were trapped on the sensing surface by specific interactions. In addition, virus translocation processes on different pore surfaces were distinguished using machine learning. The result shows that the simple and versatile PD-based biosensor surface design was effective. This advanced RPS measurement system could be a promising analytical technique.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An anti-influenza A virus microbial metabolite acts by degrading viral endonuclease PA</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35440123/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35440123/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The emergence of new highly pathogenic and drug-resistant influenza strains urges the development of novel therapeutics for influenza A virus (IAV). Here, we report the discovery of an anti-IAV microbial metabolite called APL-16-5 that was originally isolated from the plant endophytic fungus Aspergillus sp. CPCC 400735. APL-16-5 binds to both the E3 ligase TRIM25 and IAV polymerase subunit PA, leading to TRIM25 ubiquitination of PA and subsequent degradation of PA in the proteasome. This mode of action conforms to that of a proteolysis targeting chimera which employs the cellular ubiquitin-proteasome machinery to chemically induce the degradation of target proteins. Importantly, APL-16-5 potently inhibits IAV and protects mice from lethal IAV infection. Therefore, we have identified a natural microbial metabolite with potent in vivo anti-IAV activity and the potential of becoming a new IAV therapeutic. The antiviral mechanism of APL-16-5 opens the possibility of improving its anti-IAV potency and specificity by adjusting its affinity for TRIM25 and viral PA protein through medicinal chemistry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Biorecognition Layer Based On Biotin-Containing [1]Benzothieno[3,2- b][1]benzothiophene Derivative for Biosensing by Electrolyte-Gated Organic Field-Effect Transistors</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35357127/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35357127/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Requirements of speed and simplicity in testing stimulate the development of modern biosensors. Electrolyte-gated organic field-effect transistors (EGOFETs) are a promising platform for ultrasensitive, fast, and reliable detection of biological molecules for low-cost, point-of-care bioelectronic sensing. Biosensitivity of the EGOFET devices can be achieved by modification with receptors of one of the electronic active interfaces of the transistor gate or organic semiconductor surface. Functionalization of the latter gives the advantage in the creation of a planar architecture and compact devices for lab-on-chip design. Herein, we propose a universal, fast, and simple technique based on doctor blading and Langmuir-Schaefer methods for functionalization of the semiconducting surface of C8-BTBT-C8, allowing the fabrication of a large-scale biorecognition layer based on the novel functional derivative of BTBT-containing biotin fragments as a foundation for further biomodification. The fabricated devices are very efficient and operate stably in phosphate-buffered saline solution with high reproducibility of electrical properties in the EGOFET regime. The development of biorecognition properties of the proposed biolayer is based on the streptavidin-biotin interactions between the consecutive layers and can be used for a wide variety of receptors. As a proof-of-concept, we demonstrate the specific response of the BTBT-based biorecognition layer in EGOFETs to influenza A virus (H7N1 strain). The elaborated approach to biorecognition layer formation is appropriate but not limited to aptamer-based receptor molecules and can be further applied for fabricating several biosensors for various analytes on one substrate and paves the way for &amp;ldquo;electronic tongue&amp;rdquo; creation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chrysin Ameliorates Influenza Virus Infection in the Upper Airways by Repressing Virus-Induced Cell Cycle Arrest and Mitochondria-Dependent Apoptosis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35432374/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35432374/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chrysin has been proven to possess antiviral properties, but the precise underlying anti-influenza mechanism and its anti-influenza efficacy in vivo are largely unclear. In this study, we investigated the involvement of chrysin in the blockade of cell cycle and apoptosis in distinct cell lines subjected to two H1N1 influenza A virus (IAV) strains, as well as its anti-IAV activity in vivo. Here, we found an early unidentified finding that chrysin strongly impeded IAV replication through a mechanism that was autonomous of innate antiviral immune activation and viral protein interaction. Surprisingly, chrysin can suppress IAV-induced cell cycle arrest in the G0/G1 phase by downregulating the expression levels of P53 and P21 while promoting Cyclin D1/CDK4 and Cyclin E1/CDK2 activation. Furthermore, chrysin dramatically inhibited the IAV-triggered mitochondrial apoptotic pathway by altering the balance of Bax/Bcl-xl and reducing caspase-9 and caspase-3 activation. Accumulated reactive oxygen species (ROS) reduction may contribute to the inhibitory role of chrysin in cell cycle arrest and apoptosis following IAV infection. Notably, chrysin preferably inhibited IAV replication in the upper respiratory tract, indicating that it might be a promising drug for restraining the spread of respiratory viruses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Avian influenza viruses suppress innate immunity by inducing trans-transcriptional readthrough via SSU72</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35332300/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35332300/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Innate immunity plays critical antiviral roles. The highly virulent avian influenza viruses (AIVs) H5N1, H7N9, and H5N6 can better escape host innate immune responses than the less virulent seasonal H1N1 virus. Here, we report a mechanism by which transcriptional readthrough (TRT)-mediated suppression of innate immunity occurs post AIV infection. By using cell lines, mouse lungs, and patient PBMCs, we showed that genes on the complementary strand (&amp;ldquo;trans&amp;rdquo; genes) influenced by TRT were involved in the disruption of host antiviral responses during AIV infection. The trans-TRT enhanced viral lethality, and TRT abolishment increased cell viability and STAT1/2 expression. The viral NS1 protein directly bound to SSU72, and degradation of SSU72 induced TRT. SSU72 overexpression reduced TRT and alleviated mouse lung injury. Our results suggest that AIVs infection induce TRT by reducing SSU72 expression, thereby impairing host immune responses, a molecular mechanism acting through the NS1-SSU72-trans-TRT-STAT1/2 axis. Thus, restoration of SSU72 expression might be a potential strategy for preventing AIV pandemics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Syk Facilitates Influenza A Virus Replication by Restraining Innate Immunity at the Late Stage of Viral Infection</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35293768/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35293768/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spleen tyrosine kinase (Syk) has recently come forth as a critical regulator of innate immune response. Previous studies identify Syk as a key kinase for STAT1 activation at the early stage of influenza A virus (IAV) infection that is involved in initial antiviral immunity. However, the involvement of Syk in host antiviral immunity during the late phase of IAV infection and its effect on pathogenesis of the virus remain unknown. Here, we found through time course studies that Syk restrained antiviral immune response at the late stage of IAV infection, thereby promoting viral replication. Depletion of Syk suppressed IAV replication &lt;em&gt;in vitro&lt;/em&gt;, whereas ectopic expression of Syk facilitated viral replication. Moreover, Syk-deficient mice were employed, and we observed that knockout of Syk rendered mice more resistant to IAV infection, as evidenced by a lower degree of lung injury, slower body weight loss, and an increased survival rate of Syk knockout mice challenged with IAV. Furthermore, we revealed that Syk repressed the interferon response at the late stage of viral infection. Loss of Syk potentiated the expression of type I and III interferons in both Syk-depleted cells and mice. Mechanistically, Syk interacted with TBK1 and modulated its phosphorylation status, thereby impeding TBK1 activation and restraining innate immune signaling that governs interferon response. Together, these findings unveil a role of Syk in temporally regulating host antiviral immunity and advance our understanding of complicated mechanisms underlying regulation of innate immunity against viral invasion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Importance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Innate immunity must be tightly controlled to eliminate invading pathogens while avoiding autoimmune or inflammatory diseases. Syk is essential for STAT1 activation at the early stage of IAV infection, which is critical for initial antiviral responses. Surprisingly, here a time course study showed that Syk suppressed innate immunity during late phases of IAV infection and thereby promoted IAV replication. Syk deficiency enhanced the expression of type I and III interferons, inhibited IAV replication, and rendered mice more resistant to IAV infection. Syk impaired innate immune signaling through impeding TBK1 activation. These data reveal that Syk participates in the initiation of antiviral defense against IAV infection and simultaneously contributes to the restriction of innate immunity at the late stage of viral infection, suggesting that Syk serves a dual function in regulating antiviral responses. This finding provides new insights into complicated mechanisms underlying interaction between virus and host immune system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aberrant Cellular Glycosylation May Increase the Ability of Influenza Viruses to Escape Host Immune Responses through Modification of the Viral Glycome</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35285699/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35285699/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Individuals with metabolic dysregulation of cellular glycosylation often experience severe influenza disease, with a poor immune response to the virus and low vaccine efficacy. Here, we investigate the consequences of aberrant cellular glycosylation for the glycome and the biology of influenza virus. We transiently induced aberrant N-linked glycosylation in cultured cells with an oligosaccharyltransferase inhibitor, NGI-1. Cells treated with NGI-1 produced morphologically unaltered viable influenza virus with sequence-neutral glycosylation changes (primarily reduced site occupancy) in the hemagglutinin and neuraminidase proteins. Hemagglutinin with reduced glycan occupancy required a higher concentration of surfactant protein D (an important innate immunity respiratory tract collectin) for inhibition compared to that with normal glycan occupancy. Immunization of mice with NGI-1-treated virus significantly reduced antihemagglutinin and antineuraminidase titers of total serum antibody and reduced hemagglutinin protective antibody responses. Our data suggest that aberrant cellular glycosylation may increase the risk of severe influenza as a result of the increased ability of glycome-modified influenza viruses to evade the immune response.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Importance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People with disorders such as cancer, autoimmune disease, diabetes, or obesity often have metabolic dysregulation of cellular glycosylation and also have more severe influenza disease, a reduced immune response to the virus, and reduced vaccine efficacy. Since influenza viruses that infect such people do not show consistent genomic variations, it is generally assumed that the altered biology is mainly related to host factors. However, since host cells are responsible for glycosylation of influenza virus hemagglutinin and neuraminidase, and glycosylation is important for interactions of these proteins with the immune system, the viruses may have functional differences that are not reflected by their genomic sequence. Here, we show that imbalanced cellular glycosylation can modify the viral glycome without genomic changes, leading to reduced innate and adaptive host immune responses to infection. Our findings link metabolic dysregulation of host glycosylation to increased risk of severe influenza and reduced influenza virus vaccine efficacy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The RNA helicase DHX16 recognizes specific viral RNA to trigger RIG-I-dependent innate antiviral immunity</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35263596/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35263596/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An unanchored ubiquitin-binding screen links DHX16 to innate immune recognition&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;DHX16 amplifies RIG-I-dependent innate antiviral immune responses&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;TRIM6 promotes association of unanchored K48-poly-Ub with DHX16&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;DHX16 acts as a pattern recognition receptor sensing splicing signals in vRNA&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Type I interferons (IFN-I) are essential to establish antiviral innate immunity. Unanchored (or free) polyubiquitin (poly-Ub) has been shown to regulate IFN-I responses. However, few unanchored poly-Ub interactors are known. To identify factors regulated by unanchored poly-Ub in a physiological setting, we developed an approach to isolate unanchored poly-Ub from lung tissue. We identified the RNA helicase DHX16 as a potential pattern recognition receptor (PRR). Silencing of DHX16 in cells and in vivo diminished IFN-I responses against influenza virus. These effects extended to members of other virus families, including Zika and SARS-CoV-2. DHX16-dependent IFN-I production requires RIG-I and unanchored K48-poly-Ub synthesized by the E3-Ub ligase TRIM6. DHX16 recognizes a signal in influenza RNA segments that undergo splicing and requires its RNA helicase motif for direct, high-affinity interactions with specific viral RNAs. Our study establishes DHX16 as a PRR that partners with RIG-I for optimal activation of antiviral immunity requiring unanchored poly-Ub.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Osteopontin aggravates acute lung injury in influenza virus infection by promoting macrophages necroptosis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35246529/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35246529/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Infection with influenza A virus (IAV) can trigger pulmonary inflammation and lung damage. Osteopontin (OPN) is an essential regulator of cell death and immunity. However, the role and underlying mechanism of OPN in cell death in IAV-induced pulmonary injury remain poorly understood. Here, we demonstrated that OPN-deficient (OPN-/-) mice were insensitive to IAV, exhibiting decreased viral loads and attenuated lung injury after IAV infection compared to those in wild-type (WT) mice. Moreover, macrophage necroptosis was significantly reduced in OPN-/- mice infected with IAV compared to that in infected WT mice. OPN increased the expression of necroptosis-related genes and exacerbated macrophage necroptosis in IAV-infected THP1 cells. Notably, adoptive transfer of WT bone marrow-derived macrophages (BMDMs) or OPN-/- BMDMs into mice restored resistance to influenza infection, and the rescue effect of OPN-/- BMDMs was better than that of WT BMDMs. Collectively, these results suggest that OPN deficiency in macrophages reduces necroptosis, which leads to a decrease in viral titers and protects against IAV infection. Therefore, OPN is a potential target for the treatment of IAV infection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The inhibition effects and mechanisms of sulfated chitooligosaccharides on influenza A virus in vitro and in vivo</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35337521/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35337521/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sulfated chitooligosaccharide was reported to possess inhibition effect on human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) entry into host cells. Herein, we prepared chitooligosaccharide COS and its sulfate derivative SCOS and explored whether the sulfation modification can enhance the anti-influenza A virus (IAV) activity of COS. Interestingly, we discovered that SCOS possessed broad-spectrum anti-IAV effects with low toxicity, while the non-sulfated chitooligosaccharide COS had very low inhibition on IAV, verifying that the sulfation modification is essential for the anti-IAV actions of chitooligosaccharide. SCOS may target virus hemagglutinin (HA) protein to block both virus adsorption and membrane fusion processes. Oral administration of SCOS significantly decreased pulmonary viral titers and improved survival rate in IAV infected mice, comparable to the effects of Oseltamivir. Therefore, our findings support further studies on the use of SCOS as a novel entry inhibitor for IAV and as a supplement to current therapeutics for influenza.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Systematic optimization of host-directed therapeutic targets and preclinical validation of repositioned antiviral drugs</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35238349/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35238349/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inhibition of host protein functions using established drugs produces a promising antiviral effect with excellent safety profiles, decreased incidence of resistant variants and favorable balance of costs and risks. Genomic methods have produced a large number of robust host factors, providing candidates for identification of antiviral drug targets. However, there is a lack of global perspectives and systematic prioritization of known virus-targeted host proteins (VTHPs) and drug targets. There is also a need for host-directed repositioned antivirals. Here, we integrated 6140 VTHPs and grouped viral infection modes from a new perspective of enriched pathways of VTHPs. Clarifying the superiority of nonessential membrane and hub VTHPs as potential ideal targets for repositioned antivirals, we proposed 543 candidate VTHPs. We then presented a large-scale drug-virus network (DVN) based on matching these VTHPs and drug targets. We predicted possible indications for 703 approved drugs against 35 viruses and explored their potential as broad-spectrum antivirals. &lt;em&gt;In vitro&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt; tests validated the efficacy of bosutinib, maraviroc and dextromethorphan against human herpesvirus 1 (HHV-1), hepatitis B virus (HBV) and influenza A virus (IAV). Their drug synergy with clinically used antivirals was evaluated and confirmed. The results proved that low-dose dextromethorphan is better than high-dose in both single and combined treatments. This study provides a comprehensive landscape and optimization strategy for druggable VTHPs, constructing an innovative and potent pipeline to discover novel antiviral host proteins and repositioned drugs, which may facilitate their delivery to clinical application in translational medicine to combat fatal and spreading viral infections.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interferon-γ promotes monocyte-mediated lung injury during influenza infection</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35235782/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35235782/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CD8&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T cells are primary contributors to pathologic IFN-γ response during IAV infection&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IFN-γ regulates the pathologic phenotype of CCR2&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; monocytes during IAV infection&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IFN-γ deficiency mitigates IAV-mediated lung injury and improves barrier integrity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IFN-γ is dispensable to IAV clearance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Influenza A virus (IAV) infection triggers an exuberant host response that promotes acute lung injury. However, the host response factors that promote the development of a pathologic inflammatory response to IAV remain incompletely understood. In this study, we identify an interferon-γ (IFN-γ)-regulated subset of monocytes, CCR2&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; monocytes, as a driver of lung damage during IAV infection. IFN-γ regulates the recruitment and inflammatory phenotype of CCR2&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; monocytes, and mice deficient in CCR2 (CCR2&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt;) or IFN-γ (IFN-γ&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt;) exhibit reduced lung inflammation, pathology, and disease severity. Adoptive transfer of wild-type (WT) (IFN-γR1&lt;sup&gt;+/+&lt;/sup&gt;) but not IFN-γR1&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt; CCR2&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; monocytes restore the WT-like pathological phenotype of lung damage in IAV-infected CCR2&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt; mice. CD8&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T cells are the main source of IFN-γ in IAV-infected lungs. Collectively, our data highlight the requirement of IFN-γ signaling in the regulation of CCR2&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; monocyte-mediated lung pathology during IAV infection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VPS29 Exerts Opposing Effects on Endocytic Viral Entry</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35229640/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35229640/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Emerging zoonotic viral pathogens threaten global health, and there is an urgent need to discover host and viral determinants influencing infection. We performed a loss-of-function genome-wide CRISPR screen in a human lung cell line using HCoV-OC43, a human betacoronavirus. One candidate gene, VPS29, a component of the retromer complex, was required for infection by HCoV-OC43, SARS-CoV-2, other endemic- and pandemic-threat coronaviruses, as well as ebolavirus. Notably, we observed a heightened requirement for VPS29 by the recently described Omicron variant of SARS-CoV-2 compared to the ancestral variant. However, VPS29 deficiency had no effect on certain other viruses that enter cells via endosomes and had an opposing, enhancing effect on influenza A virus infection. Deficiency in VPS29 or other retromer components caused changes in endosome morphology and acidity and attenuated the activity of endosomal proteases. These changes in endosome properties caused incoming coronavirus, but not influenza virus particles, to become entrapped therein. Overall, these data show how host regulation of endosome characteristics can influence cellular susceptibility to viral infection and identify a host pathway that could serve as a pharmaceutical target for intervention in zoonotic viral diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Importance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These data identify a host pathway by which VPS29 and associated factors control the endosomal environment in a manner that influences susceptibility to viral infection. This pathway could serve as a pharmaceutical target for intervention in zoonotic viral diseases, including those caused by coronaviruses, influenza viruses, and filoviruses, all of which are pandemic threats. Our findings show how host regulation of endosome characteristics can influence viral susceptibility in both a positive and negative manner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prompt Antiviral Action of Pulmonary CD8&#43; TRM Cells Is Mediated by Rapid IFN-γ Induction and Its Downstream ISGs in the Lung</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35296070/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35296070/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Growing lines of evidence supported the importance of CD8&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; lung tissue resident memory T (T&lt;sub&gt;RM&lt;/sub&gt;) cells in protection against respiratory viruses, exemplified by influenza A virus. However, the underlying &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt; mechanism remains largely undetermined. Here, we used mouse infection models to dissect &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt; cross-protective activity of lung CD8&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T&lt;sub&gt;RM&lt;/sub&gt; cells. By simultaneously interrogating transcriptional dynamics in lung CD8&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T&lt;sub&gt;RM&lt;/sub&gt; cells and surrounding tissues during the early course of infection, we demonstrated that lung CD8&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T&lt;sub&gt;RM&lt;/sub&gt; cells react to antigen re-exposure within hours, manifested by IFN-γ upregulation, and a tissue-wide interferon-stimulated gene (ISG) program is subsequently elicited. Using antibody-mediated IFN-γ neutralization and IFN-γ receptor knockout mice, we could show that the induction of several important antiviral ISGs required IFN-γ signaling, so did the suppression of key inflammatory cytokines. Interestingly, there were also examples of ISGs unaffected in the absence of IFN-γ activity. Collectively, focusing on &lt;em&gt;in situ&lt;/em&gt; characterization of lung CD8&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T&lt;sub&gt;RM&lt;/sub&gt; cells during very early stage of infection, a critical period of host antiviral defense that has been poorly investigated, our studies highlight that these cells, once triggered by antigen re-exposure, are programmed to produce IFN-γ expeditiously to promote a lung-wide antiviral response for effective virus control.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BCG vaccination provides protection against IAV but not SARS-CoV-2</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35235831/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35235831/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;BCG vaccination provides significant protection against IAV in mice and hamsters&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;BCG provides no protection against SARS-CoV-2 in mice and hamsters&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SARS-CoV-2 induces pulmonary hemorrhage and disseminates to the bone marrow&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Monocytes from BCG-vaccinated humans induce more cytokines to IAV than SARS-CoV-2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since the vast majority of species solely rely on innate immunity for host defense, it stands to reason that a critical evolutionary trait like immunological memory evolved in this primitive branch of our immune system. There is ample evidence that vaccines such as bacillus Calmette-Guérin (BCG) induce protective innate immune memory responses (trained immunity) against heterologous pathogens. Here we show that while BCG vaccination significantly reduces morbidity and mortality against influenza A virus (IAV), it fails to provide protection against severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus-2 (SARS-CoV-2). In contrast to IAV, SARS-CoV-2 infection leads to unique pulmonary vasculature damage facilitating viral dissemination to other organs, including the bone marrow (BM), a central site for BCG-mediated trained immunity. Finally, monocytes from BCG-vaccinated individuals mount an efficient cytokine response to IAV infection, while this response is minimal following SARS-CoV-2. Collectively, our data suggest that the protective capacity of BCG vaccination is contingent on viral pathogenesis and tissue tropism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enantiomer-dependent immunological response to chiral nanoparticles</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35046606/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35046606/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chirality is a unifying structural metric of biological and abiological forms of matter. Over the past decade, considerable clarity has been achieved in understanding the chemistry and physics of chiral inorganic nanoparticles; however, little is known about their effects on complex biochemical networks. Intermolecular interactions of biological molecules and inorganic nanoparticles show some commonalities, but these structures differ in scale, in geometry and in the dynamics of chiral shapes, which can both impede and strengthen their mirror-asymmetric complexes. Here we show that achiral and left- and right-handed gold biomimetic nanoparticles show different &lt;em&gt;in vitro&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt; immune responses. We use irradiation with circularly polarized light (CPL) to synthesize nanoparticles with controllable nanometre-scale chirality and optical anisotropy factors (g-factors) of up to 0.4. We find that binding of nanoparticles to two proteins from the family of adhesion G-protein-coupled receptors (AGPCRs)-namely cluster-of-differentiation 97 (CD97) and epidermal-growth-factor-like-module receptor 1 (EMR1)-results in the opening of mechanosensitive potassium-efflux channels, the production of immune signalling complexes known as inflammasomes, and the maturation of mouse bone-marrow-derived dendritic cells. Both &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;in vitro&lt;/em&gt; immune responses depend monotonically on the g-factors of the nanoparticles, indicating that nanoscale chirality can be used to regulate the maturation of immune cells. Finally, left-handed nanoparticles show substantially higher (1,258-fold) efficiency compared with their right-handed counterparts as adjuvants for vaccination against the H9N2 influenza virus, opening a path to the use of nanoscale chirality in immunology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cis-acting lnc-Cxcl2 restrains neutrophil-mediated lung inflammation by inhibiting epithelial cell CXCL2 expression in virus infection</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34607953/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34607953/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chemokine production by epithelial cells is important for neutrophil recruitment during viral infection, the appropriate regulation of which is critical for restraining inflammation and attenuating subsequent tissue damage. Epithelial cell expression of long noncoding RNAs (lncRNAs), RNA-binding proteins, and their functional interactions during viral infection and inflammation remain to be fully understood. Here, we identified an inducible lncRNA in the &lt;em&gt;Cxcl2&lt;/em&gt; gene locus, lnc-Cxcl2, which could selectively inhibit &lt;em&gt;Cxcl2&lt;/em&gt; expression in mouse lung epithelial cells but not in macrophages. lnc-Cxcl2-deficient mice exhibited increased &lt;em&gt;Cxcl2&lt;/em&gt; expression, enhanced neutrophils recruitment, and more severe inflammation in the lung after influenza virus infection. Mechanistically, nucleus-localized lnc-Cxcl2 bound to &lt;em&gt;Cxcl2&lt;/em&gt; promoter, recruited a ribonucleoprotein La, which inhibited the chromatin accessibility of chemokine promoters, and consequently inhibited &lt;em&gt;Cxcl2&lt;/em&gt; transcription in cis However, unlike mouse lnc-Cxcl2, human lnc-CXCL2-4-1 inhibited multiple immune cytokine expressions including chemokines in human lung epithelial cells. Together, our results demonstrate a self-protecting mechanism within epithelial cells to restrain chemokine and neutrophil-mediated inflammation, providing clues for better understanding chemokine regulation and epithelial cell function in lung viral infection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MARCH8 inhibits influenza A virus infection by targeting viral M2 protein for ubiquitination-dependent degradation in lysosomes</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34285233/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34285233/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The membrane-associated RING-CH (MARCH) proteins are E3 ligases that regulate the stability of various cellular membrane proteins. MARCH8 has been reported to inhibit the infection of HIV-1 and a few other viruses, thus plays an important role in host antiviral defense. However, the antiviral spectrum and the underlying mechanisms of MARCH8 are incompletely defined. Here, we demonstrate that MARCH8 profoundly inhibits influenza A virus (IAV) replication both in vitro and in mice. Mechanistically, MARCH8 suppresses IAV release through redirecting viral M2 protein from the plasma membrane to lysosomes for degradation. Specifically, MARCH8 catalyzes the K63-linked polyubiquitination of M2 at lysine residue 78 (K78). A recombinant A/Puerto Rico/8/34 virus carrying the K78R M2 protein shows greater replication and more severe pathogenicity in cells and mice. More importantly, we found that the M2 protein of the H1N1 IAV has evolved to acquire non-lysine amino acids at positions 78/79 to resist MARCH8-mediated ubiquitination and degradation. Together, our data support the important role of MARCH8 in host anti-IAV intrinsic immune defense by targeting M2, and suggest the inhibitory pressure of MARCH8 on H1N1 IAV transmission in the human population.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IFI16 directly senses viral RNA and enhances RIG-I transcription and activation to restrict influenza virus infection</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33986530/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33986530/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The retinoic acid-inducible gene I (RIG-I) receptor senses cytoplasmic viral RNA and activates type I interferons (IFN-I) and downstream antiviral immune responses. How RIG-I binds to viral RNA and how its activation is regulated remains unclear. Here, using IFI16 knockout cells and p204-deficient mice, we demonstrate that the DNA sensor IFI16 enhances IFN-I production to inhibit influenza A virus (IAV) replication. IFI16 positively upregulates RIG-I transcription through direct binding to and recruitment of RNA polymerase II to the RIG-I promoter. IFI16 also binds to influenza viral RNA via its HINa domain and to RIG-I protein with its PYRIN domain, thus promoting IAV-induced K63-linked polyubiquitination and RIG-I activation. Our work demonstrates that IFI16 is a positive regulator of RIG-I signalling during influenza virus infection, highlighting its role in the RIG-I-like-receptor-mediated innate immune response to IAV and other RNA viruses, and suggesting its possible exploitation to modulate the antiviral response.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Selective usage of ANP32 proteins by influenza B virus polymerase: Implications in determination of host range</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33045004/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33045004/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The influenza B virus (IBV) causes seasonal influenza and has accounted for an increasing proportion of influenza outbreaks. IBV mainly causes human infections and has not been found to spread in poultry. The replication mechanism and the determinants of interspecies transmission of IBV are largely unknown. In this study, we found that the host ANP32 proteins are required for the function of the IBV polymerase. Human ANP32A/B strongly supports IBV replication, while ANP32E has a limited role. Unlike human ANP32A/B, chicken ANP32A has low support activity to IBV polymerase because of a unique 33-amino-acid insert, which, in contrast, exhibits species specific support to avian influenza A virus (IAV) replication. Chicken ANP32B and ANP32E have even lower activity compared with human ANP32B/E due to specific amino acid substitutions at sites 129-130. We further revealed that the sites 129-130 affect the binding ability of ANP32B/E to IBV polymerase, while the 33-amino-acid insert of chicken ANP32A reduces its binding stability and affinity. Taken together, the features of avian ANP32 proteins limited their abilities to support IBV polymerase, which could prevent efficient replication of IBV in chicken cells. Our results illustrate roles of ANP32 proteins in supporting IBV replication and may help to understand the ineffective replication of IBV in birds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FluPhenotype-a one-stop platform for early warnings of the influenza A virus</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32049310/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32049310/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.computationalbiology.cn:18888/IVEW&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;FluPhenotype&lt;/a&gt; is an one-stop platform for early warnings of influenza A viruses. Complete or partial genome sequences, or protein sequences of influenza A viruses could be inputted. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.computationalbiology.cn:18888/IVEW&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;FluPhenotype&lt;/a&gt; would automatically scan the genomic or protein sequences and output four kinds of information about the virus: the predicted antigenic and genetic relationship between the virus and the vaccine or reference strains,the predicted host of the virus, the mammalian virulence-related amino acids, and the drug-resistance related amino acids.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!---more---&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Motivation:&lt;/em&gt; Newly emerging influenza viruses keep challenging global public health. To evaluate the potential risk of the viruses, it is critical to rapidly determine the phenotypes of the viruses, including the antigenicity, host, virulence and drug resistance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; Here, we built &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.computationalbiology.cn:18888/IVEW&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;FluPhenotype&lt;/a&gt;, a one-stop platform to rapidly determinate the phenotypes of the influenza A viruses. The input of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.computationalbiology.cn:18888/IVEW&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;FluPhenotype&lt;/a&gt; is the complete or partial genomic/protein sequences of the influenza A viruses. The output presents five types of information about the viruses: (i) sequence annotation including the gene and protein names as well as the open reading frames, (ii) potential hosts and human-adaptation-associated amino acid markers, (iii) antigenic and genetic relationships with the vaccine strains of different HA subtypes, (iv) mammalian virulence-related amino acid markers and (v) drug resistance-related amino acid markers. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.computationalbiology.cn:18888/IVEW&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;FluPhenotype&lt;/a&gt; will be a useful bioinformatic tool for surveillance and early warnings of the newly emerging influenza A viruses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Influenza infection elicits an expansion of gut population of endogenous Bifidobacterium animalis which protects mice against infection</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32345342/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32345342/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Influenza is a severe respiratory illness that continually threatens global health. It has been widely known that gut microbiota modulates the host response to protect against influenza infection, but mechanistic details remain largely unknown. Here, we took advantage of the phenomenon of lethal dose 50 (LD&lt;sub&gt;50&lt;/sub&gt;) and metagenomic sequencing analysis to identify specific anti-influenza gut microbes and analyze the underlying mechanism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; Transferring fecal microbes from mice that survive virulent influenza H7N9 infection into antibiotic-treated mice confers resistance to infection. Some gut microbes exhibit differential features to lethal influenza infection depending on the infection outcome. Bifidobacterium pseudolongum and Bifidobacterium animalis levels are significantly elevated in surviving mice when compared to dead or mock-infected mice. Oral administration of B. animalis alone or the combination of both significantly reduces the severity of H7N9 infection in both antibiotic-treated and germ-free mice. Functional metagenomic analysis suggests that B. animalis mediates the anti-influenza effect via several specific metabolic molecules. In vivo tests confirm valine and coenzyme A produce an anti-influenza effect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; These findings show that the severity of influenza infection is closely related to the heterogeneous responses of the gut microbiota. We demonstrate the anti-influenza effect of B. animalis, and also find that the gut population of endogenous B. animalis can expand to enhance host influenza resistance when lethal influenza infection occurs, representing a novel interaction between host and gut microbiota. Further, our data suggest the potential utility of Bifidobacterium in the prevention and as a prognostic predictor of influenza.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Structure-Based Model for the Complete Transcription Cycle of Influenza Polymerase</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32304664/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32304664/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Influenza polymerase uses unique mechanisms to synthesize capped and polyadenylated mRNAs from the genomic viral RNA (vRNA) template, which is packaged inside ribonucleoprotein particles (vRNPs). Here, we visualize by cryoelectron microscopy the conformational dynamics of the polymerase during the complete transcription cycle from pre-initiation to termination, focusing on the template trajectory. After exiting the active site cavity, the template 3&amp;rsquo; extremity rebinds into a specific site on the polymerase surface. Here, it remains sequestered during all subsequent transcription steps, forcing the template to loop out as it further translocates. At termination, the strained connection between the bound template 5&amp;rsquo; end and the active site results in polyadenylation by stuttering at uridine 17. Upon product dissociation, further conformational changes release the trapped template, allowing recycling back into the pre-initiation state. Influenza polymerase thus performs transcription while tightly binding to and protecting both template ends, allowing efficient production of multiple mRNAs from a single vRNP.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>O-GlcNAc transferase promotes influenza A virus-induced cytokine storm by targeting interferon regulatory factor-5</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32494619/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32494619/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this study, we demonstrated an essential function of the hexosamine biosynthesis pathway (HBP)-associated O-linked β-N-acetylglucosamine (O-GlcNAc) signaling in influenza A virus (IAV)-induced cytokine storm. O-GlcNAc transferase (OGT), a key enzyme for protein O-GlcNAcylation, mediated IAV-induced cytokine production. Upon investigating the mechanisms driving this event, we determined that IAV induced OGT to bind to interferon regulatory factor-5 (IRF5), leading to O-GlcNAcylation of IRF5 on serine-430. O-GlcNAcylation of IRF5 is required for K63-linked ubiquitination of IRF5 and subsequent cytokine production. Analysis of clinical samples revealed that IRF5 is O-GlcNAcylated, and higher levels of proinflammatory cytokines correlated with higher levels of blood glucose in IAV-infected patients. We identified a molecular mechanism by which HBP-mediated O-GlcNAcylation regulates IRF5 function during IAV infection, highlighting the importance of glucose metabolism in IAV-induced cytokine storm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ketogenic diet activates protective γδ T cell responses against influenza virus infection</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/31732517/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/31732517/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Influenza A virus (IAV) infection-associated morbidity and mortality are a key global health care concern, necessitating the identification of new therapies capable of reducing the severity of IAV infections. In this study, we show that the consumption of a low-carbohydrate, high-fat ketogenic diet (KD) protects mice from lethal IAV infection and disease. KD feeding resulted in an expansion of γδ T cells in the lung that improved barrier functions, thereby enhancing antiviral resistance. Expansion of these protective γδ T cells required metabolic adaptation to a ketogenic diet because neither feeding mice a high-fat, high-carbohydrate diet nor providing chemical ketone body substrate that bypasses hepatic ketogenesis protected against infection. Therefore, KD-mediated immune-metabolic integration represents a viable avenue toward preventing or alleviating influenza disease.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The structure of the influenza A virus genome</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/31332385/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/31332385/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Influenza A viruses (IAVs) constitute a major threat to human health. The IAV genome consists of eight single-stranded viral RNA segments contained in separate viral ribonucleoprotein (vRNP) complexes that are packaged together into a single virus particle. The structure of viral RNA is believed to play a role in assembling the different vRNPs into budding virions1-8 and in directing reassortment between IAVs9. Reassortment between established human IAVs and IAVs harboured in the animal reservoir can lead to the emergence of pandemic influenza strains to which there is little pre-existing immunity in the human population10,11. While previous studies have revealed the overall organization of the proteins within vRNPs, characterization of viral RNA structure using conventional structural methods is hampered by limited resolution and an inability to resolve dynamic components12,13. Here, we employ multiple high-throughput sequencing approaches to generate a global high-resolution structure of the IAV genome. We show that different IAV genome segments acquire distinct RNA conformations and form both intra- and intersegment RNA interactions inside influenza virions. We use our detailed map of IAV genome structure to provide direct evidence for how intersegment RNA interactions drive vRNP cosegregation during reassortment between different IAV strains. The work presented here is a roadmap both for the development of improved vaccine strains and for the creation of a framework to &amp;lsquo;risk assess&amp;rsquo; reassortment potential to better predict the emergence of new pandemic influenza strains.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Protection against influenza infection requires early recognition by inflammatory dendritic cells through C-type lectin receptor SIGN-R1</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/31358982/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/31358982/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The early phase of influenza infection occurs in the upper respiratory tract and the trachea, but little is known about the initial events of virus recognition and control of viral dissemination by the immune system. Here, we report that inflammatory dendritic cells (IDCs) are recruited to the trachea shortly after influenza infection through type I interferon-mediated production of the chemokine CCL2. We further show that recruited IDCs express the C-type lectin receptor SIGN-R1, which mediates direct recognition of the virus by interacting with N-linked glycans present in glycoproteins of the virion envelope. Activation of IDCs via SIGN-R1 triggers the production of the chemokines CCL5, CXCL9 and CXCL10, which initiate the recruitment of protective natural killer (NK) cells in the infected trachea. In the absence of SIGN-R1, the recruitment and activation of NK cells is impaired, leading to uncontrolled viral proliferation. In sum, our results provide insight into the orchestration of the early cellular and molecular events involved in immune protection against influenza.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Single-Cell Virus Sequencing of Influenza Infections That Trigger Innate Immunity</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/31068418/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/31068418/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Influenza virus-infected cells vary widely in their expression of viral genes and only occasionally activate innate immunity. Here, we develop a new method to assess how the genetic variation in viral populations contributes to this heterogeneity. We do this by determining the transcriptome and full-length sequences of all viral genes in single cells infected with a nominally &amp;ldquo;pure&amp;rdquo; stock of influenza virus. Most cells are infected by virions with defects, some of which increase the frequency of innate-immune activation. These immunostimulatory defects are diverse and include mutations that perturb the function of the viral polymerase protein PB1, large internal deletions in viral genes, and failure to express the virus&amp;rsquo;s interferon antagonist NS1. However, immune activation remains stochastic in cells infected by virions with these defects and occasionally is triggered even by virions that express unmutated copies of all genes. Our work shows that the diverse spectrum of defects in influenza virus populations contributes to-but does not completely explain-the heterogeneity in viral gene expression and immune activation in single infected cells.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Importance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because influenza virus has a high mutation rate, many cells are infected by mutated virions. But so far, it has been impossible to fully characterize the sequence of the virion infecting any given cell, since conventional techniques such as flow cytometry and single-cell transcriptome sequencing (scRNA-seq) only detect if a protein or transcript is present, not its sequence. Here we develop a new approach that uses long-read PacBio sequencing to determine the sequences of virions infecting single cells. We show that viral genetic variation explains some but not all of the cell-to-cell variability in viral gene expression and innate immune induction. Overall, our study provides the first complete picture of how viral mutations affect the course of infection in single cells.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Direct interactions with influenza promote bacterial adherence during respiratory infections</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/31110359/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/31110359/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Epidemiological observations and animal models have long shown synergy between influenza virus infections and bacterial infections. Influenza virus infection leads to an increase in both the susceptibility to secondary bacterial infections and the severity of the bacterial infections, primarily pneumonias caused by Streptococcus pneumoniae or Staphylococcus aureus. We show that, in addition to the widely described immune modulation and tissue-remodelling mechanisms of bacterial-viral synergy, the virus interacts directly with the bacterial surface. Similar to the recent observation of direct interactions between enteric bacteria and enteric viruses, we observed a direct interaction between influenza virus on the surface of Gram-positive, S. pneumoniae and S. aureus, and Gram-negative, Moraxella catarrhalis and non-typeable Haemophilus influenzae, bacterial colonizers and pathogens in the respiratory tract. Pre-incubation of influenza virus with bacteria, followed by the removal of unbound virus, increased bacterial adherence to respiratory epithelial cells in culture. This result was recapitulated in vivo, with higher bacterial burdens in murine tissues when infected with pneumococci pre-incubated with influenza virus versus control bacteria without virus. These observations support an additional mechanism of bacteria-influenza virus synergy at the earliest steps of pathogenesis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Low ambient humidity impairs barrier function and innate resistance against influenza infection</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/31085641/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/31085641/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the temperate regions, seasonal influenza virus outbreaks correlate closely with decreases in humidity. While low ambient humidity is known to enhance viral transmission, its impact on host response to influenza virus infection and disease outcome remains unclear. Here, we showed that housing Mx1 congenic mice in low relative humidity makes mice more susceptible to severe disease following respiratory challenge with influenza A virus. We find that inhalation of dry air impairs mucociliary clearance, innate antiviral defense, and tissue repair. Moreover, disease exacerbated by low relative humidity was ameliorated in caspase-1/11-deficient Mx1 mice, independent of viral burden. Single-cell RNA sequencing revealed that induction of IFN-stimulated genes in response to viral infection was diminished in multiple cell types in the lung of mice housed in low humidity condition. These results indicate that exposure to dry air impairs host defense against influenza infection, reduces tissue repair, and inflicts caspase-dependent disease pathology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Naproxen Exhibits Broad Anti-influenza Virus Activity in Mice by Impeding Viral Nucleoprotein Nuclear Export</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/31067470/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/31067470/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Naproxen is a non-steroidal anti-inflammatory drug that has previously been shown to exert antiviral activity against influenza A virus by inhibiting nucleoprotein (NP) binding to RNA. Here, we show that naproxen is a potential broad, multi-mechanistic anti-influenza virus therapeutic, as it inhibits influenza B virus replication both in vivo and in vitro. The anti-influenza B virus activity of naproxen is more efficient than that of the commonly used neuraminidase inhibitor oseltamivir in mice. Furthermore, the NP of influenza B virus (BNP) has a higher binding affinity to naproxen than influenza A virus NP (ANP). Specifically, naproxen targets the NP at residues F209 (BNP) and Y148 (ANP). This interaction antagonizes the nuclear export of NP normally mediated by the host export protein CRM1. This study reveals a crucial mechanism of broad-spectrum anti-influenza virus activity of naproxen, suggesting that the existing drug naproxen may be used as an anti-influenza drug.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Low-Fidelity Assembly of Influenza A Virus Promotes Escape from Host Cells</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/30503209/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/30503209/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Erratum in:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Correction 1: Low-Fidelity Assembly of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674%2819%2930042-X&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Influenza A Virus Promotes Escape from Host Cells&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Correction 2: Low-Fidelity Assembly of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674%2819%2931390-X&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Influenza A Virus Promotes Escape from Host Cells&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Influenza viruses inhabit a wide range of host environments using a limited repertoire of protein components. Unlike viruses with stereotyped shapes, influenza produces virions with significant morphological variability even within clonal populations. Whether this tendency to form pleiomorphic virions is coupled to compositional heterogeneity and whether it affects replicative fitness remains unclear. Here, we address these questions by developing a strain of influenza A virus amenable to rapid compositional characterization through quantitative, site-specific labeling of viral proteins. Using this strain, we find that influenza A produces virions with broad variations in size and composition from even single infected cells. This phenotypic variability contributes to virus survival during environmental challenges, including exposure to antivirals. Complementing genetic adaptations that act over larger populations and longer times, this “low-fidelity” assembly of influenza A virus allows small populations to survive environments that fluctuate over individual replication cycles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Universal protection against influenza infection by a multidomain antibody to influenza hemagglutinin</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/30385580/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/30385580/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Broadly neutralizing antibodies against highly variable pathogens have stimulated the design of vaccines and therapeutics. We report the use of diverse camelid single-domain antibodies to influenza virus hemagglutinin to generate multidomain antibodies with impressive breadth and potency. Multidomain antibody MD3606 protects mice against influenza A and B infection when administered intravenously or expressed locally from a recombinant adeno-associated virus vector. Crystal and single-particle electron microscopy structures of these antibodies with hemagglutinins from influenza A and B viruses reveal binding to highly conserved epitopes. Collectively, our findings demonstrate that multidomain antibodies targeting multiple epitopes exhibit enhanced virus cross-reactivity and potency. In combination with adeno-associated virus-mediated gene delivery, they may provide an effective strategy to prevent infection with influenza virus and other highly variable pathogens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cell autonomous regulation of herpes and influenza virus infection by the circadian clock</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/27528682/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/27528682/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Viruses are intracellular pathogens that hijack host cell machinery and resources to replicate. Rather than being constant, host physiology is rhythmic, undergoing circadian (∼24 h) oscillations in many virus-relevant pathways, but whether daily rhythms impact on viral replication is unknown. We find that the time of day of host infection regulates virus progression in live mice and individual cells. Furthermore, we demonstrate that herpes and influenza A virus infections are enhanced when host circadian rhythms are abolished by disrupting the key clock gene transcription factor Bmal1. Intracellular trafficking, biosynthetic processes, protein synthesis, and chromatin assembly all contribute to circadian regulation of virus infection. Moreover, herpesviruses differentially target components of the molecular circadian clockwork. Our work demonstrates that viruses exploit the clockwork for their own gain and that the clock represents a novel target for modulating viral replication that extends beyond any single family of these ubiquitous pathogens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
