<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Drugs | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/drugs/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/drugs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Drugs</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Drugs</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/drugs/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Systematic optimization of host-directed therapeutic targets and preclinical validation of repositioned antiviral drugs</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35238349/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35238349/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inhibition of host protein functions using established drugs produces a promising antiviral effect with excellent safety profiles, decreased incidence of resistant variants and favorable balance of costs and risks. Genomic methods have produced a large number of robust host factors, providing candidates for identification of antiviral drug targets. However, there is a lack of global perspectives and systematic prioritization of known virus-targeted host proteins (VTHPs) and drug targets. There is also a need for host-directed repositioned antivirals. Here, we integrated 6140 VTHPs and grouped viral infection modes from a new perspective of enriched pathways of VTHPs. Clarifying the superiority of nonessential membrane and hub VTHPs as potential ideal targets for repositioned antivirals, we proposed 543 candidate VTHPs. We then presented a large-scale drug-virus network (DVN) based on matching these VTHPs and drug targets. We predicted possible indications for 703 approved drugs against 35 viruses and explored their potential as broad-spectrum antivirals. &lt;em&gt;In vitro&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt; tests validated the efficacy of bosutinib, maraviroc and dextromethorphan against human herpesvirus 1 (HHV-1), hepatitis B virus (HBV) and influenza A virus (IAV). Their drug synergy with clinically used antivirals was evaluated and confirmed. The results proved that low-dose dextromethorphan is better than high-dose in both single and combined treatments. This study provides a comprehensive landscape and optimization strategy for druggable VTHPs, constructing an innovative and potent pipeline to discover novel antiviral host proteins and repositioned drugs, which may facilitate their delivery to clinical application in translational medicine to combat fatal and spreading viral infections.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A silica-based antioxidant nanoparticle for oral delivery of Camptothecin which reduces intestinal side effects while improving drug efficacy for colon cancer treatment</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35235866/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35235866/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Camptothecin (CPT) is a potent anticancer agent for the treatment of colorectal cancer; however, it exhibits some limitations, including poor solubility, low stability, and low bioavailability via oral administration, which restrict its usability in clinical treatments. In addition, overproduction of reactive oxygen species (ROS) during chemotherapy induces drug resistance and severe intestinal side effects. In this study, silica-installed ROS scavenging nanoparticles (siRNP) with 50-60 nm in diameter were employed to overcome the aforementioned drawbacks of CPT. The solubility of CPT was significantly improved by incorporating it into the core of the nanoparticle, forming CPT-loaded siRNP (CPT@siRNP). The anticancer activity of CPT@siRNP against colorectal cancer cells (C-26) in vitro was significantly improved as compared to free CPT through higher efficiency of intracellular internalization and induction of apoptosis. Owing to its antioxidant properties, CPT@siRNP reduced cytotoxicity to normal endothelial cells, which was in sharp contrast to the high toxicity of free CPT. Oral administration of CPT and CPT@siRNP to the C-26 tumor-bearing mice exhibited antitumor activity, accompanied by effective suppression of tumor growth. Although CPT treatment suppressed tumor progression, it caused severe side effects, including intestinal damage and significant bodyweight loss. Interestingly, such noticeable side effects were not observed in the mice treated with CPT@siRNP, and the effect of tumor growth inhibition tended to be similar to or higher than that of CPT treatment. The results obtained in this study indicate that CPT@siRNP is a potential therapeutic nanomedicine for the treatment of colon cancer. STATEMENT OF SIGNIFICANCE: Here we employed silica-containing antioxidant nanoparticle (siRNP) as promising oral delivery nanocarrier of campothecin (CPT) to treat colon cancer. The design of siRNP via covalent conjugation of antioxidant nitroxide radicals and the silanol groups in the polymer backbone contributes to a significant increase in the absorption of hydrophobic drug molecules inside the core and enhances the stability of nanoparticles in the gastrointestinal environment for oral drug delivery. CPT-loaded siRNP (CPT@siRNP) significantly improved solubility of CPT. As compared to free CTP, the CPT@siRNP treatment showed a significantly higher toxicity to colon cancer cell, inhibition of cancer cell migration, and induction of apopotosis. With the antioxidant feature, siRNP also significantly suppressed the intestinal side effects caused by CPT treatment in tumor-bearing mouse model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
