<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Golgi | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/golgi/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/golgi/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Golgi</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Golgi</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/golgi/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mast cell-mediated inflammation relies on insulin-regulated aminopeptidase controlling cytokine export from the Golgi</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36708814/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36708814/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Upon activation, mast cells rapidly release preformed inflammatory mediators from large cytoplasmic granules via regulated exocytosis. This acute degranulation is followed by a late activation phase involving synthesis and secretion of cytokines, growth factors and other inflammatory molecules via the constitutive pathway that remains ill-defined.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Objective:&lt;/em&gt; Here we investigate the role for an insulin-responsive vesicle (IRV)-like endosomal compartment, marked by insulin-regulated aminopeptidase (IRAP), in the secretion of TNF-α- and IL-6 in mast cells and macrophages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; Murine ko mouse models (IRAPko and kit-Wsh/sh) were used to study inflammatory disease models and to measure and mechanistically investigate cytokine secretion and degranulation in bone-marrow-derived mast cells in vitro.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; We show that IRAPko mice are protected from TNF-α-dependent kidney injury and inflammatory arthritis. In the absence of IRAP, TNF-α and IL-6 but not IL-10 fail to be efficiently secreted. Moreover, chemical targeting of IRAP+ endosomes reduced pro-inflammatory cytokine secretion. Mechanistically, impaired TNF-α export from the Golgi and reduced co-localization of VAMP3+ TNF-α transport vesicles with Stx4 was observed in IRAPko mast cells, while VAMP8-dependent exocytosis of secretory granules was facilitated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/em&gt; Our study describes a novel role for IRAP in mast cell-mediated inflammation through the regulation of exocytic trafficking of cytokines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Precise Monitoring and Assessing Treatment Response of Sepsis-Induced Acute Lung Hypoxia with a Nitroreductase-Activated Golgi-Targetable Fluorescent Probe</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36223488/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36223488/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sepsis-induced acute lung injury (ALI) is mostly attributed to an outbreak of reactive oxygen species (ROS), which makes leukocytes infiltrate into the lung and results in lung hypoxia. Nitroreductase (NTR) is significantly upregulated under hypoxia, which is commonly regarded as a potential biomarker for assessing sepsis-induced acute lung hypoxia. Increasing evidence shows that NTR in the Golgi apparatus could be induced in sepsis-induced ALI. Meanwhile, the prolyl hydroxylase (PHD) inhibitor (dimethyloxalylglycine, DMOG) attenuated sepsis-induced ALI through further increasing the level of Golgi NTR by improving hypoxia inducible factor-1α (HIF-1α) activity, but as yet, no Golgi-targetable probe has been developed for monitoring and assessing treatment response of sepsis-induced ALI. Herein, we report a Golgi-targetable probe, Gol-NTR, for monitoring and assessing treatment response of sepsis-induced ALI through mapping the generation of NTR. The probe displayed high sensitivity with a low detection limit of 54.8 ng/mL and good selectivity to NTR. In addition, due to the excellent characteristics of Golgi-targetable, Gol-NTR was successfully applied in mapping the change of Golgi NTR in cells and zebrafish caused by various stimuli. Most importantly, the production of Golgi NTR in the sepsis-induced ALI and the PHD inhibitor (DMOG) against sepsis-induced ALI were visualized and precisely assessed for the first time with the assistance of Gol-NTR. The results demonstrated the practicability of Gol-NTR for the precise monitoring and assessing of the personalized treatment response of sepsis-induced ALI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cul3-KLHL20 E3 ubiquitin ligase plays a key role in the arms race between HIV-1 Nef and host SERINC5 restriction</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35474067/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35474067/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;HIV-1 must counteract various host restrictions to establish productive infection. SERINC5 is a potent restriction factor that blocks HIV-1 entry from virions, but its activity is counteracted by Nef. The SERINC5 and Nef activities are both initiated from the plasma membrane, where SERINC5 is packaged into virions for viral inhibition or downregulated by Nef via lysosomal degradation. However, it is still unclear how SERINC5 is localized to and how its expression is regulated on the plasma membrane. We now report that Cullin 3-KLHL20, a &lt;em&gt;trans&lt;/em&gt;-Golgi network (TGN)-localized E3 ubiquitin ligase, polyubiquitinates SERINC5 at lysine 130 via K33/K48-linked ubiquitination. The K33-linked polyubiquitination determines SERINC5 expression on the plasma membrane, and the K48-linked polyubiquitination contributes to SERINC5 downregulation from the cell surface. Our study reveals an important role of K130 polyubiquitination and K33/K48-linked ubiquitin chains in HIV-1 infection by regulating SERINC5 post-Golgi trafficking and degradation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Golgi-derived vesicle potentiates PtdIns4P to PtdIns3P conversion for endosome fission</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34183801/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34183801/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Endosome fission is essential for cargo sorting and targeting in the endosomal system. However, whether organelles other than the endoplasmic reticulum (ER) participate in endosome fission through membrane contacts is unknown. Here, we characterize a Golgi-derived vesicle, the SEC14L2 compartment, that plays a unique role in facilitating endosome fission through ternary contacts with endosomes and the ER. Localized to the ER-mediated endosome fission site, the phosphatidylinositol transfer protein SEC14L2 promotes phosphatidylinositol 4-phosphate (PtdIns4P) to phosphatidylinositol 3-phosphate (PtdIns3P) conversion before endosome fission. In the absence of SEC14L2, endosome fission is attenuated and more enlarged endosomes arise due to endosomal accumulation of PtdIns4P and reduction in PtdIns3P. Collectively, our data suggest roles of the Golgi network in ER-associated endosome fission and a mechanism involving ER-endosome contacts in the regulation of endosomal phosphoinositide conversion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Proteomics reveals distinct mechanisms regulating the release of cytokines and alarmins during pyroptosis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33691121/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33691121/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A major pathway for proinflammatory protein release by macrophages is inflammasome-mediated pyroptotic cell death. As conventional secretion, unconventional secretion, and cell death are executed simultaneously, however, the cellular mechanisms regulating this complex paracrine program remain incompletely understood. Here, we devise a quantitative proteomics strategy to define the cellular exit route for each protein by pharmacological and genetic dissection of cellular checkpoints regulating protein release. We report the release of hundreds of proteins during pyroptosis, predominantly due to cell lysis. They comprise constitutively expressed and transcriptionally induced proteins derived from the cytoplasm and specific intracellular organelles. Many low-molecular-weight proteins including the cytokine interleukin-1β, alarmins, and lysosomal-cargo proteins exit cells in the absence of cell lysis. Cytokines and alarmins are released in an endoplasmic reticulum (ER)-Golgi-dependent manner as free proteins rather than by extracellular vesicles. Our work provides an experimental framework for the dissection of cellular exit pathways and a resource for pyroptotic protein release.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Golgi Apparatus: An Emerging Platform for Innate Immunity</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/32413316/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/32413316/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Golgi apparatus serves as a receiving station where proteins from the endoplasmic reticulum (ER) are further processed before being sent to other cellular compartments. In addition to its well-appreciated roles in vesicular trafficking and protein/lipid secretion, recent studies have demonstrated that the Golgi acts as a signaling platform to facilitate multiple innate immune pathways. Moreover, the membranous networks that connect the Golgi with the ER, mitochondria, endosomes, and autophagosomes provide convenient access to innate immune signal transduction and subsequent effector responses. Here, we review the emerging knowledge about the roles of the Golgi in the initiation and activation of innate immune signaling. Moreover, microbial hijacking strategies that inhibit Golgi-associated innate immune responses will also be discussed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
