<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Proteomics | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/proteomics/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/proteomics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Proteomics</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Proteomics</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/proteomics/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Urine proteomic signatures predicting the progression from premalignancy to malignant gastric cancer</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36356476/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36356476/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Early detection of gastric cancer (GC) remains challenging. We aimed to examine urine proteomic signatures and identify protein biomarkers that predict the progression of gastric lesions and risk of GC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; A case-control study was initially designed, covering subjects with GC and gastric lesions of different stages. Subjects were aged 40-69 years, without prior diagnosis of renal or urological diseases. We enrolled a total of 255 subjects, with 123 in the discovery stage from Linqu, China, a high-risk area for GC and 132 in the validation stage from Linqu and Beijing. A prospective study was further designed for a subset of 60 subjects with gastric lesions, which were followed for 297-857 days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Findings:&lt;/em&gt; We identified 43 differentially expressed urine proteins in subjects with GC vs. mild or advanced gastric lesions. Baseline urinary levels of ANXA11, CDC42, NAPA and SLC25A4 were further positively associated with risk of gastric lesion progression. Three of them, except for SLC25A4, also had higher expression in GC than non-GC tissues. Integrating these four proteins showed outstanding performance in predicting the progression of gastric lesions (AUC (95% CI): 0.92 (0.83-1.00)) and risk of GC (AUC (95% CI): 0.81 (0.73-0.89) and 0.84 (0.77-0.92) for GC vs. mild or advanced gastric lesions respectively).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Interpretation:&lt;/em&gt; This study revealed distinct urine proteomic profiles and a panel of proteins that may predict the progression of gastric lesions and risk of GC. These biomarkers in a non-invasive approach may have translational significance for defining high-risk populations of GC and its early detection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Proteomic and phosphorylated proteomic landscape of injured lung in juvenile septic rats with therapeutic application of umbilical cord mesenchymal stem cells</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36341346/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36341346/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acute lung injury (ALI) is the most common complication of sepsis. Intravenous injection of HUMSCs can regulate the level of circulating endothelial cytokines and alleviate lung injury in juvenile septic rats. In this study, we performed proteomic and phosphorylated proteomic analysis of lung tissue of juvenile septic rats after Human Umbilical Cord Mesenchymal Stem Cells (HUMSCs) intervention for the first time, and screened the potential proteins and pathways of HUMSCs for therapeutic effect. The 4D proteome quantitative technique was used to quantitatively analyze the lung tissues of septic rats 24 hours (3 biological samples) and 24 hours after HUMSCs intervention (3 biological samples). A total of 213 proteins were identified as differentially expressed proteins, and 971 phosphorylation sites changed significantly. Based on the public database, we analyzed the functional enrichment of these proteins and phosphorylated proteins. In addition, Tenascin-C may be the key differential protein and ECM receptor interaction pathway may be the main signal pathway by using various algorithms to analyze the protein-protein interaction network. Phosphorylation analysis showed that tight junction pathway was closely related to immune inflammatory reaction, and EGFR interacted most, which may be the key differential phosphorylated protein. Finally, 123 conserved motifs of serine phosphorylation site (pS) and 17 conserved motifs of threonine (pT) phosphorylation sites were identified by motif analysis of phosphorylation sites. Results from proteomics and phosphorylated proteomics, the potential new therapeutic targets of HUMSCs in alleviating lung injury in juvenile septic rats were revealed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Complementary Nck1/2 Signaling in Podocytes Controls α Actinin-4-Mediated Actin Organization, Adhesion, and Basement Membrane Composition</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35906089/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35906089/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Maintenance of the kidney filtration barrier requires coordinated interactions between podocytes and the underlying glomerular basement membrane (GBM). GBM ligands bind podocyte integrins, which triggers actin-based signaling events critical for adhesion. Nck1/2 adaptors have emerged as essential regulators of podocyte cytoskeletal dynamics. However, the precise signaling mechanisms mediated by Nck1/2 adaptors in podocytes remain to be fully elucidated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; We generated podocytes deficient in Nck1 and Nck2 and used transcriptomic approaches to profile expression differences. Proteomic techniques identified specific binding partners for Nck1 and Nck2 in podocytes. We used cultured podocytes and mice deficient in Nck1 and/or Nck2, along with podocyte injury models, to comprehensively verify our findings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; Compound loss of Nck1/2 altered expression of genes involved in actin binding, cell adhesion, and extracellular matrix composition. Accordingly, Nck1/2-deficient podocytes showed defects in actin organization and cell adhesion &lt;em&gt;in vitro&lt;/em&gt;, with podocyte detachment and altered GBM morphology present &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt;. We identified distinct interactomes for Nck1 and Nck2 and uncovered a mechanism by which Nck1 and Nck2 cooperate to regulate actin bundling at focal adhesions via α actinin-4. Furthermore, loss of Nck1 or Nck2 resulted in increased matrix deposition &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt;, with more prominent defects in Nck2-deficient mice, consistent with enhanced susceptibility to podocyte injury.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/em&gt; These findings reveal distinct, yet complementary, roles for Nck proteins in regulating podocyte adhesion, controlling GBM composition, and sustaining filtration barrier integrity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Single-cell RNA-seq-based proteogenomics identifies glioblastoma-specific transposable elements encoding HLA-I-presented peptides</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35675780/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35675780/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Transposable elements (TEs) allow all cell population discrimination in glioblastoma&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;TE-derived peptides are presented on HLA-I molecules&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;TE subfamilies redundantly share HLA-I-presented peptide coding sequences&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Non-redundant peptide-coding TEs are more tumor-specific targets for immunotherapy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We analyze transposable elements (TEs) in glioblastoma (GBM) patients using a proteogenomic pipeline that combines single-cell transcriptomics, bulk RNA sequencing (RNA-seq) samples from tumors and healthy-tissue cohorts, and immunopeptidomic samples. We thus identify 370 human leukocyte antigen (HLA)-I-bound peptides encoded by TEs differentially expressed in GBM. Some of the peptides are encoded by repeat sequences from intact open reading frames (ORFs) present in up to several hundred TEs from recent long interspersed nuclear element (LINE)-1, long terminal repeat (LTR), and SVA subfamilies. Other HLA-I-bound peptides are encoded by single copies of TEs from old subfamilies that are expressed recurrently in GBM tumors and not expressed, or very infrequently and at low levels, in healthy tissues (including brain). These peptide-coding, GBM-specific, highly recurrent TEs represent potential tumor-specific targets for cancer immunotherapies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>iMetaLab Suite: A one-stop toolset for metaproteomics</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/imt2.25/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/imt2.25/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A one-stop solution for metaproteomics data analysis for nonexpert.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Database search and result reports that include taxonomy and function.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Interactive tools for frequently used metaproteomics data analysis tools.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Metaproteomics is a recently thriving technique that studies the collection of proteins in complex microbiomes of the human, animal, plant, and environment. The bioinformatics workflow required for metaproteomics research, from the database search and protein quantification to downstream functional and taxonomic analysis has been challenging and thus limiting the accessibility of metaproteomics to microbiome researchers. To overcome these challenges, we have developed a set of tools named &lt;a href=&#34;https://imetalab.ca/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;iMetaLab Suite&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;https://imetalab.ca/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;iMetaLab Suite&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; includes the following components:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MetaLab Desktop, an automated database search software that facilities proteins identification and quantitation from microbiomes;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the automated iMetaReport that allows users to quickly access database search results and data set profiles;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;an interactive online toolset, iMetaShiny, covering most frequently used functional, taxonomic, and statistical analysis in metaproteomics.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://imetalab.ca/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;iMetaLab Suite&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a free, easily accessible, and actively updated toolset available to assist researchers to explore metaproteomic data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
