<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mass Cytometry | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/mass-cytometry/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/mass-cytometry/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Mass Cytometry</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 26 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Mass Cytometry</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/mass-cytometry/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integrated multi-omics Landscape of liver metastases</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36574521/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36574521/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;BACKGROUND &amp;amp; AIMS&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lack of thorough knowledge for complicated immune-microenvironment (IM) within a variety of liver metastases (LMs) leads to inappropriate treatment and unsatisfactory prognosis. We aimed to characterize IM subtypes and investigate potential mechanisms in LMs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;METHODS&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mass cytometry was applied to characterize immune landscape of primary liver cancers and liver metastases cohort. Transcriptomic and whole exome sequencing were used to explore potential mechanisms across distinct IM subtypes. Single cell transcriptomic sequencing, multiplex fluorescent immunohistochemistry, cell culture, mouse model, western blot, quantitative polymerase chain reaction and immunohistochemistry were used for validation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;RESULTS&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Five IM subtypes were revealed in 100 LMs and 50 primary liver cancers. Patients featured terminally exhausted (IM1) or rare-T-cell-inflamed (IM2 and IM3) immune characteristics showed worse outcome. Increased intra-tumor heterogeneity, enriched somatic TP53, KRAS, APC, PIK3CA mutations and hyper-activated hypoxia signaling accounted for the formation of vicious subtypes. SLC2A1 promoted immune suppression and desert via increasing proportion of Spp1&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; macrophages and their inhibitory interactions with T cells in liver metastatic lesions. Furthermore, SLC2A1 promoted immune escape and liver metastasis through inducing regulatory T cells including Tregs and LAG3&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt;CD4&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T cells in primary colorectal cancer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;CONCLUSION&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The study provided integrated multi-omics landscape of liver metastasis, uncovering potential mechanisms for vicious IM subtypes and confirming the roles of SLC2A1 in regulating tumor microenvironment remodeling in both primary tumor and liver metastatic lesions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integrated T cell cytometry metrics for immune-monitoring applications in immunotherapy clinical trials</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36214223/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36214223/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mass cytometry, or cytometry by TOF (CyTOF), provides a robust means of determining protein-level measurements of more than 40 markers simultaneously. While the functional states of immune cells occur along continuous phenotypic transitions, cytometric studies surveying cell phenotypes often rely on static metrics, such as discrete cell-type abundances, based on canonical markers and/or restrictive gating strategies. To overcome this limitation, we applied single-cell trajectory inference and nonnegative matrix factorization methods to CyTOF data to trace the dynamics of T cell states. In the setting of cancer immunotherapy, we showed that patient-specific summaries of continuous phenotypic shifts in T cells could be inferred from peripheral blood-derived CyTOF mass cytometry data. We further illustrated that transfer learning enabled these T cell continuous metrics to be used to estimate patient-specific cell states in new sample cohorts from a reference patient data set. Our work establishes the utility of continuous metrics for CyTOF analysis as tools for translational discovery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Map of Human Type 1 Diabetes Progression by Imaging Mass Cytometry</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/30713109/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/30713109/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Highly multiplexed imaging of pancreas tissues from human donors with T1D&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Islet evolution through T1D progression inferred from snapshot data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The phenotype of β cells is altered prior to β cell destruction&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;T cell recruitment depends on both disease stage and islet profile&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Type 1 diabetes (T1D) results from the autoimmune destruction of insulin-producing β cells. A comprehensive picture of the changes during T1D development is lacking due to limited sample availability, inability to sample longitudinally, and the paucity of technologies enabling comprehensive tissue profiling. Here, we analyzed 1,581 islets from 12 human donors, including eight with T1D, using imaging mass cytometry (IMC). IMC enabled simultaneous measurement of 35 biomarkers with single-cell and spatial resolution. We performed pseudotime analysis of islets through T1D progression from snapshot data to reconstruct the evolution of β cell loss and insulitis. Our analyses revealed that β cell destruction is preceded by a β cell marker loss and by recruitment of cytotoxic and helper T cells. The approaches described herein demonstrate the value of IMC for improving our understanding of T1D pathogenesis, and our data lay the foundation for hypothesis generation and follow-on experiments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
