<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>shRNA | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/shrna/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/shrna/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>shRNA</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>shRNA</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/shrna/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Knockdown of circFOXO3 ameliorates cigarette smoke-induced lung injury in mice</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34789242/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34789242/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD) remains a prevalent chronic airway inflammatory disease. Circular RNAs (circRNAs) are associated with inflammation regulation; therefore, we examined distinct effects of circRNA FOXO3 (circFOXO3) against pneumonic inflammatory processes in COPD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; We first quantified and localized circFOXO3 in mouse lung epithelial cell line MLE12 by quantitative reverse-transcription PCR and in situ hybridization. Next, circFOXO3 was suppressed by therapeutic administration of circFOXO3 knockdown lentivirus in mice exposed to air or cigarette smoke (CS) for 12 weeks, and several hallmarks of COPD were evaluated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; We noticed that circFOXO3 is upregulated in CS-exposed lungs and cigarette smoke extract (CSE)-treated murine alveolar epithelial cells. Knockdown of circFOXO3 attenuated the release of CXCL1 and IL-6 as well as inflammatory processes in the lungs of CS-exposed mice. In addition, we identified miR-214-3p as a circFOXO3-targeted microRNA. MiR-214-3p overexpression exerted protective effects against pneumonic inflammation after CS exposure. Silencing of circFOXO3 downregulated IKK-β mRNA (miR-214-3p&amp;rsquo;s target), resulting in the dysfunction of the NF-κB signaling pathway and attenuation of CSE-induced inflammatory-cytokine expression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; Collectively, these findings reveal a crucial function of circFOXO3 in the pathological remodeling related to CS-induced inflammatory processes. Hence, circFOXO3 might be a good target for the treatment of inflammatory disorders similar to CS-induced lung inflammation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
