<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>PARylation | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/parylation/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/parylation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>PARylation</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>PARylation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/parylation/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tankyrases inhibit innate antiviral response by PARylating VISA/MAVS and priming it for RNF146-mediated ubiquitination and degradation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35733260/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35733260/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During viral infection, sensing of viral RNA by retinoic acid-inducible gene-I-like receptors (RLRs) initiates an antiviral innate immune response, which is mediated by the mitochondrial adaptor protein VISA (virus-induced signal adaptor; also known as mitochondrial antiviral signaling protein [MAVS]). VISA is regulated by various posttranslational modifications (PTMs), such as polyubiquitination, phosphorylation, O-linked β-d-N-acetylglucosaminylation (O-GlcNAcylation), and monomethylation. However, whether other forms of PTMs regulate VISA-mediated innate immune signaling remains elusive. Here, we report that Poly(ADP-ribosyl)ation (PARylation) is a PTM of VISA, which attenuates innate immune response to RNA viruses. Using a biochemical purification approach, we identified tankyrase 1 (TNKS1) as a VISA-associated protein. Viral infection led to the induction of TNKS1 and its homolog TNKS2, which translocated from cytosol to mitochondria and interacted with VISA. TNKS1 and TNKS2 catalyze the PARylation of VISA at Glu137 residue, thereby priming it for K48-linked polyubiquitination by the E3 ligase Ring figure protein 146 (RNF146) and subsequent degradation. Consistently, TNKS1, TNKS2, or RNF146 deficiency increased the RNA virus-triggered induction of downstream effector genes and impaired the replication of the virus. Moreover, TNKS1- or TNKS2-deficient mice produced higher levels of type I interferons (IFNs) and proinflammatory cytokines after virus infection and markedly reduced virus loads in the brains and lungs. Together, our findings uncover an essential role of PARylation of VISA in virus-triggered innate immune signaling, which represents a mechanism to avoid excessive harmful immune response.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cytoplasmic PARP1 links the genome instability to the inhibition of antiviral immunity through PARylating cGAS</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35460603/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35460603/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;DNA damage induces the cytosolic translocation of PARP1 in an iNOS-dependent manner&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;DNA-PK phosphorylates PARP1 on Thr&lt;sup&gt;594&lt;/sup&gt; and instructs its cytosolic translocation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PARP1 PARylates human cGAS on D191 or mouse cGAS on E176 to terminate its DNA binding&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PARP1-mediated PARylation of cGAS inhibits antiviral immunity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Virus infection modulates both host immunity and host genomic stability. Poly(ADP-ribose) polymerase 1 (PARP1) is a key nuclear sensor of DNA damage, which maintains genomic integrity, and the successful application of PARP1 inhibitors for clinical anti-cancer therapy has lasted for decades. However, precisely how PARP1 gains access to cytoplasm and regulates antiviral immunity remains unknown. Here, we report that DNA virus induces a reactive nitrogen species (RNS)-dependent DNA damage and activates DNA-dependent protein kinase (DNA-PK). Activated DNA-PK phosphorylates PARP1 on Thr&lt;sup&gt;594&lt;/sup&gt;, thus facilitating the cytoplasmic translocation of PARP1 to inhibit the antiviral immunity both in vitro and in vivo. Mechanistically, cytoplasmic PARP1 interacts with and directly PARylates cyclic GMP-AMP synthase (cGAS) on Asp&lt;sup&gt;191&lt;/sup&gt; to inhibit its DNA-binding ability. Together, our findings uncover an essential role of PARP1 in linking virus-induced genome instability with inhibition of host immunity, which is of relevance to cancer, autoinflammation, and other diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chromatin-associated orphan snoRNA regulates DNA damage-mediated differentiation via a non-canonical complex</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35354054/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35354054/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A subset of orphan chromatin-associated snoRNAs (casnoRNAs) is identified&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SNORA73 deregulation impacts genome stability and maintains differentiation block&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The 5′ non-canonical structure is critical for SNORA73 function and PARP1 binding&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SNORA73 assembles a non-canonical snoRNP to inhibit PARP1 PARylation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Small nucleolar RNAs (snoRNAs) are commonly acknowledged as a class of homogeneous non-coding RNAs that guide ribosomal RNA modifications. However, snoRNAs referred to as orphans have largely unknown functions. Here, we systematically profile chromatin-associated snoRNAs (casnoRNAs) in mammalian cells and identify a subgroup of orphan casnoRNAs responding to DNA damage stress, among which SNORA73 shows the most marked reduction in chromatin enrichment. Downregulated SNORA73 maintains cancer genome stability and differentiation block in hematopoietic malignancy. Mechanistically, casnoRNA the 5&amp;rsquo; end non-canonical structure of SNORA73 is critical for its function and binding to poly (ADP-ribose) polymerase 1 (PARP1). SNORA73 inhibits PARP1 auto-PARylation to affect cancer genome stability by forming a small nucleolar ribonucleoprotein (snoRNP) with PARP1 and canonical H/ACA proteins DKC1/NHP2. Our findings reveal the role of an orphan snoRNA serving as casnoRNA and highlights a link between non-canonical structure of snoRNA and their functional diversity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
