<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Intestine | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/intestine/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/intestine/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Intestine</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Intestine</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/intestine/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Biomarker-responsive engineered probiotic diagnoses, records, and ameliorates inflammatory bowel disease in mice</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/22-12-29-21-52/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/22-12-29-21-52/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;i-ROBOT converts IBD information into trackable and heritable DNA alterations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;i-ROBOT contains a self-tunable, thiosulfate-regulated drug release system&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;i-ROBOT has a replaceable biomarker-sensing element, creating a broad platform&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Summary&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rapid advances in synthetic biology have fueled interest in engineered microorganisms that can diagnose and treat disease. However, designing bacteria that detect dynamic disease-associated biomarkers that then drive treatment remains difficult. Here, we have developed an engineered probiotic that noninvasively monitors and records inflammatory bowel disease (IBD) occurrence and progression in real time and can release treatments via a self-tunable mechanism in response to these biomarkers. These intelligent responsive bacteria for diagnosis and therapy (i-ROBOT) consists of E. coli Nissle 1917 that responds to levels of the inflammatory marker thiosulfate by activating a base-editing system to generate a heritable genomic DNA sequence as well as producing a colorimetric signal. Fluctuations in thiosulfate also drive the tunable release of the immunomodulator AvCystatin. Orally administering i-ROBOT to mice with colitis generated molecular recording signals in processed fecal and colon samples and effectively ameliorated disease. i-ROBOT provides a promising paradigm for gastrointestinal and other metabolic disorders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GMrepo: a database of curated and consistently annotated human gut metagenomes</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/31504765/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/31504765/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://gmrepo.humangut.info/home&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;GMrepo&lt;/a&gt; (data repository for Gut Microbiota) is a database of curated and consistently annotated human gut metagenomes. Its main purpose is to facilitate the reusability and accessibility of the rapidly growing human metagenomic data. This is achieved by consistently annotating the microbial contents of collected samples using state-of-art toolsets and by manual curation of the meta-data of the corresponding human hosts. &lt;a href=&#34;https://gmrepo.humangut.info/home&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;GMrepo&lt;/a&gt; organizes the collected samples according to their associated phenotypes and includes all possible related meta-data such as age, sex, country, body-mass-index (BMI) and recent antibiotics usage. To make relevant information easier to access, &lt;a href=&#34;https://gmrepo.humangut.info/home&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;GMrepo&lt;/a&gt; is equipped with a graphical query builder, enabling users to make customized, complex and biologically relevant queries. For example, to find (1) samples from healthy individuals of 18 to 25 years old with BMIs between 18.5 and 24.9, or (2) projects that are related to colorectal neoplasms, with each containing &amp;gt;100 samples and both patients and healthy controls. Precomputed species/genus relative abundances, prevalence within and across phenotypes, and pairwise co-occurrence information are all available at the website and accessible through programmable interfaces. So far, &lt;a href=&#34;https://gmrepo.humangut.info/home&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;GMrepo&lt;/a&gt; contains 58 903 human gut samples/runs (including 17 618 metagenomes and 41 285 amplicons) from 253 projects concerning 92 phenotypes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Long-Term Culture Captures Injury-Repair Cycles of Colonic Stem Cells</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/31708126/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/31708126/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The colonic epithelium can undergo multiple rounds of damage and repair, often in response to excessive inflammation. The responsive stem cell that mediates this process is unclear, in part because of a lack of in vitro models that recapitulate key epithelial changes that occur in vivo during damage and repair. Here, we identify a Hopx&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; colitis-associated regenerative stem cell (CARSC) population that functionally contributes to mucosal repair in mouse models of colitis. Hopx&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; CARSCs, enriched for fetal-like markers, transiently arose from hypertrophic crypts known to facilitate regeneration. Importantly, we established a long-term, self-organizing two-dimensional (2D) epithelial monolayer system to model the regenerative properties and responses of Hopx&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; CARSCs. This system can reenact the &amp;ldquo;homeostasis-injury-regeneration&amp;rdquo; cycles of epithelial alterations that occur in vivo. Using this system, we found that hypoxia and endoplasmic reticulum stress, insults commonly present in inflammatory bowel diseases, mediated the cyclic switch of cellular status in this process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commensal viruses maintain intestinal intraepithelial lymphocytes via noncanonical RIG-I signaling</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/31636462/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/31636462/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Much attention has focused on commensal bacteria in health and disease, but the role of commensal viruses is understudied. Although metagenomic analysis shows that the intestine of healthy humans and animals harbors various commensal viruses and the dysbiosis of these viruses can be associated with inflammatory diseases, there is still a lack of causal data and underlying mechanisms to understand the physiological role of commensal viruses in intestinal homeostasis. In the present study, we show that commensal viruses are essential for the homeostasis of intestinal intraepithelial lymphocytes (IELs). Mechanistically, the cytosolic viral RNA-sensing receptor RIG-I in antigen-presenting cells can recognize commensal viruses and maintain IELs via a type I interferon-independent, but MAVS-IRF1-IL-15 axis-dependent, manner. The recovery of IELs by interleukin-15 administration reverses the susceptibility of commensal virus-depleted mice to dextran sulfate sodium-induced colitis. Collectively, our results indicate that commensal viruses maintain the IELs and consequently sustain intestinal homeostasis via noncanonical RIG-I signaling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enterovirus pathogenesis requires the host methyltransferase SETD3</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/31527793/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/31527793/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enteroviruses (EVs) comprise a large genus of positive-sense, single-stranded RNA viruses whose members cause a number of important and widespread human diseases, including poliomyelitis, myocarditis, acute flaccid myelitis and the common cold. How EVs co-opt cellular functions to promote replication and spread is incompletely understood. Here, using genome-scale CRISPR screens, we identify the actin histidine methyltransferase SET domain containing 3 (SETD3) as critically important for viral infection by a broad panel of EVs, including rhinoviruses and non-polio EVs increasingly linked to severe neurological disease such as acute flaccid myelitis (EV-D68) and viral encephalitis (EV-A71). We show that cytosolic SETD3, independent of its methylation activity, is required for the RNA replication step in the viral life cycle. Using quantitative affinity purification-mass spectrometry, we show that SETD3 specifically interacts with the viral 2A protease of multiple enteroviral species, and we map the residues in 2A that mediate this interaction. 2A mutants that retain protease activity but are unable to interact with SETD3 are severely compromised in RNA replication. These data suggest a role of the viral 2A protein in RNA replication beyond facilitating proteolytic cleavage. Finally, we show that SETD3 is essential for in vivo replication and pathogenesis in multiple mouse models for EV infection, including CV-A10, EV-A71 and EV-D68. Our results reveal a crucial role of a host protein in viral pathogenesis, and suggest targeting SETD3 as a potential mechanism for controlling viral infections.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Virtual Metabolic Human database: integrating human and gut microbiome metabolism with nutrition and disease</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/30371894/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/30371894/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A multitude of factors contribute to complex diseases and can be measured with &amp;lsquo;omics&amp;rsquo; methods. Databases facilitate data interpretation for underlying mechanisms. Here, we describe the &lt;a href=&#34;www.vmh.life&#34;&gt;Virtual Metabolic Human (VMH)&lt;/a&gt; database encapsulating current knowledge of human metabolism within five interlinked resources &amp;lsquo;Human metabolism&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;Gut microbiome&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;Disease&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;Nutrition&amp;rsquo;, and &amp;lsquo;ReconMaps&amp;rsquo;. The &lt;a href=&#34;www.vmh.life&#34;&gt;VMH&lt;/a&gt; captures 5180 unique metabolites, 17 730 unique reactions, 3695 human genes, 255 Mendelian diseases, 818 microbes, 632 685 microbial genes and 8790 food items. The &lt;a href=&#34;www.vmh.life&#34;&gt;VMH&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s unique features are (i) the hosting of the metabolic reconstructions of human and gut microbes amenable for metabolic modeling; (ii) seven human metabolic maps for data visualization; (iii) a nutrition designer; (iv) a user-friendly webpage and application-programming interface to access its content; (v) user feedback option for community engagement and (vi) the connection of its entities to 57 other web resources. The &lt;a href=&#34;www.vmh.life&#34;&gt;VMH&lt;/a&gt; represents a novel, interdisciplinary database for data interpretation and hypothesis generation to the biomedical community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Mouse Intestinal Bacterial Collection (miBC) provides host-specific insight into cultured diversity and functional potential of the gut microbiota</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/27670113/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/27670113/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Erratum in:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Corrigendum: &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nature.com/articles/nmicrobiol2016219&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;The Mouse Intestinal Bacterial Collection (miBC) provides host-specific insight into cultured diversity and functional potential of the gut microbiota&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Intestinal bacteria influence mammalian physiology, but many types of bacteria are still uncharacterized. Moreover, reference strains of mouse gut bacteria are not easily available, although mouse models are extensively used in medical research. These are major limitations for the investigation of intestinal microbiomes and their interactions with diet and host. It is thus important to study in detail the diversity and functions of gut microbiota members, including those colonizing the mouse intestine. To address these issues, we aimed at establishing the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.dsmz.de/collection/catalogue/microorganisms/special-groups-of-organisms/dzif-sammlung/maus-mikrobiomliste&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Mouse Intestinal Bacterial Collection (miBC)&lt;/a&gt;, a public repository of bacterial strains and associated genomes from the mouse gut, and studied host-specificity of colonization and sequence-based relevance of the resource. The collection includes several strains representing novel species, genera and even one family. Genomic analyses showed that certain species are specific to the mouse intestine and that a minimal consortium of 18 strains covered 50-75% of the known functional potential of metagenomes. The present work will sustain future research on microbiota-host interactions in health and disease, as it will facilitate targeted colonization and molecular studies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
