<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Intestine | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/intestine/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/intestine/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Intestine</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Intestine</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/intestine/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Identification of faecal extracellular vesicles as novel biomarkers for the non-invasive diagnosis and prognosis of colorectal cancer</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36604402/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36604402/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Colorectal cancer (CRC) is one of the most common malignancies that is usually detected late in the clinic. The currently available diagnostic tools for CRC are either invasive or insensitive to early lesions due to the dearth of reliable biomarkers. In this study, we discovered that the extracellular vesicles (EVs) in the faeces of CRC patients can act as a potent biomarker for the non-invasive diagnosis and prognosis of CRC. This finding is based on the identification of two transmembrane proteins-CD147 and A33-on faeces-derived EVs (fEVs) that are intrinsically associated with CRC. The detection results show that the levels of CD147 and A33 on fEVs were upregulated in the CRC patients (n = 48), dramatically distinguishing them from the healthy donors (n = 16). The CD147/A33-enriched EVs offer a clinical sensitivity of 89%, much higher than that (40%) of carcinoembryonic antigen (CEA), a clinically-established serum biomarker for CRC diagnosis. In addition, the analysis of longitudinal faeces samples (n = 29) demonstrated that the CD147/A33-enriched fEVs can be utilized to track the prognosis of CRC. Due to the high compliance of faeces-based detection, the CD147/A33-enriched fEVs could serve as new-generation CRC biomarkers for large-scale, non-invasive CRC screening as well as real-time monitoring of patient outcomes during clinical interventions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bifidobacterium animalis subsp. lactis BL-99 ameliorates colitis-related lung injury in mice by modulating short-chain fatty acid production and inflammatory monocytes/macrophages</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36594489/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36594489/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pulmonary inflammation as one of the extraintestinal manifestations of ulcerative colitis (UC) has attracted extensive attention, and its pathogenesis is closely related to gut dysbiosis. &lt;em&gt;Bifidobacterium animalis&lt;/em&gt; subsp. lactis BL-99 (BL-99) can alleviate osteoporosis caused by UC, but less research has been done on other extraintestinal manifestations (EIM) caused by UC. This study aimed to explore the role and potential mechanisms of BL-99 on DSS-induced pulmonary complications in colitis mice. The results showed that BL-99 decreased weight loss, disease activity index score, colonic pathology score, and the production of pro-inflammatory cytokines (&lt;em&gt;e.g.&lt;/em&gt;, TNF-α, IL-1β, and IL-6) in colitis mice. BL-99 also alleviated DSS-induced lung pathological damage by suppressing the infiltration of pro-inflammatory cytokines, inflammatory monocytes, and macrophages. Furthermore, 16S rRNA gene sequencing showed lower abundances of several potentially pathogenic bacteria (&lt;em&gt;e.g.&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Burkholderia, Shigella&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Clostridium perfringens&lt;/em&gt;) and enrichment in specific beneficial bacteria (&lt;em&gt;e.g.&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Adlercreutzia&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Bifidobacterium animalis&lt;/em&gt;) in colitis mice with BL-99 treatment. Targeted metabolomics suggested that BL-99 intervention promoted the production of intestinal acetate and butyrate. Finally, we observed that the pulmonary expression of primary acetate and butyrate receptors, including FFAR2, FFAR3, and, GPR109a, was up-regulated in BL-99-treated mice, which negatively correlated with inflammatory monocytes and macrophages. Altogether, these results suggest that BL-99 might be utilized as a probiotic intervention to prevent the incidence of colitis-related lung injury owing to its ability to shape the intestinal microbiota and suppress inflammation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TLE3 and TLE4-coordinated colonic macrophage-CD4&#43; T cell crosstalk maintains intestinal immune homeostasis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/23-01-07-09-52/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/23-01-07-09-52/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Colonic macrophages are critical for maintenance of CD4+ T cell homeostasis in intestinal lamina propria. However, the mechanisms by which this process is regulated at the transcriptional level remain unknown. Here, we found that the transcriptional corepressors TLE3 and TLE4, but not TLE1 or TLE2, in colonic macrophages controlled homeostasis of CD4&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T cell pool in colonic lamina propria. Mice lacking TLE3 or TLE4 in myeloid cells exhibited markedly increased numbers of T&lt;sub&gt;reg&lt;/sub&gt; and T&lt;sub&gt;H&lt;/sub&gt;17 cells under homeostatic conditions, rendering mice more resistant to experimental colitis. Mechanistically, TLE3 and TLE4 negatively regulated Mmp9 transcription in colonic macrophages. &lt;em&gt;Tle3&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;Tle4&lt;/em&gt; deficiency in colonic macrophages resulted in upregulated MMP9 production and thus enhanced latent TGF-β activation, which subsequently led to T&lt;sub&gt;reg&lt;/sub&gt; and T&lt;sub&gt;H&lt;/sub&gt;17 cell expansion. These results advanced our knowledge regarding the intricate crosstalk between the intestinal innate and adaptive immune compartments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Biomarker-responsive engineered probiotic diagnoses, records, and ameliorates inflammatory bowel disease in mice</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/22-12-29-21-52/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/22-12-29-21-52/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;i-ROBOT converts IBD information into trackable and heritable DNA alterations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;i-ROBOT contains a self-tunable, thiosulfate-regulated drug release system&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;i-ROBOT has a replaceable biomarker-sensing element, creating a broad platform&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Summary&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rapid advances in synthetic biology have fueled interest in engineered microorganisms that can diagnose and treat disease. However, designing bacteria that detect dynamic disease-associated biomarkers that then drive treatment remains difficult. Here, we have developed an engineered probiotic that noninvasively monitors and records inflammatory bowel disease (IBD) occurrence and progression in real time and can release treatments via a self-tunable mechanism in response to these biomarkers. These intelligent responsive bacteria for diagnosis and therapy (i-ROBOT) consists of E. coli Nissle 1917 that responds to levels of the inflammatory marker thiosulfate by activating a base-editing system to generate a heritable genomic DNA sequence as well as producing a colorimetric signal. Fluctuations in thiosulfate also drive the tunable release of the immunomodulator AvCystatin. Orally administering i-ROBOT to mice with colitis generated molecular recording signals in processed fecal and colon samples and effectively ameliorated disease. i-ROBOT provides a promising paradigm for gastrointestinal and other metabolic disorders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UBE2J1 inhibits colorectal cancer progression by promoting ubiquitination and degradation of RPS3</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36567344/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36567344/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ubiquitin-conjugating enzyme E2 J1 (UBE2J1) has been proven to participate in the ubiquitination of multiple substrate proteins. However, the underlying mechanisms of UBE2J1 as a ubiquitin-conjugating enzyme participating in cancer development and progression remain largely unknown. Here, we identified that UBE2J1 is downregulated in colorectal cancer (CRC) tissues and cell lines which are mediated by DNA hypermethylation of its promoter, and decreased UBE2J1 is associated with poor prognosis. Functionally, UBE2J1 serving as a suppressor gene inhibits the proliferation and metastasis of CRC cells. Mechanistically, UBE2J1-TRIM25, forming an E2-E3 complex, physically interacts with and targets RPS3 for ubiquitination and degradation at the K214 residue. The downregulated RPS3 caused by UBE2J1 overexpression restrains NF-κB translocation into the nucleus and therefore inactivates the NF-κB signaling pathway. Our study revealed a novel role of UBE2J1-mediated RPS3 poly-ubiquitination and degradation in disrupting the NF-κB signaling pathway, which may serve as a novel and promising biomarker and therapeutic target for CRC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The sodium channel subunit SCNN1B suppresses colorectal cancer via suppression of active c-Raf and MAPK signaling cascade</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36564468/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36564468/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The incidence of colorectal cancer (CRC) is rising worldwide. Here, we identified SCNN1B as an outlier down-regulated in CRC and it functions as a tumor suppressor. SCNN1B mRNA and protein expression were down-regulated in primary CRC and CRC cells. In a tissue microarray cohort (N = 153), SCNN1B protein was an independent prognostic factor for favorable outcomes in CRC. Ectopic expression of SCNN1B in CRC cell lines suppressed cell proliferation, induced apoptosis, and cell cycle arrest, and suppressed cell migration in vitro. Xenograft models validated tumor suppressive function of SCNN1B in vivo. Mechanistically, Gene Set Enrichment Analysis (GSEA) showed that SCNN1B correlates with KRAS signaling. Consistently, MAPK qPCR and kinase arrays revealed that SCNN1B suppressed MAPK signaling. In particular, SCNN1B overexpression suppressed p-MEK/p-ERK expression and SRE-mediated transcription activities, confirming blockade of Ras-Raf-MEK-ERK cascade. Mechanistically, SCNN1B did not affect KRAS activation, instead impairing activation of c-Raf by inducing its inhibitory phosphorylation and targeting active c-Raf for degradation. The ectopic expression of c-Raf fully rescued cell proliferation and colony formation in SCNN1B-overexpressing CRC cells, confirming c-Raf as the principal molecular target of SCNN1B. In summary, we identified SCNN1B as a tumor suppressor by functioning as a c-Raf antagonist, which in turn suppressed oncogenic MEK-ERK signaling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gut microbiota modulates lung fibrosis severity following acute lung injury in mice</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36543914/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36543914/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Independent studies demonstrate the significance of gut microbiota on the pathogenesis of chronic lung diseases; yet little is known regarding the role of the gut microbiota in lung fibrosis progression. Here we show, using the bleomycin murine model to quantify lung fibrosis in C57BL/6 J mice housed in germ-free, animal biosafety level 1 (ABSL-1), or animal biosafety level 2 (ABSL-2) environments, that germ-free mice are protected from lung fibrosis, while ABSL-1 and ABSL-2 mice develop mild and severe lung fibrosis, respectively. Metagenomic analysis reveals no notable distinctions between ABSL-1 and ABSL-2 lung microbiota, whereas greater microbial diversity, with increased Bifidobacterium and Lactobacilli, is present in ABSL-1 compared to ABSL-2 gut microbiota. Flow cytometric analysis reveals enhanced IL-6/STAT3/IL-17A signaling in pulmonary CD4 + T cells of ABSL-2 mice. Fecal transplantation of ABSL-2 stool into germ-free mice recapitulated more severe fibrosis than transplantation of ABSL-1 stool. Lactobacilli supernatant reduces collagen 1 A production in IL-17A- and TGFβ1-stimulated human lung fibroblasts. These findings support a functional role of the gut microbiota in augmenting lung fibrosis severity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chronic exposure to synthetic food colorant Allura Red AC promotes susceptibility to experimental colitis via intestinal serotonin in mice</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36539404/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36539404/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chemicals in food are widely used leading to significant human exposure. Allura Red AC (AR) is a highly common synthetic colorant; however, little is known about its impact on colitis. Here, we show chronic exposure of AR at a dose found in commonly consumed dietary products exacerbates experimental models of colitis in mice. While intermittent exposure is more akin to a typical human exposure, intermittent exposure to AR in mice for 12 weeks, does not influence susceptibility to colitis. However, exposure to AR during early life primes mice to heightened susceptibility to colitis. In addition, chronic exposure to AR induces mild colitis, which is associated with elevated colonic serotonin (5-hydroxytryptamine; 5-HT) levels and impairment of the epithelial barrier function via myosin light chain kinase (MLCK). Importantly, chronic exposure to AR does not influence colitis susceptibility in mice lacking tryptophan hydroxylase 1 (TPH1), the rate limiting enzyme for 5-HT biosynthesis. Cecal transfer of the perturbed gut microbiota by AR exposure worsens colitis severity in the recipient germ-free (GF) mice. Furthermore, chronic AR exposure elevates colonic 5-HT levels in naïve GF mice. Though it remains unknown whether AR has similar effects in humans, our study reveals that chronic long-term exposure to a common synthetic colorant promotes experimental colitis via colonic 5-HT in gut microbiota-dependent and -independent pathway in mice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deciphering colorectal cancer genetics through multi-omic analysis of 100,204 cases and 154,587 controls of European and east Asian ancestries</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36539618/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36539618/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Colorectal cancer (CRC) is a leading cause of mortality worldwide. We conducted a genome-wide association study meta-analysis of 100,204 CRC cases and 154,587 controls of European and east Asian ancestry, identifying 205 independent risk associations, of which 50 were unreported. We performed integrative genomic, transcriptomic and methylomic analyses across large bowel mucosa and other tissues. Transcriptome- and methylome-wide association studies revealed an additional 53 risk associations. We identified 155 high-confidence effector genes functionally linked to CRC risk, many of which had no previously established role in CRC. These have multiple different functions and specifically indicate that variation in normal colorectal homeostasis, proliferation, cell adhesion, migration, immunity and microbial interactions determines CRC risk. Crosstissue analyses indicated that over a third of effector genes most probably act outside the colonic mucosa. Our findings provide insights into colorectal oncogenesis and highlight potential targets across tissues for new CRC treatment and chemoprevention strategies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Study on the protective effect of berberine treatment on sepsis based on gut microbiota and metabolomic analysis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36601077/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36601077/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Introduction:&lt;/em&gt; Sepsis, an infection with multiorgan dysfunction, is a serious burden on human health. Berberine (BBR), a bioactive component, has a protective effect on sepsis and the effect may be related to gut microbiota. However, studies on the role of BBR with gut microbiota in sepsis are lacking. Therefore, this study investigated the ameliorative effects and the underlying mechanisms of BBR on cecal ligature and puncture (CLP) rats.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; This study has observed the effect of BBR on pathological injury, Inflammation, intestinal barrier function, gut microbiota, and metabolite change in CLP rats by Hematoxylin-eosin staining, enzyme-linked immunosorbent assays, flow cytometry, 16S rDNA, and metabolomics analyses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; The inhibition effects of BBR treatment on the histological damage of the lung, kidney, and ileum, the interleukin (IL)-1b, IL-6, IL-17A, and monocyte chemokine-1 levels in serum in CLP rats were proved. Also, the BBR inhibited the diamine-oxidase and fluorescein isothiocyanate-dextran 40 levels, suggesting it can improve intestinal barrier function disorders. The cluster of differentiation (CD) 4&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt;, CD8&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt;, and CD25&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; Forkhead box protein P3 (Foxp3) &lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T lymphocytes in splenocytes were up-regulated by BBR, while the IL-17A&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt;CD4&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; cell level was decreased. The abundance of gut microbiota in CLP rats was significantly different from that of the sham and BBR treatment rats. The significantly changed metabolites in the serum mainly included carbohydrates, phenols, benzoic acids, alcohols, vitamins et al. Additionally, this study predicted that the biological mechanism of BBR to ameliorate sepsis involves glycolysis-, nucleotide-, and amino acid-related metabolic pathways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Discussion: This study proved the strong correlation between the improvement effect of BBR on sepsis and gut microbiota and analyzed by metabolomics that gut microbiota may improve CLP rats through metabolites, providing a scientific basis for BBR to improve sepsis and a new direction for the study of the biological mechanism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A microbiome-dependent gut–brain pathway regulates motivation for exercise</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36517598/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36517598/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Exercise exerts a wide range of beneficial effects for healthy physiology. However, the mechanisms regulating an individual’s motivation to engage in physical activity remain incompletely understood. An important factor stimulating the engagement in both competitive and recreational exercise is the motivating pleasure derived from prolonged physical activity, which is triggered by exercise-induced neurochemical changes in the brain. Here, we report on the discovery of a gut–brain connection in mice that enhances exercise performance by augmenting dopamine signalling during physical activity. We find that microbiome-dependent production of endocannabinoid metabolites in the gut stimulates the activity of TRPV1-expressing sensory neurons and thereby elevates dopamine levels in the ventral striatum during exercise. Stimulation of this pathway improves running performance, whereas microbiome depletion, peripheral endocannabinoid receptor inhibition, ablation of spinal afferent neurons or dopamine blockade abrogate exercise capacity. These findings indicate that the rewarding properties of exercise are influenced by gut-derived interoceptive circuits and provide a microbiome-dependent explanation for interindividual variability in exercise performance. Our study also suggests that interoceptomimetic molecules that stimulate the transmission of gut-derived signals to the brain may enhance the motivation for exercise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integrative analysis and identification of key elements and pathways regulated by Traditional Chinese Medicine (Yiqi Sanjie formula) in colorectal cancer</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36582529/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36582529/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Introduction:&lt;/em&gt; The clinical efficacy of Yiqi Sanjie (YQSJ) formula in the treatment of stage III colorectal cancer (CRC) has been demonstrated. However, the underlying antitumor mechanisms remain poorly understood.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Materials and methods:&lt;/em&gt; The aim of the present study was to comprehensively characterize the molecular and microbiota changes in colon tissues and fecal samples from CRC mice and in CRC cell lines treated with YQSJ or its main active component, peiminine. Integrative tandem mass tag-based proteomics and ultra-performance liquid chromatography coupled with time-of-flight tandem mass spectrometry metabolomics were used to analyze azoxymethane/dextran sulfate sodium-induced CRC mouse colon tissues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; The results showed that 0.8% (57/7568) of all detected tissue proteins and 3.2% (37/1141) of all detected tissue metabolites were significantly changed by YQSJ treatment, with enrichment in ten and six pathways associated with colon proteins and metabolites, respectively. The enriched pathways were related to inflammation, sphingolipid metabolism, and cholesterol metabolism. Metabolomics analysis of fecal samples from YQSJ-treated mice identified 121 altered fecal metabolites and seven enriched pathways including protein digestion and absorption pathway. 16S rRNA sequencing analysis of fecal samples indicated that YQSJ restored the CRC mouse microbiota structure by increasing the levels of beneficial bacteria such as Ruminococcus_1 and Prevotellaceae_UCG_001. In HCT-116 cells treated with peiminine, data-independent acquisition-based proteomics analysis showed that 1073 of the 7152 identified proteins were significantly altered and involved in 33 pathways including DNA damage repair, ferroptosis, and TGF-β signaling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/em&gt; The present study identified key regulatory elements (proteins/metabolites/bacteria) and pathways involved in the antitumor mechanisms of YQSJ, suggesting new potential therapeutic targets in CRC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maturation and specialization of group 2 innate lymphoid cells through the lung-gut axis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36494354/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36494354/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Innate lymphoid cells (ILC) are abundant in mucosal tissues. They serve critical functions in anti-pathogen response and tissue homeostasis. However, the heterogenous composition of ILCs in mucosal sites and their various maturation trajectories are less well known. In this study, we characterize ILC types and functions from both the lung and the small intestine, and identify their tissue-specific markers. We find that ILC2s residing in the lung express CCR2, whereas intestinal ILC2s express CCR4. Through the use of CCR2 and CCR4 reporter mice, we show that ILC2s undergo translocation via the lung-gut axis upon IL-33 treatment. This trajectory of ILC2s is also observed at the postnatal stage. Allergen-induced activation of lung ILC2s affects the homeostasis of gut ILC2s. Together, our findings implicate that ILCs display tissue-specific features in both the lung and gut, and ILC2s mature along the lung-gut axis in particular homeostatic and inflammatory conditions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ruminococcus gnavus plays a pathogenic role in diarrhea-predominant irritable bowel syndrome by increasing serotonin biosynthesis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36495868/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36495868/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Diarrhea-predominant irritable bowel syndrome (IBS-D), a globally prevalent functional gastrointestinal (GI) disorder, is associated with elevated serotonin that increases gut motility. While anecdotal evidence suggests that the gut microbiota contributes to serotonin biosynthesis, mechanistic insights are limited. We determined that the bacterium Ruminococcus gnavus plays a pathogenic role in IBS-D. Monocolonization of germ-free mice with R. gnavus induced IBS-D-like symptoms, including increased GI transit and colonic secretion, by stimulating the production of peripheral serotonin. R. gnavus-mediated catabolism of dietary phenylalanine and tryptophan generated phenethylamine and tryptamine that directly stimulated serotonin biosynthesis in intestinal enterochromaffin cells via a mechanism involving activation of trace amine-associated receptor 1 (TAAR1). This R. gnavus-driven increase in serotonin levels elevated GI transit and colonic secretion but was abrogated upon TAAR1 inhibition. Collectively, our study provides molecular and pathogenetic insights into how gut microbial metabolites derived from dietary essential amino acids affect serotonin-dependent control of gut motility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mannose metabolism normalizes gut homeostasis by blocking the TNF-α-mediated proinflammatory circuit</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36471112/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36471112/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mannose is a naturally occurring sugar widely consumed in the daily diet; however, mechanistic insights into how mannose metabolism affects intestinal inflammation remain lacking. Herein, we reported that mannose supplementation ameliorated colitis development and promoted colitis recovery. Macrophage-secreted inflammatory cytokines, particularly TNF-α, induced pathological endoplasmic reticulum stress (ERS) in intestinal epithelial cells (IECs), which was prevented by mannose via normalization of protein N-glycosylation. By preserving epithelial integrity, mannose reduced the inflammatory activation of colonic macrophages. On the other hand, mannose directly suppressed macrophage TNF-α production translationally by reducing the glyceraldehyde 3-phosphate level, thus promoting GAPDH binding to TNF-α mRNA. Additionally, we found dysregulated mannose metabolism in the colonic mucosa of patients with inflammatory bowel disease. Finally, we revealed that activating PMM2 activity with epalrestat, a clinically approved drug for the treatment of diabetic neuropathy, elicited further sensitization to the therapeutic effect of mannose. Therefore, mannose metabolism prevents TNF-α-mediated pathogenic crosstalk between IECs and intestinal macrophages, thereby normalizing aberrant immunometabolism in the gut.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setd2 supports GATA3&#43;ST2&#43; thymic-derived Treg cells and suppresses intestinal inflammation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36463230/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36463230/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Treg cells acquire distinct transcriptional properties to suppress specific inflammatory responses. Transcription characteristics of Treg cells are regulated by epigenetic modifications, the mechanism of which remains obscure. Here, we report that Setd2, a histone H3K36 methyltransferase, is important for the survival and suppressive function of Treg cells, especially those from the intestine. Setd2 supports GATA3&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt;ST2&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; intestinal thymic-derived Treg (tTreg) cells by facilitating the expression and reciprocal relationship of GATA3 and ST2 in tTreg cells. IL-33 preferentially boosts Th2 cells rather than GATA3&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; Treg cells in Foxp3&lt;sup&gt;Cre-YFP&lt;/sup&gt;Setd2&lt;sup&gt;flox/flox&lt;/sup&gt; mice, corroborating the constraint of Th2 responses by Setd2 expression in Treg cells. SETD2 sustains GATA3 expression in human Treg cells, and SETD2 expression is increased in Treg cells from human colorectal cancer tissues. Epigenetically, Setd2 regulates the transcription of target genes (including &lt;em&gt;Il1rl1&lt;/em&gt;) by modulating the activity of promoters and intragenic enhancers where H3K36me3 is typically deposited. Our findings provide mechanistic insights into the regulation of Treg cells and intestinal immunity by Setd2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Targeting ferroptosis to treat colorectal cancer</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/36473802/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/36473802/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ferroptosis has emerged as a promising target for colorectal cancer (CRC) treatment. Although disrupting glutathione metabolism is the primary strategy for ferroptosis induction, additional key pathways link ferroptosis to CRC pathogenesis. Here, we discuss arachidonic acid (AA), energy metabolism, AMP-activated protein kinase (AMPK), phosphatidylinositol-3-kinase (PI3K)-protein kinase B (Akt)-mammalian target of rapamycin (mTOR), and Hippo signaling, summarize key findings, and propose new conceptual avenues for CRC treatment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gut dysbiosis induces the development of mastitis through a reduction in host anti-inflammatory enzyme activity by endotoxemia</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36451232/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36451232/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Mounting experimental evidence has shown that the gut microbiota plays a significant role in the pathogenesis of mastitis, and clinical investigations have found that the occurrence of mastitis is correlated with ruminal dysbiosis. However, the underlying mechanism by which the ruminal microbiota participates in the development of mastitis remains unknown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; In the present study, we found that cows with clinical mastitis had marked systemic inflammation, which was associated with significant ruminal dysbiosis, especially enriched Proteobacteria in the rumen. Ruminal microbiota transplantation from mastitis cows (M-RMT) to mice induced mastitis symptoms in recipient mice along with increased mammary proinflammatory signature activation of the TLR4-cGAS-STING-NF-κB/NLRP3 pathways. M-RMT also induced mucosal inflammation and impaired intestinal barrier integrity, leading to increased endotoxemia and systemic inflammation. Moreover, we showed that M-RMT mirrored ruminal microbiota disruption in the gut of recipient mice, as evidenced by enriched Proteobacteria and similar bacterial functions, which were correlated with most proinflammatory parameters and serum lipopolysaccharide (LPS) levels in mice. Recurrent low-grade LPS treatment mirrored gut dysbiosis-induced endotoxemia and caused severe mastitis in mice. Furthermore, we found that gut dysbiosis-derived LPS reduced host alkaline phosphatase activity by activating neuraminidase (Neu), which facilitates low-grade LPS exposure and E. coli-induced mastitis in mice. Conversely, treatment with calf intestinal alkaline phosphatase or the Neu inhibitor zanamivir alleviated low-grade LPS exposure and E. coli-induced mastitis in mice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; Our results suggest that ruminal dysbiosis-derived low-grade endotoxemia can cause mastitis and aggravate pathogen-induced mastitis by impairing host anti-inflammatory enzymes, which implies that regulating the ruminal or gut microbiota to prevent low-grade systemic inflammation is a potential strategy for mastitis intervention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3D bioprinted colorectal cancer models based on hyaluronic acid and signalling glycans</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36604073/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36604073/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In cancer microenvironment, aberrant glycosylation events of ECM proteins and cell surface receptors occur. We developed a protocol to generate 3D bioprinted models of colorectal cancer (CRC) crosslinking hyaluronic acid and gelatin functionalized with three signalling glycans characterized in CRC, 3&amp;rsquo;-Sialylgalactose, 6&amp;rsquo;-Sialylgalactose and 2&amp;rsquo;-Fucosylgalactose. The crosslinking, performed exploiting azide functionalized gelatin and hyaluronic acid and 4arm-PEG-dibenzocyclooctyne, resulted in biocompatible hydrogels that were 3D bioprinted with commercial CRC cells HT-29 and patient derived CRC tumoroids. The glycosylated hydrogels showed good 3D printability, biocompatibility and stability over the time. SEM and synchrotron radiation SAXS/WAXS analysis revealed the influence of glycosylation in the construct morphology, whereas MALDI-MS imaging showed that protein profiles of tumoroid cells vary with glycosylation, indicating that sialylation and fucosylation of ECM proteins induce diverse alterations to the proteome of the tumoroid and surrounding cells.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intestinal dysbiosis mediates cognitive impairment via the intestine and brain NLRP3 inflammasome activation in chronic sleep deprivation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36427810/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36427810/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Growing evidence suggests the involvement of the microbiota-gut-brain axis in cognitive impairment induced by sleep deprivation (SD), however how the microbiota-gut-brain axis work remains elusive. Here, we discovered that chronic SD induced intestinal dysbiosis, activated NLRP3 inflammasome in the colon and brain, destructed intestinal/blood-brain barrier, and impaired cognitive function in mice. Transplantation of &amp;ldquo;SD microbiota&amp;rdquo; could almost mimic the pathological and behavioral changes caused by chronic SD. Furthermore, all the behavioral and pathological abnormalities were practically reversed in chronic sleep-deprived NLRP3-/- mice. Regional knockdown NLRP3 expression in the gut and hippocampus, respectively. We observed that down-regulation of NLRP3 in the hippocampus inhibited neuroinflammation, and ameliorated synaptic dysfunction and cognitive impairment induced by chronic SD. More intriguingly, the down-regulation of NLRP3 in the gut protected the intestinal barrier, attenuated the levels of peripheral inflammatory factors, down-regulated the expression of NLRP3 in the brain, and improved cognitive function in chronic SD mice. Our results identified gut microbiota as a driver in chronic SD and highlighted the NLRP3 inflammasome as a key regulator within the microbiota-gut-brain axis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mutant RIG-I enhances cancer-related inflammation through activation of circRIG-I signaling</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36402769/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36402769/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;RIG-I/DDX58 plays a key role in host innate immunity. However, its therapeutic potential for inflammation-related cancers remains to be explored. Here we identify frameshift germline mutations of RIG-I occurring in patients with colon cancer. Accordingly, Rig-ifs/fs mice bearing a frameshift mutant Rig-i exhibit increased susceptibility to colitis-related colon cancer as well as enhanced inflammatory response to chemical, virus or bacteria. In addition to interruption of Rig-i mRNA translation, the Rig-i mutation changes the secondary structure of Rig-i pre-mRNA and impairs its association with DHX9, consequently inducing a circular RNA generation from Rig-i transcript, thereby, designated as circRIG-I. CircRIG-I is frequently upregulated in colon cancers and its upregulation predicts poor outcome of colon cancer. Mechanistically, circRIG-I interacts with DDX3X, which in turn stimulates MAVS/TRAF5/TBK1 signaling cascade, eventually activating IRF3-mediated type I IFN transcription and aggravating inflammatory damage. Reciprocally, all-trans retinoic acid acts as a DHX9 agonist, ameliorates immunopathology through suppression of circRIG-I biogenesis. Collectively, our results provide insight into mutant RIG-I action and propose a potential strategy for the treatment of colon cancer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thiram-induced hyperglycemia causes tibial dyschondroplasia by triggering aberrant ECM remodeling via the gut-pancreas axis in broiler chickens</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36423455/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36423455/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pesticide thiram is widely used in agriculture and has been demonstrated to cause tibial dyschondroplasia (TD) in birds. However, the underlying mechanism remains unclear. This work used multi-omics analysis to evaluate the molecular pathways of TD in broilers that were exposed to low level of thiram. Integrative analysis of transcriptomic, proteomic, and metabolomic revealed thiram activity in enhancing pathological ECM remodeling via attenuating the glycolysis pathway and activating the hexosamine and glucuronic acid pathways. Intriguingly, we found hyperglycemia as a crucial factor for ECM overproduction, which resulted in the development of TD. We further demonstrated that high glucose levels are caused by islet secretion dysfunction in thiram-treated broilers. A combination of factors, including lipid disorder, low-grade inflammation, and gut flora disturbance, might contribute to the dysregulation of insulin secretion. The current work revealed the underlying toxicological mechanisms of thiram-induced tibial dyschondroplasia through blood glucose disorder via the gut-pancreas axis in chickens for the first time, which makes it easier to figure out the health risks of pesticides for worldwide policy decisions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The microbiota and the gut-liver axis in primary sclerosing cholangitis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/36352157/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/36352157/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Primary sclerosing cholangitis (PSC) offers unique opportunities to explore the gut-liver axis owing to the close association between liver disease and colonic inflammation. It is well established that the gut microbiota in people with PSC differs from that of healthy individuals, but details of the microbial factors that demarcate PSC from inflammatory bowel disease (IBD) without PSC are poorly understood. In this Review, we aim to provide an overview of the latest literature on the gut microbiome in PSC and PSC with IBD, critically examining hypotheses on how microorganisms could contribute to the pathogenesis of PSC. A particular emphasis will be put on pathogenic features of the gut microbiota that might explain the occurrence of bile duct inflammation and liver disease in the context of IBD, and we postulate the potential existence of a specific yet unknown factor related to the gut-liver axis as causative in PSC. Available data are scrutinized in the perspective of therapeutic approaches related to the gut-liver axis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The intestinal barrier in disorders of the central nervous system</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/36334596/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/36334596/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The intestinal barrier, which primarily consists of a mucus layer, an epithelial barrier, and a gut vascular barrier, has a crucial role in health and disease by facilitating nutrient absorption and preventing the entry of pathogens. The intestinal barrier is in close contact with gut microbiota on its luminal side and with enteric neurons and glial cells on its tissue side. Mounting evidence now suggests that the intestinal barrier is compromised not only in digestive disorders, but also in disorders of the central nervous system (CNS), such as Parkinson&amp;rsquo;s disease, autism spectrum disorder, depression, multiple sclerosis, and Alzheimer&amp;rsquo;s disease. After providing an overview of the structure and functions of the intestinal barrier, we review existing preclinical and clinical studies supporting the notion that intestinal barrier dysfunction is present in neurological, neurodevelopmental, and psychiatric disorders. On the basis of this evidence, we discuss the mechanisms that possibly link gut barrier dysfunction and CNS disorders and the potential impact that evaluating enteric barriers in brain disorders could have on clinical practice, in terms of novel diagnostic and therapeutic strategies, in the near future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Novel Protein Encoded by Exosomal CircATG4B Induces Oxaliplatin Resistance in Colorectal Cancer by Promoting Autophagy</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36285810/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36285810/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oxaliplatin is commonly used in chemotherapeutic regimens for colorectal cancer (CRC) after surgical resection. However, acquired chemoresistance seriously affects the curative effect in CRC patients, and the mechanism is still unclear. Here, a circular RNA, circATG4B is identified, which plays an important role in oxaliplatin resistance in CRC. circATG4B expression is found to be increased in exosomes secreted by oxaliplatin-resistant CRC cells. In addition, the results suggest that circATG4B induces oxaliplatin resistance by promoting autophagy. Further in vivo and in vitro studies indicate that the effect of circATG4B is attributed to its potential to encode a novel protein, circATG4B-222aa. Next, circATG4B-222aa is found to function as a decoy to competitively interact with TMED10 and prevent TMED10 from binding to ATG4B, which leads to increased autophagy followed by induction of chemoresistance. Therefore, this study reveals that exosomal circATG4B participates in the decreased chemosensitivity of CRC cells, providing a new rationale for a potential therapeutic target for oxaliplatin resistance in CRC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DCLK1 Suppresses Tumor-Specific Cytotoxic T Lymphocyte Function Through Recruitment of MDSCs via the CXCL1-CXCR2 Axis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36309200/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36309200/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background &amp;amp; Aims&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gastrointestinal cancer stem cell marker doublecortin-like kinase (DCLK1) is strongly associated with poor outcomes in colorectal cancer (CRC). Although DCLK1’s regulatory effect on the tumor immune microenvironment has been hypothesized, its mode of action has not been shown previously in vivo, which hampers the potential intervention based on this molecule for clinical practice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To define the immunomodulatory mechanisms of DCLK1 in vivo, we generated DCLK1&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt; tumor cells by Clustered regularly interspaced short palindromic repeats (CRISPR)-CRISPR-associated protein 9 (Cas9) and developed subcutaneous and intestinal orthotopic transplantation tumor models. Tumor tissues were harvested and subjected to immunofluorescence staining, flow cytometry analysis of tumor-infiltrating immune cell populations, tumor myeloid-derived suppressor cell (MDSC) sorting by isolation kit and then co-culture with spleen T cells, and RNA sequencing for transcriptomic analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We found that DCLK1&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt; tumor cells lose their tumorigenicity under immune surveillance. Failed tumor establishment of DCLK1&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt; was associated with an increase in infiltration of CD8&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T cells and effector CD4&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T cells, and reduced numbers of MDSCs in the tumor tissue. Furthermore, DCLK1 promoted the up-regulation of C-X-C motif ligand 1, which recruits MDSCs in CRC through chemokine C-X-C motif receptor 2. The ability of in vivo tumor growth of DCLK1&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt; tumor cells was rescued by C-X-C motif ligand 1 overexpression. Collectively, we validated that DCLK1 promotes tumor growth in CRC through recruitment of T-cell–suppressive MDSCs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DCLK1-mediated immune suppression in tumor models allows escaping from the host’s antitumor response. Because DCLK1 is one of the most common markers in gastrointestinal tumors, these results identify a precise therapeutic target for related clinical interventions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intestine-specific removal of DAF-2 nearly doubles lifespan in Caenorhabditis elegans with little fitness cost</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36284093/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36284093/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Twenty-nine years following the breakthrough discovery that a single-gene mutation of daf-2 doubles Caenorhabditis elegans lifespan, it remains unclear where this insulin/IGF-1 receptor gene is expressed and where it acts to regulate ageing. Using knock-in fluorescent reporters, we determined that daf-2 and its downstream transcription factor daf-16 are expressed ubiquitously. Using tissue-specific targeted protein degradation, we determined that intracellular DAF-2-to-DAF-16 signaling in the intestine plays a major role in lifespan regulation, while that in the hypodermis, neurons, and germline plays a minor role. Notably, intestine-specific loss of DAF-2 activates DAF-16 in and outside the intestine, causes almost no adverse effects on development and reproduction, and extends lifespan by 94% in a way that partly requires non-intestinal DAF-16. Consistent with intestine supplying nutrients to the entire body, evidence from this and other studies suggests that altered metabolism, particularly down-regulation of protein and RNA synthesis, mediates longevity by reduction of insulin/IGF-1 signaling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Identification of environmental factors that promote intestinal inflammation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36266581/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36266581/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Genome-wide association studies have identified risk loci linked to inflammatory bowel disease (IBD)-a complex chronic inflammatory disorder of the gastrointestinal tract. The increasing prevalence of IBD in industrialized countries and the augmented disease risk observed in migrants who move into areas of higher disease prevalence suggest that environmental factors are also important determinants of IBD susceptibility and severity. However, the identification of environmental factors relevant to IBD and the mechanisms by which they influence disease has been hampered by the lack of platforms for their systematic investigation. Here we describe an integrated systems approach, combining publicly available databases, zebrafish chemical screens, machine learning and mouse preclinical models to identify environmental factors that control intestinal inflammation. This approach established that the herbicide propyzamide increases inflammation in the small and large intestine. Moreover, we show that an AHR-NF-κB-C/EBPβ signalling axis operates in T cells and dendritic cells to promote intestinal inflammation, and is targeted by propyzamide. In conclusion, we developed a pipeline for the identification of environmental factors and mechanisms of pathogenesis in IBD and, potentially, other inflammatory diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gut bacteria alleviate smoking-related NASH by degrading gut nicotine</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36261549/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36261549/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tobacco smoking is positively correlated with non-alcoholic fatty liver disease (NAFLD), but the underlying mechanism for this association is unclear. Here we report that nicotine accumulates in the intestine during tobacco smoking and activates intestinal AMPKα. We identify the gut bacterium Bacteroides xylanisolvens as an effective nicotine degrader. Colonization of B.xylanisolvens reduces intestinal nicotine concentrations in nicotine-exposed mice, and it improves nicotine-exacerbated NAFLD progression. Mechanistically, AMPKα promotes the phosphorylation of sphingomyelin phosphodiesterase 3 (SMPD3), stabilizing the latter and therefore increasing intestinal ceramide formation, which contributes to NAFLD progression to non-alcoholic steatohepatitis (NASH). Our results establish a role for intestinal nicotine accumulation in NAFLD progression and reveal an endogenous bacterium in the human intestine with the ability to metabolize nicotine. These findings suggest a possible route to reduce tobacco smoking-exacerbated NAFLD progression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gut microbiota-derived succinate aggravates acute lung injury after intestinal ischemia/reperfusion in mice</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36229053/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36229053/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Introduction:&lt;/em&gt; Acute lung injury (ALI) is a major cause of morbidity and mortality after intestinal ischemia/reperfusion (I/R). Gut microbiota and their metabolic byproducts act as important modulators of the gut-lung axis. This study aimed to define the role of succinate, a key microbiota metabolite, in intestinal I/R-induced ALI progression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; Gut and lung microbiota of mice subjected to intestinal I/R were analysed using 16S rRNA gene sequencing. Succinate level alterations were measured in Germ-free (GF) mice or conventional mice treated with antibiotics. Succinate-induced alveolar macrophage polarisation and its effects on alveolar epithelial apoptosis were evaluated in succinate receptor1 (&lt;em&gt;Sucnr1&lt;/em&gt;)-deficient mice and in murine alveolar macrophages transfected with &lt;em&gt;Sucnr1&lt;/em&gt;-siRNA. Succinate levels were measured in patients undergoing cardiopulmonary bypass, including intestinal I/R.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; Succinate accumulated in lungs after intestinal I/R, and this was associated with an imbalance of succinate-producing and succinate-consuming bacteria in the gut, but not the lungs. Succinate accumulation was absent in GF mice and was reversed by gut microbiota depletion with antibiotics, indicating that gut microbiota are a source of lung succinate. Moreover, succinate promoted alveolar macrophage polarisation, alveolar epithelial apoptosis, and lung injury during intestinal I/R. Conversely, knockdown of &lt;em&gt;Sucnr1&lt;/em&gt; or blockage of SUCNR1 &lt;em&gt;in vitro&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt; reversed the effects of succinate by modulating PI3K-AKT/HIF-1α pathway. Plasma succinate levels significantly correlated with intestinal I/R-related lung injury after cardiopulmonary bypass.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/em&gt; Gut microbiota-derived succinate exacerbates intestinal I/R-induced ALI through SUCNR1-dependent alveolar macrophage polarisation, identifying succinate as a novel target for gut-derived ALI in critically ill patients.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>gutMDisorder v2.0: a comprehensive database for dysbiosis of gut microbiota in phenotypes and interventions</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36215029/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36215029/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gut microbiota plays a significant role in maintaining host health, and conversely, disorders potentially lead to dysbiosis, an imbalance in the composition of the gut microbial community. Intervention approaches, such as medications, diets, and several others, also alter the gut microbiota in either a beneficial or harmful direction. In 2020, the &lt;a href=&#34;http://bio-annotation.cn/gutMDisorder/home.dhtml&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;gutMDisorder&lt;/a&gt; was developed to facilitate researchers in the investigation of dysbiosis of gut microbes as occurs in various disorders as well as with therapeutic interventions. The database has been updated this year, following revision of previous publications and newly published reports to manually integrate confirmed associations under multitudinous conditions. Additionally, the microbial contents of downloaded gut microbial raw sequencing data were annotated, the metadata of the corresponding hosts were manually curated, and the interactive charts were developed to enhance visualization. The improvements have assembled into &lt;a href=&#34;http://bio-annotation.cn/gutMDisorder/home.dhtml&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;gutMDisorder&lt;/a&gt; v2.0, a more advanced search engine and an upgraded web interface.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Single-cell Transcriptomics Reveals Early Molecular and Immune Alterations Underlying the Serrated Neoplasia Pathway Toward Colorectal Cancer</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36216310/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36216310/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background &amp;amp; aims:&lt;/em&gt; Approximately one-third of colorectal cancers develop from serrated lesions (SLs), including hyperplastic polyp (HP), sessile serrated lesion (SSL), traditional serrated adenoma (TSA), and SSL with dysplasia (SSLD) through the serrated neoplasia pathway, which progresses faster than the conventional adenoma-carcinoma pathway. We sought to depict the currently unclarified molecular and immune alterations by the single-cell landscape in SLs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; We performed single-cell RNA sequencing of 16 SLs (including 4 proximal HPs, 5 SSLs, 2 SSLDs, and 5 TSAs) vs 3 normal colonic tissues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; A total of 60,568 high-quality cells were obtained. Two distinct epithelial clusters with redox imbalance in SLs were observed, along with upregulation of tumor-promoting SerpinB6 that regulated ROS level. Epithelial clusters of SSL and TSA showed distinct molecular features: SSL-specific epithelium manifested overexpressed proliferative markers with Notch pathway activation, whereas TSA-specific epithelium showed Paneth cell metaplasia with aberrant lysozyme expression. As for immune contexture, enhanced cytotoxic activity of CD8&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T cells was observed in SLs; it was mainly attributable to increased proportion of CD103&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt;CD8&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; tissue-resident memory T cells, which might be regulated by retinoic acid metabolism. Microenvironment of SLs was generally immune-activated, whereas some immunosuppressive cells (regulatory T cells, anti-inflammatory macrophages, MDK&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt;IgA&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; plasma cells, MMP11-secreting PDGFRA&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; fibroblasts) also emerged at early stage and further accumulated in SSLD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/em&gt; Epithelial, immune, and stromal components in the serrated pathway undergo fundamental alterations. Future molecular subtypes of SLs and potential immune therapy might be developed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intestinal mucin is a chaperone of multivalent copper</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36206754/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36206754/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mucus protects the epithelial cells of the digestive and respiratory tracts from pathogens and other hazards. Progress in determining the molecular mechanisms of mucus barrier function has been limited by the lack of high-resolution structural information on mucins, the giant, secreted, gel-forming glycoproteins that are the major constituents of mucus. Here, we report how mucin structures we determined enabled the discovery of an unanticipated protective role of mucus: managing the toxic transition metal copper. Using two juxtaposed copper binding sites, one for Cu&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt; and the other for Cu&lt;sup&gt;1+&lt;/sup&gt;, the intestinal mucin, MUC2, prevents copper toxicity by blocking futile redox cycling and the squandering of dietary antioxidants, while nevertheless permitting uptake of this important trace metal into cells. These findings emphasize the value of molecular structure in advancing mucosal biology, while introducing mucins, produced in massive quantities to guard extensive mucosal surfaces, as extracellular copper chaperones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intestinal Microbiota-derived Propionic Acid Protects against Zinc Oxide Nanoparticle-induced Lung Injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36150095/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36150095/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the rapid development of nanotechnology, the risks of accidental and/or occupational exposure to zinc oxide nanoparticles (ZnONPs) are increasing. Inhalation of ZnONPs induces metal fume fever in humans and acute lung injury (ALI) in animal models. Although the intestinal microbiota is considered an important modulator of various diseases, the role and mechanism of intestinal microbiota in the pathology of ZnONP-induced ALI are unclear. Herein, we established an intratracheal instillation of a ZnONP-induced ALI mouse model and found that the inhalation of ZnONPs caused ALI along with a perturbation of intestinal flora. Antibiotic cocktail treatment-mediated depletion of intestinal microbiota aggravated ZnONP-induced ALI, and in contrast, fecal microbiota transplantation-mediated restoration of intestinal microbiota exerted the opposite effects. A decrease in short-chain fatty acids, the intestinal microbiota-derived metabolites in the plasma-in particular, acetic acid and propionic acid-occurred after exposure to ZnONPs. It is important to note that supplementation with propionic acid, but not acetic acid, ameliorated ZnONP-induced ALI. We also showed that the source of inflammatory cytokines might partially be the infiltration of macrophages. Supplementation with propionic acid was found to act on macrophages through the receptor GPR43, because knockdown of GPR43 sharply reversed the protective effects of propionic acid during the ZnONP-induced inflammatory response and oxidative stress in both primary alveolar macrophages and RAW 264.7 macrophage cell lines. Altogether, a novel gut-lung axis mechanism is revealed in which intestinal microbiota and their derived metabolite propionic acid play protective roles against ZnONP-induced ALI and suggest that fecal microbiota transplantation and supplementation with propionic acid are potential remedy strategies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Global burden of colorectal cancer in 2020 and 2040: incidence and mortality estimates from GLOBOCAN</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36604116/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36604116/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Objective:&lt;/em&gt; Colorectal cancer (CRC) is the third most common cancer worldwide. The geographical and temporal burden of this cancer provides insights into risk factor prevalence and progress in cancer control strategies. We examine the current and future burden of CRC in 185 countries in 2020 and 2040.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; Data on CRC cases and deaths were extracted from the GLOBOCAN database for the year 2020. Age-standardised incidence and mortality rates were calculated by sex, country, world region and Human Development Index (HDI) for 185 countries. Age-specific rates were also estimated. The predicted number of cases and deaths in 2040 were calculated based on global demographic projections by HDI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; Over 1.9 million new CRC cases and 930 000 deaths were estimated in 2020. Incidence rates were highest in Australia/ New Zealand and European regions (40.6 per 100 000, males) and lowest in several African regions and Southern Asia (4.4 per 100 000, females). Similar patterns were observed for mortality rates, with the highest observed in Eastern Europe (20.2 per 100 000, males) and the lowest in Southern Asia (2.5 per 100 000, females). The burden of CRC is projected to increase to 3.2 million new cases and 1.6 million deaths by 2040 with most cases predicted to occur in high or very high HDI countries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; CRC is a highly frequent cancer worldwide, and largely preventable through changes in modifiable risk factors, alongside the detection and removal of precancerous lesions. With increasing rates in transitioning countries and younger adults, there is a pressing need to better understand and act on findings to avert future cases and deaths from the disease.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Long noncoding RNA LINC00239 inhibits ferroptosis in colorectal cancer by binding to Keap1 to stabilize Nrf2</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36038548/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36038548/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ferroptosis, a novel regulated cell death induced by iron-dependent lipid peroxidation, plays an important role in tumor development and drug resistance. Long noncoding RNAs (lncRNAs) are associated with various types of cancer. However, the precise roles of many lncRNAs in tumorigenesis remain elusive. Here we explored the transcriptomic profiles of lncRNAs in primary CRC tissues and corresponding paired adjacent non-tumor tissues by RNA-seq and found that LINC00239 was significantly overexpressed in colorectal cancer tissues. Abnormally high expression of LINC00239 predicts poorer survival and prognosis in colorectal cancer patients. Concurrently, we elucidated the role of LINC00239 as a tumor-promoting factor in CRC through in vitro functional studies and in vivo tumor xenograft models. Importantly, overexpression of LINC00239 decreased the anti-tumor activity of erastin and RSL3 by inhibiting ferroptosis. Collectively, these data suggest that LINC00239 plays a novel and indispensable role in ferroptosis by nucleotides 1-315 of LINC00239 to interact with the Kelch domain (Nrf2-binding site) of Keap1, inhibiting Nrf2 ubiquitination and increasing Nrf2 protein stability. Considering the recurrence and chemoresistance constitute the leading cause of death in colorectal cancer (CRC), ferroptosis induction may be a promising therapeutic strategy for CRC patients with low LINC00239 expression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advances and challenges in cataloging the human gut virome</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/35834962/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/35834962/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The human gut virome, which is often referred to as the &amp;ldquo;dark matter&amp;rdquo; of the gut microbiome, remains understudied. A better understanding of the composition and variations of the gut virome across populations is critical for exploring its impact on diseases and health. A series of advances in the characterization of human gut virome have unveiled high genetic diversity and various functional potentials of gut viruses. Here, we summarize the recently available human gut virome databases and discuss their features, procedures, and challenges with the intention to provide a reference to researchers to use while choosing a profiling database. We also propose a &amp;ldquo;best practice&amp;rdquo; for cataloging the viral population.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oral administration of asparagine and 3-indolepropionic acid prolongs survival time of rats with traumatic colon injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35791006/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35791006/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Traumatic colon injury (TCI) is a common disease during wartime. Prolongation of posttraumatic survival time is an effective approach to patient outcome improvement. However, there is a lack of basic research in this field. This study aimed to elucidate the mechanisms underlying TCI progression and to develop novel regimens to buy time for TCI patients on the battlefield.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; A total of 669 Sprague-Dawley rats were used in this study. Surgical colon incision was performed to generate the TCI rat model. The landscape of colon microbiota compositions was depicted using 16S rRNA sequencing and metabolites in the intestinal contents were detected by metabolomics profiling. The signaling transduction in the intestinal epithelium was investigated using antibody microarrays and Western blotting. The enzyme-linked immunosorbent assay was conducted to measure the levels of interleukin-6 and tumor necrosis factor-α in intestines and plasma for the detection of inflammatory responses. Diamine oxidase, D-lactate and endotoxin in plasma and protein expression of zonula occludens 1 and occludin were selected as the indicators of intestinal barrier permeability. To investigate alterations of microbiota symbiosis, the relative abundances of specific bacterial genera were detected using quantitative real-time PCR.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; As a type of lethal injury, TCI induced acute disruption of intestinal homeostasis, characterized by inflammatory responses, intestinal barrier hyperpermeability and microbiota dysbiosis (&lt;em&gt;P&lt;/em&gt; &amp;lt; 0.05). Significant alterations in bacterial metabolic patterns were detected with decreases in many metabolites. After a series of screenings, we found that oral administration of asparagine (Asn) and 3-indolepropionic acid (IPA) effectively prolonged posttraumatic survival time (Asn plus IPA vs. Vehicle: hazard ratio (HR) = 0.105, 95% CI 0.031-0.356, &lt;em&gt;P&lt;/em&gt; = 0.0003) and restored intestinal homeostasis in TCI rats (&lt;em&gt;P&lt;/em&gt; &amp;lt; 0.05). Mechanistically, this combinational strategy protected the rats against TCI through synergistic activation of Akt signaling in the intestinal epithelium (&lt;em&gt;P&lt;/em&gt; &amp;lt; 0.05).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; Abrupt dysregulation of intestinal homeostasis plays a critical role in the progression toward TCI-induced death. Oral administration of Asn plus IPA may serve as an effective regimen to restore intestinal functions and prolong the posttraumatic survival time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>circEXOC6B interacting with RRAGB, an mTORC1 activator, inhibits the progression of colorectal cancer by antagonizing the HIF1A-RRAGB-mTORC1 positive feedback loop</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35739524/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35739524/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; In recent years, an increasing number of studies have indicated that circular RNA plays crucial roles in regulating tumor development and chemoresistance. Using two high-throughput RNA sequence datasets, we previously found that circEXOC6B was downregulated in colon cancer. However, its role and mechanism in colorectal cancer (CRC) remained unknown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; Real-time quantitative PCR was used to examine the expression of circEXOC6B in CRC tissues. In vivo and in vitro functional experiments were performed to determine the suppressor role of circEXOC6B in CRC progression. RNA pull-down, mass spectrometry, RNA-binding protein immunoprecipitation, co-immunoprecipitation, fluorescence in situ hybridization, and immunofluorescence were applied to investigate the possible mechanisms connecting circEXOC6B to CRC growth and 5-fluorouracil-induced apoptosis. Chromatin immunoprecipitation, dual-luciferase assay, western blot, and immunohistochemistry were used to explore the mechanisms underlying the HIF1A regulation of RRAGB transcription.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; circEXOC6B was downregulated in CRC tissues, and its lower expression was associated with poor prognosis of patients. Functional experiments showed that circEXOC6B inhibited growth and increased the 5-fluorouracil-induced apoptosis of CRC cells in vitro and in vivo. Mechanistically, circEXOC6B inhibited the heterodimer formation of RRAGB by binding to it, thereby suppressing the mTORC1 pathway and HIF1A level. In addition, HIF1A upregulated the transcription of RRAGB by binding to its promoter region. Altogether, the results demonstrated that a HIF1A-RRAGB-mTORC1 positive feedback loop drives tumor progression in CRC, which could be interrupted by circEXOC6B.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; circEXOC6B inhibits the progression of CRC and enhances the chemosensitivity of CRC cells to 5-fluorouracil by antagonizing the HIF1A-RRAGB-mTORC1 positive feedback loop. circEXOC6B is a possible therapeutic target for CRC treatment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mucus sialylation determines intestinal host-commensal homeostasis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35303419/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35303419/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A local sialyltransferase dominantly controls intestinal protein sialylation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sialylation protects intestinal mucus integrity from bacterial degradation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mucus sialylation is critical for commensalism and bacterial metabolite homeostasis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Treatment with sialylated mucins ameliorates gut inflammation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Summary&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Intestinal mucus forms the first line of defense against bacterial invasion while providing nutrition to support microbial symbiosis. How the host controls mucus barrier integrity and commensalism is unclear. We show that terminal sialylation of glycans on intestinal mucus by ST6GALNAC1 (ST6), the dominant sialyltransferase specifically expressed in goblet cells and induced by microbial pathogen-associated molecular patterns, is essential for mucus integrity and protecting against excessive bacterial proteolytic degradation. Glycoproteomic profiling and biochemical analysis of ST6 mutations identified in patients show that decreased sialylation causes defective mucus proteins and congenital inflammatory bowel disease (IBD). Mice harboring a patient ST6 mutation have compromised mucus barriers, dysbiosis, and susceptibility to intestinal inflammation. Based on our understanding of the ST6 regulatory network, we show that treatment with sialylated mucin or a Foxo3 inhibitor can ameliorate IBD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Therapeutic potential of traditional Chinese medicine for the treatment of NAFLD: A promising drug Potentilla discolor Bunge</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/36176915/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/36176915/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nonalcoholic fatty liver disease (NAFLD) is characterized by excessive accumulation of hepatic lipids and metabolic stress-induced liver injury. There are currently no approved effective pharmacological treatments for NAFLD. Traditional Chinese medicine (TCM) has been used for centuries to treat patients with chronic liver diseases without clear disease types and mechanisms. More recently, TCM has been shown to have unique advantages in the treatment of NAFLD. We performed a systematic review of the medical literature published over the last two decades and found that many TCM formulas have been reported to be beneficial for the treatment of metabolic dysfunctions, including &lt;em&gt;Potentilla discolor&lt;/em&gt; Bunge (PDB). PDB has a variety of active compounds, including flavonoids, terpenoids, organic acids, steroids and tannins. Many compounds have been shown to exhibit a series of beneficial effects for the treatment of NAFLD, including anti-oxidative and anti-inflammatory functions, improvement of lipid metabolism and reversal of insulin resistance. In this review, we summarize potential therapeutic effects of TCM formulas for the treatment of NAFLD, focusing on the medicinal properties of natural active compounds from PDB and their underlying mechanisms. We point out that PDB can be classified as a novel candidate for the treatment and prevention of NAFLD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Long noncoding RNA LINC01606 protects colon cancer cells from ferroptotic cell death and promotes stemness by SCD1-Wnt/β-catenin-TFE3 feedback loop signalling</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35485210/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35485210/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Ferroptosis is principally caused by iron catalytic activity and intracellular lipid peroxidation. Long noncoding RNAs (lncRNAs) play crucial roles in tumorigenesis. However, the potential interplay between lncRNA LINC01606 and ferroptosis in colon cancer remains elusive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; The expression level of LNC01606 in colon cancer tissue was detected by quantitative real-time polymerase chain reaction. The functional role of LNC01606 was investigated by gain- and loss-of-function assays both in vitro and in vivo. The LINC01606-SCD1-Wnt/β-catenin-TFE3 axis were screened and validated by DNA/RNA pull down, gas chromatography-mass spectrometry, RNA immunoprecipitation and dual-luciferase reporter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; The expression of lncRNA LINC01606 was frequently upregulated in human colon cancer and strongly associated with a poor prognosis. LINC01606 functioned as an oncogene and promotes colon cancer cell growth, invasion and stemness both in vitro and in vivo. Moreover, LINC01606 protected colon cancer cells from ferroptosis by decreasing the concentration of iron, lipid reactive oxygen species, mitochondrial superoxide and increasing mitochondrial membrane potential. Mechanistically, LINC01606 enhanced the expression of stearoyl-CoA desaturase 1 (SCD1), serving as a competing endogenous RNA to modulate miR-423-5p expression, subsequently activating the canonical Wnt/β-catenin signaling, and transcription factor binding to IGHM enhancer 3 (TFE3) increased LINC01606 transcription after recruitment to the promoter regions of LINC01606. Furthermore, we confirmed that upregulated LINC01606 and Wnt/β-catenin formed a positive feedback regulatory loop, further inhibiting ferroptosis and enhancing stemness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; LINC01606 functions as an oncogene to facilitate tumor cell stemness, proliferation and inhibit ferroptosis and is a promising therapeutic target for colon cancer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Single-cell and spatial analysis reveal interaction of FAP&#43; fibroblasts and SPP1&#43; macrophages in colorectal cancer</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35365629/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35365629/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Colorectal cancer (CRC) is among the most common malignancies with limited treatments other than surgery. The tumor microenvironment (TME) profiling enables the discovery of potential therapeutic targets. Here, we profile 54,103 cells from tumor and adjacent tissues to characterize cellular composition and elucidate the potential origin and regulation of tumor-enriched cell types in CRC. We demonstrate that the tumor-specific FAP&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; fibroblasts and SPP1&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; macrophages were positively correlated in 14 independent CRC cohorts containing 2550 samples and validate their close localization by immuno-fluorescent staining and spatial transcriptomics. This interaction might be regulated by chemerin, TGF-β, and interleukin-1, which would stimulate the formation of immune-excluded desmoplasic structure and limit the T cell infiltration. Furthermore, we find patients with high FAP or SPP1 expression achieved less therapeutic benefit from an anti-PD-L1 therapy cohort. Our results provide a potential therapeutic strategy by disrupting FAP&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; fibroblasts and SPP1&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; macrophages interaction to improve immunotherapy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>m6A mRNA modification maintains colonic epithelial cell homeostasis via NF-κB-mediated antiapoptotic pathway</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35333576/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35333576/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Colonic mucosal barrier dysfunction is one of the major causes of inflammatory bowel disease (IBD). However, the mechanisms underlying mucosal barrier dysfunction are poorly understood. N6-methyladenosine (m6A) mRNA modification is an important modulator of epitranscriptional regulation of gene expression, participating in multiple physiological and pathological processes. However, the function of m6A modification in colonic epithelial cells and stem cells is unknown. Here, we show that m6A modification is essential for maintaining the homeostatic self-renewal in colonic stem cells. Specific deletion of the methyltransferase 14 (Mettl14) gene in mouse colon resulted in colonic stem cell apoptosis, causing mucosal barrier dysfunction and severe colitis. Mechanistically, we revealed that Mettl14 restricted colonic epithelial cell death by regulating the stability of Nfkbia mRNA and modulating the NF-κB pathway. Our results identified a previously unidentified role for m6A modification in colonic epithelial cells and stem cells, suggesting that m6A modification may be a potential therapeutic target for IBD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PUMILIO proteins promote colorectal cancer growth via suppressing p21</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35338151/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35338151/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PUMILIO (PUM) proteins belong to the highly conserved PUF family post-transcriptional regulators involved in diverse biological processes. However, their function in carcinogenesis remains under-explored. Here, we report that Pum1 and Pum2 display increased expression in human colorectal cancer (CRC). Intestine-specific knockout of Pum1 and Pum2 in mice significantly inhibits the progression of colitis-associated cancer in the AOM/DSS model. Knockout or knockdown of Pum1 and/or Pum2 in human CRC cells result in a significant decrease in the tumorigenicity and delayed G1/S transition. We identify p21/Cdkn1a as a direct target of PUM1. Abrogation of the PUM1 binding site in the p21 mRNA also results in decreased cancer cell growth and delayed G1/S transition. Furthermore, intravenous injection of nanoparticle-encapsulated anti-Pum1 and Pum2 siRNAs reduces colorectal tumor growth in murine orthotopic colon cancer models. These findings reveal the requirement of PUM proteins for CRC progression and their potential as therapeutic targets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intestinal butyrate-metabolizing species contribute to autoantibody production and bone erosion in rheumatoid arthritis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35148177/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35148177/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The imbalance between pathogenic and beneficial species of the intestinal microbiome and metabolism in rheumatoid arthritis (RA) remains unclarified. Here, using shotgun-based metagenome sequencing for a treatment-naïve patient cohort and a &amp;ldquo;quasi-paired cohort&amp;rdquo; method, we observed a deficiency of butyrate-producing species and an overwhelming number of butyrate consumers in RA patients. These outcomes mainly occurred in patients with positive ACPA, with a mean AUC of 0.94. This panel was also validated in established RA with an AUC of 0.986 in those with joint deformity. In addition, we showed that butyrate promoted T&lt;sub&gt;regs&lt;/sub&gt;, while suppressing T&lt;sub&gt;convs&lt;/sub&gt; and osteoclasts, due to potentiation of the reduction in HDAC expression and down-regulation of proinflammatory cytokine genes. Dietary butyrate supplementation conferred anti-inflammatory benefits in a mouse model by rebalancing T&lt;sub&gt;FH&lt;/sub&gt; cells and T&lt;sub&gt;regs&lt;/sub&gt;, as well as reducing antibody production. These findings reveal the critical role of butyrate-metabolizing species and suggest the potential of butyrate-based therapies for RA patients.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Berberine Relieves Metabolic Syndrome in Mice by Inhibiting Liver Inflammation Caused by a High-Fat Diet and Potential Association With Gut Microbiota</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35095784/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35095784/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whether berberine mediates its anti-inflammatory and blood sugar and lipid-lowering effects solely by adjusting the structure of the gut microbiota or by first directly regulating the expression of host pro-inflammatory proteins and activation of macrophages and subsequently acting on gut microbiota, is currently unclear. To clarify the mechanism of berberine-mediated regulation of metabolism, we constructed an obese mouse model using SPF-grade C57BL/6J male mice and conducted a systematic study of liver tissue pathology, inflammatory factor expression, and gut microbiota structure. We screened the gut microbiota targets of berberine and showed that the molecular mechanism of berberine-mediated treatment of metabolic syndrome involves the regulation of gut microbiota structure and the expression of inflammatory factors. Our results revealed that a high-fat diet (HFD) significantly changed mice gut microbiota, thereby probably increasing the level of toxins in the intestine, and triggered the host inflammatory response. The HFD also reduced the proportion of short-chain fatty acid (SCFA)-producing genes, thereby hindering mucosal immunity and cell nutrition, and increased the host inflammatory response and liver fat metabolism disorders. Further, berberine could improve the chronic HFD-induced inflammatory metabolic syndrome to some extent and effectively improved the metabolism of high-fat foods in mice, which correlated with the gut microbiota composition. Taken together, our study may improve our understanding of host-microbe interactions during the treatment of metabolic diseases and provide useful insights into the action mechanism of berberine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AMDB: a database of animal gut microbial communities with manually curated metadata</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34747470/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34747470/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Variations in gut microbiota can be explained by animal host characteristics, including host phylogeny and diet. However, there are currently no databases that allow for easy exploration of the relationship between gut microbiota and diverse animal hosts. The &lt;a href=&#34;http://leb.snu.ac.kr/amdb&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Animal Microbiome Database (AMDB)&lt;/a&gt; is the first database to provide taxonomic profiles of the gut microbiota in various animal species. &lt;a href=&#34;http://leb.snu.ac.kr/amdb&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;AMDB&lt;/a&gt; contains 2530 amplicon data from 34 projects with manually curated metadata. The total data represent 467 animal species and contain 10 478 bacterial taxa. This novel database provides information regarding gut microbiota structures and the distribution of gut bacteria in animals, with an easy-to-use interface. Interactive visualizations are also available, enabling effective investigation of the relationship between the gut microbiota and animal hosts. &lt;a href=&#34;http://leb.snu.ac.kr/amdb&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;AMDB&lt;/a&gt; will contribute to a better understanding of the gut microbiota of animals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>gutMGene: a comprehensive database for target genes of gut microbes and microbial metabolites</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34500458/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34500458/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://bio-annotation.cn/gutmgene&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;gutMGene&lt;/a&gt;, a manually curated database, aims at providing a comprehensive resource of target genes of gut microbes and microbial metabolites in humans and mice. Metagenomic sequencing of fecal samples has identified 3.3 × 106 non-redundant microbial genes from up to 1500 different species. One of the contributions of gut microbiota to host biology is the circulating pool of bacterially derived small-molecule metabolites. It has been estimated that 10% of metabolites found in mammalian blood are derived from the gut microbiota, where they can produce systemic effects on the host through activating or inhibiting gene expression. The current version of &lt;a href=&#34;http://bio-annotation.cn/gutmgene&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;gutMGene&lt;/a&gt; documents 1331 curated relationships between 332 gut microbes, 207 microbial metabolites and 223 genes in humans, and 2349 curated relationships between 209 gut microbes, 149 microbial metabolites and 544 genes in mice. Each entry in the &lt;a href=&#34;http://bio-annotation.cn/gutmgene&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;gutMGene&lt;/a&gt; contains detailed information on a relationship between gut microbe, microbial metabolite and target gene, a brief description of the relationship, experiment technology and platform, literature reference and so on. &lt;a href=&#34;http://bio-annotation.cn/gutmgene&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;gutMGene&lt;/a&gt; provides a user-friendly interface to browse and retrieve each entry using gut microbes, disorders and intervention measures. It also offers the option to download all the entries and submit new experimentally validated associations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Identification of a choroid plexus vascular barrier closing during intestinal inflammation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34672740/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34672740/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Up to 40% of patients with inflammatory bowel disease present with psychosocial disturbances. We previously identified a gut vascular barrier that controls the dissemination of bacteria from the intestine to the liver. Here, we describe a vascular barrier in the brain choroid plexus (PVB) that is modulated in response to intestinal inflammation through bacteria-derived lipopolysaccharide. The inflammatory response induces PVB closure after gut vascular barrier opening by the up-regulation of the wingless-type, catenin-beta 1 (Wnt/β-catenin) signaling pathway, rendering it inaccessible to large molecules. In a model of genetically driven closure of choroid plexus endothelial cells, we observed a deficit in short-term memory and anxiety-like behavior, suggesting that PVB closure may correlate with mental deficits. Inflammatory bowel disease–related mental symptoms may thus be the consequence of a deregulated gut–brain vascular axis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spatiotemporal Immune Landscape of Colorectal Cancer Liver Metastasis at Single-Cell Level</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34417225/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34417225/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Liver metastasis, the leading cause of colorectal cancer mortality, exhibits a highly heterogeneous and suppressive immune microenvironment. Here, we sequenced 97 matched samples by using single-cell RNA sequencing and spatial transcriptomics. Strikingly, the metastatic microenvironment underwent remarkable spatial reprogramming of immunosuppressive cells such as &lt;em&gt;MRC1&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;CCL18&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; M2-like macrophages. We further developed scMetabolism, a computational pipeline for quantifying single-cell metabolism, and observed that those macrophages harbored enhanced metabolic activity. Interestingly, neoadjuvant chemotherapy could block this status and restore the antitumor immune balance in responsive patients, whereas the nonresponsive patients deteriorated into a more suppressive one. Our work described the immune evolution of metastasis and uncovered the black box of how tumors respond to neoadjuvant chemotherapy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Significance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We present a single-cell and spatial atlas of colorectal liver metastasis and found the highly metabolically activated &lt;em&gt;MRC1&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;CCL18&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; M2-like macrophages in metastatic sites. Efficient neoadjuvant chemotherapy can slow down such metabolic activation, raising the possibility to target metabolism pathways in metastasis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enterically derived high-density lipoprotein restrains liver injury through the portal vein</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34437091/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34437091/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The biogenesis of high-density lipoprotein (HDL) requires apoA1 and the cholesterol transporter ABCA1. Although the liver generates most of the HDL in the blood, HDL synthesis also occurs in the small intestine. Here, we show that intestine-derived HDL traverses the portal vein in the HDL3 subspecies form, in complex with lipopolysaccharide (LPS)-binding protein (LBP). HDL3, but not HDL2 or low-density lipoprotein, prevented LPS binding to and inflammatory activation of liver macrophages and instead supported extracellular inactivation of LPS. In mouse models involving surgical, dietary, or alcoholic intestinal insult, loss of intestine-derived HDL worsened liver injury, whereas outcomes were improved by therapeutics that elevated and depended upon raising intestinal HDL. Thus, protection of the liver from injury in response to gut-derived LPS is a major function of intestinally synthesized HDL.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HIPK2 phosphorylates HDAC3 for NF-κB acetylation to ameliorate colitis-associated colorectal carcinoma and sepsis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34244427/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34244427/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although inflammation is critical for the clearance of pathogens, uncontrolled inflammation also contributes to the development of multiple diseases such as cancer and sepsis. Since NF-κB-mediated transactivation in the nucleus is pivotal downstream of various stimuli to induce inflammation, searching the nuclear-localized targets specifically regulating NF-κB activation will provide important therapeutic application. Here, we have identified that homeodomain-interacting protein kinase 2 (HIPK2), a nuclear serine/threonine kinase, increases its expression in inflammatory macrophages. Importantly, HIPK2 deficiency or overexpression could enhance or inhibit inflammatory responses in LPS-stimulated macrophages, respectively. HIPK2-deficient mice were more susceptible to LPS-induced endotoxemia and CLP-induced sepsis. Adoptive transfer of &lt;em&gt;Hipk2&lt;sup&gt;+/-&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; bone marrow cells (BMs) also aggravated AOM/DSS-induced colorectal cancer. Mechanistically, HIPK2 bound and phosphorylated histone deacetylase 3 (HDAC3) at serine 374 to inhibit its enzymatic activity, thus reducing the deacetylation of p65 at lysine 218 to suppress NF-κB activation. Notably, the HDAC3 inhibitors protected wild-type or &lt;em&gt;Hipk2&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; BMs-reconstituted mice from LPS-induced endotoxemia. Our findings suggest that the HIPK2-HDAC3-p65 module in macrophages restrains excessive inflammation, which may represent a new layer of therapeutic mechanism for colitis-associated colorectal cancer and sepsis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intestinal MYC modulates obesity-related metabolic dysfunction</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34211180/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34211180/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MYC is a transcription factor with broad biological functions, notably in the control of cell proliferation. Here, we show that intestinal MYC regulates systemic metabolism. We find that MYC expression is increased in ileum biopsies from individuals with obesity and positively correlates with body mass index. Intestine-specific reduction of MYC in mice improves high-fat-diet-induced obesity, insulin resistance, hepatic steatosis and steatohepatitis. Mechanistically, reduced expression of MYC in the intestine promotes glucagon-like peptide-1 (GLP-1) production and secretion. Moreover, we identify Cers4, encoding ceramide synthase 4, catalysing de novo ceramide synthesis, as a MYC target gene. Finally, we show that administration of the MYC inhibitor 10058-F4 has beneficial effects on high-fat-diet-induced metabolic disorders, and is accompanied by increased GLP-1 and reduced ceramide levels in serum. This study positions intestinal MYC as a putative drug target against metabolic diseases, including non-alcoholic fatty liver disease and non-alcoholic steatohepatitis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Metagenomic compendium of 189,680 DNA viruses from the human gut microbiome</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34168315/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34168315/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bacteriophages have important roles in the ecology of the human gut microbiome but are under-represented in reference databases. To address this problem, we assembled the Metagenomic Gut Virus catalogue that comprises 189,680 viral genomes from 11,810 publicly available human stool metagenomes. Over 75% of genomes represent double-stranded DNA phages that infect members of the Bacteroidia and Clostridia classes. Based on sequence clustering we identified 54,118 candidate viral species, 92% of which were not found in existing databases. The Metagenomic Gut Virus catalogue improves detection of viruses in stool metagenomes and accounts for nearly 40% of CRISPR spacers found in human gut Bacteria and Archaea. We also produced a catalogue of 459,375 viral protein clusters to explore the functional potential of the gut virome. This revealed tens of thousands of diversity-generating retroelements, which use error-prone reverse transcription to mutate target genes and may be involved in the molecular arms race between phages and their bacterial hosts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Endogenous retroviruses promote homeostatic and inflammatory responses to the microbiota</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34166614/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34166614/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The microbiota plays a fundamental role in regulating host immunity. However, the processes involved in the initiation and regulation of immunity to the microbiota remain largely unknown. Here, we show that the skin microbiota promotes the discrete expression of defined endogenous retroviruses (ERVs). Keratinocyte-intrinsic responses to ERVs depended on cyclic GMP-AMP synthase (cGAS)/stimulator of interferon genes protein (STING) signaling and promoted the induction of commensal-specific T cells. Inhibition of ERV reverse transcription significantly impacted these responses, resulting in impaired immunity to the microbiota and its associated tissue repair function. Conversely, a lipid-enriched diet primed the skin for heightened ERV- expression in response to commensal colonization, leading to increased immune responses and tissue inflammation. Together, our results support the idea that the host may have co-opted its endogenous virome as a means to communicate with the exogenous microbiota, resulting in a multi-kingdom dialog that controls both tissue homeostasis and inflammation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DHX15 is required to control RNA virus-induced intestinal inflammation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34161762/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34161762/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;RNA helicases play critical roles in various biological processes, including serving as viral RNA sensors in innate immunity. Here, we find that RNA helicase DEAH-box helicase 15 (DHX15) is essential for type I interferon (IFN-I, IFN-β), type III IFN (IFN-λ3), and inflammasome-derived cytokine IL-18 production by intestinal epithelial cells (IECs) in response to poly I:C and RNA viruses with preference of enteric RNA viruses, but not DNA virus. Importantly, we generate IEC-specific Dhx15-knockout mice and demonstrate that DHX15 is required for controlling intestinal inflammation induced by enteric RNA virus rotavirus in suckling mice and reovirus in adult mice in vivo, which owes to impaired IFN-β, IFN-λ3, and IL-18 production in IECs from Dhx15-deficient mice. Mechanistically, DHX15 interacts with NLRP6 to trigger NLRP6 inflammasome assembly and activation for inducing IL-18 secretion in IECs. Collectively, our report reveals critical roles for DHX15 in sensing enteric RNA viruses in IECs and controlling intestinal inflammation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GPR34-mediated sensing of lysophosphatidylserine released by apoptotic neutrophils activates type 3 innate lymphoid cells to mediate tissue repair</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34107271/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34107271/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Neutrophils migrate rapidly to damaged tissue and play critical roles in host defense and tissue homeostasis. Here we investigated the mechanisms whereby neutrophils participate in tissue repair. In an intestinal epithelia injury model, neutrophil depletion exacerbated colitis and associated with reduced interleukin (IL)-22 and limited activation of type 3 innate lymphoid cells (ILC3s). Co-culture with neutrophils activated ILC3s in a manner dependent on neutrophil apoptosis. Metabolomic analyses revealed that lysophosphatidylserine (LysoPS) from apoptotic neutrophils directly stimulated ILC3 activation. ILC3-specific deletion of Gpr34, encoding the LysoPS receptor GPR34, or inhibition of downstream PI3K-AKT or ERK suppressed IL-22 production in response to apoptotic neutrophils. Gpr34&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt; mice exhibited compromised ILC3 activation and tissue repair during colon injury, and neutrophil depletion abrogated these defects. GPR34 deficiency in ILC3s limited IL-22 production and tissue repair in vivo in settings of colon and skin injury. Thus, GPR34 is an ILC3-expressed damage-sensing receptor that triggers tissue repair upon recognition of dying neutrophils.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Early-Life Microbial Restitution Reduces Colitis Risk Promoted by Antibiotic-Induced Gut Dysbiosis in Interleukin 10-/- Mice</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34111469/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34111469/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background &amp;amp; aims:&lt;/em&gt; Perturbations in the early-life gut microbiome are associated with increased risk for complex immune disorders like inflammatory bowel diseases. We previously showed that maternal antibiotic-induced gut dysbiosis vertically transmitted to offspring increases experimental colitis risk in interleukin (IL) 10 gene deficient (IL10-/-) mice, a finding that may result from the loss/lack of essential microbes needed for appropriate immunologic education early in life. Here, we aimed to identify key microbes required for proper development of the early-life gut microbiome that decrease colitis risk in genetically susceptible animals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; Metagenomic sequencing followed by reconstruction of metagenome-assembled genomes was performed on fecal samples of IL10-/- mice with and without antibiotic-induced dysbiosis to identify potential missing microbial members needed for immunologic education. One high-value target strain was then engrafted early and/or late into the gut microbiomes of IL10-/- mice with antibiotic-induced dysbiosis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; Early-, but not late-, life engraftment of a single dominant Bacteroides strain of non-antibiotic-treated IL10-/- mice was sufficient to restore the development of the gut microbiome, promote immune tolerance, and prevent colitis in IL10-/- mice that had antibiotic-induced dysbiosis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; Restitution of a keystone microbial strain missing in the early-life antibiotic-induced gut dysbiosis results in recovery of the microbiome, proper development of immune tolerance, and reduced risk for colitis in genetically prone hosts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>gutMEGA: a database of the human gut MEtaGenome Atlas</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32496513/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32496513/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The gut microbiota plays important roles in human health through regulating both physiological homeostasis and disease emergence. The accumulation of metagenomic sequencing studies enables us to better understand the temporal and spatial variations of the gut microbiota under different physiological and pathological conditions. However, it is inconvenient for scientists to query and retrieve published data; thus, a comprehensive resource for the quantitative gut metagenome is urgently needed. In this study, we developed &lt;a href=&#34;http://gutmega.omicsbio.info/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;gut MEtaGenome Atlas (gutMEGA)&lt;/a&gt;, a well-annotated comprehensive database, to curate and host published quantitative gut microbiota datasets from Homo sapiens. By carefully curating the gut microbiota composition, phenotypes and experimental information, &lt;a href=&#34;http://gutmega.omicsbio.info/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;gutMEGA&lt;/a&gt; finally integrated 59 132 quantification events for 6457 taxa at seven different levels (kingdom, phylum, class, order, family, genus and species) under 776 conditions. Moreover, with various browsing and search functions, &lt;a href=&#34;http://gutmega.omicsbio.info/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;gutMEGA&lt;/a&gt; provides a fast and simple way for users to obtain the relative abundances of intestinal microbes among phenotypes. Overall, &lt;a href=&#34;http://gutmega.omicsbio.info/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;gutMEGA&lt;/a&gt; is a convenient and comprehensive resource for gut metagenome research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Temporal landscape of human gut RNA and DNA virome in SARS-CoV-2 infection and severity</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33853691/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33853691/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) caused by the enveloped RNA virus SARS-CoV-2 primarily affects the respiratory and gastrointestinal tracts. SARS-CoV-2 was isolated from fecal samples, and active viral replication was reported in human intestinal cells. The human gut also harbors an enormous amount of resident viruses (collectively known as the virome) that play a role in regulating host immunity and disease pathophysiology. Understanding gut virome perturbation that underlies SARS-CoV-2 infection and severity is an unmet need.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; We enrolled 98 COVID-19 patients with varying disease severity (3 asymptomatic, 53 mild, 34 moderate, 5 severe, 3 critical) and 78 non-COVID-19 controls matched for gender and co-morbidities. All subjects had fecal specimens sampled at inclusion. Blood specimens were collected for COVID-19 patients at admission to test for inflammatory markers and white cell counts. Among COVID-19 cases, 37 (38%) patients had serial fecal samples collected 2 to 3 times per week from time of hospitalization until after discharge. Using shotgun metagenomics sequencing, we sequenced and profiled the fecal RNA and DNA virome. We investigated alterations and longitudinal dynamics of the gut virome in association with disease severity and blood parameters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; Patients with COVID-19 showed underrepresentation of Pepper mild mottle virus (RNA virus) and multiple bacteriophage lineages (DNA viruses) and enrichment of environment-derived eukaryotic DNA viruses in fecal samples, compared to non-COVID-19 subjects. Such gut virome alterations persisted up to 30 days after disease resolution. Fecal virome in SARS-CoV-2 infection harbored more stress-, inflammation-, and virulence-associated gene encoding capacities including those pertaining to bacteriophage integration, DNA repair, and metabolism and virulence associated with their bacterial host. Baseline fecal abundance of 10 virus species (1 RNA virus, pepper chlorotic spot virus, and 9 DNA virus species) inversely correlated with disease COVID-19 severity. These viruses inversely correlated with blood levels of pro-inflammatory proteins, white cells, and neutrophils. Among the 10 COVID-19 severity-associated DNA virus species, 4 showed inverse correlation with age; 5 showed persistent lower abundance both during disease course and after disease resolution relative to non-COVID-19 subjects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; Both enteric RNA and DNA virome in COVID-19 patients were different from non-COVID-19 subjects, which persisted after disease resolution of COVID-19. Gut virome may calibrate host immunity and regulate severity to SARS-CoV-2 infection. Our observation that gut viruses inversely correlated with both severity of COVID-19 and host age may partly explain that older subjects are prone to severe and worse COVID-19 outcomes. Altogether, our data highlight the importance of human gut virome in severity and potentially therapeutics of COVID-19.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integrated gut virome and bacteriome dynamics in COVID-19 patients</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33678150/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33678150/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SARS-CoV-2 is the cause of the current global pandemic of COVID-19; this virus infects multiple organs, such as the lungs and gastrointestinal tract. The microbiome in these organs, including the bacteriome and virome, responds to infection and might also influence disease progression and treatment outcome. In a cohort of 13 COVID-19 patients in Beijing, China, we observed that the gut virome and bacteriome in the COVID-19 patients were notably different from those of five healthy controls. We identified a bacterial dysbiosis signature by observing reduced diversity and viral shifts in patients, and among the patients, the bacterial/viral compositions were different between patients of different severities, although these differences are not entirely distinguishable from the effect of antibiotics. Severe cases of COVID-19 exhibited a greater abundance of opportunistic pathogens but were depleted for butyrate-producing groups of bacteria compared with mild to moderate cases. We replicated our findings in a mouse COVID-19 model, confirmed virome differences and bacteriome dysbiosis due to SARS-CoV-2 infection, and observed that immune/infection-related genes were differentially expressed in gut epithelial cells during infection, possibly explaining the virome and bacteriome dynamics. Our results suggest that the components of the microbiome, including the bacteriome and virome, are affected by SARS-CoV-2 infections, while their compositional signatures could reflect or even contribute to disease severity and recovery processes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Massive expansion of human gut bacteriophage diversity</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33606979/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33606979/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bacteriophages drive evolutionary change in bacterial communities by creating gene flow networks that fuel ecological adaptions. However, the extent of viral diversity and its prevalence in the human gut remains largely unknown. Here, we introduce the Gut Phage Database, a collection of ∼142,000 non-redundant viral genomes (&amp;gt;10 kb) obtained by mining a dataset of 28,060 globally distributed human gut metagenomes and 2,898 reference genomes of cultured gut bacteria. Host assignment revealed that viral diversity is highest in the Firmicutes phyla and that ∼36% of viral clusters (VCs) are not restricted to a single species, creating gene flow networks across phylogenetically distinct bacterial species. Epidemiological analysis uncovered 280 globally distributed VCs found in at least 5 continents and a highly prevalent phage clade with features reminiscent of p-crAssphage. This high-quality, large-scale catalog of phage genomes will improve future virome studies and enable ecological and evolutionary analysis of human gut bacteriophages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Heat Shock Factor 1-dependent extracellular matrix remodeling mediates the transition from chronic intestinal inflammation to colon cancer</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33288768/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33288768/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the colon, long-term exposure to chronic inflammation drives colitis-associated colon cancer (CAC) in patients with inflammatory bowel disease. While the causal and clinical links are well established, molecular understanding of how chronic inflammation leads to the development of colon cancer is lacking. Here we deconstruct the evolving microenvironment of CAC by measuring proteomic changes and extracellular matrix (ECM) organization over time in a mouse model of CAC. We detect early changes in ECM structure and composition, and report a crucial role for the transcriptional regulator heat shock factor 1 (HSF1) in orchestrating these events. Loss of HSF1 abrogates ECM assembly by colon fibroblasts in cell-culture, prevents inflammation-induced ECM remodeling in mice and inhibits progression to CAC. Establishing relevance to human disease, we find high activation of stromal HSF1 in CAC patients, and detect the HSF1-dependent proteomic ECM signature in human colorectal cancer. Thus, HSF1-dependent ECM remodeling plays a crucial role in mediating inflammation-driven colon cancer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A STAT3 palmitoylation cycle promotes TH17 differentiation and colitis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33029007/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33029007/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cysteine palmitoylation (S-palmitoylation) is a reversible post-translational modification that is installed by the DHHC family of palmitoyltransferases and is reversed by several acyl protein thioesterases. Although thousands of human proteins are known to undergo S-palmitoylation, how this modification is regulated to modulate specific biological functions is poorly understood. Here we report that the key T helper 17 (T&lt;sub&gt;H&lt;/sub&gt;17) cell differentiation stimulator, STAT3, is subject to reversible S-palmitoylation on cysteine 108. DHHC7 palmitoylates STAT3 and promotes its membrane recruitment and phosphorylation. Acyl protein thioesterase 2 (APT2, also known as LYPLA2) depalmitoylates phosphorylated STAT3 (p-STAT3) and enables it to translocate to the nucleus. This palmitoylation-depalmitoylation cycle enhances STAT3 activation and promotes T&lt;sub&gt;H&lt;/sub&gt;17 cell differentiation; perturbation of either palmitoylation or depalmitoylation negatively affects T&lt;sub&gt;H&lt;/sub&gt;17 cell differentiation. Overactivation of T&lt;sub&gt;H&lt;/sub&gt;17 cells is associated with several inflammatory diseases, including inflammatory bowel disease (IBD). In a mouse model, pharmacological inhibition of APT2 or knockout of Zdhhc7-which encodes DHHC7-relieves the symptoms of IBD. Our study reveals not only a potential therapeutic strategy for the treatment of IBD but also a model through which S-palmitoylation regulates cell signalling, which might be broadly applicable for understanding the signalling functions of numerous S-palmitoylation events.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Longitudinal Multi-omics Reveals Subset-Specific Mechanisms Underlying Irritable Bowel Syndrome</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32916129/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32916129/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Erratum in:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674%2820%2931447-1&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Longitudinal Multi-omics Reveals Subset-Specific Mechanisms Underlying Irritable Bowel Syndrome&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The gut microbiome has been implicated in multiple human chronic gastrointestinal (GI) disorders. Determining its mechanistic role in disease has been difficult due to apparent disconnects between animal and human studies and lack of an integrated multi-omics view of disease-specific physiological changes. We integrated longitudinal multi-omics data from the gut microbiome, metabolome, host epigenome, and transcriptome in the context of irritable bowel syndrome (IBS) host physiology. We identified IBS subtype-specific and symptom-related variation in microbial composition and function. A subset of identified changes in microbial metabolites correspond to host physiological mechanisms that are relevant to IBS. By integrating multiple data layers, we identified purine metabolism as a novel host-microbial metabolic pathway in IBS with translational potential. Our study highlights the importance of longitudinal sampling and integrating complementary multi-omics data to identify functional mechanisms that can serve as therapeutic targets in a comprehensive treatment strategy for chronic GI diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Excessive deubiquitination of NLRP3-R779C variant contributes to very-early-onset inflammatory bowel disease development</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32941940/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32941940/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Very-early-onset inflammatory bowel disease (VEOIBD) is a chronic inflammatory disease of the gastrointestinal tract occurring during infancy or early childhood. NOD-like receptor family, pyrin domain containing 3 (NLRP3) inflammasome has emerged as a crucial regulator of intestinal homeostasis; however, whether NLRP3 variants may modify VEOIBD risk is unknown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Objective:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We sought to investigate whether and how a rare NLRP3 variant, found in 3 patients with gastrointestinal symptoms, contributes to VEOIBD development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whole-exome sequencing and bioinformatic analysis were performed to screen disease-associated NLRP3 variants from a cohort of children with VEOIBD. Inflammasome activation was determined in reconstituted HEK293T human embryonic kidney cells with NLRP3 inflammasome components, doxycycline-inducible NLRP3 macrophages, as well as PBMCs and biopsies from patients with NLRP3 variants. Pathogenesis of the variants was determined using a dextran sulfate sodium-induced acute colitis model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We identified a dominant gain-of-function missense variant of NLRP3, encoded by rs772009059 (R779C), in 3 patients with gastrointestinal symptoms. Functional analysis revealed that R779C increased NLRP3 inflammasome activation and pyroptosis in macrophages. This was mediated by enhanced deubiquitination of NLRP3 via binding with deubiquitinases BRCC3 and JOSD2, which are highly expressed in myeloid cells. In a dextran sulfate sodium-induced acute colitis model, NLRP3-R779C in hematopoietic cells resulted in more severe colitis, which can be ameliorated via knockdown of BRCC3 or JOSD2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BRCC3 and JOSD2 mediate NLRP3-R779C deubiquitination, which promotes NLRP3 inflammasome activation and the risk of developing VEOIBD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Gut Virome Database Reveals Age-Dependent Patterns of Virome Diversity in the Human Gut</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32841606/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32841606/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The gut microbiome profoundly affects human health and disease, and their infecting viruses are likely as important, but often missed because of reference database limitations. Here, we (1) built a human Gut Virome Database (GVD) from 2,697 viral particle or microbial metagenomes from 1,986 individuals representing 16 countries, (2) assess its effectiveness, and (3) report a meta-analysis that reveals age-dependent patterns across healthy Westerners. The GVD contains 33,242 unique viral populations (approximately species-level taxa) and improves average viral detection rates over viral RefSeq and IMG/VR nearly 182-fold and 2.6-fold, respectively. GVD meta-analyses show highly personalized viromes, reveal that inter-study variability from technical artifacts is larger than any &amp;ldquo;disease&amp;rdquo; effect at the population level, and document how viral diversity changes from human infancy into senescence. Together, this compact foundational resource, these standardization guidelines, and these meta-analysis findings provide a systematic toolkit to help maximize our understanding of viral roles in health and disease.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interferon regulatory factor 1 regulates PANoptosis to prevent colorectal cancer</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32554929/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32554929/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interferon regulatory factor 1 (IRF1) regulates diverse biological functions, including modulation of cellular responses involved in tumorigenesis. Genetic mutations and altered IRF1 function are associated with several cancers. Although the function of IRF1 in the immunobiology of cancer is emerging, IRF1-specific mechanisms regulating tumorigenesis and tissue homeostasis in vivo are not clear. Here, we found that mice lacking IRF1 were hypersusceptible to colorectal tumorigenesis. IRF1 functions in both the myeloid and epithelial compartments to confer protection against AOM/DSS-induced colorectal tumorigenesis. We further found that IRF1 also prevents tumorigenesis in a spontaneous mouse model of colorectal cancer. The attenuated cell death in the colons of Irf1-/- mice was due to defective pyroptosis, apoptosis, and necroptosis (PANoptosis). IRF1 does not regulate inflammation and the inflammasome in the colon. Overall, our study identified IRF1 as an upstream regulator of PANoptosis to induce cell death during colitis-associated tumorigenesis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Influenza infection elicits an expansion of gut population of endogenous Bifidobacterium animalis which protects mice against infection</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32345342/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32345342/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Influenza is a severe respiratory illness that continually threatens global health. It has been widely known that gut microbiota modulates the host response to protect against influenza infection, but mechanistic details remain largely unknown. Here, we took advantage of the phenomenon of lethal dose 50 (LD&lt;sub&gt;50&lt;/sub&gt;) and metagenomic sequencing analysis to identify specific anti-influenza gut microbes and analyze the underlying mechanism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; Transferring fecal microbes from mice that survive virulent influenza H7N9 infection into antibiotic-treated mice confers resistance to infection. Some gut microbes exhibit differential features to lethal influenza infection depending on the infection outcome. Bifidobacterium pseudolongum and Bifidobacterium animalis levels are significantly elevated in surviving mice when compared to dead or mock-infected mice. Oral administration of B. animalis alone or the combination of both significantly reduces the severity of H7N9 infection in both antibiotic-treated and germ-free mice. Functional metagenomic analysis suggests that B. animalis mediates the anti-influenza effect via several specific metabolic molecules. In vivo tests confirm valine and coenzyme A produce an anti-influenza effect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; These findings show that the severity of influenza infection is closely related to the heterogeneous responses of the gut microbiota. We demonstrate the anti-influenza effect of B. animalis, and also find that the gut population of endogenous B. animalis can expand to enhance host influenza resistance when lethal influenza infection occurs, representing a novel interaction between host and gut microbiota. Further, our data suggest the potential utility of Bifidobacterium in the prevention and as a prognostic predictor of influenza.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interaction Between the Microbiota, Epithelia, and Immune Cells in the Intestine</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/32340570/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/32340570/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The gastrointestinal tract harbors numerous commensal bacteria, referred to as the microbiota, that benefit host health by digesting dietary components and eliminating pathogens. The intestinal microbiota maintains epithelial barrier integrity and shapes the mucosal immune system, balancing host defense and oral tolerance with microbial metabolites, components, and attachment to host cells. To avoid aberrant immune responses, epithelial cells segregate the intestinal microbiota from immune cells by constructing chemical and physical barriers, leading to the establishment of host-commensal mutualism. Furthermore, intestinal immune cells participate in the maintenance of a healthy microbiota community and reinforce epithelial barrier functions. Perturbations of the microbiota composition are commonly observed in patients with autoimmune diseases and chronic inflammatory disorders. An understanding of the intimate interactions between the intestinal microbiota, epithelial cells, and immune cells that are crucial for the maintenance of intestinal homeostasis might promote advances in diagnostic and therapeutic approaches for various diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Association to Causality: the Role of the Gut Microbiota and Its Functional Products on Host Metabolism</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/32234490/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/32234490/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many genomic studies have revealed associations between the gut microbiota composition and host metabolism. These observations led to the idea that a causal relationship could exist between the microbiota and metabolic diseases, a concept supported by studies showing compositional changes in the microbial community in metabolic diseases and transmissibility of host phenotype via microbiota transfer. Accumulating data suggest that the microbiota may affect host metabolic phenotypes through the production of metabolites. These bioactive microbial metabolites, sensitive fingerprints of microbial function, can act as inter-kingdom signaling messengers via penetration into host blood circulation and tissues. These fingerprints may be used for diagnostic purposes, and increased understanding of strain specificity in producing microbial metabolites can identify bacterial strains or specific metabolites that can be used for therapeutic purposes. Here, we will review data supporting the causal role of the gut microbiota in metabolism and discuss mechanisms and potential clinical implications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Altered Gut Microbiome Profile in Patients With Pulmonary Arterial Hypertension</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32088998/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32088998/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pulmonary arterial hypertension (PAH) is considered a disease of the pulmonary vasculature. Limited progress has been made in preventing or arresting progression of PAH despite extensive efforts. Our previous studies indicated that PAH could be considered a systemic disease since its pathology involves interplay of multiple organs. This, coupled with increasing implication of the gut and its microbiome in chronic diseases, led us to hypothesize that patients with PAH exhibit a distinct gut microbiome that contributes to, and predicts, the disease. Fecal microbiome of 18 type 1 PAH patients (mean pulmonary arterial pressure, 57.4, SD 16.7 mm Hg) and 13 reference subjects were compared by shotgun metagenomics to evaluate this hypothesis. Significant taxonomic and functional changes in microbial communities in the PAH cohort were observed. Pathways for the synthesis of arginine, proline, and ornithine were increased in PAH cohort compared with reference cohort. Additionally, groups of bacterial communities associated with trimethylamine/ trimethylamine N-oxide and purine metabolism were increased in PAH cohort. In contrast, butyrate-and propionate-producing bacteria such as Coprococcus, Butyrivibrio, Lachnospiraceae, Eubacterium, Akkermansia, and Bacteroides were increased in reference cohort. A random forest model predicted PAH from the composition of the gut microbiome with 83% accuracy. Finally, virome analysis showed enrichment of Enterococcal and relative depletion of Lactococcal phages in the PAH cohort. In conclusion, patients with PAH exhibit a unique microbiome profile that has the high predictive potential for PAH. This highlights previously unknown roles of gut bacteria in this disease and could lead to new therapeutic, diagnostic, or management paradigms for PAH.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GMrepo: a database of curated and consistently annotated human gut metagenomes</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/31504765/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/31504765/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://gmrepo.humangut.info/home&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;GMrepo&lt;/a&gt; (data repository for Gut Microbiota) is a database of curated and consistently annotated human gut metagenomes. Its main purpose is to facilitate the reusability and accessibility of the rapidly growing human metagenomic data. This is achieved by consistently annotating the microbial contents of collected samples using state-of-art toolsets and by manual curation of the meta-data of the corresponding human hosts. &lt;a href=&#34;https://gmrepo.humangut.info/home&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;GMrepo&lt;/a&gt; organizes the collected samples according to their associated phenotypes and includes all possible related meta-data such as age, sex, country, body-mass-index (BMI) and recent antibiotics usage. To make relevant information easier to access, &lt;a href=&#34;https://gmrepo.humangut.info/home&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;GMrepo&lt;/a&gt; is equipped with a graphical query builder, enabling users to make customized, complex and biologically relevant queries. For example, to find (1) samples from healthy individuals of 18 to 25 years old with BMIs between 18.5 and 24.9, or (2) projects that are related to colorectal neoplasms, with each containing &amp;gt;100 samples and both patients and healthy controls. Precomputed species/genus relative abundances, prevalence within and across phenotypes, and pairwise co-occurrence information are all available at the website and accessible through programmable interfaces. So far, &lt;a href=&#34;https://gmrepo.humangut.info/home&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;GMrepo&lt;/a&gt; contains 58 903 human gut samples/runs (including 17 618 metagenomes and 41 285 amplicons) from 253 projects concerning 92 phenotypes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wnt Signaling in 3D: Recent Advances in the Applications of Intestinal Organoids</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/31718893/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/31718893/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Using organoid technology, adult epithelial stem cells can be expanded &lt;em&gt;in vitro&lt;/em&gt; to generate self-organizing 3D epithelial structures that closely recapitulate the architecture and cellular composition of the tissue of origin.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Because of their strict dependence on Wnt ligands for survival and growth, intestinal organoids have become the tool of choice for &lt;em&gt;in vitro&lt;/em&gt; studies aimed at revealing mechanistic aspects of Wnt signaling.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Adult stem cell- and patient-derived intestinal organoids can serve as a platform for investigating mutation-induced disease mechanisms. Insights into how specific mutations alter Wnt activity are becoming a key determinant for tailored therapeutic approaches.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Given the rapid expansion of the organoid field and its applications, there is an increasing need for a standardized method to interpret organoid genotype–phenotype relationships.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Intestinal organoids grown from adult stem cells have emerged as prototype 3D organotypic models for studying tissue renewal and homeostasis. Owing to their strict dependence on Wnt signaling, intestinal organoids offer an unprecedented opportunity to examine Wnt pathway regulation in normal physiology and cancer. We review how alterations in growth factor dependency and organoid morphology can be exploited to identify Wnt signaling mechanisms, characterize mutated pathway components, and predict responses of patient-derived tumors to targeted therapy. We discuss current deficits in the understanding of genotype-phenotype relationships that are to be considered when interpreting mutation-induced changes in organoid morphology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Long-Term Culture Captures Injury-Repair Cycles of Colonic Stem Cells</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/31708126/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/31708126/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The colonic epithelium can undergo multiple rounds of damage and repair, often in response to excessive inflammation. The responsive stem cell that mediates this process is unclear, in part because of a lack of in vitro models that recapitulate key epithelial changes that occur in vivo during damage and repair. Here, we identify a Hopx&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; colitis-associated regenerative stem cell (CARSC) population that functionally contributes to mucosal repair in mouse models of colitis. Hopx&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; CARSCs, enriched for fetal-like markers, transiently arose from hypertrophic crypts known to facilitate regeneration. Importantly, we established a long-term, self-organizing two-dimensional (2D) epithelial monolayer system to model the regenerative properties and responses of Hopx&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; CARSCs. This system can reenact the &amp;ldquo;homeostasis-injury-regeneration&amp;rdquo; cycles of epithelial alterations that occur in vivo. Using this system, we found that hypoxia and endoplasmic reticulum stress, insults commonly present in inflammatory bowel diseases, mediated the cyclic switch of cellular status in this process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commensal viruses maintain intestinal intraepithelial lymphocytes via noncanonical RIG-I signaling</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/31636462/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/31636462/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Much attention has focused on commensal bacteria in health and disease, but the role of commensal viruses is understudied. Although metagenomic analysis shows that the intestine of healthy humans and animals harbors various commensal viruses and the dysbiosis of these viruses can be associated with inflammatory diseases, there is still a lack of causal data and underlying mechanisms to understand the physiological role of commensal viruses in intestinal homeostasis. In the present study, we show that commensal viruses are essential for the homeostasis of intestinal intraepithelial lymphocytes (IELs). Mechanistically, the cytosolic viral RNA-sensing receptor RIG-I in antigen-presenting cells can recognize commensal viruses and maintain IELs via a type I interferon-independent, but MAVS-IRF1-IL-15 axis-dependent, manner. The recovery of IELs by interleukin-15 administration reverses the susceptibility of commensal virus-depleted mice to dextran sulfate sodium-induced colitis. Collectively, our results indicate that commensal viruses maintain the IELs and consequently sustain intestinal homeostasis via noncanonical RIG-I signaling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enterovirus pathogenesis requires the host methyltransferase SETD3</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/31527793/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/31527793/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enteroviruses (EVs) comprise a large genus of positive-sense, single-stranded RNA viruses whose members cause a number of important and widespread human diseases, including poliomyelitis, myocarditis, acute flaccid myelitis and the common cold. How EVs co-opt cellular functions to promote replication and spread is incompletely understood. Here, using genome-scale CRISPR screens, we identify the actin histidine methyltransferase SET domain containing 3 (SETD3) as critically important for viral infection by a broad panel of EVs, including rhinoviruses and non-polio EVs increasingly linked to severe neurological disease such as acute flaccid myelitis (EV-D68) and viral encephalitis (EV-A71). We show that cytosolic SETD3, independent of its methylation activity, is required for the RNA replication step in the viral life cycle. Using quantitative affinity purification-mass spectrometry, we show that SETD3 specifically interacts with the viral 2A protease of multiple enteroviral species, and we map the residues in 2A that mediate this interaction. 2A mutants that retain protease activity but are unable to interact with SETD3 are severely compromised in RNA replication. These data suggest a role of the viral 2A protein in RNA replication beyond facilitating proteolytic cleavage. Finally, we show that SETD3 is essential for in vivo replication and pathogenesis in multiple mouse models for EV infection, including CV-A10, EV-A71 and EV-D68. Our results reveal a crucial role of a host protein in viral pathogenesis, and suggest targeting SETD3 as a potential mechanism for controlling viral infections.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Virtual Metabolic Human database: integrating human and gut microbiome metabolism with nutrition and disease</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/30371894/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/30371894/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A multitude of factors contribute to complex diseases and can be measured with &amp;lsquo;omics&amp;rsquo; methods. Databases facilitate data interpretation for underlying mechanisms. Here, we describe the &lt;a href=&#34;www.vmh.life&#34;&gt;Virtual Metabolic Human (VMH)&lt;/a&gt; database encapsulating current knowledge of human metabolism within five interlinked resources &amp;lsquo;Human metabolism&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;Gut microbiome&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;Disease&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;Nutrition&amp;rsquo;, and &amp;lsquo;ReconMaps&amp;rsquo;. The &lt;a href=&#34;www.vmh.life&#34;&gt;VMH&lt;/a&gt; captures 5180 unique metabolites, 17 730 unique reactions, 3695 human genes, 255 Mendelian diseases, 818 microbes, 632 685 microbial genes and 8790 food items. The &lt;a href=&#34;www.vmh.life&#34;&gt;VMH&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s unique features are (i) the hosting of the metabolic reconstructions of human and gut microbes amenable for metabolic modeling; (ii) seven human metabolic maps for data visualization; (iii) a nutrition designer; (iv) a user-friendly webpage and application-programming interface to access its content; (v) user feedback option for community engagement and (vi) the connection of its entities to 57 other web resources. The &lt;a href=&#34;www.vmh.life&#34;&gt;VMH&lt;/a&gt; represents a novel, interdisciplinary database for data interpretation and hypothesis generation to the biomedical community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optogenetic and chemogenetic techniques for neurogastroenterology</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/29184183/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/29184183/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Optogenetics and chemogenetics comprise a wide variety of applications in which genetically encoded actuators and indicators are used to modulate and monitor activity with high cellular specificity. Over the past 10 years, development of these genetically encoded tools has contributed tremendously to our understanding of integrated physiology. In concert with the continued refinement of probes, strategies to target transgene expression to specific cell types have also made much progress in the past 20 years. In addition, the successful implementation of optogenetic and chemogenetic techniques thrives thanks to ongoing advances in live imaging microscopy and optical technology. Although innovation of optogenetic and chemogenetic methods has been primarily driven by researchers studying the central nervous system, these techniques also hold great promise to boost research in neurogastroenterology. In this Review, we describe the different classes of tools that are currently available and give an overview of the strategies to target them to specific cell types in the gut wall. We discuss the possibilities and limitations of optogenetic and chemogenetic technology in the gut and provide an overview of their current use, with a focus on the enteric nervous system. Furthermore, we suggest some experiments that can advance our understanding of how the intrinsic and extrinsic neural networks of the gut control gastrointestinal function.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Mouse Intestinal Bacterial Collection (miBC) provides host-specific insight into cultured diversity and functional potential of the gut microbiota</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/27670113/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/27670113/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Erratum in:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Corrigendum: &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nature.com/articles/nmicrobiol2016219&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;The Mouse Intestinal Bacterial Collection (miBC) provides host-specific insight into cultured diversity and functional potential of the gut microbiota&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Intestinal bacteria influence mammalian physiology, but many types of bacteria are still uncharacterized. Moreover, reference strains of mouse gut bacteria are not easily available, although mouse models are extensively used in medical research. These are major limitations for the investigation of intestinal microbiomes and their interactions with diet and host. It is thus important to study in detail the diversity and functions of gut microbiota members, including those colonizing the mouse intestine. To address these issues, we aimed at establishing the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.dsmz.de/collection/catalogue/microorganisms/special-groups-of-organisms/dzif-sammlung/maus-mikrobiomliste&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Mouse Intestinal Bacterial Collection (miBC)&lt;/a&gt;, a public repository of bacterial strains and associated genomes from the mouse gut, and studied host-specificity of colonization and sequence-based relevance of the resource. The collection includes several strains representing novel species, genera and even one family. Genomic analyses showed that certain species are specific to the mouse intestine and that a minimal consortium of 18 strains covered 50-75% of the known functional potential of metagenomes. The present work will sustain future research on microbiota-host interactions in health and disease, as it will facilitate targeted colonization and molecular studies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commensal microbiota from patients with inflammatory bowel disease produce genotoxic metabolites</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36302024/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jun 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36302024/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Introduction&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gut microbiota can potentially contribute to the development and progression of colorectal cancer (CRC) by producing small-molecule genotoxins. For example, select commensal &lt;em&gt;Escherichia coli&lt;/em&gt; strains produce the canonical microbiota-derived genotoxin colibactin, which engenders the formation of DNA double-strand breaks (DSBs) in intestinal epithelial cells and exacerbates CRC in mouse models. Furthermore, human CRCs harbor colibactin-associated mutational signatures, implying a direct role for microbiota-induced DNA damage in CRC. However, the impacts of microbiota-derived genotoxins beyond colibactin remain largely unexplored.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rationale&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given the extensive diversity of small-molecule metabolites produced by bacteria, we hypothesized that additional taxa from the human gut microbiome might produce previously undiscovered small molecules that cause DNA damage in host cells. Identifying and characterizing such genotoxins and their respective biosynthetic pathways may reveal causal roles of gut microbes in shaping host biology and disease susceptibility. Thus, we designed a large-scale electrophoresis-based DNA damage screening pipeline to evaluate the genotoxicity of a collection of more than 100 gut commensals isolated from patients with inflammatory bowel disease (IBD).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We identified diverse bacteria from the human microbiota whose small-molecule metabolites caused genotoxicity in both cell-free and cell-based DNA damage assays. For example, small-molecule metabolites from gram-positive bacteria (including &lt;em&gt;Clostridium perfringens&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Clostridium ramosum&lt;/em&gt; strains) and gram-negative bacteria (including multiple &lt;em&gt;Morganella morganii&lt;/em&gt; strains) directly damaged DNA in cell-free assays and induced the expression of the DSB marker γ-H2AX and cell-cycle arrest in epithelial cells. However, the DNA damage patterns caused by these metabolites were distinct from colibactin-induced cross-links, and these isolates lacked the biosynthetic machinery to produce colibactin or other known genotoxins. These data thus implied the existence of previously unrecognized microbiota-derived genotoxins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;M. morganii&lt;/em&gt; is enriched in the gut microbiota of both IBD and CRC patients. Using a combination of comparative metabolomics and bioactivity-guided natural product-discovery techniques, we discovered a family of &lt;em&gt;M. morganii&lt;/em&gt;-derived small-molecule genotoxins—termed the indolimines—that elicited DNA damage in cell-based and cell-free assays. Furthermore, we identified a previously uncharacterized bacterial decarboxylase (annotated as an aspartate aminotransferase encoded by the &lt;em&gt;aat&lt;/em&gt; gene) that was essential for indolimine synthesis and constructed an isogenic aat mutant &lt;em&gt;M. morganii&lt;/em&gt; that lacked genotoxicity in both cell-free and cell-based DNA damage assays.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Compared with the non–indolimine-producing mutant, wild-type &lt;em&gt;M. morganii&lt;/em&gt; caused increased intestinal permeability and induced transcriptional signatures associated with abnormal DNA replication and intestinal epithelial cell proliferation in gnotobiotic mice. Furthermore, indolimine-producing &lt;em&gt;M. morganii&lt;/em&gt; induced increased colonic tumor burden in the context of a mock microbial community in a mouse model of CRC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By leveraging function-based assessments of the microbiome, we uncovered the existence of a broader universe of microbiota-derived small-molecule genotoxins. We found that diverse bacterial strains isolated from IBD patients exhibited DNA-damaging activities and discovered a previously undescribed family of genotoxins, termed the indolimines, produced by the IBD- and CRC-associated species &lt;em&gt;M. morganii&lt;/em&gt;. Indolimine-producing &lt;em&gt;M. morganii&lt;/em&gt; caused increased intestinal permeability and exacerbated colon tumorigenesis in gnotobiotic mice. Overall, these studies imply an expanded role for microbiota-derived genotoxins in shaping host biology and disease susceptibility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
