<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Intestine | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/intestine/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/intestine/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Intestine</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Intestine</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/intestine/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Biomarker-responsive engineered probiotic diagnoses, records, and ameliorates inflammatory bowel disease in mice</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/22-12-29-21-52/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/22-12-29-21-52/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;i-ROBOT converts IBD information into trackable and heritable DNA alterations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;i-ROBOT contains a self-tunable, thiosulfate-regulated drug release system&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;i-ROBOT has a replaceable biomarker-sensing element, creating a broad platform&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Summary&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rapid advances in synthetic biology have fueled interest in engineered microorganisms that can diagnose and treat disease. However, designing bacteria that detect dynamic disease-associated biomarkers that then drive treatment remains difficult. Here, we have developed an engineered probiotic that noninvasively monitors and records inflammatory bowel disease (IBD) occurrence and progression in real time and can release treatments via a self-tunable mechanism in response to these biomarkers. These intelligent responsive bacteria for diagnosis and therapy (i-ROBOT) consists of E. coli Nissle 1917 that responds to levels of the inflammatory marker thiosulfate by activating a base-editing system to generate a heritable genomic DNA sequence as well as producing a colorimetric signal. Fluctuations in thiosulfate also drive the tunable release of the immunomodulator AvCystatin. Orally administering i-ROBOT to mice with colitis generated molecular recording signals in processed fecal and colon samples and effectively ameliorated disease. i-ROBOT provides a promising paradigm for gastrointestinal and other metabolic disorders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Virtual Metabolic Human database: integrating human and gut microbiome metabolism with nutrition and disease</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/30371894/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/30371894/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A multitude of factors contribute to complex diseases and can be measured with &amp;lsquo;omics&amp;rsquo; methods. Databases facilitate data interpretation for underlying mechanisms. Here, we describe the &lt;a href=&#34;www.vmh.life&#34;&gt;Virtual Metabolic Human (VMH)&lt;/a&gt; database encapsulating current knowledge of human metabolism within five interlinked resources &amp;lsquo;Human metabolism&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;Gut microbiome&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;Disease&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;Nutrition&amp;rsquo;, and &amp;lsquo;ReconMaps&amp;rsquo;. The &lt;a href=&#34;www.vmh.life&#34;&gt;VMH&lt;/a&gt; captures 5180 unique metabolites, 17 730 unique reactions, 3695 human genes, 255 Mendelian diseases, 818 microbes, 632 685 microbial genes and 8790 food items. The &lt;a href=&#34;www.vmh.life&#34;&gt;VMH&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s unique features are (i) the hosting of the metabolic reconstructions of human and gut microbes amenable for metabolic modeling; (ii) seven human metabolic maps for data visualization; (iii) a nutrition designer; (iv) a user-friendly webpage and application-programming interface to access its content; (v) user feedback option for community engagement and (vi) the connection of its entities to 57 other web resources. The &lt;a href=&#34;www.vmh.life&#34;&gt;VMH&lt;/a&gt; represents a novel, interdisciplinary database for data interpretation and hypothesis generation to the biomedical community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Mouse Intestinal Bacterial Collection (miBC) provides host-specific insight into cultured diversity and functional potential of the gut microbiota</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/27670113/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/27670113/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Erratum in:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Corrigendum: &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nature.com/articles/nmicrobiol2016219&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;The Mouse Intestinal Bacterial Collection (miBC) provides host-specific insight into cultured diversity and functional potential of the gut microbiota&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Intestinal bacteria influence mammalian physiology, but many types of bacteria are still uncharacterized. Moreover, reference strains of mouse gut bacteria are not easily available, although mouse models are extensively used in medical research. These are major limitations for the investigation of intestinal microbiomes and their interactions with diet and host. It is thus important to study in detail the diversity and functions of gut microbiota members, including those colonizing the mouse intestine. To address these issues, we aimed at establishing the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.dsmz.de/collection/catalogue/microorganisms/special-groups-of-organisms/dzif-sammlung/maus-mikrobiomliste&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Mouse Intestinal Bacterial Collection (miBC)&lt;/a&gt;, a public repository of bacterial strains and associated genomes from the mouse gut, and studied host-specificity of colonization and sequence-based relevance of the resource. The collection includes several strains representing novel species, genera and even one family. Genomic analyses showed that certain species are specific to the mouse intestine and that a minimal consortium of 18 strains covered 50-75% of the known functional potential of metagenomes. The present work will sustain future research on microbiota-host interactions in health and disease, as it will facilitate targeted colonization and molecular studies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
