<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Gall bladder | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/gall-bladder/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/gall-bladder/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Gall bladder</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Gall bladder</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/gall-bladder/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>LncRNA MNX1-AS1 sustains inactivation of Hippo pathway through a positive feedback loop with USP16/IGF2BP3 axis in gallbladder cancer</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35953000/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35953000/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MNX1-AS1 expression is upregulated in GBC and predicts poor prognosis.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Overexpression of MNX1-AS1 facilitates the proliferation and metastasis of GBC cells in vitro and in vivo.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MNX1-AS1 acts as a scaffold for recruiting USP16 to stabilize IGF2BP3.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MNX1-AS1/IGF2BP3/Hippo pathway positive feedback loop contributes to GBC progression.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The long non-coding RNAs (lncRNAs) have been implicated in multiple human cancers, which may offer great potential as putative targets for cancer diagnosis and treatment. However, the roles of most lncRNAs in gallbladder cancer (GBC) remain poorly understood. The objective of this research involves investigating the clinical implications and underlying mechanism of lncRNA motor neuron and pancreas homeobo×1 antisense RNA 1 (MNX1-AS1) in GBC. This study shows that MNX1-AS1 expression is elevated in the tissues of GBC patients, and is strongly associated with reduced patient survival. Functionally, MNX1-AS1 significantly stimulates the proliferation and metastasis of GBC cells in vitro and in vivo. Mechanistically, MNX1-AS1 is transcriptionally activated by TEA domain family member 4 (TEAD4), and suppresses insulin-like growing factor 2 mRNA-binding protein 3 (IGF2BP3) degradation by recruiting ubiquitin specific peptidase 16 (USP16). Furthermore, MNX1-AS1/IGF2BP3 axis inhibits the Hippo signaling pathway and subsequently activates TEAD4, thereby forming a positive feedback loop. According to our results, MNX1-AS1 facilitates tumorigenesis, progression and metastasis of GBC through a MNX1-AS1/IGF2BP3/Hippo pathway positive feedback loop, which could be both diagnostically and therapeutically helpful in GBC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LncRNA-HGBC stabilized by HuR promotes gallbladder cancer progression by regulating miR-502-3p/SET/AKT axis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/31752906/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/31752906/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Erratum in:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Correction to: &lt;a href=&#34;https://molecular-cancer.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12943-021-01386-8&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;LncRNA-HGBC stabilized by HuR promotes gallbladder cancer progression by regulating miR-502-3p/SET/AKT axis&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Backgrounds:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Long non-coding RNAs (lncRNAs) are essential factors that regulate tumor development and metastasis via diverse molecular mechanisms in a broad type of cancers. However, the pathological roles of lncRNAs in gallbladder carcinoma (GBC) remain largely unknown. Here we discovered a novel lncRNA termed lncRNA Highly expressed in GBC (lncRNA-HGBC) which was upregulated in GBC tissue and aimed to investigate its role and regulatory mechanism in the development and progression of GBC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The expression level of lncRNA-HGBC in GBC tissue and different cell lines was determined by quantitative real-time PCR. The full length of lncRNA-HGBC was obtained by 5&amp;rsquo; and 3&amp;rsquo; rapid amplification of the cDNA ends (RACE). Cellular localization of lncRNA-HGBC was detected by fluorescence in situ hybridization (FISH) assays and subcellular fractionation assay. In vitro and in vivo assays were preformed to explore the biological effects of lncRNA-HGBC in GBC cells. RNA pull-down assay, mass spectrometry, and RNA immunoprecipitation (RIP) assay were used to identify lncRNA-HGBC-interacting proteins. Dual luciferase reporter assays, AGO2-RIP, and MS2-RIP assays were performed to verify the interaction between lncRNA-HGBC and miR-502-3p.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We found that lncRNA-HGBC was upregulated in GBC and its upregulation could predict poor survival. Overexpression or knockdown of lncRNA-HGBC in GBC cell lines resulted in increased or decreased, respectively, cell proliferation and invasion in vitro and in xenografted tumors. LncRNA-HGBC specifically bound to RNA binding protein Hu Antigen R (HuR) that in turn stabilized lncRNA-HGBC. LncRNA-HGBC functioned as a competitive endogenous RNA to bind to miR-502-3p that inhibits target gene SET. Overexpression, knockdown or mutation of lncRNA-HGBC altered the inhibitory effects of miR-502-3p on SET expression and downstream activation of AKT. Clinically, lncRNA-HGBC expression was negatively correlated with miR-502-3p, but positively correlated with SET and HuR in GBC tissue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our study demonstrates that lncRNA-HGBC promotes GBC metastasis via activation of the miR-502-3p-SET-AKT cascade, pointing to lncRNA-HGBC as a new prognostic predictor and a therapeutic target.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
