<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Epidemiology | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/epidemiology/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/epidemiology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Epidemiology</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Epidemiology</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/epidemiology/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hypertension in China: epidemiology and treatment initiatives</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/36631532/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/36631532/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The past two to three decades have seen a steady increase in the prevalence of hypertension in China, largely owing to increased life expectancy and lifestyle changes (particularly among individuals aged 35-44 years). Data from the China hypertension survey conducted in 2012-2015 revealed a high prevalence of grade 3 hypertension (systolic blood pressure ≥180 mmHg and diastolic blood pressure ≥110 mmHg) in the general population, which increased with age to up to 5% among individuals aged ≥65 years. The risk profile of patients with hypertension in China has also been a subject of intense study in the past 30 years. Dietary sodium and potassium intake have remained largely the same in China in the past three decades, and salt substitution strategies seem to be effective in reducing blood pressure levels and the risk of cardiovascular events and death. However, the number of individuals with risk factors for hypertension and cardiovascular disease in general, such as physical inactivity and obesity, has increased dramatically in the same period. Moreover, even in patients diagnosed with hypertension, their disease is often poorly managed owing to a lack of patient education and poor treatment compliance. In this Review, we summarize the latest epidemiological data on hypertension in China, discuss the risk factors for hypertension that are specific to this population, and describe several ongoing nationwide hypertension control initiatives that target these risk factors, especially in the low-resource rural setting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Key points&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The prevalence of hypertension in China has increased substantially in the past 30 years, and hypertension now affects approximately a quarter of all Chinese adults; this increase is mainly attributable to increased life expectancy among the general population, but also to lifestyle changes among individuals aged 35–44 years.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The north–south gradient in the prevalence of hypertension in China, which was apparent from data in 1991, is no longer prominent given the increasing prevalence of hypertension in the entire region.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The prevalence of grade 3 hypertension is high (1.6%) and increases substantially with age to up to 5% in patients aged ≥65 years.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The blood pressure control rate among patients in China is generally low owing to poor awareness and poor treatment adherence; several ongoing initiatives are aimed at improving blood pressure control, especially in the low-resource rural setting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seroepidemiology of enterovirus A71 infection in prospective cohort studies of children in southern China, 2013-2018</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36435844/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36435844/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enterovirus A71 (EV-A71)-related hand, foot, and mouth disease (HFMD) imposes a substantial clinical burden in the Asia Pacific region. To inform policy on the introduction of the EV-A71 vaccine into the National Immunization Programme, we investigated the seroepidemiological characteristics of EV-A71 in two prospective cohorts of children in southern China conducted between 2013 and 2018. Our results show that maternal antibody titres declined rapidly in neonates, with over half becoming susceptible to EV-A71 at 1 month of age. Between 6 months and 2 years of age, over 80% of study participants were susceptible, while one third remained susceptible at 5 years old. The highest incidence of EV-A71 infections was observed in children aged 5-6 months. Our findings support EV-A71 vaccination before 6 months for birth cohorts in southern China, potentially with a one-time catch-up vaccination for children 6 months-5 years old. More regionally representative longitudinal seroepidemiological studies are needed to further validate these findings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Global burden of colorectal cancer in 2020 and 2040: incidence and mortality estimates from GLOBOCAN</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36604116/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36604116/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Objective:&lt;/em&gt; Colorectal cancer (CRC) is the third most common cancer worldwide. The geographical and temporal burden of this cancer provides insights into risk factor prevalence and progress in cancer control strategies. We examine the current and future burden of CRC in 185 countries in 2020 and 2040.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; Data on CRC cases and deaths were extracted from the GLOBOCAN database for the year 2020. Age-standardised incidence and mortality rates were calculated by sex, country, world region and Human Development Index (HDI) for 185 countries. Age-specific rates were also estimated. The predicted number of cases and deaths in 2040 were calculated based on global demographic projections by HDI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; Over 1.9 million new CRC cases and 930 000 deaths were estimated in 2020. Incidence rates were highest in Australia/ New Zealand and European regions (40.6 per 100 000, males) and lowest in several African regions and Southern Asia (4.4 per 100 000, females). Similar patterns were observed for mortality rates, with the highest observed in Eastern Europe (20.2 per 100 000, males) and the lowest in Southern Asia (2.5 per 100 000, females). The burden of CRC is projected to increase to 3.2 million new cases and 1.6 million deaths by 2040 with most cases predicted to occur in high or very high HDI countries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; CRC is a highly frequent cancer worldwide, and largely preventable through changes in modifiable risk factors, alongside the detection and removal of precancerous lesions. With increasing rates in transitioning countries and younger adults, there is a pressing need to better understand and act on findings to avert future cases and deaths from the disease.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Virome characterization of game animals in China reveals a spectrum of emerging pathogens</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35298912/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35298912/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1,941 game animals from five mammalian orders were surveyed for viruses&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;102 mammalian-infecting viruses were discovered, 21 posing a potential risk to humans&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Civets carried a relatively higher number of potentially “high-risk” viruses&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Human-infecting viruses were also identified in game animals&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Game animals are wildlife species traded and consumed as food and are potential reservoirs for SARS-CoV and SARS-CoV-2. We performed a meta-transcriptomic analysis of 1,941 game animals, representing 18 species and five mammalian orders, sampled across China. From this, we identified 102 mammalian-infecting viruses, with 65 described for the first time. Twenty-one viruses were considered as potentially high risk to humans and domestic animals. Civets (&lt;em&gt;Paguma larvata&lt;/em&gt;) carried the highest number of potentially high-risk viruses. We inferred the transmission of bat-associated coronavirus from bats to civets, as well as cross-species jumps of coronaviruses from bats to hedgehogs, from birds to porcupines, and from dogs to raccoon dogs. Of note, we identified avian &lt;em&gt;Influenza A virus&lt;/em&gt; H9N2 in civets and Asian badgers, with the latter displaying respiratory symptoms, as well as cases of likely human-to-wildlife virus transmission. These data highlight the importance of game animals as potential drivers of disease emergence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cigarette Smoke Exposure and Acute Respiratory Distress Syndrome in Sepsis: Epidemiology, Clinical Features, and Biologic Markers</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35050845/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35050845/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rationale:&lt;/em&gt; Cigarette smoke exposure is associated with an increased risk of developing acute respiratory distress syndrome (ARDS) in trauma, transfusion, and nonpulmonary sepsis. It is unknown whether this relationship exists in the general sepsis population. Furthermore, it is unknown if patients with ARDS have differences in underlying biology based on smoking status.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Objectives:&lt;/em&gt; To assess the relationship between cigarette smoke exposure and ARDS in sepsis and identify tobacco-related biomarkers of lung injury.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; We studied a prospective cohort of 592 patients with sepsis from 2009 to 2017. Plasma cotinine and urine NNAL [urine 4-(methylnitrosamino)-1-(3-pyridyl)-1-butanol] were measured to categorize smoking status. Plasma biomarkers of inflammation and lung injury were measured, including in a smaller cohort of trauma patients with ARDS to increase generalizability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Measurements and Main Results:&lt;/em&gt; Passive and active smoking were associated with increased odds of developing ARDS in patients with sepsis. Among patients with sepsis and ARDS, active cigarette smokers were younger and had lower severity of illness than nonsmokers. Patients with ARDS with cigarette smoke exposure had lower plasma levels of IL-8 (P = 0.01) and sTNFR-1 (soluble tumor necrosis factor 1; P = 0.01) compared with those without exposure. Similar biomarker patterns were observed in blunt trauma patients with ARDS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; Passive and active smoking are associated with an increased risk of developing ARDS in patients with pulmonary and nonpulmonary sepsis. Among patients with ARDS, those with cigarette smoke exposure have less systemic inflammation, while active smokers also have lower severity of illness compared with nonsmokers, suggesting that smoking contributes to biological heterogeneity in ARDS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
