<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Molecular Interactions | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/molecular-interactions/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/molecular-interactions/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Molecular Interactions</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Molecular Interactions</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/molecular-interactions/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>SGPPI: structure-aware prediction of protein-protein interactions in rigorous conditions with graph convolutional network</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36682013/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36682013/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While deep learning (DL)-based models have emerged as powerful approaches to predict protein-protein interactions (PPIs), the reliance on explicit similarity measures (e.g. sequence similarity and network neighborhood) to known interacting proteins makes these methods ineffective in dealing with novel proteins. The advent of AlphaFold2 presents a significant opportunity and also a challenge to predict PPIs in a straightforward way based on monomer structures while controlling bias from protein sequences. In this work, we established Structure and Graph-based Predictions of Protein Interactions (SGPPI), a structure-based DL framework for predicting PPIs, using the graph convolutional network. In particular, SGPPI focused on protein patches on the protein-protein binding interfaces and extracted the structural, geometric and evolutionary features from the residue contact map to predict PPIs. We demonstrated that our model outperforms traditional machine learning methods and state-of-the-art DL-based methods using non-representation-bias benchmark datasets. Moreover, our model trained on human dataset can be reliably transferred to predict yeast PPIs, indicating that SGPPI can capture converging structural features of protein interactions across various species.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Co-evolution-based prediction of metal-binding sites in proteomes by machine learning</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36593274/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36593274/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Metal ions have various important biological roles in proteins, including structural maintenance, molecular recognition and catalysis. Previous methods of predicting metal-binding sites in proteomes were based on either sequence or structural motifs. Here we developed a co-evolution-based pipeline named &amp;lsquo;MetalNet&amp;rsquo; to systematically predict metal-binding sites in proteomes. We applied MetalNet to proteomes of four representative prokaryotic species and predicted 4,849 potential metalloproteins, which substantially expands the currently annotated metalloproteomes. We biochemically and structurally validated previously unannotated metal-binding sites in several proteins, including apo-citrate lyase phosphoribosyl-dephospho-CoA transferase citX, an Escherichia coli enzyme lacking structural or sequence homology to any known metalloprotein (Protein Data Bank (PDB) codes: 7DCM and 7DCN ). MetalNet also successfully recapitulated all known zinc-binding sites from the human spliceosome complex. The pipeline of MetalNet provides a unique and enabling tool for interrogating the hidden metalloproteome and studying metal biology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DNA-modularized construction of bivalent ligands precisely regulates receptor binding and activation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/chempr.2022.12.002/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/chempr.2022.12.002/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A DNA-modularized strategy is developed to automatically construct bivalent ligands&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deoxynucleotides serve as spacers to regulate the conformation of bivalent ligands&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Recognition conformation of bivalent ligands is regulated at the single-nucleotide level&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“AA” is the optimal spacer of B-DNA-X connectomes for selective activation of M1R&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The bigger picture&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bivalent ligands are frequently developed in the drug industry to improve drug efficacy and selectivity and to reduce drug resistance. Spacers of bivalent ligands play a key role in coordinating their conformation and activation for optimal drug efficacy. Conventional strategies, which rely on polymers as spacers, suffer from the paucity of structural precision and variability with time-consuming ligation procedures. Here, we originate a DNA-modularized strategy capable of constructing bivalent ligands in an automatic and high-throughput manner. In this strategy, DNA becomes the spacer that precisely regulates the conformation and activation of receptors at the single-nucleotide level. Considering that a myriad of protein targets require bivalent ligands to bind with them and then coordinate a ligand-protein complex for optimal drug effects, our DNA-modularized strategy will be extended to the construction of many bivalent ligands in the drug industry for the benefit of human health.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Great interest is focused on the construction of bivalent ligands, where the spacer is crucial to coordinate the distance and orientation of two pharmacophores for optimal biological effects. Current strategies rely on polymers as spacers but suffer from the paucity of structural precision and variability with time-consuming ligation procedures. Herein, we originate a DNA-modularized strategy where pharmacophores are modularly modified with the protecting groups used for automatic DNA synthesis while natural deoxynucleotides serve as spacers. By programmably regulating the number and permutation of the bridged DNA spacer, the two pharmacophores are adjusted with a defined distance and versatile orientation. Using this strategy, we successfully constructed a reservoir of bivalent ligands containing an orthosteric agonist and an allosteric modulator, exhibiting a single-nucleotide difference in the selective activation of muscarinic acetylcholine receptors. Our strategy opens a new avenue for the precise construction and efficient screening of bivalent ligands toward a myriad of biomedical applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Genetic dissection of intercellular interactions in vivo by membrane-permeable protein</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36574652/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36574652/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unraveling cell-cell interaction is fundamental to understanding many biological processes. To date, genetic tools for labeling neighboring cells in mammals are not available. Here, we developed a labeling strategy based on the Cre-induced intercellular labeling protein (CILP). Cre-expressing donor cells release a lipid-soluble and membrane-permeable fluorescent protein that is then taken up by recipient cells, enabling fluorescent labeling of neighboring cells. Using CILP, we specifically labeled endothelial cells surrounding a special population of hepatocytes in adult mice and revealed their distinct gene signatures. Our results highlight the potential of CILP as a platform to reveal cell-cell interactions and communications &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R-loop-derived cytoplasmic RNA-DNA hybrids activate an immune response</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36544021/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36544021/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;R-loops are RNA–DNA-hybrid-containing nucleic acids with important cellular roles. Deregulation of R-loop dynamics can lead to DNA damage and genome instability, which has been linked to the action of endonucleases such as XPG. However, the mechanisms and cellular consequences of such processing have remained unclear. Here we identify a new population of RNA–DNA hybrids in the cytoplasm that are R-loop-processing products. When nuclear R-loops were perturbed by depleting the RNA–DNA helicase senataxin (SETX) or the breast cancer gene BRCA1, we observed XPG- and XPF-dependent cytoplasmic hybrid formation. We identify their source as a subset of stable, overlapping nuclear hybrids with a specific nucleotide signature. Cytoplasmic hybrids bind to the pattern recognition receptors cGAS and TLR3, activating IRF3 and inducing apoptosis. Excised hybrids and an R-loop-induced innate immune response were also observed in SETX-mutated cells from patients with ataxia oculomotor apraxia type 2 and in BRCA1-mutated cancer cells. These findings establish RNA–DNA hybrids as immunogenic species that aberrantly accumulate in the cytoplasm after R-loop processing, linking R-loop accumulation to cell death through the innate immune response. Aberrant R-loop processing and subsequent innate immune activation may contribute to many diseases, such as neurodegeneration and cancer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Engineered cell entry links receptor biology with single-cell genomics</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36516854/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36516854/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ENTER displays ligands, delivers payloads, and records receptor specificity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ENTER enables antigen-specific expansion or depletion of T or B cells&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ENTER-seq maps TCR specificity, clonality, and cell state in single cells&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ENTER-seq of patient sample decodes antiviral T cell memory&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cells communicate with each other via receptor-ligand interactions. Here, we describe lentiviral-mediated cell entry by engineered receptor-ligand interaction (ENTER) to display ligand proteins, deliver payloads, and record receptor specificity. We optimize ENTER to decode interactions between T cell receptor (TCR)-MHC peptides, antibody-antigen, and other receptor-ligand pairs. A viral presentation strategy allows ENTER to capture interactions between B cell receptor and any antigen. We engineer ENTER to deliver genetic payloads to antigen-specific T or B cells to selectively modulate cellular behavior in mixed populations. Single-cell readout of ENTER by RNA sequencing (ENTER-seq) enables multiplexed enumeration of antigen specificities, TCR clonality, cell type, and states of individual T cells. ENTER-seq of CMV-seropositive patient blood samples reveals the viral epitopes that drive effector memory T cell differentiation and inter-clonal vs. intra-clonal phenotypic diversity targeting the same epitope. ENTER technology enables systematic discovery of receptor specificity, linkage to cell fates, and antigen-specific cargo delivery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pan-cancer analyses reveal molecular and clinical characteristics of cuproptosis regulators</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/imt2.68/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/imt2.68/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therapeutics that discriminate between the genetic makeup of normal cells and tumour cells are valuable for treating and understanding cancer. Small molecules with oncogene-selective lethality may reveal novel functions of oncoproteins and enable the creation of more selective drugs. Here we describe the mechanism of action of the selective anti-tumour agent erastin, involving the RAS-RAF-MEK signalling pathway functioning in cell proliferation, differentiation and survival. Erastin exhibits greater lethality in human tumour cells harbouring mutations in the oncogenes HRAS, KRAS or BRAF. Using affinity purification and mass spectrometry, we discovered that erastin acts through mitochondrial voltage-dependent anion channels (VDACs)&amp;ndash;a novel target for anti-cancer drugs. We show that erastin treatment of cells harbouring oncogenic RAS causes the appearance of oxidative species and subsequent death through an oxidative, non-apoptotic mechanism. RNA-interference-mediated knockdown of VDAC2 or VDAC3 caused resistance to erastin, implicating these two VDAC isoforms in the mechanism of action of erastin. Moreover, using purified mitochondria expressing a single VDAC isoform, we found that erastin alters the permeability of the outer mitochondrial membrane. Finally, using a radiolabelled analogue and a filter-binding assay, we show that erastin binds directly to VDAC2. These results demonstrate that ligands to VDAC proteins can induce non-apoptotic cell death selectively in some tumour cells harbouring activating mutations in the RAS-RAF-MEK pathway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Monitoring of cell-cell communication and contact history in mammals</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36454848/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36454848/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Monitoring of cell-cell communication in multicellular organisms is fundamental to understanding diverse biological processes such as embryogenesis and tumorigenesis. To track cell-cell contacts in vivo, we developed an intercellular genetic technology to monitor cell-cell contact and to trace cell contact histories by permanently marking contacts between cells. In mice, we engineered an artificial Notch ligand into one cell (the sender cell) and an artificial receptor into another cell (the receiver cell). Contact between the sender and receiver cells triggered a synthetic Notch signaling that activated downstream transcriptional programs in the receiver cell, thereby transiently or permanently labeling it. In vivo cell-cell contact was observed during development, tissue homeostasis, and tumor growth. This technology may be useful for studying dynamic in vivo cell-cell contacts and cell fate plasticity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quantification of extracellular proteins, protein complexes and mRNAs in single cells by proximity sequencing</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36456784/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36456784/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We present proximity sequencing (Prox-seq) for simultaneous measurement of proteins, protein complexes and mRNAs in thousands of single cells. Prox-seq combines proximity ligation assay with single-cell sequencing to measure proteins and their complexes from all pairwise combinations of targeted proteins, providing quadratically scaled multiplexing. We validate Prox-seq and analyze a mixture of T cells and B cells to show that it accurately identifies these cell types and detects well-known protein complexes. Next, by studying human peripheral blood mononuclear cells, we discover that naïve CD8+ T cells display the protein complex CD8-CD9. Finally, we study protein interactions during Toll-like receptor (TLR) signaling in human macrophages. We observe the formation of signal-specific protein complexes, find CD36 co-receptor activity and additive signal integration under lipopolysaccharide (TLR4) and Pam2CSK4 (TLR2) stimulation, and show that quantification of protein complexes identifies signaling inputs received by macrophages. Prox-seq provides access to an untapped measurement modality for single-cell phenotyping and can discover uncharacterized protein interactions in different cell types.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interference with LTβR signaling by tick saliva facilitates transmission of Lyme disease spirochetes</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36383602/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36383602/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lyme spirochetes have coevolved with ticks to optimize transmission to hosts using tick salivary molecules (TSMs) to counteract host defenses. TSMs modulate various molecular events at the tick-host interface. Lymphotoxin-beta receptor (LTβR) is a vital immune receptor and plays protective roles in host immunity against microbial infections. We found that &lt;em&gt;Ltbr&lt;/em&gt; knockout mice were more susceptible to Lyme disease spirochetes, suggesting the involvement of LTβR signaling in tick-borne &lt;em&gt;Borrelia&lt;/em&gt; infection. Further investigation showed that a 15-kDa TSM protein from &lt;em&gt;Ixodes persulcatus&lt;/em&gt; (&lt;em&gt;I. persulcatus salivary&lt;/em&gt; protein; IpSAP) functioned as an immunosuppressant to facilitate the transmission and infection of Lyme disease spirochetes. IpSAP directly interacts with LTβR to block its activation, thus inhibiting the downstream signaling and consequently suppressing immunity. IpSAP immunization provided mice with significant protection against &lt;em&gt;I. persulcatus&lt;/em&gt;-mediated &lt;em&gt;Borrelia garinii&lt;/em&gt; infection. Notably, the immunization showed considerable cross-protection against other &lt;em&gt;Borrelia&lt;/em&gt; infections mediated by other ixodid ticks. One of the IpSAP homologs from other ixodid ticks showed similar effects on Lyme spirochete transmission. Together, our findings suggest that LTβR signaling plays an important role in blocking the transmission and pathogenesis of tick-borne Lyme disease spirochetes, and that IpSAP and its homologs are promising candidates for broad-spectrum vaccine development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NPInter v5.0: ncRNA interaction database in a new era</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36373614/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36373614/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://bigdata.ibp.ac.cn/npinter5/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;NPInter&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; documents functional interactions between noncoding RNAs (except tRNAs and rRNAs) and biomolecules (proteins, RNAs and DNAs) which are experimentally verified. By functional interactions, we mean primarily physical interactions, although several interactions of other forms also appear here. Interactions are manually collected from publication in peer-reviewed journals, followed by an annotation process against known databases including NONCODE, miRBase and UniProt. We introduce a classification of the functional interaction data, which is based on the functional interaction process the ncRNA takes part in. &lt;a href=&#34;http://bigdata.ibp.ac.cn/npinter5/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;NPInter&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; also provides an efficient search option, allowing discovery of interactions, related publications and other information. &lt;a href=&#34;http://bigdata.ibp.ac.cn/npinter5/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;NPInter&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is one of the 42 expert databases chosen by RNAcentral database.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!---more---&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Noncoding RNAs (ncRNAs) play key regulatory roles in biological processes by interacting with other biomolecules. With the development of high-throughput sequencing and experimental technologies, extensive ncRNA interactions have been accumulated. Therefore, we updated the &lt;a href=&#34;http://bigdata.ibp.ac.cn/npinter5/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;NPInter&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; database to a fifth version to document these interactions. ncRNA interaction entries were doubled from 1 100 618 to 2 596 695 by manual literature mining and high-throughput data processing. We integrated global RNA-DNA interactions from iMARGI, ChAR-seq and GRID-seq, greatly expanding the number of RNA-DNA interactions (from 888 915 to 8 329 382). In addition, we collected different types of RNA interaction between SARS-CoV-2 virus and its host from recently published studies. Long noncoding RNA (lncRNA) expression specificity in different cell types from tumor single cell RNA-seq (scRNA-seq) data were also integrated to provide a cell-type level view of interactions. A new module named RBP was built to display the interactions of RNA-binding proteins with annotations of localization, binding domains and functions. In conclusion, &lt;a href=&#34;http://bigdata.ibp.ac.cn/npinter5/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;NPInter v5.0&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; provides informative and valuable ncRNA interactions for biological researchers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spatially resolved epigenomic profiling of single cells in complex tissues</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36272405/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36272405/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Epigenomic MERFISH enables spatially resolved single-cell epigenomic profiling&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Epigenomic MERFISH maps active promoters and putative enhancers in mouse brain&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Epigenomic MERFISH reveals putative enhancer hubs in embryonic mouse brain&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Epigenomic MERFISH images show sub-nuclear distributions of epigenetic loci&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The recent development of spatial omics methods has enabled single-cell profiling of the transcriptome and 3D genome organization with high spatial resolution. Expanding the repertoire of spatial omics tools, a spatially resolved single-cell epigenomics method will accelerate understanding of the spatial regulation of cell and tissue functions. Here, we report a method for spatially resolved epigenomic profiling of single cells using in situ tagmentation and transcription followed by multiplexed imaging. We demonstrated the ability to profile histone modifications marking active promoters, putative enhancers, and silent promoters in individual cells, and generated high-resolution spatial atlas of hundreds of active promoters and putative enhancers in embryonic and adult mouse brains. Our results suggested putative promoter-enhancer pairs and enhancer hubs regulating developmentally important genes. We envision this approach will be generally applicable to spatial profiling of epigenetic modifications and DNA-binding proteins, advancing our understanding of how gene expression is spatiotemporally regulated by the epigenome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BP5 alleviates endotoxemia-induced acute lung injury by activating Nrf2 via dual regulation of the Keap1-Nrf2 interaction and the Akt (Ser473)/GSK3β (Ser9)/Fyn pathway</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36272670/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36272670/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oxidative stress and inflammation play a crucial role in the pathogenesis of acute lung injury (ALI). Previously, pentapeptide bursopentin (BP5, Cys-Lys-Arg-Val-Tyr) was reported to possess significant antioxidant activity and inhibit lipopolysaccharides (LPS)-induced NF-κB activation in vitro, whereas little is known about its effects in vivo. In this study, we explored the effects of BP5 on endotoxemia-induced ALI in mice and the underlying molecular mechanisms. Our studies revealed that BP5 markedly improved survival and effectively alleviated lung injury by reducing overoxidation and excessive inflammatory response in endotoxemia mice. In LPS-stimulated mouse primary macrophages and RAW 264.7 cells, BP5 also exhibited antioxidant and anti-inflammatory properties by enhancing Nrf2 activation. Importantly, these beneficial effects were abolished by Nrf2 knockdown. To further elucidate the underlying mechanisms, we performed localized surface plasmon resonance (LSPR) assays, molecular docking, together with cell-based studies, and found that BP5 inhibited the Keap1-Nrf2 interaction to promote Nrf2 nuclear translocation and activation. Moreover, BP5-induced Nrf2 activation was shown to be accompanied by an increase in the phosphorylation of Akt (at Ser473) and GSK3β (at Ser9), and a decrease in Fyn nuclear accumulation both in vitro and in vivo. Pharmacologically inhibiting phosphorylation of Akt and GSK3β obviously enhanced Fyn nuclear accumulation in RAW 264.7 cells, which partially attenuated the promoting effect of BP5 on Nrf2 nuclear accumulation and activation. Furthermore, In Nrf2-/- mice, the protective effects of BP5 on the endotoxemia-induced ALI in WT mice were largely vanished. Our findings indicated that BP5 effectively protected endotoxemia-induced ALI against oxidative stress and inflammatory response, which are largely dependent on activation of the Nrf2 pathway. Underlying mechanisms include dual regulation of the Keap-Nrf2 interaction and the Akt (Ser473)/GSK3β (Ser9)/Fyn pathway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RNA-Sequencing approach for exploring the therapeutic effect of umbilical cord mesenchymal stem/stromal cells on lipopolysaccharide-induced acute lung injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36341363/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36341363/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acute lung injury (ALI) is significantly associated with morbidity and mortality in patients with critical diseases. In recent years, studies have identified that mesenchymal stem/stromal cells (MSCs) ameliorate ALI and pulmonary fibrosis. However, the mechanism underlying this outcome in ALI has not yet been investigated. In this study, RNA sequencing technology was used to analyze the gene expression profile of lung tissue in lipopolysaccharide (LPS)-induced ALI rats following treatment with human umbilical cord MSC (HUCMSC). Differential expression analyses, gene ontology annotation, Kyoto Encyclopedia of Genes and Genomes enrichment, protein-protein interaction network identification, and hub gene analysis were also performed. HUCMSC treatment decreased inflammatory factor production and alveolar exudates, and attenuated lung damage in LPS-induced ALI rats. The RNA-Seq data indicated that HUCMSC treatment activated the IL-17, JAK-STAT, NF-κB, and TNF-α signaling pathways, increased oxygen transport, and decreased extracellular matrix organization. HUCMSC exert beneficial effects on ALI via these signaling pathways by reducing inflammation, inhibiting pulmonary fibrosis, and improving lung ventilation. Moreover, our study further revealed the hub genes (&lt;em&gt;Tbx2&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Nkx2-1&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Atf5&lt;/em&gt;) and signaling pathways involved in HUCMSC treatment, thus providing novel perspectives for future research into the molecular mechanisms underlying cell treatment of ALI. HUCMSC can regulate multiple genes and signaling pathways, which can prevent LPS-induced lung damage in an ALI rat model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Circ_CEA promotes the interaction between the p53 and cyclin-dependent kinases 1 as a scaffold to inhibit the apoptosis of gastric cancer</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36167685/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36167685/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Circular RNAs (circRNAs) have been reported to play essential roles in tumorigenesis and progression. This study aimed to identify dysregulated circRNAs in gastric cancer (GC) and investigate the functions and underlying mechanism of these circRNAs in GC development. Here, we identify circ_CEA, a circRNA derived from the back-splicing of CEA cell adhesion molecule 5 (CEA) gene, as a novel oncogenic driver of GC. Circ_CEA is significantly upregulated in GC tissues and cell lines. Circ_CEA knockdown suppresses GC progression, and enhances stress-induced apoptosis in vitro and in vivo. Mechanistically, circ_CEA interacts with p53 and cyclin-dependent kinases 1 (CDK1) proteins. It serves as a scaffold to enhance the association between p53 and CDK1. As a result, circ_CEA promotes CDK1-mediated p53 phosphorylation at Ser315, then decreases p53 nuclear retention and suppresses its activity, leading to the downregulation of p53 target genes associated with apoptosis. These findings suggest that circ_CEA protects GC cells from stress-induced apoptosis, via acting as a protein scaffold and interacting with p53 and CDK1 proteins. Combinational therapy of targeting circ_CEA and chemo-drug caused more cell apoptosis, decreased tumor volume and alleviated side effect induced by chemo-drug. Therefore, targeting circ_CEA might present a novel treatment strategy for GC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Identification of Lsd1-interacting non-coding RNAs as regulators of fly oogenesis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36044841/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36044841/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Lsd1-interacting non-coding RNAs&lt;/em&gt; (&lt;em&gt;LINRs&lt;/em&gt;) regulate fly egg production&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;LINRs&lt;/em&gt; are long hairpin RNAs that interact with Lsd1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;LINR-2&lt;/em&gt; regulates the differentiation of GSCs and follicle cells&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;LINR-2&lt;/em&gt; modulates the expression and function of Lsd1 in regulating oogenesis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lysine-specific demethylase 1 (Lsd1) plays a key role in balancing cell proliferation and differentiation. Lsd1 has been recently reported to associate with specific long noncoding RNAs (lncRNAs) to account for oncogenic gene expression in cancer cells. However, how lncRNA-Lsd1 interplay affects cell-specific differentiation remains elusive in vivo. Here, through Lsd1 specific RNA immunopecipitation sequencing (RIP-seq) experiments, we identify three long hairpin RNAs as &lt;em&gt;Lsd1-interacting non-coding RNAs&lt;/em&gt; (&lt;em&gt;LINRs&lt;/em&gt;) from fly ovaries. Knocking out &lt;em&gt;LINR-1&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;LINR-2&lt;/em&gt; affects fly egg production, while each of the &lt;em&gt;LINR&lt;/em&gt; deletion mutant females produce eggs with reduced hatch rate, indicating important functions of &lt;em&gt;LINRs&lt;/em&gt; in supporting oogenesis. At the cellular level, &lt;em&gt;LINR-2&lt;/em&gt; regulates the differentiation of germline stem cells and follicle progenitors likely though modulating the expression and function of &lt;em&gt;Lsd1 in vivo&lt;/em&gt;. Our identification of ovarian &lt;em&gt;LINRs&lt;/em&gt; presents a physiological example of dynamic lncRNA-Lsd1 interplay that regulates stem cell/progenitor differentiation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Circular RNA circNFKB1 promotes osteoarthritis progression through interacting with ENO1 and sustaining NF-κB signaling</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35945200/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35945200/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inflammatory cytokines-induced activation of the nuclear factor κB (NF-κB) pathway plays a critical role in the pathogenesis of osteoarthritis (OA). Circular RNA (circRNA) has been identified as important epigenetic factor in numerous diseases. However, the biological roles of inflammation-related circRNAs in regulating OA pathogenesis remain elusive. Here, we revealed circRNA expression profiles in human primary chondrocytes with interleukin-1β (IL-1β) stimulation by circRNA sequencing. We identified a highly upregulated circRNA, termed as circNFKB1 in inflamed chondrocytes and osteoarthritic cartilage. As a circRNA derived from exon 2-5 of NFKB1, circNFKB1 is located in both cytoplasm and nucleus of chondrocytes. Furthermore, knockdown of circNFKB1 inhibited extracellular matrix (ECM) catabolism and rescued IL-1β impaired ECM anabolism whereas ectopic expression of circNFKB1 significantly promoted chondrocytes degradation in vitro. Moreover, intraarticular injection of adenovirus-circNFKB1 in mouse joints triggered spontaneous cartilage loss and OA development. Mechanistically, circNFKB1 interacted with α-enolase (ENO1), regulated the expression of its parental gene NFKB1 and sustained the activation of NF-κB signaling pathway in chondrocytes. Therefore, this study highlights a novel ENO1-interacting circNFKB1 in OA pathogenesis, and provides valuable insights into understanding the regulatory mechanism of NF-κB signaling in chondrocytes and a promising therapeutic target for the treatment of OA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Energy homeostasis mediated by the LcSnRK1α-LcbZIP1/3 signaling pathway modulates litchi fruit senescence</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35634876/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35634876/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cellular energy status is a key factor deciding the switch-on of the senescence of horticultural crops. Despite the established significance of the conserved energy master regulator sucrose non-fermenting 1 (SNF1)-related protein kinase 1 (SnRK1) in plant development, its working mechanism and related signaling pathway in the regulation of fruit senescence remain enigmatic. Here, we demonstrate that energy deficit accelerates fruit senescence, whereas exogenous ATP treatment delays it. The transient suppression of &lt;em&gt;LcSnRK1α&lt;/em&gt; in litchi (&lt;em&gt;Litchi chinensis&lt;/em&gt; Sonn.) fruit inhibited the expression of energy metabolism-related genes, while its ectopic expression in tomato (&lt;em&gt;Solanum lycopersicum&lt;/em&gt;) promoted ripening and a high energy level. Biochemical analyses revealed that LcSnRK1α interacted with and phosphorylated the transcription factors LcbZIP1 and LcbZIP3, which directly bound to the promoters to activate the expression of &lt;em&gt;DARK-INDUCIBLE 10&lt;/em&gt; (&lt;em&gt;LcDIN10&lt;/em&gt;), &lt;em&gt;ASPARAGINE SYNTHASE 1&lt;/em&gt; (&lt;em&gt;LcASN1&lt;/em&gt;), and &lt;em&gt;ANTHOCYANIN SYNTHASE&lt;/em&gt; (&lt;em&gt;LcANS&lt;/em&gt;), thereby fine-tuning the metabolic reprogramming to ensure energy and redox homeostasis. Altogether, these observations reveal a post-translational modification mechanism by which &lt;em&gt;LcSnRK1α&lt;/em&gt;-mediated phosphorylation of LcbZIP1 and LcbZIP3 regulates the expression of metabolic reprogramming-related genes, consequently modulating litchi fruit senescence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An anti-influenza A virus microbial metabolite acts by degrading viral endonuclease PA</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35440123/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35440123/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The emergence of new highly pathogenic and drug-resistant influenza strains urges the development of novel therapeutics for influenza A virus (IAV). Here, we report the discovery of an anti-IAV microbial metabolite called APL-16-5 that was originally isolated from the plant endophytic fungus Aspergillus sp. CPCC 400735. APL-16-5 binds to both the E3 ligase TRIM25 and IAV polymerase subunit PA, leading to TRIM25 ubiquitination of PA and subsequent degradation of PA in the proteasome. This mode of action conforms to that of a proteolysis targeting chimera which employs the cellular ubiquitin-proteasome machinery to chemically induce the degradation of target proteins. Importantly, APL-16-5 potently inhibits IAV and protects mice from lethal IAV infection. Therefore, we have identified a natural microbial metabolite with potent in vivo anti-IAV activity and the potential of becoming a new IAV therapeutic. The antiviral mechanism of APL-16-5 opens the possibility of improving its anti-IAV potency and specificity by adjusting its affinity for TRIM25 and viral PA protein through medicinal chemistry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An oxygen-adaptive interaction between SNHG12 and occludin maintains blood-brain barrier integrity</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35417709/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35417709/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;lncRNA SNHG12 is critical for maintaining the blood-brain barrier (BBB) integrity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Oxygen levels regulate SNHG12 interaction with occludin to maintain BBB integrity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Endothelium Snhg12 knockout aggravates hypoxia-induced occludin degradation in mice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Endothelium SNHG12 overexpression alleviates hypoxia-induced BBB disruption in mice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tight junctions (TJs) of brain microvascular endothelial cells (BMECs) play a pivotal role in maintaining the blood-brain barrier (BBB) integrity; however, precise regulation of TJs stability in response to physiological and pathological stimuli remains elusive. Here, using RNA immunoprecipitation with next-generation sequencing (RIP-seq) and functional characterization, we identify SNHG12, a long non-coding RNA (lncRNA), as being critical for maintaining the BBB integrity by directly interacting with TJ protein occludin. The interaction between SNHG12 and occludin is oxygen adaptive and could block Itch (an E3 ubiquitin ligase)-mediated ubiquitination and degradation of occludin in human BMECs. Genetic ablation of endothelial Snhg12 in mice results in occludin reduction and BBB leakage and significantly aggravates hypoxia-induced BBB disruption. The detrimental effects of hypoxia on BBB could be alleviated by exogenous SNHG12 overexpression in brain endothelium. Together, we identify a direct TJ modulator lncRNA SNHG12 that is critical for the BBB integrity maintenance and oxygen adaption.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Polycarcin V induces DNA-damage response and enables the profiling of DNA-binding proteins</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36601137/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36601137/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To maintain genomic integrity and avoid diseases, the DNA-damage response (DDR) not only detects and repairs DNA lesions, but also contributes to the resistance to DNA-damaging chemotherapeutics. Targeting the DDR plays a significant role in drug discovery using the principle of synthetic lethality. The incomplete current knowledge of the DDR encouraged us to develop new strategies to identify and study its components and pathways. Polycarcin V, belonging to the C-aryl glycoside natural products, is a light-activatable DNA-intercalating agent that causes DNA damage by forming a covalent [2+2] cycloadduct with thymine residue under 365-450 nm of light irradiation in a DNA-sequence-independent manner. Taking advantage of the light-activatable feature and temporal control of DDR, we designed and synthesized polycarcin V-based bifunctional chemical probes, including one that cross-links DNA to DNA-binding protein to explore the DDR induced by polycarcin V and uncover novel DNA-protein interactions. Utilizing this chemical probe and activity-based protein profiling-stable isotope labeling with amino acids in cell culture, we identified 311 DNA-binding protein candidates, including known DDR factors and additional proteins that may be of interest in discovering new biology. We validated our approach by showing that our probe could specifically cross-link proteins involved in nucleotide excision repair (NER) that repair bulky DNA adducts. Our studies showed that the [2+2] cycloadduct formed by polycarcin V could indeed be repaired by NER in vivo. As a DNA-damaging agent, polycarcin V or its drug-like derivative plus blue light showed promising properties for psoriasis treatment, suggesting that it may itself hold promise for clinic applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Early rRNA processing is a stress-dependent regulatory event whose inhibition maintains nucleolar integrity</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34928368/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34928368/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The production of ribosomes is an energy-intensive process owing to the intricacy of these massive macromolecular machines. Each human ribosome contains 80 ribosomal proteins and four non-coding RNAs. Accurate assembly requires precise regulation of protein and RNA subunits. In response to stress, the integrated stress response (ISR) rapidly inhibits global translation. How rRNA is coordinately regulated with the rapid inhibition of ribosomal protein synthesis is not known. Here, we show that stress specifically inhibits the first step of rRNA processing. Unprocessed rRNA is stored within the nucleolus, and when stress resolves, it re-enters the ribosome biogenesis pathway. Retention of unprocessed rRNA within the nucleolus aids in the maintenance of this organelle. This response is independent of the ISR or inhibition of cellular translation but is independently regulated. Failure to coordinately control ribosomal protein translation and rRNA production results in nucleolar fragmentation. Our study unveils how the rapid translational shut-off in response to stress coordinates with rRNA synthesis production to maintain nucleolar integrity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>XDeathDB: a visualization platform for cell death molecular interactions</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34907160/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34907160/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lots of cell death initiator and effector molecules, signalling pathways and subcellular sites have been identified as key mediators in both cell death processes in cancer. The &lt;a href=&#34;https://pcm2019.shinyapps.io/XDeathDB/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;XDeathDB&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; visualization platform provides a comprehensive cell death and their crosstalk resource for deciphering the signaling network organization of interactions among different cell death modes associated with 1461 cancer types and COVID-19, with an aim to understand the molecular mechanisms of physiological cell death in disease and facilitate systems-oriented novel drug discovery in inducing cell deaths properly. Apoptosis, autosis, efferocytosis, ferroptosis, immunogenic cell death, intrinsic apoptosis, lysosomal cell death, mitotic cell death, mitochondrial permeability transition, necroptosis, parthanatos, and pyroptosis related to 12 cell deaths and their crosstalk can be observed systematically by the platform. Big data for cell death gene-disease associations, gene-cell death pathway associations, pathway-cell death mode associations, and cell death-cell death associations is collected by literature review articles and public database from iRefIndex, STRING, BioGRID, Reactom, Pathway&amp;rsquo;s commons, DisGeNET, DrugBank, and Therapeutic Target Database (TTD). An interactive webtool, &lt;a href=&#34;https://pcm2019.shinyapps.io/XDeathDB/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;XDeathDB&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, is built by web applications with R-Shiny, JavaScript (JS) and Shiny Server Iso. With this platform, users can search specific interactions from vast interdependent networks that occur in the realm of cell death. A multilayer spectral graph clustering method that performs convex layer aggregation to identify crosstalk function among cell death modes for a specific cancer. 147 hallmark genes of cell death could be observed in detail in these networks. These potential druggable targets are displayed systematically and tailoring networks to visualize specified relations is available to fulfil user-specific needs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>preMLI: a pre-trained method to uncover microRNA-lncRNA potential interactions</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34850810/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34850810/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The interaction between microribonucleic acid and long non-coding ribonucleic acid plays a very important role in biological processes, and the prediction of the one is of great significance to the study of its mechanism of action. Due to the limitations of traditional biological experiment methods, more and more computational methods are applied to this field. However, the existing methods often have problems, such as inadequate acquisition of potential features of the sequence due to simple coding and the need to manually extract features as input. We propose a deep learning model, preMLI, based on rna2vec pre-training and deep feature mining mechanism. We use rna2vec to train the ribonucleic acid (RNA) dataset and to obtain the RNA word vector representation and then mine the RNA sequence features separately and finally concatenate the two feature vectors as the input of the prediction task. The preMLI performs better than existing methods on benchmark datasets and has cross-species prediction capabilities. Experiments show that both pre-training and deep feature mining mechanisms have a positive impact on the prediction performance of the model. To be more specific, pre-training can provide more accurate word vector representations. The deep feature mining mechanism also improves the prediction performance of the model. Meanwhile, The preMLI only needs RNA sequence as the input of the model and has better cross-species prediction performance than the most advanced prediction models, which have reference value for related research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The 40 S-LARP1 complex reprograms the cellular translatome upon mTOR inhibition to preserve the protein synthetic capacity</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34818049/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34818049/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ribosomes execute the transcriptional program in every cell. Critical to sustain nearly all cellular activities, ribosome biogenesis requires the translation of ~200 factors of which 80 are ribosomal proteins (RPs). As ribosome synthesis depends on RP mRNA translation, a priority within the translatome architecture should exist to ensure the preservation of ribosome biogenesis capacity, particularly under adverse growth conditions. Here, we show that under critical metabolic constraints characterized by mTOR inhibition, LARP1 complexed with the 40S subunit protects from ribophagy the mRNAs regulon for ribosome biogenesis and protein synthesis, acutely preparing the translatome to promptly resume ribosomes production after growth conditions return permissive. Characterizing the LARP1-protected translatome revealed a set of 5′TOP transcript isoforms other than RPs involved in energy production and in mitochondrial function, among other processes, indicating that the mTOR-LARP1-5′TOP axis acts at the translational level as a primary guardian of the cellular anabolic capacity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The chemokine CCL1 triggers an AMFR-SPRY1 pathway that promotes differentiation of lung fibroblasts into myofibroblasts and drives pulmonary fibrosis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34407391/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34407391/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Erratum in:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cell.com/immunity/fulltext/S1074-7613%2821%2900394-0&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The chemokine CCL1 triggers an AMFR-SPRY1 pathway that promotes differentiation of lung fibroblasts into myofibroblasts and drives pulmonary fibrosis&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CCL1 expression positively correlates with the development of lung fibrosis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CCL1 exerts its fibrogenic activity by signaling through AMFR on fibroblasts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CCL1-AMFR interaction relieves Spry1-repressed Ras-ERK-p70S6K activity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Suppression of the CCL1-AMFR-Ras-ERK-p70S6K axis reduces lung fibrosis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recruitment of immune cells to the site of inflammation by the chemokine CCL1 is important in the pathology of inflammatory diseases. Here, we examined the role of CCL1 in pulmonary fibrosis (PF). Bronchoalveolar lavage fluid from PF mouse models contained high amounts of CCL1, as did lung biopsies from PF patients. Immunofluorescence analyses revealed that alveolar macrophages and CD4+ T cells were major producers of CCL1 and targeted deletion of Ccl1 in these cells blunted pathology. Deletion of the CCL1 receptor Ccr8 in fibroblasts limited migration, but not activation, in response to CCL1. Mass spectrometry analyses of CCL1 complexes identified AMFR as a CCL1 receptor, and deletion of Amfr impaired fibroblast activation. Mechanistically, CCL1 binding triggered ubiquitination of the ERK inhibitor Spry1 by AMFR, thus activating Ras-mediated profibrotic protein synthesis. Antibody blockade of CCL1 ameliorated PF pathology, supporting the therapeutic potential of targeting this pathway for treating fibroproliferative lung diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Encyclopedia of transcription factor</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tool/2021-08-06-en-tf/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/tool/2021-08-06-en-tf/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://services.healthtech.dtu.dk/service.php?Promoter-2.0&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Promoter2.0&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; predicts transcription start sites of vertebrate PolII promoters in DNA sequences. It has been developed as an evolution of simulated transcription factors that interact with sequences in promoter regions. i It builds on principles that are common to neural networks and genetic algorithms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://jaspar.genereg.net/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;JASPAR&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a regularly maintained open-access database storing manually curated transcription factors (TF) binding profiles as position frequency matrices (PFMs). PFMs summarize occurrences of each nucleotide at each position in a set of observed TF-DNA interactions. PFMs can be transformed to probabilistic or energistic models to construct position weight matrices (PWMs) or position-specific scoring matrices (PSSMs), which can be used to scan any DNA sequence to predict TF binding sites (TFBSs). The &lt;a href=&#34;https://jaspar.genereg.net/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;JASPAR&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; database provides TFBSs predicted using the profiles in the CORE collection.
The motifs in &lt;a href=&#34;https://jaspar.genereg.net/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;JASPAR&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; are collected in two ways:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Internally: de novo generated motifs, by analyzing ChIP-seq/-exo sequences using a custom motif discovery pipeline (check the code at our repository).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Externally: motifs taken directly from other publications and/or resources.
In both cases, the selected motifs are manually curated. Specifically, our curators assess the quality of the motif and search for an orthogonal publication providing support to the motif as the bona fide motif recognized by the TF of interest (e.g., a motif found in ChIP-seq peaks looks similar to one found by SELEX-seq). The Pubmed ID associated with the orthogonal support is provided in the TF profile metadata.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://jaspar.genereg.net/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;JASPAR&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is the only database with this scope where the data can be used with no restrictions (open source). For a comprehensive review of models and how they can be used, please see the following reviews:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/25045190/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Modeling the specificity of protein-DNA interactions Quant Biol. 2013 Jun;1(2):115-130&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/15131651/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Applied bioinformatics for the identification of regulatory elements Nat Rev Genet. 2004 Apr;5(4):276-87&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;http://motifmap.ics.uci.edu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MotifMap&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; system provides comprehensive maps of candidate regulatory elements encoded in the genomes of model species using databases of transcription factor binding motifs, refined genome alignments, and a comparative genomic statistical approach- Bayesian Branch Length Score. Users can filter the results by various criteria and export them to severals file formats or view them directly in the UCSC genome browser.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://gene-regulation.com/pub/databases.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TRANSFAC&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; provides data on eukaryotic transcription factors, their experimentally-proven binding sites, consensus binding sequences (positional weight matrices) and regulated genes. TRANSCompel contains data on eukaryotic transcription factors experimentally proven to act together in a synergistic or antagonistic manner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;http://the_brain.bwh.harvard.edu/uniprobe/index.php&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UniPROBE (Universal PBM Resource for Oligonucleotide Binding Evaluation)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; database hosts data generated by universal protein binding microarray (PBM) technology on the in vitro DNA binding specificities of proteins. This initial release of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://the_brain.bwh.harvard.edu/uniprobe/index.php&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UniPROBE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; database provides a centralized resource for accessing comprehensive data on the preferences of proteins for all possible sequence variants (&amp;lsquo;words&amp;rsquo;) of length k (&amp;lsquo;k-mers&amp;rsquo;), as well as position weight matrix (PWM) and graphical sequence logo representations of the k-mer data. In total, the database currently hosts DNA binding data for 726 nonredundant proteins and complexes from a diverse collection of organisms, including the prokaryote Vibrio harveyi, the eukaryotic malarial parasite Plasmodium falciparum, the parasitic Apicomplexan Cryptosporidium parvum, the yeast Saccharomyces cerevisiae, the worm Caenorhabditis elegans, mouse, and human. The database&amp;rsquo;s web tools (on the right) include a text-based search, a function for assessing motif similarity between user-entered data and database PWMs, and a function for locating putative binding sites along user-entered nucleotide sequences. Please click on each tool&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;help&amp;rdquo; link for more information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;http://bioinfo.wilmer.jhu.edu/PDI/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Human Protein-DNA Interactome (hPDI)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; database holds experimental protein-DNA interaction data for humans identified by protein microarray assays. The current release of &lt;a href=&#34;http://bioinfo.wilmer.jhu.edu/PDI/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;hPDI&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; contains 17,718 protein-DNA interactions for 1013 human DNA-binding proteins. These DNA-binding proteins include 493 human transcription factors (TFs) and 520 unconventional DNA binding proteins (uDBPs). Here TFs are defined as proteins either are annotated as &amp;ldquo;regulation of transcription&amp;rdquo; defined by GO database or contain known DNA binding domains defined by Pfam database and, uDBPs are defined proteins that have not been previously found to binding DNA specifically.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://v1.factorbook.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Factorbook&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a transcription factor (TF)-centric web-based repository of integrative analysis associated with ENCODE ChIP-seq data. It includes de novo discovered motifs, chromatin features surrounding ChIP-seq peaks (histone modification patterns, DNase I cleavage footprints, and nucleosome positioning profiles), deep-learned models of sequence features driving TF binding, and integration with GWAS variants and the ENCODE Registry of candidate cis-regulatory elements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://hocomoco.autosome.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HOmo sapiens COmprehensive MOdel COllection (HOCOMOCO)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; v11 provides transcription factor (TF) binding models for 680 human and 453 mouse TFs. Since v11, &lt;a href=&#34;https://hocomoco.autosome.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HOCOMOCO&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is complemented by MoLoTool, an interactive web tool to mark motif occurrences in a given set of DNA sequences. In addition to basic mononucleotide position weight matrices (PWMs), &lt;a href=&#34;https://hocomoco.autosome.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HOCOMOCO&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; provides dinucleotide position weight matrices based on ChIP-Seq data. All the models were produced by the ChIPMunk motif discovery tool. Model quality ratings are results of a comprehensive cross-validation benchmark. ChIP-Seq data for motif discovery was extracted from GTRD database of BioUML platform, that also provides an interface for motif finding (sequence scanning) with &lt;a href=&#34;https://hocomoco.autosome.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HOCOMOCO&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; models.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://meme-suite.org/meme/index.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MEME&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; discovers novel, ungapped motifs (recurring, fixed-length patterns) in your sequences (sample output from sequences). &lt;a href=&#34;https://meme-suite.org/meme/index.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MEME&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; splits variable-length patterns into two or more separate motifs. A motif is an approximate sequence pattern that occurs repeatedly in a group of related sequences. &lt;a href=&#34;https://meme-suite.org/meme/index.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MEME&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; represents motifs as position-dependent letter-probability matrices that describe the probability of each possible letter at each position in the pattern. Individual &lt;a href=&#34;https://meme-suite.org/meme/index.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MEME&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; motifs do not contain gaps. Patterns with variable-length gaps are split by &lt;a href=&#34;https://meme-suite.org/meme/index.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MEME&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; into two or more separate motifs. &lt;a href=&#34;https://meme-suite.org/meme/index.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MEME&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; takes as input a group of sequences and outputs as many motifs as requested. &lt;a href=&#34;https://meme-suite.org/meme/index.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MEME&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; uses statistical modeling techniques to automatically choose the best width, number of occurrences, and description for each motif. &lt;a href=&#34;https://meme-suite.org/meme/index.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MEME&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; on the web can take a second (control) set of input sequences and then discovers motifs that are enriched in the primary set relative to the control set. This is called discriminative motif discovery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://cistrome.org/db/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cistrome DB&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; uses the standard analysis pipeline ChiLin (1) to process all chromatin profiling reads.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Transcription factors (TFs) as key regulators could modulate the expression of target genes by binding to specific DNA sequences of their promoter(s) or enhancer(s). The spatiotemporal TF-target regulations play vital roles throughout the life course of organisms, especially for human beings. Thus, the identification of TF-target regulation in human is a basis for understanding the molecular regulatory mechanisms underlying biological processes including the development and pathogenesis. &lt;a href=&#34;http://bioinfo.life.hust.edu.cn/hTFtarget#!/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;hTFtarget&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; has curated comprehensive TF-target regulations from large-scale of ChIP-Seq data of human TFs (7,190 experiment samples of 659 TFs) in 569 conditions (399 types of cell line, 129 classes of tissues or cells, and 141 kinds of treatments). &lt;a href=&#34;http://bioinfo.life.hust.edu.cn/hTFtarget#!/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;hTFtarget&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; customized an analysis workflow to detect reliable TF-target regulations, which integrated the peak information of ChIP-Seq data with epigenomic modification status (Details in Document page). hTFtarget could help users to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Browse and investigate the target gene(s) of TF(s);&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Explore which TF(s) could regulate the query gene(s);&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Survey public ChIP-Seq samples for the query TF(s);&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;View ChIP-Seq peaks of the query TF(s) in user-defined manner;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Investigate potential co-associations between TFs in selected cell line(s);&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Inquire candidate co-regulation of TFs for the query gene(s);&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Predict binding sites of TF(s) on given sequence(s).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://alggen.lsi.upc.es/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PROMO&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a virtual laboratory for the identification of putative transcription factor binding sites (TFBS) in DNA sequences from a species or groups of species of interest. TFBS defined in the TRANSFAC database are used to construct specific binding site weight matrices for TFBS prediction. The user can inspect the result of the search through a graphical interface and downloadable text files.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;www.softberry.com&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Softberry&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, Inc. is a leading developer of software tools for genomic research focused on computational methods of high throughput biomedical data analysis, including software to support next generation sequencing technologies, transcriptome analysis (with RNASeq data), SNP detection and selection of disease specific SNP subsets. Its research-oriented programs have been used in thousand research projects. For example, fgenesh eukaryotic gene identification program is cited in more than 3000 articles, bprom, bacterial promoter prediction is cited in ~700 research papers. Just in 2015 our software applications have been used in more then 2000 research publications. Hundreds software applications developed in &lt;a href=&#34;www.softberry.com&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Softberry&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; can be executed on-line at &lt;a href=&#34;www.softberry.com&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Softberry&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; or downloaded for free academic usage. &lt;a href=&#34;www.softberry.com&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Softberry&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; started its commercial activities on May 1997 and is headquartered in Mount Kisco, NY, USA, with a satellite office in Novosibirsk, Russia. It participated in a number of academic collaborations on various research projects around the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://promirna.molgen.mpg.de/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PROmiRNA&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a program for annotating miRNA promoters in human, as well as other species. It uses deepCAGE data from the FANTOM4 Consortium and integrated cage tag counts and other promoter features, such as CpG content, conservation and TATA box affinity, to score the potential of a candidate regions to be a promoter. Given a list of genomic regions of interest, in the form of a gff file, &lt;a href=&#34;http://promirna.molgen.mpg.de/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PROmiRNA&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; returns the most probable promoter locations, together with the posterior probabilities calculated by the model. More informations on how to run &lt;a href=&#34;http://promirna.molgen.mpg.de/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PROmiRNA&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; on your regions of interest can be found in the README file inside the &lt;a href=&#34;http://promirna.molgen.mpg.de/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PROmiRNA&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; directory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/tag/databases/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Databases&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/tool/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Tools &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Identification and Characterization of Robust Hepatocellular Carcinoma Prognostic Subtypes Based on an Integrative Metabolite-Protein Interaction Network</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34247449/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34247449/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Metabolite-protein interactions (MPIs) play key roles in cancer metabolism. However, our current knowledge about MPIs in cancers remains limited due to the complexity of cancer cells. Herein, the authors construct an integrative MPI network and propose a MPI network based hepatocellular carcinoma (HCC) subtyping and mechanism exploration workflow. Based on the expressions of hub proteins on the MPI network, two prognosis-distinctive HCC subtypes are identified. Meanwhile, multiple interdependent features of the poor prognostic subtype are observed, including hypoxia, DNA hypermethylation of metabolic pathways, fatty acid accumulation, immune pathway up-regulation, and exhausted T-cell infiltration. Notably, the immune pathway up-regulation is probably induced by accumulated unsaturated fatty acids which are predicted to interact with multiple immune regulators like SRC and TGFB1. Moreover, based on tumor microenvironment compositions, the poor prognostic subtype is further divided into two sub-populations showing remarkable differences in metabolism. The subtyping shows a strong consistency across multiple HCC cohorts including early-stage HCC. Overall, the authors redefine robust HCC prognosis subtypes and identify potential MPIs linking metabolism to immune regulations, thus promoting understanding and clinical applications about HCC metabolism heterogeneity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An atlas of protein-protein interactions across mouse tissues</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34214469/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34214469/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cellular processes arise from the dynamic organization of proteins in networks of physical interactions. Mapping the interactome has therefore been a central objective of high-throughput biology. However, the dynamics of protein interactions across physiological contexts remain poorly understood. Here, we develop a quantitative proteomic approach combining protein correlation profiling with stable isotope labeling of mammals (PCP-SILAM) to map the interactomes of seven mouse tissues. The resulting maps provide a proteome-scale survey of interactome rewiring across mammalian tissues, revealing more than 125,000 unique interactions at a quality comparable to the highest-quality human screens. We identify systematic suppression of cross-talk between the evolutionarily ancient housekeeping interactome and younger, tissue-specific modules. Rewired proteins are tightly regulated by multiple cellular mechanisms and are implicated in disease. Our study opens up new avenues to uncover regulatory mechanisms that shape in vivo interactome responses to physiological and pathophysiological stimuli in mammalian systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MYC protein interactors in gene transcription and cancer</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/34188192/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/34188192/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The transcription factor and oncoprotein MYC is a potent driver of many human cancers and can regulate numerous biological activities that contribute to tumorigenesis. How a single transcription factor can regulate such a diverse set of biological programmes is central to the understanding of MYC function in cancer. In this Perspective, we highlight how multiple proteins that interact with MYC enable MYC to regulate several central control points of gene transcription. These include promoter binding, epigenetic modifications, initiation, elongation and post-transcriptional processes. Evidence shows that a combination of multiple protein interactions enables MYC to function as a potent oncoprotein, working together in a &amp;lsquo;coalition model&amp;rsquo;, as presented here. Moreover, as MYC depends on its protein interactome for function, we discuss recent research that emphasizes an unprecedented opportunity to target protein interactors to directly impede MYC oncogenesis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Global in situ profiling of RNA-RNA spatial interactions with RIC-seq</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34021296/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34021296/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To learn more about the technique, following article published in Nature may teach you a lot:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cai, Z. et al. &lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/32499643/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;RIC-seq for global in situ profiling of RNA-RNA spatial interactions&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-020-2249-1&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Nature&lt;/a&gt; 582, 432–437 (2020).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Emerging evidence has demonstrated that RNA-RNA interactions are vital in controlling diverse biological processes, including transcription, RNA splicing and protein translation. RNA in situ conformation sequencing (RIC-seq) is a technique for capturing protein-mediated RNA-RNA proximal interactions globally in living cells at single-base resolution. Cells are first treated with formaldehyde to fix all the protein-mediated RNA-RNA interactions in situ. After cell permeabilization and micrococcal nuclease digestion, the proximally interacting RNAs are 3&amp;rsquo; end-labeled with pCp-biotin and subsequently ligated using T4 RNA ligase. The chimeric RNAs are then enriched and converted into libraries for paired-end sequencing. After deep sequencing, computational analysis yields interaction strength scores for every base on proximally interacting RNAs in the starting populations. The whole experimental procedure is designed to be completed within 6 d, followed by an additional 8 d for computational analysis. RIC-seq technology can unbiasedly detect intra- and intermolecular RNA-RNA interactions, thereby rendering it useful for reconstructing RNA higher-order structures and identifying direct noncoding RNA targets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interaction of the NRF2 and p63 transcription factors promotes keratinocyte proliferation in the epidermis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33764436/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33764436/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Epigenetic regulation of cell and tissue function requires the coordinated action of transcription factors. However, their combinatorial activities during regeneration remain largely unexplored. Here, we discover an unexpected interaction between the cytoprotective transcription factor NRF2 and p63- a key player in epithelial morphogenesis. Chromatin immunoprecipitation combined with sequencing and reporter assays identifies enhancers and promoters that are simultaneously activated by NRF2 and p63 in human keratinocytes. Modeling of p63 and NRF2 binding to nucleosomal DNA suggests their chromatin-assisted interaction. Pharmacological and genetic activation of NRF2 increases NRF2-p63 binding to enhancers and promotes keratinocyte proliferation, which involves the common NRF2-p63 target cyclin-dependent kinase 12. These results unravel a collaborative function of NRF2 and p63 in the control of epidermal renewal and suggest their combined activation as a strategy to promote repair of human skin and other stratified epithelia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integrated Protein-Protein Interaction and Weighted Gene Co-expression Network Analysis Uncover Three Key Genes in Hepatoblastoma</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33718368/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33718368/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hepatoblastoma (HB) is the most common liver tumor in the pediatric population, with typically poor outcomes for advanced-stage or chemotherapy-refractory HB patients. The objective of this study was to identify genes involved in HB pathogenesis via microarray analysis and subsequent experimental validation. We identified 856 differentially expressed genes (DEGs) between HB and normal liver tissue based on two publicly available microarray datasets (GSE131329 and GSE75271) after data merging and batch effect correction. Protein-protein interaction (PPI) analysis and weighted gene co-expression network analysis (WGCNA) were conducted to explore HB-related critical modules and hub genes. Subsequently, Gene Ontology (GO) analysis was used to reveal critical biological functions in the initiation and progression of HB. Kyoto Encyclopedia of Genes and Genomes (KEGG) analysis showed that genes involved in cell cycle phase transition and the PI3K/AKT signaling were associated with HB. The intersection of hub genes identified by both PPI and WGCNA analyses revealed five potential candidate genes. Based on receiver operating characteristic (ROC) curve analysis and reports in the literature, we selected CCNA2, CDK1, and CDC20 as key genes of interest to validate experimentally. CCNA2, CDK1, or CDC20 small interfering RNA (siRNA) knockdown inhibited aggressive biological properties of both HepG2 and HuH-6 cell lines in vitro. In conclusion, we identified CCNA2, CDK1, and CDC20 as new potential therapeutic biomarkers for HB, providing novel insights into important and viable targets in future HB treatment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deciphering molecular interactions by proximity labeling</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/33432242/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/33432242/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many biological processes are executed and regulated through the molecular interactions of proteins and nucleic acids. Proximity labeling (PL) is a technology for tagging the endogenous interaction partners of specific protein ‘baits’, via genetic fusion to promiscuous enzymes that catalyze the generation of diffusible reactive species in living cells. Tagged molecules that interact with baits can then be enriched and identified by mass spectrometry or nucleic acid sequencing. Here we review the development of PL technologies and highlight studies that have applied PL to the discovery and analysis of molecular interactions. In particular, we focus on the use of PL for mapping protein–protein, protein–RNA and protein–DNA interactions in living cells and organisms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transcriptome-wide profiles of circular RNA and RNA-binding protein interactions reveal effects on circular RNA biogenesis and cancer pathway expression</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33287884/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33287884/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Circular RNAs (circRNAs) are stable, often highly expressed RNA transcripts with potential to modulate other regulatory RNAs. A few circRNAs have been shown to bind RNA-binding proteins (RBPs); however, little is known about the prevalence and distribution of these interactions in different biological contexts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; We conduct an extensive screen of circRNA-RBP interactions in the ENCODE cell lines HepG2 and K562. We profile circRNAs in deep-sequenced total RNA samples and analyze circRNA-RBP interactions using a large set of eCLIP data with binding sites of 150 RBPs. We validate interactions for select circRNAs and RBPs by performing RNA immunoprecipitation and functionally characterize our most interesting candidates by conducting knockdown studies followed by RNA-Seq.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; We generate a comprehensive catalog of circRNA-RBP interactions in HepG2 and K562 cells. We show that KHSRP binding sites are enriched in flanking introns of circRNAs and that KHSRP depletion affects circRNA biogenesis. We identify circRNAs that are highly covered by RBP binding sites and experimentally validate individual circRNA-RBP interactions. We show that circCDYL, a highly expressed circRNA with clinical and functional implications in bladder cancer, is almost completely covered with GRWD1 binding sites in HepG2 cells, and that circCDYL depletion counteracts the effect of GRWD1 depletion. Furthermore, we confirm interactions between circCDYL and RBPs in bladder cancer cells and demonstrate that circCDYL depletion affects hallmarks of cancer and perturbs the expression of key cancer genes, e.g., TP53. Finally, we show that elevated levels of circCDYL are associated with overall survival of bladder cancer patients.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; Our study demonstrates transcriptome-wide and cell-type-specific circRNA-RBP interactions that could play important regulatory roles in tumorigenesis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Online tools decoding RNA-RNA regulatory networks</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tool/2020-11-10-rri/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/tool/2020-11-10-rri/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://circinteractome.nia.nih.gov/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;CircInteractome&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; predicts the miRNAs which can potentially target the circRNAs using the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.targetscan.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Targetscan&lt;/a&gt; prediction tool. This computational tool enables the prediction and mapping of binding sites for RBPs and miRNAs on reported circRNAs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights of &lt;a href=&#34;%28https://circinteractome.nia.nih.gov/%29&#34;&gt;CircInteractome&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Searches circRNAs name&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Searches the genomic position and best-matching transcripts of the circRNA&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Retrieves genomic and mature circRNA sequences&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Searches RBPs binding to a circRNA and to sequences upstream/downstream of the circRNA&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Identifies RBPs binding to the circRNA junctions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Identifies miRNAs targeting a circRNA&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Designs divergent primers for circRNAs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Designs siRNAs Specific to circRNA&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://starbase.sysu.edu.cn/index.php&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;ENCORI (The Encyclopedia of RNA Interactomes)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is an openly licensed and state-of-the-art platform to decode the cellular interaction networks among thousands of RNA binding proteins (RBPs) and various RNAs. We have identified millions of RBP-RNA and RNA-RNA interactions through analyzing thousands of CLIP-seq and various high-throughput sequencing data by developing new software and tools, and studied their functions and mechanisms in human diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/tag/databases/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Databases&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/tool/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Tools &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A reference map of the human binary protein interactome</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32296183/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32296183/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Global insights into cellular organization and genome function require comprehensive understanding of the interactome networks that mediate genotype-phenotype relationships. Here we present a human &amp;lsquo;all-by-all&amp;rsquo; reference interactome map of human binary protein interactions, or &amp;lsquo;HuRI&amp;rsquo;. With approximately 53,000 protein-protein interactions, HuRI has approximately four times as many such interactions as there are high-quality curated interactions from small-scale studies. The integration of HuRI with genome, transcriptome and proteome data enables cellular function to be studied within most physiological or pathological cellular contexts. We demonstrate the utility of HuRI in identifying the specific subcellular roles of protein-protein interactions. Inferred tissue-specific networks reveal general principles for the formation of cellular context-specific functions and elucidate potential molecular mechanisms that might underlie tissue-specific phenotypes of Mendelian diseases. HuRI is a systematic proteome-wide reference that links genomic variation to phenotypic outcomes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How RNA-Binding Proteins Interact with RNA: Molecules and Mechanisms</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/32243832/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/32243832/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;RNA-binding proteins (RBPs) comprise a large class of over 2,000 proteins that interact with transcripts in all manner of RNA-driven processes. The structures and mechanisms that RBPs use to bind and regulate RNA are incredibly diverse. In this review, we take a look at the components of protein-RNA interaction, from the molecular level to multi-component interaction. We first summarize what is known about protein-RNA molecular interactions based on analyses of solved structures. We additionally describe software currently available for predicting protein-RNA interaction and other resources useful for the study of RBPs. We then review the structure and function of seventeen known RNA-binding domains and analyze the hydrogen bonds adopted by protein-RNA structures on a domain-by-domain basis. We conclude with a summary of the higher-level mechanisms that regulate protein-RNA interactions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Discovery of Protein-RNA Interactions</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tool/2019-10-25-pri/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/tool/2019-10-25-pri/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://s.tartaglialab.com/page/catrapid_group&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;catRAPID&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is an algorithm to estimate the binding propensity of protein-RNA pairs. By combining secondary structure, hydrogen bonding and van der Waals contributions, &lt;a href=&#34;http://s.tartaglialab.com/page/catrapid_group&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;catRAPID&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; predicts protein-RNA associations with great accuracy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://circinteractome.nia.nih.gov/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;CircInteractome&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; predicts the miRNAs which can potentially target the circRNAs using the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.targetscan.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Targetscan&lt;/a&gt; prediction tool. This computational tool enables the prediction and mapping of binding sites for RBPs and miRNAs on reported circRNAs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights of &lt;a href=&#34;%28https://circinteractome.nia.nih.gov/%29&#34;&gt;CircInteractome&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Searches circRNAs name&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Searches the genomic position and best-matching transcripts of the circRNA&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Retrieves genomic and mature circRNA sequences&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Searches RBPs binding to a circRNA and to sequences upstream/downstream of the circRNA&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Identifies RBPs binding to the circRNA junctions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Identifies miRNAs targeting a circRNA&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Designs divergent primers for circRNAs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Designs siRNAs Specific to circRNA&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://starbase.sysu.edu.cn/index.php&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;ENCORI (The Encyclopedia of RNA Interactomes)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is an openly licensed and state-of-the-art platform to decode the cellular interaction networks among thousands of RNA binding proteins (RBPs) and various RNAs. We have identified millions of RBP-RNA and RNA-RNA interactions through analyzing thousands of CLIP-seq and various high-throughput sequencing data by developing new software and tools, and studied their functions and mechanisms in human diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/tag/databases/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Databases&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/tool/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Tools &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Targeting Degradation of the Transcription Factor C/EBPβ Reduces Lung Fibrosis by Restoring Activity of the Ubiquitin-Editing Enzyme A20 in Macrophages</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/31471107/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/31471107/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although recent progress provides mechanistic insights into the pathogenesis of pulmonary fibrosis (PF), rare anti-PF therapeutics show definitive promise for treating this disease. Repeated lung epithelial injury results in injury-repairing response and inflammation, which drive the development of PF. Here, we report that chronic lung injury inactivated the ubiquitin-editing enzyme A20, causing progressive accumulation of the transcription factor C/EBPβ in alveolar macrophages (AMs) from PF patients and mice, which upregulated a number of immunosuppressive and profibrotic factors promoting PF development. In response to chronic lung injury, elevated glycogen synthase kinase-3β (GSK-3β) interacted with and phosphorylated A20 to suppress C/EBPβ degradation. Ectopic expression of A20 or pharmacological restoration of A20 activity by disturbing the A20-GSK-3β interaction accelerated C/EBPβ degradation and showed potent therapeutic efficacy against experimental PF. Our study indicates that a regulatory mechanism of the GSK-3β-A20-C/EBPβ axis in AMs may be a potential target for treating PF and fibroproliferative lung diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Explore protein-protein interaction networks with online dababases</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tool/2018-06-12-ppi/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/tool/2018-06-12-ppi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://string-db.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;STRING&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a database of known and predicted protein-protein interactions. The interactions include direct (physical) and indirect (functional) associations; they stem from computational prediction, from knowledge transfer between organisms, and from interactions aggregated from other (primary) databases. The &lt;a href=&#34;https://string-db.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;STRING&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; database currently covers 24,584,628 proteins from 5,090 organisms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/tag/databases/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Databases&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/tool/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Tools &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The harmonizome: a collection of processed datasets gathered to serve and mine knowledge about genes and proteins</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/27374120/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/27374120/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Thanks to technological advances in genomics, transcriptomics, proteomics, metabolomics, and related fields, projects that generate a large number of measurements of the properties of cells, tissues, model organisms, and patients are becoming commonplace in biomedical research. In addition, curation projects are making great progress mining biomedical literature to extract and aggregate decades worth of research findings into online databases. Such projects are generating a wealth of information that potentially can guide research toward novel biomedical discoveries and advances in healthcare. To facilitate access to and learning from biomedical Big Data, we created the &lt;a href=&#34;https://maayanlab.cloud/Harmonizome/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Harmonizome&lt;/a&gt;: a collection of information about genes and proteins from 112 datasets provided by 65 online resources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!---more---&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Genomics, epigenomics, transcriptomics, proteomics and metabolomics efforts rapidly generate a plethora of data on the activity and levels of biomolecules within mammalian cells. At the same time, curation projects that organize knowledge from the biomedical literature into online databases are expanding. Hence, there is a wealth of information about genes, proteins and their associations, with an urgent need for data integration to achieve better knowledge extraction and data reuse. For this purpose, we developed the &lt;a href=&#34;https://maayanlab.cloud/Harmonizome/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Harmonizome&lt;/a&gt;: a collection of processed datasets gathered to serve and mine knowledge about genes and proteins from over 70 major online resources. We extracted, abstracted and organized data into ∼72 million functional associations between genes/proteins and their attributes. Such attributes could be physical relationships with other biomolecules, expression in cell lines and tissues, genetic associations with knockout mouse or human phenotypes, or changes in expression after drug treatment. We stored these associations in a relational database along with rich metadata for the genes/proteins, their attributes and the original resources. The freely available &lt;a href=&#34;https://maayanlab.cloud/Harmonizome/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Harmonizome&lt;/a&gt; web portal provides a graphical user interface, a web service and a mobile app for querying, browsing and downloading all of the collected data. To demonstrate the utility of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://maayanlab.cloud/Harmonizome/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Harmonizome&lt;/a&gt;, we computed and visualized gene–gene and attribute–attribute similarity networks, and through unsupervised clustering, identified many unexpected relationships by combining pairs of datasets such as the association between kinase perturbations and disease signatures. We also applied supervised machine learning methods to predict novel substrates for kinases, endogenous ligands for G-protein coupled receptors, mouse phenotypes for knockout genes, and classified unannotated transmembrane proteins for likelihood of being ion channels. The &lt;a href=&#34;https://maayanlab.cloud/Harmonizome/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Harmonizome&lt;/a&gt; is a comprehensive resource of knowledge about genes and proteins, and as such, it enables researchers to discover novel relationships between biological entities, as well as form novel data-driven hypotheses for experimental validation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
