<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>HIF | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/hif/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/hif/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>HIF</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>HIF</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/hif/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mitochondria bridge HIF signaling and ferroptosis blockage in acute kidney injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/35387983/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/35387983/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ferroptosis, a form of regulated cell death, plays an important role in acute kidney injury (AKI). Previous studies have shown that prolyl hydroxylase domain protein (PHD) inhibitors that activate HIF signaling provide strong protection against AKI, which is characterized by marked cell death. However, the relationship between PHD inhibition/HIF signaling and ferroptosis in AKI has not been elucidated. Here, we review recent studies to explore the issue. First, we will review the literature concerning the functions of HIF in promoting mitophagy, suppressing mitochondrial respiration and modulating redox homeostasis. Second, we will describe the current understanding of ferroptosis and its role in AKI, particularly from the perspective of mitochondrial dysfunction. Finally, we will discuss the possibility that mitochondria link PHD inhibition/HIF signaling and ferroptosis in AKI. In conclusion, we propose that HIF may protect renal cells against ferroptosis in AKI by reducing mitochondrial oxidative stress and damage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Facts&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ferroptosis plays an important role in the development of AKI.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Activation of HIF signaling provides protection against AKI.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mitochondrial ROS facilitate ferroptosis in many cases.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;HIF signaling regulates multiple mitochondrial activities, including mitochondrial oxidative capacity, redox homeostasis and autophagy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Open questions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Can HIF signaling alleviate ferroptosis in AKI with different etiologies?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is mitochondrial pathway decisive for HIF-offered protection in situations like AKI, given that HIF signaling has extensive downstream effects?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Would PHD inhibitors be effective in AKI prevention and treatment clinically?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
