<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Methylation | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/methylation/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/methylation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Methylation</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Methylation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/methylation/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>NPY methylated ctDNA is a promising biomarker for treatment response monitoring in metastatic colorectal cancer</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36716292/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36716292/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Purpose Analysis of methylation markers in liquid biopsies is a promising technique for the follow-up of metastatic colorectal cancer (mCRC) patients, since they can be used in all patients, regardless of their mutational status. Therefore, we studied the value of NPY methylation analysis in circulating tumor DNA (ctDNA) for accurate response monitoring in mCRC patients in the PANIB trial. Experimental design The PANIB trial was a randomized phase two trial designed to compare FOLFOX plus panitumumab and FOLFOX plus bevacizumab in patients with RAS wild-type unresectable mCRC. The results of sequential liquid biopsies were correlated with results of imaging. Results Forty patients were included from six Belgian hospitals. Analysis of the liquid biopsies revealed that higher baseline levels of methylated ctDNA was associated with a significantly shorter overall survival (HR, 1.015; 95% CI 1.005 -1.025 and p=0.002). Furthermore, thirty-seven patients provided at least two liquid biopsies. Thirty-one of them showed a decrease in the methylation ratio after the start of therapy, which corresponded with stable disease or response on imaging at the first evaluation. When comparing the panitumumab and bevacizumab arm, significantly higher objective response and early tumor shrinkage rates were observed in the panitumumab arm (p=0.048 and p=0.015, respectively). However, due to a small study population, the trial was underpowered to detect a significant difference in survival. Conclusions The results of this study confirm that baseline methylated ctDNA is a prognostic marker and indicate that NPY methylation is a promising marker for response monitoring in patients with mCRC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>YTHDF2 orchestrates tumor-associated macrophage reprogramming and controls antitumor immunity through CD8&#43; T cells</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36658237/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36658237/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite tumor-associated macrophages (TAMs) playing a key role in shaping the tumor microenvironment (TME), the mechanisms by which TAMs influence the TME and contribute to cancer progression remain unclear. Here, we show that the N&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;-methyladenosine reader YTHDF2 regulates the antitumor functions of TAMs. YTHDF2 deficiency in TAMs suppressed tumor growth by reprogramming TAMs toward an antitumoral phenotype and increasing their antigen cross-presentation ability, which in turn enhanced CD8&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T cell-mediated antitumor immunity. YTHDF2 deficiency facilitated the reprogramming of TAMs by targeting interferon-γ-STAT1 signaling. The expression of YTHDF2 in TAMs was regulated by interleukin-10-STAT3 signaling. Selectively targeting YTHDF2 in TAMs using a Toll-like receptor 9 agonist-conjugated small interfering RNA reprogrammed TAMs toward an antitumoral phenotype, restrained tumor growth and enhanced the efficacy of PD-L1 antibody therapy. Collectively, our findings describe the role of YTHDF2 in orchestrating TAMs and suggest that YTHDF2 inhibition is an effective approach to enhance cancer immunotherapy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RNA methylation influences TDP43 binding and disease pathogenesis in models of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and frontotemporal dementia</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36634675/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36634675/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The RNA-binding protein TDP43 preferentially binds N6-methyladenosine (m6A)-modified RNA&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Post-mortem samples from ALS patients display widespread RNA hypermethylation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Methylated RNA overlaps with TDP43 pathology in ALS patient spinal cord&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reduction of the m6A reader YTHDF2 mitigates TDP43-mediated toxicity in ALS models&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;RNA methylation at adenosine N6 (m6A) is one of the most common RNA modifications, impacting RNA stability, transport, and translation. Previous studies uncovered RNA destabilization in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) models in association with accumulation of the RNA-binding protein TDP43. Here, we show that TDP43 recognizes m6A RNA and that RNA methylation is critical for both TDP43 binding and autoregulation. We also observed extensive RNA hypermethylation in ALS spinal cord, corresponding to methylated TDP43 substrates. Emphasizing the importance of m6A for TDP43 binding and function, we identified several m6A factors that enhance or suppress TDP43-mediated toxicity via single-cell CRISPR-Cas9 in primary neurons. The most promising modifier-the canonical m6A reader YTHDF2-accumulated within ALS spinal neurons, and its knockdown prolonged the survival of human neurons carrying ALS-associated mutations. Collectively, these data show that m6A modifications modulate RNA binding by TDP43 and that m6A is pivotal for TDP43-related neurodegeneration in ALS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A DNA methylation atlas of normal human cell types</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36599988/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36599988/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DNA methylation is a fundamental epigenetic mark that governs gene expression and chromatin organization, thus providing a window into cellular identity and developmental processes1. Current datasets typically include only a fraction of methylation sites and are often based either on cell lines that underwent massive changes in culture or on tissues containing unspecified mixtures of cells2-5. Here we describe a human methylome atlas, based on deep whole-genome bisulfite sequencing, allowing fragment-level analysis across thousands of unique markers for 39 cell types sorted from 205 healthy tissue samples. Replicates of the same cell type are more than 99.5% identical, demonstrating the robustness of cell identity programmes to environmental perturbation. Unsupervised clustering of the atlas recapitulates key elements of tissue ontogeny and identifies methylation patterns retained since embryonic development. Loci uniquely unmethylated in an individual cell type often reside in transcriptional enhancers and contain DNA binding sites for tissue-specific transcriptional regulators. Uniquely hypermethylated loci are rare and are enriched for CpG islands, Polycomb targets and CTCF binding sites, suggesting a new role in shaping cell-type-specific chromatin looping. The atlas provides an essential resource for study of gene regulation and disease-associated genetic variants, and a wealth of potential tissue-specific biomarkers for use in liquid biopsies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PCR Primer Design</title>
      <link>https://example.com/books/2023-01-01-primer-design-3ed/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/books/2023-01-01-primer-design-3ed/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Section A: &lt;em&gt;Primer Design for Genotyping&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chapter 1&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/uploads/34773611.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;The Significance of PCR Primer Design in Genetic Diversity Studies: Exemplified by Recent Research into the Genetic Structure of Marine Species&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chapter 2&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/uploads/34773612.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Enhancing Cohort PASA Efficiency from Lessons Assimilated by Mutant Genotyping in C. elegans&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chapter 3&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/uploads/34773613.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Design of Oligonucleotides for Allele-Specific Amplification Based on PCR and Isothermal Techniques&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chapter 4&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/uploads/34773614.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Detection of Rubella Virus by Tri-Primer RT-PCR Assay and Genotyping by Fragment RT-PCR&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chapter 5&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/uploads/34773615.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Design of Mismatch Primers to Identify and Differentiate Closely Related (Sub)Species: Application to the Authentication of Meat Products&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chapter 6&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/uploads/34773616.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Primer Design for the Analysis of Closely Related Species: Application of Noncoding mtDNA and cpDNA Sequences&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chapter 7&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/uploads/34773617.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Designing PCR Primers for the Amplification-Refractory Mutation System&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Section B: &lt;em&gt;Primer Design for Genome-Wide Identification of Specific Regions&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chapter 8&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/uploads/34773618.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Validation of Circular RNAs by PCR&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chapter 9&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/uploads/34773619.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Primer Designing for Amplifying an AT-Rich Promoter from Arabidopsis thaliana&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Section C: &lt;em&gt;Primer Design for Multiplex PCR&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chapter 10&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/uploads/34773620.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;PLASmid TAXonomic PCR (PlasTax-PCR), a Multiplex Relaxase MOB Typing to Assort Plasmids into Taxonomic Units&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chapter 11&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/uploads/34773621.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Multiplex PCR Design for Scalable Resequencing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Section D: &lt;em&gt;Primer Design for qPCR&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chapter 12&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/uploads/34773622.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Identification of Gene Copy Number in the Transgenic Plants by Quantitative Polymerase Chain Reaction (qPCR)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chapter 13&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/uploads/34773623.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;qPrimerDB: A Powerful and User-Friendly Database for qPCR Primer Design&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Section E: &lt;em&gt;Primer Design for Identification of Plant and Animal Viruses&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chapter 14&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/uploads/34773624.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;PCR Primer Design for the Rapidly Evolving SARS-CoV-2 Genome&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chapter 15&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/uploads/34773625.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Universal Primers for Detection of Novel Plant Capsid-Less Viruses: Papaya Umbra-like Viruses as Examp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Section F: &lt;em&gt;Use of Software for Primer Design&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chapter 16&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/uploads/34773626.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A Guide to Using FASTPCR Software for PCR, In Silico PCR, and Oligonucleotide Analysis&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Section G: &lt;em&gt;Primer Design for Newer PCR Approaches&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chapter 17&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/uploads/34773627.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Pyrosequencing Primer Design for Forensic Biology Applications&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chapter 18&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/uploads/34773628.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Phosphate-Methylated Oligonucleotides as a Novel Primer for PCR and RT-PCR&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/books/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Books &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>High-precision mapping reveals rare N6-deoxyadenosine methylation in the mammalian genome</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36575183/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36575183/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;N&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;-deoxyadenosine methylation (6mA) is the most widespread type of DNA modification in prokaryotes and is also abundantly distributed in some unicellular eukaryotes. However, 6mA levels are remarkably low in mammals. The lack of a precise and comprehensive mapping method has hindered more advanced investigations of 6mA. Here, we report a new method MM-seq (modification-induced mismatch sequencing) for genome-wide 6mA mapping based on a novel detection principle. We found that modified DNA bases are prone to form a local open region that allows capture by antibody, for example, via a DNA breathing or base-flipping mechanism. Specified endonuclease or exonuclease can recognize the antibody-stabilized mismatch-like structure and mark the exact modified sites for sequencing readout. Using this method, we examined the genomic positions of 6mA in bacteria (E. coli), green algae (C. reinhardtii), and mammalian cells (HEK239T, Huh7, and HeLa cells). In contrast to bacteria and green algae, human cells possess a very limited number of 6mA sites which are sporadically distributed across the genome of different cell types. After knocking out the RNA m&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;A methyltransferase METTL3 in mouse ES cells, 6mA becomes mostly diminished. Our results imply that rare 6mA in the mammalian genome is introduced by RNA m&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;A machinery via a non-targeted mechanism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SESAME-catalyzed H3T11 phosphorylation inhibits Dot1-catalyzed H3K79me3 to regulate autophagy and telomere silencing</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36473858/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36473858/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The glycolytic enzyme, pyruvate kinase Pyk1 maintains telomere heterochromatin by phosphorylating histone H3T11 (H3pT11), which promotes SIR (silent information regulator) complex binding at telomeres and prevents autophagy-mediated Sir2 degradation. However, the exact mechanism of action for H3pT11 is poorly understood. Here, we report that H3pT11 directly inhibits Dot1-catalyzed H3K79 tri-methylation (H3K79me3) and uncover how this histone crosstalk regulates autophagy and telomere silencing. Mechanistically, Pyk1-catalyzed H3pT11 directly reduces the binding of Dot1 to chromatin and inhibits Dot1-catalyzed H3K79me3, which leads to transcriptional repression of autophagy genes and reduced autophagy. Despite the antagonism between H3pT11 and H3K79me3, they work together to promote the binding of SIR complex at telomeres to maintain telomere silencing. Furthermore, we identify Reb1 as a telomere-associated factor that recruits Pyk1-containing SESAME (Serine-responsive SAM-containing Metabolic Enzyme) complex to telomere regions to phosphorylate H3T11 and prevent the invasion of H3K79me3 from euchromatin into heterochromatin to maintain telomere silencing. Together, these results uncover a histone crosstalk and provide insights into dynamic regulation of silent heterochromatin and autophagy in response to cell metabolism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Active DNA demethylation promotes cell fate specification and the DNA damage response</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36454826/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36454826/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Neurons harbor high levels of single-strand DNA breaks (SSBs) that are targeted to neuronal enhancers, but the source of this endogenous damage remains unclear. Using two systems of postmitotic lineage specification-induced pluripotent stem cell-derived neurons and transdifferentiated macrophages-we show that thymidine DNA glycosylase (TDG)-driven excision of methylcytosines oxidized with ten-eleven translocation enzymes (TET) is a source of SSBs. Although macrophage differentiation favors short-patch base excision repair to fill in single-nucleotide gaps, neurons also frequently use the long-patch subpathway. Disrupting this gap-filling process using anti-neoplastic cytosine analogs triggers a DNA damage response and neuronal cell death, which is dependent on TDG. Thus, TET-mediated active DNA demethylation promotes endogenous DNA damage, a process that normally safeguards cell identity but can also provoke neurotoxicity after anticancer treatments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aberrant methylation of Serpine1 mediates lung injury in neonatal mice prenatally exposed to intrauterine inflammation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36183130/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36183130/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Intrauterine inflammation (IUI) alters epigenetic modifications in offspring, leading to lung injury. However, the epigenetic mechanism underlying IUI-induced lung injury remains uncertain. In the present study, we aim to investigate the effect of IUI on lung development, and to identify the key molecule involved in this process and its epigenetic regulatory mechanism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; Serpine1 was upregulated in the lung tissue of neonatal mice with IUI. Intranasal delivery of Serpine1 siRNA markedly reversed IUI-induced lung injury. Serpine1 overexpression substantially promoted cell senescence of both human and murine lung epithelial cells, reflected by decreased cell proliferation and increased senescence-associated β-galactosidase activity, G0/G1 cell fraction, senescence marker, and oxidative and DNA damage marker expression. IUI decreased the methylation level of the Serpine1 promoter, and methylation of the promoter led to transcriptional repression of Serpine1. Furthermore, IUI promoted the expression of Tet1 potentially through TNF-α, while Tet1 facilitated the demethylation of Serpine1 promoter. DNA pull-down and ChIP assays revealed that the Serpine1 promoter was regulated by Rela and Hdac2. DNA demethylation increased the recruitment of Rela to the Serpine1 promoter and induced the release of Hdac2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/em&gt; Increased Serpine1 expression mediated by DNA demethylation causes lung injury in neonatal mice with IUI. Therefore, therapeutic interventions targeting Serpine1 may effectively prevent IUI-induced lung injury.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Structural basis for product specificities of MLL family methyltransferases</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36108631/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36108631/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Human mixed-lineage leukemia (MLL) family methyltransferases methylate histone H3 lysine 4 to different methylation states (me1/me2/me3) with distinct functional outputs, but the mechanism underlying the different product specificities of MLL proteins remains unclear. Here, we develop methodologies to quantitatively measure the methylation rate difference between mono-, di-, and tri-methylation steps and demonstrate that MLL proteins possess distinct product specificities in the context of the minimum MLL-RBBP5-ASH2L complex. Comparative structural analyses of MLL complexes by X-ray crystal structures, fluorine-19 nuclear magnetic resonance, and molecular dynamics simulations reveal that the dynamics of two conserved tyrosine residues at the &amp;ldquo;F/Y (phenylalanine/tyrosine) switch&amp;rdquo; positions fine-tune the product specificity. The variation in the intramolecular interaction between SET-N and SET-C affects the F/Y switch dynamics, thus determining the product specificities of MLL proteins. These results indicate a modified F/Y switch rule applicable for most SET domain methyltransferases and implicate the functional divergence of MLL proteins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ALKBH5-mediated m6A modification of circCCDC134 facilitates cervical cancer metastasis by enhancing HIF1A transcription</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36028854/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36028854/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Metastasis is the main cause of mortality in cervical cancer (CC). Circular RNAs (circRNAs) have been demonstrated to play a crucial role in carcinoma biology. However, the expression and function of circRNAs in cervical cancer metastasis are still unclear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; In the present study, we identified a circRNA with an N6-methyladenosine (m6A) modification, circCCDC134, whose expression was increased in CC tissues by circRNA-Seq and qPCR. CircCCDC134 upregulation in CC was fine-tuned by ALKBH5-mediated m6A modification, which enhanced its stability in a YTHDF2-dependent manner. The functional experiments illustrated that circCCDC134 enhanced tumour proliferation and metastasis in vitro and in vivo. For the comprehensive identification of RNA-binding proteins, circRNA pull-down and mass spectrometry (ChIRP-MS), chromatin immunoprecipitation-seq (Chip-seq), RNA binding protein immunoprecipitation (RIP) and luciferase reporter assays were used to perform mechanistic investigations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; The results revealed that circCCDC134 recruited p65 in the nucleus and acted as a miR-503-5p sponge to regulate the expression of MYB in the cytoplasm, ultimately stimulating HIF1A transcription and facilitating CC growth and metastasis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/em&gt; These findings indicate that circCCDC134 is an important therapeutic target and provide new regulatory model insights for exploring the carcinogenic mechanism of circCCDC134 in CC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>METTL3 potentiates progression of cervical cancer by suppressing ER stress via regulating m6A modification of TXNDC5 mRNA</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35987795/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35987795/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;N6-methyladenosine (m&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;A) is the most abundant chemical modification on mRNA and plays significant roles in many bioprocesses. However, the functions of m&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;A on cervical cancer (CC) tumorigenesis remain unclear. Here we found methyltransferase-like 3 (METTL3), a core member of the m&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;A methyltransferase family, was greatly upregulated as an independent prognostic factor in CC. Mechanistically, the transcription factor ETS1 recruited P300 and WDR5 which separately mediated H3K27ac and H3K4me3 histone modification in the promoter of METTL3 and induced METTL3 transcription activation. Furthermore, we identified TXNDC5 as a target of METTL3-mediated m&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;A modification through MeRIP-seq, and revealed that METTL3-mediated TXNDC5 expression relied on the m&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;A reader-dependent manner. Functionally, we verified that METTL3 promoted proliferation and metastasis of CC cells by regulating of TXNDC5 expression through in vitro and in vivo experiments. In addition, our study verified the effect of METTL3/TXNDC5 axis on ER stress. Taken together, METTL3 facilitates the malignant progression of CC, suggesting that METTL3 might be a potential prognostic biomarker and therapeutic target for CC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ZNF354C Mediated by DNMT1 Ameliorates Lung Ischemia-Reperfusion Oxidative Stress Injury by Reducing TFPI Promoter Methylation to Upregulate TFPI</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35915612/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35915612/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Pulmonary ischemia reperfusion- (I/R-) induced dysfunction is a significant clinical problem after lung transplantation. In this study, we aim to explore the molecular mechanism of lung I/R injury (LIRI).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; Bioinformatic analysis of gene involved in oxidative stress. A HUVEC oxygen glucose deprivation/reoxygenation (OGD/R) model and I/R mouse model were first established via I/R. The cellular proliferation, migration, reactive oxygen species (ROS), and parameters of lung injury were assessed via CCK-8, EdU staining, Transwell, cellular ROS kit, and H&amp;amp;E staining. We also confirmed related gene expressions and protein levels and the interaction between the tissue factor pathway inhibitor (TFPI) promotor and ZNF354C.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; Bioinformatic analysis results showed TFPI contributed to oxidative stress. OGD/R caused a reduction in cell viability and migration, hypermethylation of TFPI, increased ROS, and downregulation of ZNF354C, TFPI, and DNA methyltransferases (DNMTs) in HUVECs. Besides, ZNF354C could directly bind to the TFPI promoter, enhance proliferation and migration, and inhibit ROS in OGD/R-induced HUVECs by upregulating TFPI. More importantly, we discovered that 5-Aza could reduce TFPI methylation, upregulate TFPI, and enhance the binding of ZNF354C to the TFPI promoter in LIRI. Furthermore, DNMT1 silencing could induce proliferation and migration and prevent ROS in OGD/R-induced HUVECs by upregulating ZNF354C. Additionally, we verified that ZNF354C could alleviate LIRI by preventing DNA methylation &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; ZNF354C overexpression induced proliferation and migration, as well as suppressed ROS in OGD/R-induced HUVECs, and alleviated LIRI in mice by inhibiting TFPI promoter methylation to upregulate TFPI. Therefore, ZNF354C and TFPI methylation might be promising molecular markers for LIRI therapy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SHF Acts as a Novel Tumor Suppressor in Glioblastoma Multiforme by Disrupting STAT3 Dimerization</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35843865/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35843865/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sustained activation of signal transducer and activator of transcription 3 (STAT3) is a critical contributor in tumorigenesis and chemoresistance, thus making it an attractive cancer therapeutic target. Here, SH2 domain-containing adapter protein F (SHF) is identified as a tumor suppressor in glioblastoma Multiforme (GBM) and its negative regulation of STAT3 activity is characterized. Mechanically, SHF selectively binds and inhibits acetylated STAT3 dimerization without affecting STAT3 phosphorylation or acetylation. Additionally, by blocking STAT3-DNMT1 (DNA Methyltransferase 1) interaction, SHF relieves methylation of tumor suppressor genes. The SH2 domain is documented to be essential for SHF&amp;rsquo;s actions on STAT3, and almost entirely replaces the functions of SHF on STAT3 independently. Moreover, the peptide C16 a peptide derived from the STAT3-binding sites of SHF inhibits STAT3 dimerization and STAT3/DNMT1 interaction, and achieves remarkable growth inhibition in GBM cells in vitro and in vivo. These findings strongly identify targeting of the SHF/STAT3 interaction as a promising strategy for developing an optimal STAT3 inhibitor and provide early evidence of the potential clinical efficacy of STAT3 inhibitors such as C16 in GBM.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OCT4 activates a Suv39h1-repressive antisense lncRNA to couple histone H3 Lysine 9 methylation to pluripotency</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35762231/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35762231/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Histone H3 Lysine 9 (H3K9) methylation, a characteristic mark of heterochromatin, is progressively implemented during development to contribute to cell fate restriction as differentiation proceeds. Accordingly, in undifferentiated and pluripotent mouse Embryonic Stem (ES) cells the global levels of H3K9 methylation are rather low and increase only upon differentiation. How global H3K9 methylation levels are coupled with the loss of pluripotency remains largely unknown. Here, we identify SUV39H1, a major H3K9 di- and tri-methylase, as an indirect target of the pluripotency network of Transcription Factors (TFs). We find that pluripotency TFs, principally OCT4, activate the expression of Suv39h1as, an antisense long non-coding RNA to Suv39h1. In turn, Suv39h1as downregulates Suv39h1 transcription in cis via a mechanism involving the modulation of the chromatin status of the locus. The targeted deletion of the Suv39h1as promoter region triggers increased SUV39H1 expression and H3K9me2 and H3K9me3 levels, affecting all heterochromatic regions, particularly peri-centromeric major satellites and retrotransposons. This increase in heterochromatinization efficiency leads to accelerated and more efficient commitment into differentiation. We report, therefore, a simple genetic circuitry coupling the genetic control of pluripotency with the global efficiency of H3K9 methylation associated with a major cell fate restriction, the irreversible loss of pluripotency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TWIST1 methylation by SETD6 selectively antagonizes LINC-PINT expression in glioma</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35694846/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35694846/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gliomas are one of the most common and lethal brain tumors among adults. One process that contributes to glioma progression and recurrence is the epithelial to mesenchymal transition (EMT). EMT is regulated by a set of defined transcription factors which tightly regulate this process, among them is the basic helix-loop-helix family member, TWIST1. Here we show that TWIST1 is methylated on lysine-33 at chromatin by SETD6, a methyltransferase with expression levels correlating with poor survival in glioma patients. RNA-seq analysis in U251 glioma cells suggested that both SETD6 and TWIST1 regulate cell adhesion and migration processes. We further show that TWIST1 methylation attenuates the expression of the long-non-coding RNA, LINC-PINT, thereby promoting EMT in glioma. Mechanistically, TWIST1 methylation represses the transcription of LINC-PINT by increasing the occupancy of EZH2 and the catalysis of the repressive H3K27me3 mark at the LINC-PINT locus. Under un-methylated conditions, TWIST1 dissociates from the LINC-PINT locus, allowing the expression of LINC-PINT which leads to increased cell adhesion and decreased cell migration. Together, our findings unravel a new mechanistic dimension for selective expression of LINC-PINT mediated by TWIST1 methylation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neutrophil extracellular traps mediate m6A modification and regulates sepsis-associated acute lung injury by activating ferroptosis in alveolar epithelial cells</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35637949/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35637949/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Neutrophil extracellular traps (NETs) production is a major strategy employed by polymorphonuclear neutrophils (PMNs) to fight against microbes. NETs have been implicated in the pathogenesis of various lung injuries, although few studies have explored NETs in sepsis-associated acute lung injury (SI-ALI). Here, we demonstrate a major contribution of NETs to the pathology of sepsis-associated ALI by inducing ferroptosis of alveolar epithelial cells. Using both &lt;em&gt;in vitro&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt; studies, our findings show enhanced NETs accumulation in sepsis-associated ALI patients and mice, as well as the closely related upregulation of ferroptosis, the induction of which depends on METTL3-induced m&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;A modification of GPX4. Using a CLP-induced sepsis-associated ALI mouse model established with &lt;em&gt;METTL3&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; versus WT mice, in addition to METTL3 knockout and overexpression in vitro, we elucidated and confirmed the critical role of ferroptosis in NETs-induced ALI. These findings support a role for NETs-induced METTL3 modification and the subsequent induction of ferroptosis in the pathogenesis of sepsis-associated ALI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The N6-methyladenosine modification enhances ferroptosis resistance through inhibiting SLC7A11 mRNA deadenylation in hepatoblastoma</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35522946/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35522946/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Solute carrier family 7 member 11 (SLC7A11) is overexpressed in multiple human tumours and functions as a transporter importing cystine for glutathione biosynthesis. It promotes tumour development in part by suppressing ferroptosis, a newly identified form of cell death that plays a pivotal role in the suppression of tumorigenesis. However, the role and underlying mechanisms of SLC7A11-mediated ferroptosis in hepatoblastoma (HB) remain largely unknown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; Reverse transcription quantitative real-time PCR (RT-qPCR) and western blotting were used to measure SLC7A11 levels. Cell proliferation, colony formation, lipid reactive oxygen species (ROS), MDA concentration, 4-HNE, GSH/GSSG ratio and cell death assays as well as subcutaneous xenograft experiments were used to elucidate the effects of SLC7A11 in HB cell proliferation and ferroptosis. Furthermore, MeRIP-qPCR, dual luciferase reporter, RNA pulldown, RNA immunoprecipitation (RIP) and RACE-PAT assays were performed to elucidate the underlying mechanism through which SLC7A11 was regulated by the m6A modification in HB.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; SLC7A11 expression was highly upregulated in HB. SLC7A11 upregulation promoted HB cell proliferation in vitro and in vivo, inhibiting HB cell ferroptosis. Mechanistically, SLC7A11 mRNA exhibited abnormal METTL3-mediated m6A modification, which enhanced its stability and expression. IGF2 mRNA-binding protein 1 (IGF2BP1) was identified as the m6A reader of SLC7A11, enhancing &lt;em&gt;SLC7A11&lt;/em&gt; mRNA stability and expression by inhibiting &lt;em&gt;SLC7A11&lt;/em&gt; mRNA deadenylation in an m6A-dependent manner. Moreover, IGF2BP1 was found to block BTG2/CCR4-NOT complex recruitment via competitively binding to PABPC1, thereby suppressing &lt;em&gt;SLC7A11&lt;/em&gt; mRNA deadenylation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; Our findings demonstrated that the METTL3-mediated SLC7A11 m6A modification enhances HB ferroptosis resistance. The METTL3/IGF2BP1/m6A modification promotes &lt;em&gt;SLC7A11&lt;/em&gt; mRNA stability and upregulates its expression by inhibiting the deadenylation process. Our study highlights a critical role of the m6A modification in SLC7A11-mediated ferroptosis, providing a potential strategy for HB therapy through blockade of the m6A-SLC7A11 axis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Targeting SMYD2 inhibits angiogenesis and increases the efficiency of apatinib by suppressing EGFL7 in colorectal cancer</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35503397/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35503397/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Angiogenesis is an essential factor affecting the occurrence and development of solid tumors. SET And MYND Domain Containing 2 (SMYD2) serves as an oncogene in various cancers. However, whether SMYD2 is involved in tumor angiogenesis remains unclear. Here, we report that SMYD2 expression is associated with microvessel density in colorectal cancer (CRC) tissues. SMYD2 promotes CRC angiogenesis in vitro and in vivo. Mechanistically, SMYD2 physically interacts with HNRNPK and mediates lysine monomethylation at K422 of HNRNPK, which substantially increases RNA binding activity. HNRNPK acts by binding and stabilizing EGFL7 mRNA. As an angiogenic stimulant, EGFL7 enhances CRC angiogenesis. H3K4me3 maintained by PHF8 mediates the abnormal overexpression of SMYD2 in CRC. Moreover, targeting SMYD2 blocks CRC angiogenesis in tumor xenografts. Treatment with BAY-598, a functional inhibitor of SMYD2, can also synergize with apatinib in patient-derived xenografts. Overall, our findings reveal a new regulatory axis of CRC angiogenesis and provide a potential strategy for antiangiogenic therapy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dynamic N6-methyladenosine modification of lncRNA modulated by METTL3 during bacterial disease development in an echinoderm</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35483599/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35483599/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Long non-coding RNAs (lncRNAs) are novel functional non-coding RNAs which engaged in many aspects of biological processes. N6-methyladenosine (m6A) as a kind of abundant epitranscriptomic modification in eukaryotes, plays important roles in regulation of gene expression for various physiological functions. Our previous study demonstrated that sea cucumber lncRNAs were differentially expressed during bacterial infection. However, whether the post-transcriptional regulation of lncRNAs influenced by m6A modification in sea cucumbers with different stages of skin ulceration syndrome (SUS) are largely unknown. Here, we generated the genome-wide map of m6A lncRNAs in SUS-diseased and SUS-resistant sea cucumbers for the first time, revealed that m6A levels in lncRNAs were mainly upregulated in SUS-resistant group. Intriguingly, most of the m6A lncRNAs showed a positive correlation between the expression levels and m6A levels based on conjoint analysis, suggesting that m6A modification on a lncRNA may contribute to its RNA stability. Furthermore, the host genes of lncRNAs with dysregulated m6A peaks were enriched in immune pathway. More importantly, methyltransferase METTL3 was required for m6A methylation modification and played positive roles in lncRNA expression. Collectively, this study presents the comprehensive characters of m6A lncRNAs in marine invertebrate. These m6A modified lncRNAs may be served as potential regulators associated with SUS and provide a promising avenue for disease therapy through targeting METTL3.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Universal lung epithelium DNA methylation markers for detection of lung damage in liquid biopsies</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35450968/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35450968/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Circulating biomarkers for lung damage are lacking. Lung epithelium-specific DNA methylation patterns can potentially report the presence of lung-derived cell-free DNA (cfDNA) in blood, as an indication of lung cell death.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; We sorted human lung alveolar and bronchial epithelial cells from surgical specimens, and obtained their methylomes using whole-genome bisulfite sequencing. We developed a PCR sequencing assay determining the methylation status of 17 loci with lung-specific methylation patterns, and used it to assess lung-derived cfDNA in the plasma of healthy volunteers and patients with lung disease.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; Loci that are uniquely unmethylated in alveolar or bronchial epithelial cells are enriched for enhancers controlling lung-specific genes. Methylation markers extracted from these methylomes revealed that normal lung cell turnover probably releases cfDNA into the air spaces, rather than to blood. People with advanced lung cancer show a massive elevation of lung cfDNA concentration in blood. Among individuals undergoing bronchoscopy, lung-derived cfDNA is observed in the plasma of those later diagnosed with lung cancer, and to a lesser extent in those diagnosed with other lung diseases. Lung cfDNA is also elevated in patients with acute exacerbation of COPD compared with patients with stable disease, and is associated with future exacerbation and mortality in these patients.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; Universal cfDNA methylation markers of normal lung epithelium allow for mutation-independent, sensitive and specific detection of lung-derived cfDNA, reporting on ongoing lung injury. Such markers can find broad utility in the study of normal and pathologic human lung dynamics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>KMT2C deficiency promotes small cell lung cancer metastasis through DNMT3A-mediated epigenetic reprogramming</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35449309/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35449309/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Small cell lung cancer (SCLC) is notorious for its early and frequent metastases, which contribute to it as a recalcitrant malignancy. To understand the molecular mechanisms underlying SCLC metastasis, we generated SCLC mouse models with orthotopically transplanted genome-edited lung organoids and performed multiomics analyses. We found that a deficiency of KMT2C, a histone H3 lysine 4 methyltransferase frequently mutated in extensive-stage SCLC, promoted multiple-organ metastases in mice. Metastatic and KMT2C-deficient SCLC displayed both histone and DNA hypomethylation. Mechanistically, KMT2C directly regulated the expression of DNMT3A, a de novo DNA methyltransferase, through histone methylation. Forced DNMT3A expression restrained metastasis of KMT2C-deficient SCLC through repressing metastasis-promoting MEIS/HOX genes. Further, S-(5′-adenosyl)-L-methionine, the common cofactor of histone and DNA methyltransferases, inhibited SCLC metastasis. Thus, our study revealed a concerted epigenetic reprogramming of KMT2C- and DNMT3A-mediated histone and DNA hypomethylation underlying SCLC metastasis, which suggested a potential epigenetic therapeutic vulnerability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inhibition of METTL3 attenuates renal injury and inflammation by alleviating TAB3 m6A modifications via IGF2BP2-dependent mechanisms</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35417191/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35417191/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The role of N&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;-methyladenosine (m6A) modifications in renal diseases is largely unknown. Here, we characterized the role of N&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;-adenosine-methyltransferase-like 3 (METTL3), whose expression is elevated in renal tubules in different acute kidney injury (AKI) models as well as in human biopsies and cultured tubular epithelial cells (TECs). &lt;em&gt;METTL3&lt;/em&gt; silencing alleviated renal inflammation and programmed cell death in TECs in response to stimulation by tumor necrosis factor-α (TNF-α), cisplatin, and lipopolysaccharide (LPS), whereas METTL3 overexpression had the opposite effects. Conditional knockout of &lt;em&gt;METTL3&lt;/em&gt; from mouse kidneys attenuated cisplatin- and ischemic/reperfusion (I/R)-induced renal dysfunction, injury, and inflammation. Moreover, &lt;em&gt;TAB3&lt;/em&gt; [TGF-β-activated kinase 1 (MAP3K7) binding protein 3] was identified as a target of METTL3 by m6A methylated RNA immunoprecipitation sequencing and RNA sequencing. The stability of TAB3 was increased through binding of IGF2BP2 (insulin-like growth factor 2 binding protein 2) to its m6A-modified stop codon regions. The proinflammatory effects of TAB3 were then explored both &lt;em&gt;in vitro&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt;. Adeno-associated virus 9 (AAV9)-mediated &lt;em&gt;METTL3&lt;/em&gt; silencing attenuated renal injury and inflammation in cisplatin- and LPS-induced AKI mouse models. We further identified Cpd-564 as a METTL3 inhibitor that had better protective effects against cisplatin- and ischemia/reperfusion-induced renal injury and inflammation than S-adenosyl-l-homocysteine, a previously identified METTL3 inhibitor. Collectively, METTL3 promoted m6A modifications of TAB3 and enhanced its stability via IGF2BP2-dependent mechanisms. Both genetic and pharmacological inhibition of METTL3 attenuated renal injury and inflammation, suggesting that the METTL3/TAB3 axis is a potential target for treatment of AKI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lupus enhancer risk variant causes dysregulation of IRF8 through cooperative lncRNA and DNA methylation machinery</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35388006/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35388006/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite strong evidence that human genetic variants affect the expression of many key transcription factors involved in autoimmune diseases, establishing biological links between non-coding risk variants and the gene targets they regulate remains a considerable challenge. Here, we combine genetic, epigenomic, and CRISPR activation approaches to screen for functional variants that regulate IRF8 expression. We demonstrate that the locus containing rs2280381 is a cell-type-specific enhancer for IRF8 that spatially interacts with the IRF8 promoter. Further, rs2280381 mediates IRF8 expression through enhancer RNA AC092723.1, which recruits TET1 to the IRF8 promoter regulating IRF8 expression by affecting methylation levels. The alleles of rs2280381 modulate PU.1 binding and chromatin state to regulate AC092723.1 and IRF8 expression differentially. Our work illustrates an integrative strategy to define functional genetic variants that regulate the expression of critical genes in autoimmune diseases and decipher the mechanisms underlying the dysregulation of IRF8 expression mediated by lupus risk variants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Epigenetic regulation of EIF4A1 through DNA methylation and an oncogenic role of eIF4A1 through BRD2 signaling in prostate cancer</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35361883/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35361883/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In prostate cancers, elongation initiation factor 4A1 (eIF4A1) supports an oncogenic translation program and is highly expressed, but its role remains elusive. By the use of human specimens and cell models, we addressed the role of eIF4A1 in prostate cancer &lt;em&gt;in vitro&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;em&gt;EIF4A1&lt;/em&gt; expression, as determined by mRNA and protein levels, was higher in primary prostate cancers relative to normal prostate tissue. Also, for primary prostate cancers, elevated mRNA levels of &lt;em&gt;EIF4A1&lt;/em&gt; correlated with DNA hypomethylation levels in the CpG-rich island of &lt;em&gt;EIF4A1&lt;/em&gt;. Using a DNMT3a CRISPR-Cas9-based tool for specific targeting of DNA methylation, we characterized, in human prostate cancer cells, the epigenetic regulation of &lt;em&gt;EIF4A1&lt;/em&gt; transcripts through DNA methylation in the CpG-rich island of &lt;em&gt;EIF4A1&lt;/em&gt;. Next, we investigated the oncogenic effect of &lt;em&gt;EIF4A1&lt;/em&gt; on cancer cell proliferation &lt;em&gt;in vitro&lt;/em&gt; and tumor growth &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt;. For prostate cancer cells, &lt;em&gt;EIF4A1&lt;/em&gt; heterozygous knockout or knockdown inhibited protein translation and tumor growth. In addition, using RNA immunoprecipitation with RNA sequencing, we discovered the eIF4A1-mediated translational regulation of the oncogene &lt;em&gt;BRD2&lt;/em&gt;, which contains the most enriched eIF4A1-binding motifs in its 5&amp;rsquo; untranslated region, establishing an eIF4A1-BRD2 axis for oncogenic translation. Finally, we found a positive correlation between expression levels of &lt;em&gt;eIF4A1&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;BRD2&lt;/em&gt; in primary prostate cancers. Our results demonstrate, for prostate cancer cells, epigenetic regulation of &lt;em&gt;EIF4A1&lt;/em&gt; transcripts through DNA methylation and an oncogenic role of eIF4A1 through BRD2 signaling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Epigenetic regulation of CXCR4 signaling in cancer pathogenesis and progression</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/35346802/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/35346802/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Signaling involving chemokine receptor CXCR4 and its ligand SDF-1/CXL12 has been investigated for many years for its possible role in cancer progression and pathogenesis. Evidence emerging from clinical studies in recent years has further established diagnostic as well as prognostic importance of CXCR4 signaling. CXCR4 and SDF-1 are routinely reported to be elevated in tumors, distant metastases, which correlates with poor survival of patients. These findings have kindled interest in the mechanisms that regulate CXCR4/SDF-1 expression. Of note, there is a particular interest in the epigenetic regulation of CXCR4 signaling that may be responsible for upregulated CXCR4 in primary as well as metastatic cancers. This review first lists the clinical evidence supporting CXCR4 signaling as putative cancer diagnostic and/or prognostic biomarker, followed by a discussion on reported epigenetic mechanisms that affect CXCR4 expression. These mechanisms include regulation by non-coding RNAs, such as, microRNAs, long non-coding RNAs and circular RNAs. Additionally, we also discuss the regulation of CXCR4 expression through methylation and acetylation. Better understanding and appreciation of epigenetic regulation of CXCR4 signaling can invariably lead to identification of novel therapeutic targets as well as therapies to regulate this oncogenic signaling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>m6A mRNA modification maintains colonic epithelial cell homeostasis via NF-κB-mediated antiapoptotic pathway</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35333576/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35333576/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Colonic mucosal barrier dysfunction is one of the major causes of inflammatory bowel disease (IBD). However, the mechanisms underlying mucosal barrier dysfunction are poorly understood. N6-methyladenosine (m6A) mRNA modification is an important modulator of epitranscriptional regulation of gene expression, participating in multiple physiological and pathological processes. However, the function of m6A modification in colonic epithelial cells and stem cells is unknown. Here, we show that m6A modification is essential for maintaining the homeostatic self-renewal in colonic stem cells. Specific deletion of the methyltransferase 14 (Mettl14) gene in mouse colon resulted in colonic stem cell apoptosis, causing mucosal barrier dysfunction and severe colitis. Mechanistically, we revealed that Mettl14 restricted colonic epithelial cell death by regulating the stability of Nfkbia mRNA and modulating the NF-κB pathway. Our results identified a previously unidentified role for m6A modification in colonic epithelial cells and stem cells, suggesting that m6A modification may be a potential therapeutic target for IBD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Detection of recurrent colorectal cancer with high specificity using a reporting threshold for circulating tumor DNA methylated in BCAT1 and IKZF1</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35290664/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35290664/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; A blood assay measuring methylated BCAT1 and IKZF1 can detect recurrent colorectal cancer (CRC) with high sensitivity but suboptimal specificity. This study aimed to establish an upper reference limit (URL) of these biomarkers in a reference population without CRC, apply that threshold to detecting clinical recurrence in patients who had undergone definitive therapy for CRC, and compare the performance of the biomarkers with carcinoembryonic antigen (CEA).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; The level of methylation was reported as the aggregate methylated BCAT1 and IKZF1 expressed as a percentage of total plasma DNA. A reference population of patients confirmed to have no colorectal neoplasia (n = 857) was used to determine the URL. Test accuracy for clinical recurrence was determined in a post-treatment surveillance population (n = 549; 77 recurrence cases).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; A methylation level of 0.07%, corresponding to the 98th percentile in the reference population, was set as the URL. In the surveillance population, 60 patients had methylation levels above 0.07%, and 81.7% of these had recurrence. In comparison with no minimum threshold being applied, assay sensitivity with a URL of 0.07% yielded similar sensitivity (63.6% [CI, 51.9%-74.3%] vs 64.9% [CI, 53.8%-74.7%]; &lt;em&gt;P&lt;/em&gt; = .87) and higher specificity (97.7% [CI, 95.9%-98.8%] vs 91.3% [CI, 88.4%-93.5%]; &lt;em&gt;P&lt;/em&gt; &amp;lt; .001). The BCAT1/IKZF1 test was 2.5-fold more sensitive than CEA for detecting recurrences considered amenable to surgery with curative intent (50.0% vs 20.8%; &lt;em&gt;P&lt;/em&gt; = .016).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; Applying a threshold for positivity to the methylated BCAT1/IKZF1 blood assay improved the specificity for CRC recurrence without compromising sensitivity. Both the sensitivity and the specificity were superior to those of CEA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The arginine methyltransferase PRMT7 promotes extravasation of monocytes resulting in tissue injury in COPD</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35288557/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35288557/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Extravasation of monocytes into tissue and to the site of injury is a fundamental immunological process, which requires rapid responses via post translational modifications (PTM) of proteins. Protein arginine methyltransferase 7 (PRMT7) is an epigenetic factor that has the capacity to mono-methylate histones on arginine residues. Here we show that in chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD) patients, PRMT7 expression is elevated in the lung tissue and localized to the macrophages. In mouse models of COPD, lung fibrosis and skin injury, reduced expression of PRMT7 associates with decreased recruitment of monocytes to the site of injury and hence less severe symptoms. Mechanistically, activation of NF-κB/RelA in monocytes induces PRMT7 transcription and consequential mono-methylation of histones at the regulatory elements of RAP1A, which leads to increased transcription of this gene that is responsible for adhesion and migration of monocytes. Persistent monocyte-derived macrophage accumulation leads to ALOX5 over-expression and accumulation of its metabolite LTB4, which triggers expression of ACSL4 a ferroptosis promoting gene in lung epithelial cells. Conclusively, inhibition of arginine mono-methylation might offer targeted intervention in monocyte-driven inflammatory conditions that lead to extensive tissue damage if left untreated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multi-omic characterization of genome-wide abnormal DNA methylation reveals diagnostic and prognostic markers for esophageal squamous-cell carcinoma</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35210398/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35210398/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Viruses are intracellular pathogens that hijack host cell machinery and resources to replicate. Rather than being constant, host physiology is rhythmic, undergoing circadian (∼24 h) oscillations in many virus-relevant pathways, but whether daily rhythms impact on viral replication is unknown. We find that the time of day of host infection regulates virus progression in live mice and individual cells. Furthermore, we demonstrate that herpes and influenza A virus infections are enhanced when host circadian rhythms are abolished by disrupting the key clock gene transcription factor Bmal1. Intracellular trafficking, biosynthetic processes, protein synthesis, and chromatin assembly all contribute to circadian regulation of virus infection. Moreover, herpesviruses differentially target components of the molecular circadian clockwork. Our work demonstrates that viruses exploit the clockwork for their own gain and that the clock represents a novel target for modulating viral replication that extends beyond any single family of these ubiquitous pathogens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Epigenetic modifications in spinal ligament aging</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/35218968/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/35218968/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spinal ligament aging is a complex process involving genetic, epigenetic, and environmental factors.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;DNA methylation, histone modifications and ncRNAs exert vital functions in spinal ligament aging.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Epigenetic alterations provide promising diagnostic and therapeutic targets for spinal ligament aging.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spinal stenosis is a common degenerative spine disorder in the aged population and the spinal ligament aging is a main contributor to this chronic disease. However, the underlying mechanisms of spinal ligament aging remain unclear. Epigenetics is the study of heritable and reversible changes in the function of a gene or genome that occur without any alteration in the primary DNA sequence. Epigenetic alterations have been demonstrated to play crucial roles in age-related diseases and conditions, and they are recently studied as biomarkers and therapeutic targets in the field of cancer research. The main epigenetic modifications, including DNA methylation alteration, histone modifications as well as dysregulated noncoding RNA modulation, have all been implicated in spinal ligament aging diseases. DNA methylation modulates the expression of critical genes including WNT5A, GDNF, ACSM5, miR-497 and miR-195 during spinal ligament degeneration. Histone modifications widely affect gene expression and obvious histone modification abnormalities have been found in spinal ligament aging. MicroRNAs (miRNAs), long noncoding RNAs (lncRNAs) and circular RNAs (circRNAs) exert crucial regulating effects on spinal ligament aging conditions via targeting various osteogenic or fibrogenic differentiation related genes. To our knowledge, there is no systematic review yet to summarize the involvement of epigenetic mechanisms of spinal ligament aging in degenerative spinal diseases. In this study, we systematically discussed the different epigenetic modifications and their potential functions in spinal ligament aging process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Epigenomic and enhancer dysregulation in uterine leiomyomas</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/35199155/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/35199155/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Uterine leiomyomas, also known as uterine fibroids or myomas, are the most common benign gynecological tumors and are found in women of reproductive and postmenopausal age. There is an exceptionally high prevalence of this tumor in women by the age of 50 years. Black women are particularly affected, with an increased incidence, earlier age of onset, larger and faster growing fibroids and greater severity of symptoms as compared to White women. Although advances in identifying genetic and environmental factors to delineate these fibroids have already been made, only recently has the role of epigenomics in the pathogenesis of this disease been considered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Objective and rationale:&lt;/em&gt; Over recent years, studies have identified multiple epigenomic aberrations that may contribute to leiomyoma development and growth. This review will focus on the most recent discoveries in three categories of epigenomic changes found in uterine fibroids, namely aberrant DNA methylation, histone tail modifications and histone variant exchange, and their translation into altered target gene architecture and transcriptional outcome. The findings demonstrating how the altered 3D shape of the enhancer can regulate gene expression from millions of base pairs away will be discussed. Additionally, translational implications of these discoveries and potential roadblocks in leiomyoma treatment will be addressed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Search methods:&lt;/em&gt; A comprehensive PubMed search was performed to identify published articles containing keywords relevant to the focus of the review, such as: uterine leiomyoma, uterine fibroids, epigenetic alterations, epigenomics, stem cells, chromatin modifications, extracellular matrix [ECM] organization, DNA methylation, enhancer, histone post-translational modifications and dysregulated gene expression. Articles until September 2021 were explored and evaluated to identify relevant updates in the field. Most of the articles focused on in the discussion were published between 2015 and 2021, although some key discoveries made before 2015 were included for background information and foundational purposes. We apologize to the authors whose work was not included because of space restrictions or inadvertent omission.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Outcomes:&lt;/em&gt; Chemical alterations to the DNA structure and of nucleosomal histones, without changing the underlying DNA sequence, have now been implicated in the phenotypic manifestation of uterine leiomyomas. Genome-wide DNA methylation analysis has revealed subsets of either suppressed or overexpressed genes accompanied by aberrant promoter methylation. Furthermore, differential promoter access resulting from altered 3D chromatin structure and histone modifications plays a role in regulating transcription of key genes thought to be involved in leiomyoma etiology. The dysregulated genes function in tumor suppression, apoptosis, angiogenesis, ECM formation, a variety of cancer-related signaling pathways and stem cell differentiation. Aberrant DNA methylation or histone modification is also observed in altering enhancer architecture, which leads to changes in enhancer-promoter contact strength, producing novel explanations for the overexpression of high mobility group AT-hook 2 and gene dysregulation found in mediator complex subunit 12 mutant fibroids. While many molecular mechanisms and epigenomic features have been investigated, the basis for the racial disparity observed among those in the Black population remains unclear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Wider implications:&lt;/em&gt; A comprehensive understanding of the exact pathogenesis of uterine leiomyoma is lacking and requires attention as it can provide clues for prevention and viable non-surgical treatment. These findings will widen our knowledge of the role epigenomics plays in the mechanisms related to uterine leiomyoma development and highlight novel approaches for the prevention and identification of epigenome targets for long-term non-invasive treatment options of this significantly common disease.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>H3K36 methylation and DNA-binding both promote Ioc4 recruitment and Isw1b remodeler function</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35188579/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35188579/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Isw1b chromatin-remodeling complex is specifically recruited to gene bodies to help retain pre-existing histones during transcription by RNA polymerase II. Recruitment is dependent on H3K36 methylation and the Isw1b subunit Ioc4, which contains an N-terminal PWWP domain. Here, we present the crystal structure of the Ioc4-PWWP domain, including a detailed functional characterization of the domain on its own as well as in the context of full-length Ioc4 and the Isw1b remodeler. The Ioc4-PWWP domain preferentially binds H3K36me3-containing nucleosomes. Its ability to bind DNA is required for nucleosome binding. It is also furthered by the unique insertion motif present in Ioc4-PWWP. The ability to bind H3K36me3 and DNA promotes the interaction of full-length Ioc4 with nucleosomes in vitro and they are necessary for its recruitment to gene bodies &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt;. Furthermore, a fully functional Ioc4-PWWP domain promotes efficient remodeling by Isw1b and the maintenance of ordered chromatin &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt;, thereby preventing the production of non-coding RNAs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deciphering the etiology and role in oncogenic transformation of the CpG island methylator phenotype: a pan-cancer analysis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35134107/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35134107/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Numerous cancer types have shown to present hypermethylation of CpG islands, also known as a CpG island methylator phenotype (CIMP), often associated with survival variation. Despite extensive research on CIMP, the etiology of this variability remains elusive, possibly due to lack of consistency in defining CIMP. In this work, we utilize a pan-cancer approach to further explore CIMP, focusing on 26 cancer types profiled in the Cancer Genome Atlas (TCGA). We defined CIMP systematically and agnostically, discarding any effects associated with age, gender or tumor purity. We then clustered samples based on their most variable DNA methylation values and analyzed resulting patient groups. Our results confirmed the existence of CIMP in 19 cancers, including gliomas and colorectal cancer. We further showed that CIMP was associated with survival differences in eight cancer types and, in five, represented a prognostic biomarker independent of clinical factors. By analyzing genetic and transcriptomic data, we further uncovered potential drivers of CIMP and classified them in four categories: mutations in genes directly involved in DNA demethylation; mutations in histone methyltransferases; mutations in genes not involved in methylation turnover, such as KRAS and BRAF; and microsatellite instability. Among the 19 CIMP-positive cancers, very few shared potential driver events, and those drivers were only IDH1 and SETD2 mutations. Finally, we found that CIMP was strongly correlated with tumor microenvironment characteristics, such as lymphocyte infiltration. Overall, our results indicate that CIMP does not exhibit a pan-cancer manifestation; rather, general dysregulation of CpG DNA methylation is caused by heterogeneous mechanisms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The establishment of CDK9/RNA PolII/H3K4me3/DNA methylation feedback promotes HOTAIR expression by RNA elongation enhancement in cancer</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35121112/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35121112/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Long non-coding RNA HOX Transcript Antisense RNA (HOTAIR) is overexpressed in multiple cancers with diverse genetic profiles. Importantly, since HOTAIR heavily contributes to cancer progression by promoting tumor growth and metastasis, HOTAIR becomes a potential target for cancer therapy. However, the underlying mechanism leading to HOTAIR deregulation is largely unexplored. Here, we performed a pan-cancer analysis using more than 4,200 samples and found that intragenic exon CpG island (Ex-CGI) was hypermethylated and was positively correlated to HOTAIR expression. Also, we revealed that Ex-CGI methylation promotes HOTAIR expression through enhancing the transcription elongation process. Furthermore, we linked up the aberrant intragenic tri-methylation on H3 at lysine 4 (H3K4me3) and Ex-CGI DNA methylation in promoting transcription elongation of HOTAIR. Targeting the oncogenic CDK7-CDK9-H3K4me3 axis downregulated HOTAIR expression and inhibited cell growth in many cancers. To our knowledge, this is the first time that a positive feedback loop that involved CDK9-mediated phosphorylation of RNA Polymerase II Serine 2 (RNA PolII Ser2), H3K4me3, and intragenic DNA methylation, which induced robust transcriptional elongation and heavily contributed to the upregulation of oncogenic lncRNA in cancer has been demonstrated. Targeting the oncogenic CDK7-CDK9-H3K4me3 axis could be a novel therapy in many cancers through inhibiting the HOTAIR expression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MethReg: estimating the regulatory potential of DNA methylation in gene transcription</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35100398/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35100398/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Epigenome-wide association studies often detect many differentially methylated sites, and many are located in distal regulatory regions. To further prioritize these significant sites, there is a critical need to better understand the functional impact of CpG methylation. Recent studies demonstrated that CpG methylation-dependent transcriptional regulation is a widespread phenomenon. Here, we present &lt;a href=&#34;https://bioconductor.org/packages/release/bioc/html/MethReg.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;MethReg&lt;/a&gt;, an R/Bioconductor package that analyzes matched DNA methylation and gene expression data, along with external transcription factor (TF) binding information, to evaluate, prioritize and annotate CpG sites with high regulatory potential. At these CpG sites, TF-target gene associations are often only present in a subset of samples with high (or low) methylation levels, so they can be missed by analyses that use all samples. Using colorectal cancer and Alzheimer&amp;rsquo;s disease datasets, we show &lt;a href=&#34;https://bioconductor.org/packages/release/bioc/html/MethReg.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;MethReg&lt;/a&gt; significantly enhances our understanding of the regulatory roles of DNA methylation in complex diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DNA methylation signatures in Blood DNA of Hutchinson-Gilford Progeria syndrome</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35045206/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35045206/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hutchinson-Gilford Progeria Syndrome (HGPS) is an extremely rare genetic disorder caused by mutations in the LMNA gene and characterized by premature and accelerated aging beginning in childhood. In this study, we performed the first genome-wide methylation analysis on blood DNA of 15 patients with progeroid laminopathies using Infinium Methylation EPIC arrays including 8 patients with classical HGPS. We could observe DNA methylation alterations at 61 CpG sites as well as 32 significant regions following a 5 Kb tiling analysis. Differentially methylated probes were enriched for phosphatidylinositol biosynthetic process, phospholipid biosynthetic process, sarcoplasm, sarcoplasmic reticulum, phosphatase regulator activity, glycerolipid biosynthetic process, glycerophospholipid biosynthetic process, and phosphatidylinositol metabolic process. Differential methylation analysis at the level of promoters and CpG islands revealed no significant methylation changes in blood DNA of progeroid laminopathy patients. Nevertheless, we could observe significant methylation differences in classic HGPS when specifically looking at probes overlapping solo-WCGW partially methylated domains. Comparing aberrantly methylated sites in progeroid laminopathies, classic Werner syndrome, and Down syndrome revealed a common significantly hypermethylated region in close vicinity to the transcription start site of a long non-coding RNA located anti-sense to the Catenin Beta Interacting Protein 1 gene (CTNNBIP1). By characterizing epigenetically altered sites, we identify possible pathways/mechanisms that might have a role in the accelerated aging of progeroid laminopathies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vitamin C Deficiency Causes Cell Type-Specific Epigenetic Reprogramming and Acute Tubular Necrosis in a Mouse Model</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34983833/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34983833/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Vitamin C deficiency is found in patients with variable kidney diseases. However, the role of vitamin C as an epigenetic regulator in renal homeostasis and pathogenesis remains largely unknown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; We showed that vitamin C deficiency leads to acute tubular necrosis (ATN) using a vitamin C-deficient mouse model (Gulo knock-out). DNA/RNA epigenetic modifications and injured S3 proximal tubule cells were identified in the vitamin C-deficient kidneys using whole-genome bisulfite sequencing, methylated RNA immunoprecipitation sequencing, and single-cell RNA sequencing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; Integrated evidence suggested that epigenetic modifications affected the proximal tubule cells and fenestrated endothelial cells, leading to tubule injury and hypoxia through transcriptional regulation. Strikingly, loss of DNA hydroxymethylation and DNA hypermethylation in vitamin C-deficient kidneys preceded the histologic sign of tubule necrosis, indicating the causality of vitamin C-induced epigenetic modification in ATN. Consistently, prophylactic supplementation of an oxidation-resistant vitamin C derivative, ascorbyl phosphate magnesium, promoted DNA demethylation and prevented the progression of cisplatin-induced ATN.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; Vitamin C played a critical role in renal homeostasis and pathogenesis in a mouse model, suggesting vitamin supplementation may be an approach to lower the risk of kidney injury.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>scMethBank: a database for single-cell whole genome DNA methylation maps</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34570235/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34570235/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Single-cell bisulfite sequencing methods are widely used to assess epigenomic heterogeneity in cell states. Over the past few years, large amounts of data have been generated and facilitated deeper understanding of the epigenetic regulation of many key biological processes including early embryonic development, cell differentiation and tumor progression. It is an urgent need to build a functional resource platform with the massive amount of data. Here, we present scMethBank, the first open access and comprehensive database dedicated to the collection, integration, analysis and visualization of single-cell DNA methylation data and metadata. Current release of scMethBank includes processed single-cell bisulfite sequencing data and curated metadata of 8328 samples derived from 15 public single-cell datasets, involving two species (human and mouse), 29 cell types and two diseases. In summary, scMethBank aims to assist researchers who are interested in cell heterogeneity to explore and utilize whole genome methylation data at single-cell level by providing browse, search, visualization, download functions and user-friendly online tools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ALKBH7-mediated demethylation regulates mitochondrial polycistronic RNA processing</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34253897/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34253897/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Members of the mammalian AlkB family are known to mediate nucleic acid demethylation. ALKBH7, a mammalian AlkB homologue, localizes in mitochondria and affects metabolism, but its function and mechanism of action are unknown. Here we report an approach to site-specifically detect N&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;-methyladenosine (m&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;A), N&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;-methylcytidine (m&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;C), N&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;-methylguanosine (m&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;G) and N&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;,N&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;-dimethylguanosine (m&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;G) modifications simultaneously within all cellular RNAs, and discovered that human ALKBH7 demethylates m&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;G and m&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;A within mitochondrial Ile and Leu1 pre-tRNA regions, respectively, in nascent polycistronic mitochondrial RNA. We further show that ALKBH7 regulates the processing and structural dynamics of polycistronic mitochondrial RNAs. Depletion of ALKBH7 leads to increased polycistronic mitochondrial RNA processing, reduced steady-state mitochondria-encoded tRNA levels and protein translation, and notably decreased mitochondrial activity. Thus, we identify ALKBH7 as an RNA demethylase that controls nascent mitochondrial RNA processing and mitochondrial activity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arginine monomethylation by PRMT7 controls MAVS-mediated antiviral innate immunity</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34171297/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34171297/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Accurate control of innate immune responses is required to eliminate invading pathogens and simultaneously avoid autoinflammation and autoimmune diseases. Here, we demonstrate that arginine monomethylation precisely regulates the mitochondrial antiviral-signaling protein (MAVS)-mediated antiviral response. Protein arginine methyltransferase 7 (PRMT7) forms aggregates to catalyze MAVS monomethylation at arginine residue 52 (R52), attenuating its binding to TRIM31 and RIG-I, which leads to the suppression of MAVS aggregation and subsequent activation. Upon virus infection, aggregated PRMT7 is disabled in a timely manner due to automethylation at arginine residue 32 (R32), and SMURF1 is recruited to PRMT7 by MAVS to induce proteasomal degradation of PRMT7, resulting in the relief of PRMT7 suppression of MAVS activation. Therefore, we not only reveal that arginine monomethylation by PRMT7 negatively regulates MAVS-mediated antiviral signaling in vitro and in vivo but also uncover a mechanism by which PRMT7 is tightly controlled to ensure the timely activation of antiviral defense.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>miRNA-mediated loss of m6A increases nascent translation in glioblastoma</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33684100/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33684100/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Within the glioblastoma cellular niche, glioma stem cells (GSCs) can give rise to differentiated glioma cells (DGCs) and, when necessary, DGCs can reciprocally give rise to GSCs to maintain the cellular equilibrium necessary for optimal tumor growth. Here, using ribosome profiling, transcriptome and m&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;A RNA sequencing, we show that GSCs from patients with different subtypes of glioblastoma share a set of transcripts, which exhibit a pattern of m&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;A loss and increased protein translation during differentiation. The target sequences of a group of miRNAs overlap the canonical RRACH m&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;A motifs of these transcripts, many of which confer a survival advantage in glioblastoma. Ectopic expression of the RRACH-binding miR-145 induces loss of m&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;A, formation of FTO/AGO1/ILF3/miR-145 complexes on a clinically relevant tumor suppressor gene (CLIP3) and significant increase in its nascent translation. Inhibition of miR-145 maintains RRACH m&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;A levels of CLIP3 and inhibits its nascent translation. This study highlights a critical role of miRNAs in assembling complexes for m&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;A demethylation and induction of protein translation during GSC state transition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>N6-methyladenine is incorporated into mammalian genome by DNA polymerase</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32355286/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32355286/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Erratum in:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Author Correction: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nature.com/articles/s41422-020-0339-0&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;N&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;-methyladenine is incorporated into mammalian genome by DNA polymerase&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No abstract available&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Homeobox oncogene activation by pan-cancer DNA hypermethylation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/30097071/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/30097071/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Cancers have long been recognized to be not only genetically but also epigenetically distinct from their tissues of origin. Although genetic alterations underlying oncogene upregulation have been well studied, to what extent epigenetic mechanisms, such as DNA methylation, can also induce oncogene expression remains unknown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; Here, through pan-cancer analysis of 4174 genome-wide profiles, including whole-genome bisulfite sequencing data from 30 normal tissues and 35 solid tumors, we discover a strong correlation between gene-body hypermethylation of DNA methylation canyons, defined as broad under-methylated regions, and overexpression of approximately 43% of homeobox genes, many of which are also oncogenes. To gain insights into the cause-and-effect relationship, we use a newly developed dCas9-SunTag-DNMT3A system to methylate genomic sites of interest. The locus-specific hypermethylation of gene-body canyon, but not promoter, of homeobox oncogene DLX1, can directly increase its gene expression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; Our pan-cancer analysis followed by functional validation reveals DNA hypermethylation as a novel epigenetic mechanism for homeobox oncogene upregulation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Principles of DNA methylation and their implications for biology and medicine</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/30100054/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/30100054/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DNA methylation represents an annotation system for marking the genetic text, thus providing instruction as to how and when to read the information and control transcription. Unlike sequence information, which is inherited, methylation patterns are established in a programmed process that continues throughout development, thus setting up stable gene expression profiles. This DNA methylation paradigm is a key player in medicine. Some changes in methylation closely correlate with age providing a marker for biological ageing, and these same sites could also play a part in cancer. The genome continues to undergo programmed variation in methylation after birth in response to environmental inputs, serving as a memory device that could affect ageing and predisposition to various metabolic, autoimmune, and neurological diseases. Taking advantage of tissue-specific differences, methylation can be used to detect cell death and thereby monitor many common diseases with a simple cell-free circulating-DNA blood test.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Short-term exposure to fine particulate air pollution and genome-wide DNA methylation: A randomized, double-blind, crossover trial</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/30081103/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/30081103/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Previous studies have associated fine particulate (PM&lt;sub&gt;2.5&lt;/sub&gt;) exposure with changes in gene-specific DNA methylation. However, the evidence was still limited and inconsistent in genome-wide DNA methylation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Objective:&lt;/em&gt; To examine the impact of short-term PM&lt;sub&gt;2.5&lt;/sub&gt; exposure on genome-wide DNA methylation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; We designed a randomized, double-blind, crossover trial among 36 healthy young adults in Shanghai, China. A two-stage intervention with alternative use of real and sham air purifiers in dormitory rooms for consecutive 9 days were conducted to create natural low and high exposure scenarios of PM&lt;sub&gt;2.5&lt;/sub&gt;. Blood genome-wide DNA methylation was analyzed using the Illumina Infinium Human Methylation EPIC BeadChip (850k). Mixed-effect models were used to evaluate the impacts of changes in PM&lt;sub&gt;2.5&lt;/sub&gt; levels on genome-wide DNA methylation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; There was a drastic contrast for PM&lt;sub&gt;2.5&lt;/sub&gt; exposure levels in the two scenarios (24-h averages: 53.1 and 24.3 μg/m&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;). Between the high and low exposure groups, methylation levels were changed significantly with a false discovery rate &amp;lt; 0.01 at 49 CpG loci, of which 31 CpG sites were annotated to the specific genes. DNA methylation of these annotated genes were elevated in response to increased PM&lt;sub&gt;2.5&lt;/sub&gt; exposure, which were implicated in insulin resistance, glucose and lipid metabolism, inflammation, oxidative stress, platelet activation, and cell survival and apoptosis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; Our results provided novel biological pathways linking ambient PM&lt;sub&gt;2.5&lt;/sub&gt; exposure to systemic adverse response through variations in DNA methylation and reinforced the hypothesized role of epigenetics in the development of cardiometabolic diseases induced by PM&lt;sub&gt;2.5&lt;/sub&gt; exposure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RNA N6-methyladenosine modification in cancers: current status and perspectives</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/29686311/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/29686311/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;N&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;-methyladenosine (m&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;A), the most abundant internal modification in eukaryotic messenger RNAs (mRNAs), has been shown to play critical roles in various normal bioprocesses such as tissue development, stem cell self-renewal and differentiation, heat shock or DNA damage response, and maternal-to-zygotic transition. The m&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;A modification is deposited by the m&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;A methyltransferase complex (MTC; i.e., writer) composed of METTL3, METTL14 and WTAP, and probably also VIRMA and RBM15, and can be removed by m&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;A demethylases (i.e., erasers) such as FTO and ALKBH5. The fates of m&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;A-modified mRNAs rely on the functions of distinct proteins that recognize them (i.e., readers), which may affect the stability, splicing, and/or translation of target mRNAs. Given the functional importance of the m&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;A modification machinery in normal bioprocesses, it is not surprising that evidence is emerging that dysregulation of m&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;A modification and the associated proteins also contributes to the initiation, progression, and drug response of cancers. In this review, we focus on recent advances in the study of biological functions and the underlying molecular mechanisms of dysregulated m&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;A modification and the associated machinery in the pathogenesis and drug response of various types of cancers. In addition, we also discuss possible therapeutic interventions against the dysregulated m&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;A machinery to treat cancers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
