<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Methylation | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/methylation/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/methylation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Methylation</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Methylation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/methylation/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>PCR Primer Design</title>
      <link>https://example.com/books/2023-01-01-primer-design-3ed/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/books/2023-01-01-primer-design-3ed/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Section A: &lt;em&gt;Primer Design for Genotyping&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chapter 1&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/uploads/34773611.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;The Significance of PCR Primer Design in Genetic Diversity Studies: Exemplified by Recent Research into the Genetic Structure of Marine Species&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chapter 2&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/uploads/34773612.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Enhancing Cohort PASA Efficiency from Lessons Assimilated by Mutant Genotyping in C. elegans&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chapter 3&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/uploads/34773613.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Design of Oligonucleotides for Allele-Specific Amplification Based on PCR and Isothermal Techniques&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chapter 4&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/uploads/34773614.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Detection of Rubella Virus by Tri-Primer RT-PCR Assay and Genotyping by Fragment RT-PCR&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chapter 5&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/uploads/34773615.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Design of Mismatch Primers to Identify and Differentiate Closely Related (Sub)Species: Application to the Authentication of Meat Products&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chapter 6&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/uploads/34773616.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Primer Design for the Analysis of Closely Related Species: Application of Noncoding mtDNA and cpDNA Sequences&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chapter 7&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/uploads/34773617.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Designing PCR Primers for the Amplification-Refractory Mutation System&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Section B: &lt;em&gt;Primer Design for Genome-Wide Identification of Specific Regions&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chapter 8&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/uploads/34773618.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Validation of Circular RNAs by PCR&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chapter 9&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/uploads/34773619.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Primer Designing for Amplifying an AT-Rich Promoter from Arabidopsis thaliana&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Section C: &lt;em&gt;Primer Design for Multiplex PCR&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chapter 10&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/uploads/34773620.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;PLASmid TAXonomic PCR (PlasTax-PCR), a Multiplex Relaxase MOB Typing to Assort Plasmids into Taxonomic Units&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chapter 11&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/uploads/34773621.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Multiplex PCR Design for Scalable Resequencing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Section D: &lt;em&gt;Primer Design for qPCR&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chapter 12&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/uploads/34773622.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Identification of Gene Copy Number in the Transgenic Plants by Quantitative Polymerase Chain Reaction (qPCR)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chapter 13&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/uploads/34773623.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;qPrimerDB: A Powerful and User-Friendly Database for qPCR Primer Design&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Section E: &lt;em&gt;Primer Design for Identification of Plant and Animal Viruses&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chapter 14&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/uploads/34773624.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;PCR Primer Design for the Rapidly Evolving SARS-CoV-2 Genome&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chapter 15&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/uploads/34773625.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Universal Primers for Detection of Novel Plant Capsid-Less Viruses: Papaya Umbra-like Viruses as Examp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Section F: &lt;em&gt;Use of Software for Primer Design&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chapter 16&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/uploads/34773626.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A Guide to Using FASTPCR Software for PCR, In Silico PCR, and Oligonucleotide Analysis&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Section G: &lt;em&gt;Primer Design for Newer PCR Approaches&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chapter 17&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/uploads/34773627.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Pyrosequencing Primer Design for Forensic Biology Applications&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chapter 18&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/uploads/34773628.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Phosphate-Methylated Oligonucleotides as a Novel Primer for PCR and RT-PCR&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/books/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Books &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>High-precision mapping reveals rare N6-deoxyadenosine methylation in the mammalian genome</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36575183/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36575183/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;N&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;-deoxyadenosine methylation (6mA) is the most widespread type of DNA modification in prokaryotes and is also abundantly distributed in some unicellular eukaryotes. However, 6mA levels are remarkably low in mammals. The lack of a precise and comprehensive mapping method has hindered more advanced investigations of 6mA. Here, we report a new method MM-seq (modification-induced mismatch sequencing) for genome-wide 6mA mapping based on a novel detection principle. We found that modified DNA bases are prone to form a local open region that allows capture by antibody, for example, via a DNA breathing or base-flipping mechanism. Specified endonuclease or exonuclease can recognize the antibody-stabilized mismatch-like structure and mark the exact modified sites for sequencing readout. Using this method, we examined the genomic positions of 6mA in bacteria (E. coli), green algae (C. reinhardtii), and mammalian cells (HEK239T, Huh7, and HeLa cells). In contrast to bacteria and green algae, human cells possess a very limited number of 6mA sites which are sporadically distributed across the genome of different cell types. After knocking out the RNA m&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;A methyltransferase METTL3 in mouse ES cells, 6mA becomes mostly diminished. Our results imply that rare 6mA in the mammalian genome is introduced by RNA m&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;A machinery via a non-targeted mechanism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SESAME-catalyzed H3T11 phosphorylation inhibits Dot1-catalyzed H3K79me3 to regulate autophagy and telomere silencing</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36473858/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36473858/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The glycolytic enzyme, pyruvate kinase Pyk1 maintains telomere heterochromatin by phosphorylating histone H3T11 (H3pT11), which promotes SIR (silent information regulator) complex binding at telomeres and prevents autophagy-mediated Sir2 degradation. However, the exact mechanism of action for H3pT11 is poorly understood. Here, we report that H3pT11 directly inhibits Dot1-catalyzed H3K79 tri-methylation (H3K79me3) and uncover how this histone crosstalk regulates autophagy and telomere silencing. Mechanistically, Pyk1-catalyzed H3pT11 directly reduces the binding of Dot1 to chromatin and inhibits Dot1-catalyzed H3K79me3, which leads to transcriptional repression of autophagy genes and reduced autophagy. Despite the antagonism between H3pT11 and H3K79me3, they work together to promote the binding of SIR complex at telomeres to maintain telomere silencing. Furthermore, we identify Reb1 as a telomere-associated factor that recruits Pyk1-containing SESAME (Serine-responsive SAM-containing Metabolic Enzyme) complex to telomere regions to phosphorylate H3T11 and prevent the invasion of H3K79me3 from euchromatin into heterochromatin to maintain telomere silencing. Together, these results uncover a histone crosstalk and provide insights into dynamic regulation of silent heterochromatin and autophagy in response to cell metabolism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Active DNA demethylation promotes cell fate specification and the DNA damage response</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36454826/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36454826/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Neurons harbor high levels of single-strand DNA breaks (SSBs) that are targeted to neuronal enhancers, but the source of this endogenous damage remains unclear. Using two systems of postmitotic lineage specification-induced pluripotent stem cell-derived neurons and transdifferentiated macrophages-we show that thymidine DNA glycosylase (TDG)-driven excision of methylcytosines oxidized with ten-eleven translocation enzymes (TET) is a source of SSBs. Although macrophage differentiation favors short-patch base excision repair to fill in single-nucleotide gaps, neurons also frequently use the long-patch subpathway. Disrupting this gap-filling process using anti-neoplastic cytosine analogs triggers a DNA damage response and neuronal cell death, which is dependent on TDG. Thus, TET-mediated active DNA demethylation promotes endogenous DNA damage, a process that normally safeguards cell identity but can also provoke neurotoxicity after anticancer treatments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Structural basis for product specificities of MLL family methyltransferases</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36108631/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36108631/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Human mixed-lineage leukemia (MLL) family methyltransferases methylate histone H3 lysine 4 to different methylation states (me1/me2/me3) with distinct functional outputs, but the mechanism underlying the different product specificities of MLL proteins remains unclear. Here, we develop methodologies to quantitatively measure the methylation rate difference between mono-, di-, and tri-methylation steps and demonstrate that MLL proteins possess distinct product specificities in the context of the minimum MLL-RBBP5-ASH2L complex. Comparative structural analyses of MLL complexes by X-ray crystal structures, fluorine-19 nuclear magnetic resonance, and molecular dynamics simulations reveal that the dynamics of two conserved tyrosine residues at the &amp;ldquo;F/Y (phenylalanine/tyrosine) switch&amp;rdquo; positions fine-tune the product specificity. The variation in the intramolecular interaction between SET-N and SET-C affects the F/Y switch dynamics, thus determining the product specificities of MLL proteins. These results indicate a modified F/Y switch rule applicable for most SET domain methyltransferases and implicate the functional divergence of MLL proteins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>METTL3 potentiates progression of cervical cancer by suppressing ER stress via regulating m6A modification of TXNDC5 mRNA</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35987795/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35987795/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;N6-methyladenosine (m&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;A) is the most abundant chemical modification on mRNA and plays significant roles in many bioprocesses. However, the functions of m&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;A on cervical cancer (CC) tumorigenesis remain unclear. Here we found methyltransferase-like 3 (METTL3), a core member of the m&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;A methyltransferase family, was greatly upregulated as an independent prognostic factor in CC. Mechanistically, the transcription factor ETS1 recruited P300 and WDR5 which separately mediated H3K27ac and H3K4me3 histone modification in the promoter of METTL3 and induced METTL3 transcription activation. Furthermore, we identified TXNDC5 as a target of METTL3-mediated m&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;A modification through MeRIP-seq, and revealed that METTL3-mediated TXNDC5 expression relied on the m&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;A reader-dependent manner. Functionally, we verified that METTL3 promoted proliferation and metastasis of CC cells by regulating of TXNDC5 expression through in vitro and in vivo experiments. In addition, our study verified the effect of METTL3/TXNDC5 axis on ER stress. Taken together, METTL3 facilitates the malignant progression of CC, suggesting that METTL3 might be a potential prognostic biomarker and therapeutic target for CC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SHF Acts as a Novel Tumor Suppressor in Glioblastoma Multiforme by Disrupting STAT3 Dimerization</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35843865/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35843865/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sustained activation of signal transducer and activator of transcription 3 (STAT3) is a critical contributor in tumorigenesis and chemoresistance, thus making it an attractive cancer therapeutic target. Here, SH2 domain-containing adapter protein F (SHF) is identified as a tumor suppressor in glioblastoma Multiforme (GBM) and its negative regulation of STAT3 activity is characterized. Mechanically, SHF selectively binds and inhibits acetylated STAT3 dimerization without affecting STAT3 phosphorylation or acetylation. Additionally, by blocking STAT3-DNMT1 (DNA Methyltransferase 1) interaction, SHF relieves methylation of tumor suppressor genes. The SH2 domain is documented to be essential for SHF&amp;rsquo;s actions on STAT3, and almost entirely replaces the functions of SHF on STAT3 independently. Moreover, the peptide C16 a peptide derived from the STAT3-binding sites of SHF inhibits STAT3 dimerization and STAT3/DNMT1 interaction, and achieves remarkable growth inhibition in GBM cells in vitro and in vivo. These findings strongly identify targeting of the SHF/STAT3 interaction as a promising strategy for developing an optimal STAT3 inhibitor and provide early evidence of the potential clinical efficacy of STAT3 inhibitors such as C16 in GBM.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>KMT2C deficiency promotes small cell lung cancer metastasis through DNMT3A-mediated epigenetic reprogramming</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35449309/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35449309/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Small cell lung cancer (SCLC) is notorious for its early and frequent metastases, which contribute to it as a recalcitrant malignancy. To understand the molecular mechanisms underlying SCLC metastasis, we generated SCLC mouse models with orthotopically transplanted genome-edited lung organoids and performed multiomics analyses. We found that a deficiency of KMT2C, a histone H3 lysine 4 methyltransferase frequently mutated in extensive-stage SCLC, promoted multiple-organ metastases in mice. Metastatic and KMT2C-deficient SCLC displayed both histone and DNA hypomethylation. Mechanistically, KMT2C directly regulated the expression of DNMT3A, a de novo DNA methyltransferase, through histone methylation. Forced DNMT3A expression restrained metastasis of KMT2C-deficient SCLC through repressing metastasis-promoting MEIS/HOX genes. Further, S-(5′-adenosyl)-L-methionine, the common cofactor of histone and DNA methyltransferases, inhibited SCLC metastasis. Thus, our study revealed a concerted epigenetic reprogramming of KMT2C- and DNMT3A-mediated histone and DNA hypomethylation underlying SCLC metastasis, which suggested a potential epigenetic therapeutic vulnerability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lupus enhancer risk variant causes dysregulation of IRF8 through cooperative lncRNA and DNA methylation machinery</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35388006/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35388006/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite strong evidence that human genetic variants affect the expression of many key transcription factors involved in autoimmune diseases, establishing biological links between non-coding risk variants and the gene targets they regulate remains a considerable challenge. Here, we combine genetic, epigenomic, and CRISPR activation approaches to screen for functional variants that regulate IRF8 expression. We demonstrate that the locus containing rs2280381 is a cell-type-specific enhancer for IRF8 that spatially interacts with the IRF8 promoter. Further, rs2280381 mediates IRF8 expression through enhancer RNA AC092723.1, which recruits TET1 to the IRF8 promoter regulating IRF8 expression by affecting methylation levels. The alleles of rs2280381 modulate PU.1 binding and chromatin state to regulate AC092723.1 and IRF8 expression differentially. Our work illustrates an integrative strategy to define functional genetic variants that regulate the expression of critical genes in autoimmune diseases and decipher the mechanisms underlying the dysregulation of IRF8 expression mediated by lupus risk variants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>m6A mRNA modification maintains colonic epithelial cell homeostasis via NF-κB-mediated antiapoptotic pathway</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35333576/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35333576/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Colonic mucosal barrier dysfunction is one of the major causes of inflammatory bowel disease (IBD). However, the mechanisms underlying mucosal barrier dysfunction are poorly understood. N6-methyladenosine (m6A) mRNA modification is an important modulator of epitranscriptional regulation of gene expression, participating in multiple physiological and pathological processes. However, the function of m6A modification in colonic epithelial cells and stem cells is unknown. Here, we show that m6A modification is essential for maintaining the homeostatic self-renewal in colonic stem cells. Specific deletion of the methyltransferase 14 (Mettl14) gene in mouse colon resulted in colonic stem cell apoptosis, causing mucosal barrier dysfunction and severe colitis. Mechanistically, we revealed that Mettl14 restricted colonic epithelial cell death by regulating the stability of Nfkbia mRNA and modulating the NF-κB pathway. Our results identified a previously unidentified role for m6A modification in colonic epithelial cells and stem cells, suggesting that m6A modification may be a potential therapeutic target for IBD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>scMethBank: a database for single-cell whole genome DNA methylation maps</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34570235/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34570235/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Single-cell bisulfite sequencing methods are widely used to assess epigenomic heterogeneity in cell states. Over the past few years, large amounts of data have been generated and facilitated deeper understanding of the epigenetic regulation of many key biological processes including early embryonic development, cell differentiation and tumor progression. It is an urgent need to build a functional resource platform with the massive amount of data. Here, we present scMethBank, the first open access and comprehensive database dedicated to the collection, integration, analysis and visualization of single-cell DNA methylation data and metadata. Current release of scMethBank includes processed single-cell bisulfite sequencing data and curated metadata of 8328 samples derived from 15 public single-cell datasets, involving two species (human and mouse), 29 cell types and two diseases. In summary, scMethBank aims to assist researchers who are interested in cell heterogeneity to explore and utilize whole genome methylation data at single-cell level by providing browse, search, visualization, download functions and user-friendly online tools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ALKBH7-mediated demethylation regulates mitochondrial polycistronic RNA processing</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34253897/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34253897/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Members of the mammalian AlkB family are known to mediate nucleic acid demethylation. ALKBH7, a mammalian AlkB homologue, localizes in mitochondria and affects metabolism, but its function and mechanism of action are unknown. Here we report an approach to site-specifically detect N&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;-methyladenosine (m&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;A), N&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;-methylcytidine (m&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;C), N&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;-methylguanosine (m&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;G) and N&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;,N&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;-dimethylguanosine (m&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;G) modifications simultaneously within all cellular RNAs, and discovered that human ALKBH7 demethylates m&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;G and m&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;A within mitochondrial Ile and Leu1 pre-tRNA regions, respectively, in nascent polycistronic mitochondrial RNA. We further show that ALKBH7 regulates the processing and structural dynamics of polycistronic mitochondrial RNAs. Depletion of ALKBH7 leads to increased polycistronic mitochondrial RNA processing, reduced steady-state mitochondria-encoded tRNA levels and protein translation, and notably decreased mitochondrial activity. Thus, we identify ALKBH7 as an RNA demethylase that controls nascent mitochondrial RNA processing and mitochondrial activity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arginine monomethylation by PRMT7 controls MAVS-mediated antiviral innate immunity</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34171297/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34171297/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Accurate control of innate immune responses is required to eliminate invading pathogens and simultaneously avoid autoinflammation and autoimmune diseases. Here, we demonstrate that arginine monomethylation precisely regulates the mitochondrial antiviral-signaling protein (MAVS)-mediated antiviral response. Protein arginine methyltransferase 7 (PRMT7) forms aggregates to catalyze MAVS monomethylation at arginine residue 52 (R52), attenuating its binding to TRIM31 and RIG-I, which leads to the suppression of MAVS aggregation and subsequent activation. Upon virus infection, aggregated PRMT7 is disabled in a timely manner due to automethylation at arginine residue 32 (R32), and SMURF1 is recruited to PRMT7 by MAVS to induce proteasomal degradation of PRMT7, resulting in the relief of PRMT7 suppression of MAVS activation. Therefore, we not only reveal that arginine monomethylation by PRMT7 negatively regulates MAVS-mediated antiviral signaling in vitro and in vivo but also uncover a mechanism by which PRMT7 is tightly controlled to ensure the timely activation of antiviral defense.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>miRNA-mediated loss of m6A increases nascent translation in glioblastoma</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33684100/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33684100/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Within the glioblastoma cellular niche, glioma stem cells (GSCs) can give rise to differentiated glioma cells (DGCs) and, when necessary, DGCs can reciprocally give rise to GSCs to maintain the cellular equilibrium necessary for optimal tumor growth. Here, using ribosome profiling, transcriptome and m&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;A RNA sequencing, we show that GSCs from patients with different subtypes of glioblastoma share a set of transcripts, which exhibit a pattern of m&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;A loss and increased protein translation during differentiation. The target sequences of a group of miRNAs overlap the canonical RRACH m&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;A motifs of these transcripts, many of which confer a survival advantage in glioblastoma. Ectopic expression of the RRACH-binding miR-145 induces loss of m&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;A, formation of FTO/AGO1/ILF3/miR-145 complexes on a clinically relevant tumor suppressor gene (CLIP3) and significant increase in its nascent translation. Inhibition of miR-145 maintains RRACH m&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;A levels of CLIP3 and inhibits its nascent translation. This study highlights a critical role of miRNAs in assembling complexes for m&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;A demethylation and induction of protein translation during GSC state transition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>N6-methyladenine is incorporated into mammalian genome by DNA polymerase</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32355286/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32355286/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Erratum in:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Author Correction: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nature.com/articles/s41422-020-0339-0&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;N&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;-methyladenine is incorporated into mammalian genome by DNA polymerase&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No abstract available&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Homeobox oncogene activation by pan-cancer DNA hypermethylation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/30097071/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/30097071/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Cancers have long been recognized to be not only genetically but also epigenetically distinct from their tissues of origin. Although genetic alterations underlying oncogene upregulation have been well studied, to what extent epigenetic mechanisms, such as DNA methylation, can also induce oncogene expression remains unknown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; Here, through pan-cancer analysis of 4174 genome-wide profiles, including whole-genome bisulfite sequencing data from 30 normal tissues and 35 solid tumors, we discover a strong correlation between gene-body hypermethylation of DNA methylation canyons, defined as broad under-methylated regions, and overexpression of approximately 43% of homeobox genes, many of which are also oncogenes. To gain insights into the cause-and-effect relationship, we use a newly developed dCas9-SunTag-DNMT3A system to methylate genomic sites of interest. The locus-specific hypermethylation of gene-body canyon, but not promoter, of homeobox oncogene DLX1, can directly increase its gene expression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; Our pan-cancer analysis followed by functional validation reveals DNA hypermethylation as a novel epigenetic mechanism for homeobox oncogene upregulation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Principles of DNA methylation and their implications for biology and medicine</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/30100054/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/30100054/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DNA methylation represents an annotation system for marking the genetic text, thus providing instruction as to how and when to read the information and control transcription. Unlike sequence information, which is inherited, methylation patterns are established in a programmed process that continues throughout development, thus setting up stable gene expression profiles. This DNA methylation paradigm is a key player in medicine. Some changes in methylation closely correlate with age providing a marker for biological ageing, and these same sites could also play a part in cancer. The genome continues to undergo programmed variation in methylation after birth in response to environmental inputs, serving as a memory device that could affect ageing and predisposition to various metabolic, autoimmune, and neurological diseases. Taking advantage of tissue-specific differences, methylation can be used to detect cell death and thereby monitor many common diseases with a simple cell-free circulating-DNA blood test.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Short-term exposure to fine particulate air pollution and genome-wide DNA methylation: A randomized, double-blind, crossover trial</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/30081103/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/30081103/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Previous studies have associated fine particulate (PM&lt;sub&gt;2.5&lt;/sub&gt;) exposure with changes in gene-specific DNA methylation. However, the evidence was still limited and inconsistent in genome-wide DNA methylation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Objective:&lt;/em&gt; To examine the impact of short-term PM&lt;sub&gt;2.5&lt;/sub&gt; exposure on genome-wide DNA methylation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; We designed a randomized, double-blind, crossover trial among 36 healthy young adults in Shanghai, China. A two-stage intervention with alternative use of real and sham air purifiers in dormitory rooms for consecutive 9 days were conducted to create natural low and high exposure scenarios of PM&lt;sub&gt;2.5&lt;/sub&gt;. Blood genome-wide DNA methylation was analyzed using the Illumina Infinium Human Methylation EPIC BeadChip (850k). Mixed-effect models were used to evaluate the impacts of changes in PM&lt;sub&gt;2.5&lt;/sub&gt; levels on genome-wide DNA methylation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; There was a drastic contrast for PM&lt;sub&gt;2.5&lt;/sub&gt; exposure levels in the two scenarios (24-h averages: 53.1 and 24.3 μg/m&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;). Between the high and low exposure groups, methylation levels were changed significantly with a false discovery rate &amp;lt; 0.01 at 49 CpG loci, of which 31 CpG sites were annotated to the specific genes. DNA methylation of these annotated genes were elevated in response to increased PM&lt;sub&gt;2.5&lt;/sub&gt; exposure, which were implicated in insulin resistance, glucose and lipid metabolism, inflammation, oxidative stress, platelet activation, and cell survival and apoptosis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; Our results provided novel biological pathways linking ambient PM&lt;sub&gt;2.5&lt;/sub&gt; exposure to systemic adverse response through variations in DNA methylation and reinforced the hypothesized role of epigenetics in the development of cardiometabolic diseases induced by PM&lt;sub&gt;2.5&lt;/sub&gt; exposure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RNA N6-methyladenosine modification in cancers: current status and perspectives</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/29686311/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/29686311/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;N&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;-methyladenosine (m&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;A), the most abundant internal modification in eukaryotic messenger RNAs (mRNAs), has been shown to play critical roles in various normal bioprocesses such as tissue development, stem cell self-renewal and differentiation, heat shock or DNA damage response, and maternal-to-zygotic transition. The m&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;A modification is deposited by the m&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;A methyltransferase complex (MTC; i.e., writer) composed of METTL3, METTL14 and WTAP, and probably also VIRMA and RBM15, and can be removed by m&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;A demethylases (i.e., erasers) such as FTO and ALKBH5. The fates of m&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;A-modified mRNAs rely on the functions of distinct proteins that recognize them (i.e., readers), which may affect the stability, splicing, and/or translation of target mRNAs. Given the functional importance of the m&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;A modification machinery in normal bioprocesses, it is not surprising that evidence is emerging that dysregulation of m&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;A modification and the associated proteins also contributes to the initiation, progression, and drug response of cancers. In this review, we focus on recent advances in the study of biological functions and the underlying molecular mechanisms of dysregulated m&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;A modification and the associated machinery in the pathogenesis and drug response of various types of cancers. In addition, we also discuss possible therapeutic interventions against the dysregulated m&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;A machinery to treat cancers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
