<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Methylation | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/methylation/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/methylation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Methylation</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Methylation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/methylation/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>PCR Primer Design</title>
      <link>https://example.com/books/2023-01-01-primer-design-3ed/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/books/2023-01-01-primer-design-3ed/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Section A: &lt;em&gt;Primer Design for Genotyping&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chapter 1&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/uploads/34773611.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;The Significance of PCR Primer Design in Genetic Diversity Studies: Exemplified by Recent Research into the Genetic Structure of Marine Species&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chapter 2&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/uploads/34773612.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Enhancing Cohort PASA Efficiency from Lessons Assimilated by Mutant Genotyping in C. elegans&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chapter 3&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/uploads/34773613.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Design of Oligonucleotides for Allele-Specific Amplification Based on PCR and Isothermal Techniques&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chapter 4&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/uploads/34773614.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Detection of Rubella Virus by Tri-Primer RT-PCR Assay and Genotyping by Fragment RT-PCR&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chapter 5&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/uploads/34773615.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Design of Mismatch Primers to Identify and Differentiate Closely Related (Sub)Species: Application to the Authentication of Meat Products&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chapter 6&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/uploads/34773616.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Primer Design for the Analysis of Closely Related Species: Application of Noncoding mtDNA and cpDNA Sequences&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chapter 7&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/uploads/34773617.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Designing PCR Primers for the Amplification-Refractory Mutation System&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Section B: &lt;em&gt;Primer Design for Genome-Wide Identification of Specific Regions&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chapter 8&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/uploads/34773618.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Validation of Circular RNAs by PCR&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chapter 9&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/uploads/34773619.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Primer Designing for Amplifying an AT-Rich Promoter from Arabidopsis thaliana&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Section C: &lt;em&gt;Primer Design for Multiplex PCR&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chapter 10&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/uploads/34773620.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;PLASmid TAXonomic PCR (PlasTax-PCR), a Multiplex Relaxase MOB Typing to Assort Plasmids into Taxonomic Units&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chapter 11&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/uploads/34773621.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Multiplex PCR Design for Scalable Resequencing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Section D: &lt;em&gt;Primer Design for qPCR&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chapter 12&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/uploads/34773622.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Identification of Gene Copy Number in the Transgenic Plants by Quantitative Polymerase Chain Reaction (qPCR)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chapter 13&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/uploads/34773623.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;qPrimerDB: A Powerful and User-Friendly Database for qPCR Primer Design&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Section E: &lt;em&gt;Primer Design for Identification of Plant and Animal Viruses&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chapter 14&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/uploads/34773624.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;PCR Primer Design for the Rapidly Evolving SARS-CoV-2 Genome&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chapter 15&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/uploads/34773625.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Universal Primers for Detection of Novel Plant Capsid-Less Viruses: Papaya Umbra-like Viruses as Examp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Section F: &lt;em&gt;Use of Software for Primer Design&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chapter 16&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/uploads/34773626.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A Guide to Using FASTPCR Software for PCR, In Silico PCR, and Oligonucleotide Analysis&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Section G: &lt;em&gt;Primer Design for Newer PCR Approaches&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chapter 17&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/uploads/34773627.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Pyrosequencing Primer Design for Forensic Biology Applications&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chapter 18&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/uploads/34773628.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Phosphate-Methylated Oligonucleotides as a Novel Primer for PCR and RT-PCR&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/books/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Books &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>scMethBank: a database for single-cell whole genome DNA methylation maps</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34570235/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34570235/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Single-cell bisulfite sequencing methods are widely used to assess epigenomic heterogeneity in cell states. Over the past few years, large amounts of data have been generated and facilitated deeper understanding of the epigenetic regulation of many key biological processes including early embryonic development, cell differentiation and tumor progression. It is an urgent need to build a functional resource platform with the massive amount of data. Here, we present scMethBank, the first open access and comprehensive database dedicated to the collection, integration, analysis and visualization of single-cell DNA methylation data and metadata. Current release of scMethBank includes processed single-cell bisulfite sequencing data and curated metadata of 8328 samples derived from 15 public single-cell datasets, involving two species (human and mouse), 29 cell types and two diseases. In summary, scMethBank aims to assist researchers who are interested in cell heterogeneity to explore and utilize whole genome methylation data at single-cell level by providing browse, search, visualization, download functions and user-friendly online tools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ALKBH7-mediated demethylation regulates mitochondrial polycistronic RNA processing</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34253897/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34253897/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Members of the mammalian AlkB family are known to mediate nucleic acid demethylation. ALKBH7, a mammalian AlkB homologue, localizes in mitochondria and affects metabolism, but its function and mechanism of action are unknown. Here we report an approach to site-specifically detect N&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;-methyladenosine (m&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;A), N&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;-methylcytidine (m&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;C), N&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;-methylguanosine (m&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;G) and N&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;,N&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;-dimethylguanosine (m&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;G) modifications simultaneously within all cellular RNAs, and discovered that human ALKBH7 demethylates m&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;G and m&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;A within mitochondrial Ile and Leu1 pre-tRNA regions, respectively, in nascent polycistronic mitochondrial RNA. We further show that ALKBH7 regulates the processing and structural dynamics of polycistronic mitochondrial RNAs. Depletion of ALKBH7 leads to increased polycistronic mitochondrial RNA processing, reduced steady-state mitochondria-encoded tRNA levels and protein translation, and notably decreased mitochondrial activity. Thus, we identify ALKBH7 as an RNA demethylase that controls nascent mitochondrial RNA processing and mitochondrial activity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arginine monomethylation by PRMT7 controls MAVS-mediated antiviral innate immunity</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34171297/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34171297/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Accurate control of innate immune responses is required to eliminate invading pathogens and simultaneously avoid autoinflammation and autoimmune diseases. Here, we demonstrate that arginine monomethylation precisely regulates the mitochondrial antiviral-signaling protein (MAVS)-mediated antiviral response. Protein arginine methyltransferase 7 (PRMT7) forms aggregates to catalyze MAVS monomethylation at arginine residue 52 (R52), attenuating its binding to TRIM31 and RIG-I, which leads to the suppression of MAVS aggregation and subsequent activation. Upon virus infection, aggregated PRMT7 is disabled in a timely manner due to automethylation at arginine residue 32 (R32), and SMURF1 is recruited to PRMT7 by MAVS to induce proteasomal degradation of PRMT7, resulting in the relief of PRMT7 suppression of MAVS activation. Therefore, we not only reveal that arginine monomethylation by PRMT7 negatively regulates MAVS-mediated antiviral signaling in vitro and in vivo but also uncover a mechanism by which PRMT7 is tightly controlled to ensure the timely activation of antiviral defense.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>miRNA-mediated loss of m6A increases nascent translation in glioblastoma</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33684100/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33684100/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Within the glioblastoma cellular niche, glioma stem cells (GSCs) can give rise to differentiated glioma cells (DGCs) and, when necessary, DGCs can reciprocally give rise to GSCs to maintain the cellular equilibrium necessary for optimal tumor growth. Here, using ribosome profiling, transcriptome and m&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;A RNA sequencing, we show that GSCs from patients with different subtypes of glioblastoma share a set of transcripts, which exhibit a pattern of m&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;A loss and increased protein translation during differentiation. The target sequences of a group of miRNAs overlap the canonical RRACH m&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;A motifs of these transcripts, many of which confer a survival advantage in glioblastoma. Ectopic expression of the RRACH-binding miR-145 induces loss of m&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;A, formation of FTO/AGO1/ILF3/miR-145 complexes on a clinically relevant tumor suppressor gene (CLIP3) and significant increase in its nascent translation. Inhibition of miR-145 maintains RRACH m&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;A levels of CLIP3 and inhibits its nascent translation. This study highlights a critical role of miRNAs in assembling complexes for m&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;A demethylation and induction of protein translation during GSC state transition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>N6-methyladenine is incorporated into mammalian genome by DNA polymerase</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32355286/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32355286/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Erratum in:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Author Correction: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nature.com/articles/s41422-020-0339-0&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;N&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;-methyladenine is incorporated into mammalian genome by DNA polymerase&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No abstract available&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Homeobox oncogene activation by pan-cancer DNA hypermethylation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/30097071/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/30097071/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Cancers have long been recognized to be not only genetically but also epigenetically distinct from their tissues of origin. Although genetic alterations underlying oncogene upregulation have been well studied, to what extent epigenetic mechanisms, such as DNA methylation, can also induce oncogene expression remains unknown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; Here, through pan-cancer analysis of 4174 genome-wide profiles, including whole-genome bisulfite sequencing data from 30 normal tissues and 35 solid tumors, we discover a strong correlation between gene-body hypermethylation of DNA methylation canyons, defined as broad under-methylated regions, and overexpression of approximately 43% of homeobox genes, many of which are also oncogenes. To gain insights into the cause-and-effect relationship, we use a newly developed dCas9-SunTag-DNMT3A system to methylate genomic sites of interest. The locus-specific hypermethylation of gene-body canyon, but not promoter, of homeobox oncogene DLX1, can directly increase its gene expression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; Our pan-cancer analysis followed by functional validation reveals DNA hypermethylation as a novel epigenetic mechanism for homeobox oncogene upregulation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Short-term exposure to fine particulate air pollution and genome-wide DNA methylation: A randomized, double-blind, crossover trial</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/30081103/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/30081103/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Previous studies have associated fine particulate (PM&lt;sub&gt;2.5&lt;/sub&gt;) exposure with changes in gene-specific DNA methylation. However, the evidence was still limited and inconsistent in genome-wide DNA methylation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Objective:&lt;/em&gt; To examine the impact of short-term PM&lt;sub&gt;2.5&lt;/sub&gt; exposure on genome-wide DNA methylation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; We designed a randomized, double-blind, crossover trial among 36 healthy young adults in Shanghai, China. A two-stage intervention with alternative use of real and sham air purifiers in dormitory rooms for consecutive 9 days were conducted to create natural low and high exposure scenarios of PM&lt;sub&gt;2.5&lt;/sub&gt;. Blood genome-wide DNA methylation was analyzed using the Illumina Infinium Human Methylation EPIC BeadChip (850k). Mixed-effect models were used to evaluate the impacts of changes in PM&lt;sub&gt;2.5&lt;/sub&gt; levels on genome-wide DNA methylation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; There was a drastic contrast for PM&lt;sub&gt;2.5&lt;/sub&gt; exposure levels in the two scenarios (24-h averages: 53.1 and 24.3 μg/m&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;). Between the high and low exposure groups, methylation levels were changed significantly with a false discovery rate &amp;lt; 0.01 at 49 CpG loci, of which 31 CpG sites were annotated to the specific genes. DNA methylation of these annotated genes were elevated in response to increased PM&lt;sub&gt;2.5&lt;/sub&gt; exposure, which were implicated in insulin resistance, glucose and lipid metabolism, inflammation, oxidative stress, platelet activation, and cell survival and apoptosis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; Our results provided novel biological pathways linking ambient PM&lt;sub&gt;2.5&lt;/sub&gt; exposure to systemic adverse response through variations in DNA methylation and reinforced the hypothesized role of epigenetics in the development of cardiometabolic diseases induced by PM&lt;sub&gt;2.5&lt;/sub&gt; exposure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
