<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Adipose | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/adipose/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/adipose/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Adipose</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Adipose</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/adipose/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transcriptomic profiling reveals sex-specific molecular signatures of adipose endothelial cells under obesogenic conditions</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36624843/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36624843/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Female mice display greater adipose angiogenesis and maintain healthier adipose tissue than do males upon high-fat diet feeding. Through transcriptome analysis of endothelial cells (EC) from the white adipose tissue of male and female mice high-fat-fed for 7 weeks, we found that adipose EC exhibited pronouncedly sex-distinct transcriptomes. Genes upregulated in female adipose EC were associated with proliferation, oxidative phosphorylation, and chromatin remodeling contrasting the dominant enrichment for genes related to inflammation and a senescence-associated secretory of male EC. Similar sex-biased phenotypes of adipose EC were detectable in a dataset of aged EC. The highly proliferative phenotype of female EC was observed also in culture conditions. In turn, male EC displayed greater inflammatory potential than female EC in culture, based on basal and tumor necrosis factor alpha-stimulated patterns of gene expression. Our study provides insights into molecular programs that distinguish male and female EC responses to pathophysiological conditions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Light modulates glucose metabolism by a retina-hypothalamus-brown adipose tissue axis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36669474/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36669474/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Photoreception of ipRGCs mediates light modulation of glucose tolerance (GT) in mice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hypothalamic supraoptic nucleus is essential for light modulation of GT in mice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Light modulates GT via a neuro circuit that alters adaptive thermogenesis in mice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Light modulates human GT at the temperature where brown adipose tissue is active&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Public health studies indicate that artificial light is a high-risk factor for metabolic disorders. However, the neural mechanism underlying metabolic modulation by light remains elusive. Here, we found that light can acutely decrease glucose tolerance (GT) in mice by activation of intrinsically photosensitive retinal ganglion cells (ipRGCs) innervating the hypothalamic supraoptic nucleus (SON). Vasopressin neurons in the SON project to the paraventricular nucleus, then to the GABAergic neurons in the solitary tract nucleus, and eventually to brown adipose tissue (BAT). Light activation of this neural circuit directly blocks adaptive thermogenesis in BAT, thereby decreasing GT. In humans, light also modulates GT at the temperature where BAT is active. Thus, our work unveils a retina-SON-BAT axis that mediates the effect of light on glucose metabolism, which may explain the connection between artificial light and metabolic dysregulation, suggesting a potential prevention and treatment strategy for managing glucose metabolic disorders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>High yield engineered nanovesicles from ADSC with enriched miR-21-5p promote angiogenesis in adipose tissue regeneration</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36528594/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36528594/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Mesenchymal stem cell-derived extracellular vesicles (MSC-EVs) have been found to have a great potential for soft tissue repair due to various biological functions, including pro-angiogenesis and low immunogenicity. However, the low yield and heterogeneity of MSC-EVs limited their clinical transformation. This study was designed to develop a novel adipose-derived stem cell engineered nanovesicles (ADSC-NVs) with high production and explore its pro-angiogenetic effect and application in adipose tissue regeneration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; Adipose-derived stem cell-derived extracellular vesicles (ADSC-EVs) were isolated from an EVs-free culture medium for human ADSCs (hADSCs). ADSC-NVs were prepared by sequentially extruding ADSCs followed by iodixanol density gradient ultracentrifugation and were compared with ADSC-EVs in morphology, size distribution, protein contents and yield. The pro-angiogenetic effect of ADSC-NVs in different doses (0, 5, 20 and 80 μg/mL) in vitro was determined using transwell assay, tube formation assay, western blot and qRT-PCR. In vivo, BALB/c nude mice were administered injection of a mixture of fat granules and different dose of ADSC-NVs and grafts were harvested at 12 weeks post-transplantation for further analysis. By analyzing the weight and volume of grafts and histological evaluation, we investigated the effect of ADSC-NVs in vessel formation and adipose tissue regeneration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; Our results showed yield of purified ADSC-NVs was approximately 20 times more than that of ADSC-EVs secreted by the same number of ADSCs. In vitro, both ADSC-NVs and ADSC-EVs exhibited a dose-dependent pro-angiogenetic effect, despite their distinct miRNA profiles. These effects of ADSC-NVs may be mediated by enriched miR-21-5p via PTEN inhibition and PI3K/p-Akt signaling activation. Furthermore, after a mixed injection of ADSC-NVs, vessel formation and adipose regeneration were observed in vivo in fat implants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; Our study developed a potent alternative of ADSC-EVs. ADSC-NVs have a high pro-angiogenesis potential and can be used as cell-free therapeutic biomaterials in soft tissue regeneration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
