<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blood-Brain Barrier | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/blood-brain-barrier/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/blood-brain-barrier/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Blood-Brain Barrier</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Blood-Brain Barrier</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/blood-brain-barrier/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blood-brain barrier Permeable nanoparticles for Alzheimer&#39;s disease treatment by selective mitophagy of microglia</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35965114/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35965114/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Current treatments for Alzheimer&amp;rsquo;s disease (AD) that focus on inhibition of Aβ aggregation failed to show effectiveness in people who already had Alzheimer&amp;rsquo;s symptoms. Strategies that synergistically exert neuroprotection and alleviation of oxidative stress could be a promising approach to correct the pathological brain microenvironment. Based on the key roles of microglia in modulation of AD microenvironment, we describe here the development of Prussian blue/polyamidoamine (PAMAM) dendrimer/Angiopep-2 (PPA) nanoparticles that can regulate the mitophagy of microglia as a potential AD treatment. PPA nanoparticles exhibit superior blood-brain barrier (BBB) permeability and exert synergistic effects of ROS scavenging and restoration of mitochondrial function of microglia. PPA nanoparticles effectively reduce neurotoxic Aβ aggregate and rescue the cognitive functions in APP/PS1 model mice. Together, our data suggest that these multifunctional dendrimer nanoparticles exhibit efficient neuroprotection and microglia modulation and can be exploited as a promising approach for the treatment of AD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
