<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blood-Brain Barrier | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/blood-brain-barrier/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/blood-brain-barrier/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Blood-Brain Barrier</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Blood-Brain Barrier</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/blood-brain-barrier/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mitochondria-containing extracellular vesicles (EV) reduce mouse brain infarct sizes and EV/HSP27 protect ischemic brain endothelial cultures</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36642252/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36642252/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ischemic stroke causes brain endothelial cell (BEC) death and damages tight junction integrity of the blood-brain barrier (BBB). We harnessed the innate mitochondrial load of BEC-derived extracellular vesicles (EVs) and utilized mixtures of EV/exogenous 27 kDa heat shock protein (HSP27) as a one-two punch strategy to increase BEC survival (via EV mitochondria) and preserve their tight junction integrity (via HSP27 effects). We demonstrated that the medium-to-large (m/lEV) but not small EVs (sEV) transferred their mitochondrial load, that subsequently colocalized with the mitochondrial network of the recipient primary human BECs. Recipient BECs treated with m/lEVs showed increased relative ATP levels and mitochondrial function. To determine if the m/lEV-meditated increase in recipient BEC ATP levels was associated with m/lEV mitochondria, we isolated m/lEVs from donor BECs pre-treated with oligomycin A (OGM, mitochondria electron transport complex V inhibitor), referred to as OGM-m/lEVs. BECs treated with naïve m/lEVs showed a significant increase in ATP levels compared to untreated OGD cells, OGM-m/lEVs treated BECs showed a loss of ATP levels suggesting that the m/lEV-mediated increase in ATP levels is likely a function of their innate mitochondrial load. In contrast, sEV-mediated ATP increases were not affected by inhibition of mitochondrial function in the donor BECs. Intravenously administered m/lEVs showed a reduction in brain infarct sizes compared to vehicle-injected mice in a mouse middle cerebral artery occlusion model of ischemic stroke. We formulated binary mixtures of human recombinant HSP27 protein with EVs: EV/HSP27 and ternary mixtures of HSP27 and EVs with a cationic polymer, poly (ethylene glycol)-b-poly (diethyltriamine): (PEG-DET/HSP27)/EV. (PEG-DET/HSP27)/EV and EV/HSP27 mixtures decreased the paracellular permeability of small and large molecular mass fluorescent tracers in oxygen glucose-deprived primary human BECs. This one-two punch approach to increase BEC metabolic function and tight junction integrity may be a promising strategy for BBB protection and prevention of long-term neurological dysfunction post-ischemic stroke.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Photoacoustic Probe with Blood-Brain Barrier Crossing Ability for Imaging Oxidative Stress Dynamics in the Mouse Brain</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36597890/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36597890/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spatiotemporal assessment of the oxidative stress dynamics in the brain is crucial for understanding the molecular mechanism underlying neurodegenerative diseases. However, existing oxidative stress probes have poor blood-brain barrier permeability or poor penetration depth, making them unsuitable for brain imaging. Herein, we developed a photoacoustic probe that enables real-time imaging of oxidative stress dynamics in the mouse brain. The probe not only responds to oxidative stress in a reversible and ratiometric manner, but it can also cross the blood-brain barrier of the mouse brain. Notably, the probe displayed excellent photoacoustic imaging of oxidative stress dynamics in the brains of Parkinson&amp;rsquo;s disease mouse models. In addition, we investigated the antioxidant properties of natural polyphenols in the brain of a Parkinson&amp;rsquo;s disease mouse model using the probe as an imaging agent and suggested the potential of the probe for screening anti-oxidative stress agents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Circulating Proteins Influencing Psychiatric Disease: A Mendelian Randomization Study</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36280454/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36280454/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; There is a pressing need for novel drug targets for psychiatric disorders. Circulating proteins are potential candidates because they are relatively easy to measure and modulate and play important roles in signaling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; We performed two-sample Mendelian randomization analyses to estimate the associations between circulating protein abundances and risk of 10 psychiatric disorders. Genetic variants associated with 1611 circulating protein abundances identified in 6 large-scale proteomic studies were used as genetic instruments. Effects of the circulating proteins on psychiatric disorders were estimated by Wald ratio or inverse variance-weighted ratio tests. Horizontal pleiotropy, colocalization, and protein-altering effects were examined to validate the assumptions of Mendelian randomization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; Nine circulating protein-to-disease associations withstood multiple sensitivity analyses. Among them, 2 circulating proteins had associations replicated in 3 proteomic studies. A 1 standard deviation increase in the genetically predicted circulating TIMP4 level was associated with a reduced risk of anorexia nervosa (minimum odds ratio [OR] = 0.83; 95% CI, 0.76-0.91) and bipolar disorder (minimum OR = 0.88; 95% CI, 0.82-0.94). A 1 standard deviation increase in the genetically predicted circulating ESAM level was associated with an increased risk of schizophrenia (maximum OR = 1.32; 95% CI, 1.22-1.43). In addition, 58 suggestive protein-to-disease associations warrant validation with observational or experimental evidence. For instance, a 1 standard deviation increase in the ERLEC1-201-to-ERLEC1-202 splice variant ratio was associated with a reduced risk of schizophrenia (OR = 0.94; 95% CI, 0.90-0.97).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; Prioritized circulating proteins appear to influence the risk of psychiatric disease and may be explored as intervention targets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exosomal miR-532-5p induced by long-term exercise rescues blood-brain barrier function in 5XFAD mice via downregulation of EPHA4</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36494892/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36494892/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The breakdown of the blood-brain barrier, which develops early in Alzheimer&amp;rsquo;s disease (AD), contributes to cognitive impairment. Exercise not only reduces the risk factors for AD but also confers direct protection against cognitive decline. However, the exact molecular mechanisms remain elusive, particularly whether exercise can liberate the function of the blood-brain barrier. Here, we demonstrate that long-term exercise promotes the clearance of brain amyloid-β by improving the function of the blood-brain barrier in 5XFAD mice. Significantly, treating primary brain pericytes or endothelial cells with exosomes isolated from the brain of exercised 5XFAD mice improves cell proliferation and upregulates PDGFRβ, ZO-1, and claudin-5. Moreover, exosomes isolated from exercised mice exhibit significant changes in miR-532-5p. Administration or transfection of miR-532-5p to sedentary mice or primary brain pericytes and endothelial cells reproduces the improvement of blood-brain barrier function. Exosomal miR-532-5p targets EPHA4, and accordingly, expression of EphA4 is decreased in exercised mice and miR-532-5p overexpressed mice. A specific siRNA targeting EPHA4 recapitulates the effects on blood-brain barrier-associated cells observed in exercised 5XFAD mice. Overall, our findings suggest that exosomes released by the brain contain a specific miRNA that is altered by exercise and has an impact on blood-brain barrier function in AD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blood-brain barrier Permeable nanoparticles for Alzheimer&#39;s disease treatment by selective mitophagy of microglia</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35965114/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35965114/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Current treatments for Alzheimer&amp;rsquo;s disease (AD) that focus on inhibition of Aβ aggregation failed to show effectiveness in people who already had Alzheimer&amp;rsquo;s symptoms. Strategies that synergistically exert neuroprotection and alleviation of oxidative stress could be a promising approach to correct the pathological brain microenvironment. Based on the key roles of microglia in modulation of AD microenvironment, we describe here the development of Prussian blue/polyamidoamine (PAMAM) dendrimer/Angiopep-2 (PPA) nanoparticles that can regulate the mitophagy of microglia as a potential AD treatment. PPA nanoparticles exhibit superior blood-brain barrier (BBB) permeability and exert synergistic effects of ROS scavenging and restoration of mitochondrial function of microglia. PPA nanoparticles effectively reduce neurotoxic Aβ aggregate and rescue the cognitive functions in APP/PS1 model mice. Together, our data suggest that these multifunctional dendrimer nanoparticles exhibit efficient neuroprotection and microglia modulation and can be exploited as a promising approach for the treatment of AD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An oxygen-adaptive interaction between SNHG12 and occludin maintains blood-brain barrier integrity</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35417709/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35417709/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;lncRNA SNHG12 is critical for maintaining the blood-brain barrier (BBB) integrity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Oxygen levels regulate SNHG12 interaction with occludin to maintain BBB integrity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Endothelium Snhg12 knockout aggravates hypoxia-induced occludin degradation in mice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Endothelium SNHG12 overexpression alleviates hypoxia-induced BBB disruption in mice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tight junctions (TJs) of brain microvascular endothelial cells (BMECs) play a pivotal role in maintaining the blood-brain barrier (BBB) integrity; however, precise regulation of TJs stability in response to physiological and pathological stimuli remains elusive. Here, using RNA immunoprecipitation with next-generation sequencing (RIP-seq) and functional characterization, we identify SNHG12, a long non-coding RNA (lncRNA), as being critical for maintaining the BBB integrity by directly interacting with TJ protein occludin. The interaction between SNHG12 and occludin is oxygen adaptive and could block Itch (an E3 ubiquitin ligase)-mediated ubiquitination and degradation of occludin in human BMECs. Genetic ablation of endothelial Snhg12 in mice results in occludin reduction and BBB leakage and significantly aggravates hypoxia-induced BBB disruption. The detrimental effects of hypoxia on BBB could be alleviated by exogenous SNHG12 overexpression in brain endothelium. Together, we identify a direct TJ modulator lncRNA SNHG12 that is critical for the BBB integrity maintenance and oxygen adaption.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neutrophil-vascular interactions drive myeloperoxidase accumulation in the brain in Alzheimer&#39;s disease</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35331340/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35331340/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Introduction:&lt;/em&gt; Neutrophil accumulation is a well-established feature of Alzheimer&amp;rsquo;s disease (AD) and has been linked to cognitive impairment by modulating disease-relevant neuroinflammatory and vascular pathways. Neutrophils express high levels of the oxidant-generating enzyme myeloperoxidase (MPO), however there has been controversy regarding the cellular source and localisation of MPO in the AD brain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Materials and methods:&lt;/em&gt; We used immunostaining and immunoassays to quantify the accumulation of neutrophils in human AD tissue microarrays and in the brains of APP/PS1 mice. We also used multiplexed immunolabelling to define the presence of NETs in AD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; There was an increase in neutrophils in AD brains as well as in the murine APP/PS1 model of AD. Indeed, MPO expression was almost exclusively confined to S100A8-positive neutrophils in both human AD and murine APP/PS1 brains. The vascular localisation of neutrophils in both human AD and mouse models of AD was striking and driven by enhanced neutrophil adhesion to small vessels. We also observed rare infiltrating neutrophils and deposits of MPO around plaques. Citrullinated histone H3, a marker of neutrophil extracellular traps (NETs), was also detected in human AD cases at these sites, indicating the presence of extracellular MPO in the vasculature. Finally, there was a reduction in the endothelial glycocalyx in AD that may be responsible for non-productive neutrophil adhesion to the vasculature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/em&gt; Our report indicates that vascular changes may drive neutrophil adhesion and NETosis, and that neutrophil-derived MPO may lead to vascular oxidative stress and be a relevant therapeutic target in AD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The role of S100B/RAGE-enhanced ADAM17 activation in endothelial glycocalyx shedding after traumatic brain injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35148784/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35148784/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Traumatic brain injury (TBI) remains one of the main causes for disability and death worldwide. While the primary mechanical injury cannot be avoided, the prevention of secondary injury is the focus of TBI research. Present study aimed to elucidate the effects and mechanisms of S100B and its receptor RAGE on mediating secondary injury after TBI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; This study established TBI animal model by fluid percussion injury in rats, cell model by stretch-injured in astrocytes, and endothelial injury model with conditioned medium stimulation. Pharmacological intervention was applied to interfere the activities of S100B/RAGE/ADAM17 signaling pathway, respectively. The expressions or contents of S100B, RAGE, syndecan-1 and ADAM17 in brain and serum, as well as in cultured cells and medium, were detected by western blot. The distribution of relative molecules was observed with immunofluorescence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; We found that TBI could activate the release of S100B, mostly from astrocytes, and S100B and RAGE could mutually regulate their expression and activation. Most importantly, present study revealed an obvious increase of syndecan-1 in rat serum or in endothelial cultured medium after injury, and a significant decrease in tissue and in cultured endothelial cells, indicating TBI-induced shedding of endothelial glycocalyx. The data further proved that the activation of S100B/RAGE signaling could promote the shedding of endothelial glycocalyx by enhancing the expression, translocation and activity of ADAM17, an important sheddase, in endothelial cells. The damage of endothelial glycocalyx consequently aggravated blood brain barrier (BBB) dysfunction and systemic vascular hyper-permeability, overall resulting in secondary brain and lung injury.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; TBI triggers the activation of S100B/RAGE signal pathway. The regulation S100B/RAGE on ADAM17 expression, translocation and activation further promotes the shedding of endothelial glycocalyx, aggravates the dysfunction of BBB, and increases the vascular permeability, leading to secondary brain and lung injury. Present study may open a new corridor for the more in-depth understanding of the molecular processes responsible for cerebral and systemic vascular barrier impairment and secondary injury after TBI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
