<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blood-Brain Barrier | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/blood-brain-barrier/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/blood-brain-barrier/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Blood-Brain Barrier</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Blood-Brain Barrier</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/blood-brain-barrier/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blood-brain barrier Permeable nanoparticles for Alzheimer&#39;s disease treatment by selective mitophagy of microglia</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35965114/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35965114/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Current treatments for Alzheimer&amp;rsquo;s disease (AD) that focus on inhibition of Aβ aggregation failed to show effectiveness in people who already had Alzheimer&amp;rsquo;s symptoms. Strategies that synergistically exert neuroprotection and alleviation of oxidative stress could be a promising approach to correct the pathological brain microenvironment. Based on the key roles of microglia in modulation of AD microenvironment, we describe here the development of Prussian blue/polyamidoamine (PAMAM) dendrimer/Angiopep-2 (PPA) nanoparticles that can regulate the mitophagy of microglia as a potential AD treatment. PPA nanoparticles exhibit superior blood-brain barrier (BBB) permeability and exert synergistic effects of ROS scavenging and restoration of mitochondrial function of microglia. PPA nanoparticles effectively reduce neurotoxic Aβ aggregate and rescue the cognitive functions in APP/PS1 model mice. Together, our data suggest that these multifunctional dendrimer nanoparticles exhibit efficient neuroprotection and microglia modulation and can be exploited as a promising approach for the treatment of AD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An oxygen-adaptive interaction between SNHG12 and occludin maintains blood-brain barrier integrity</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35417709/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35417709/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;lncRNA SNHG12 is critical for maintaining the blood-brain barrier (BBB) integrity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Oxygen levels regulate SNHG12 interaction with occludin to maintain BBB integrity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Endothelium Snhg12 knockout aggravates hypoxia-induced occludin degradation in mice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Endothelium SNHG12 overexpression alleviates hypoxia-induced BBB disruption in mice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tight junctions (TJs) of brain microvascular endothelial cells (BMECs) play a pivotal role in maintaining the blood-brain barrier (BBB) integrity; however, precise regulation of TJs stability in response to physiological and pathological stimuli remains elusive. Here, using RNA immunoprecipitation with next-generation sequencing (RIP-seq) and functional characterization, we identify SNHG12, a long non-coding RNA (lncRNA), as being critical for maintaining the BBB integrity by directly interacting with TJ protein occludin. The interaction between SNHG12 and occludin is oxygen adaptive and could block Itch (an E3 ubiquitin ligase)-mediated ubiquitination and degradation of occludin in human BMECs. Genetic ablation of endothelial Snhg12 in mice results in occludin reduction and BBB leakage and significantly aggravates hypoxia-induced BBB disruption. The detrimental effects of hypoxia on BBB could be alleviated by exogenous SNHG12 overexpression in brain endothelium. Together, we identify a direct TJ modulator lncRNA SNHG12 that is critical for the BBB integrity maintenance and oxygen adaption.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neutrophil-vascular interactions drive myeloperoxidase accumulation in the brain in Alzheimer&#39;s disease</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35331340/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35331340/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Introduction:&lt;/em&gt; Neutrophil accumulation is a well-established feature of Alzheimer&amp;rsquo;s disease (AD) and has been linked to cognitive impairment by modulating disease-relevant neuroinflammatory and vascular pathways. Neutrophils express high levels of the oxidant-generating enzyme myeloperoxidase (MPO), however there has been controversy regarding the cellular source and localisation of MPO in the AD brain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Materials and methods:&lt;/em&gt; We used immunostaining and immunoassays to quantify the accumulation of neutrophils in human AD tissue microarrays and in the brains of APP/PS1 mice. We also used multiplexed immunolabelling to define the presence of NETs in AD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; There was an increase in neutrophils in AD brains as well as in the murine APP/PS1 model of AD. Indeed, MPO expression was almost exclusively confined to S100A8-positive neutrophils in both human AD and murine APP/PS1 brains. The vascular localisation of neutrophils in both human AD and mouse models of AD was striking and driven by enhanced neutrophil adhesion to small vessels. We also observed rare infiltrating neutrophils and deposits of MPO around plaques. Citrullinated histone H3, a marker of neutrophil extracellular traps (NETs), was also detected in human AD cases at these sites, indicating the presence of extracellular MPO in the vasculature. Finally, there was a reduction in the endothelial glycocalyx in AD that may be responsible for non-productive neutrophil adhesion to the vasculature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/em&gt; Our report indicates that vascular changes may drive neutrophil adhesion and NETosis, and that neutrophil-derived MPO may lead to vascular oxidative stress and be a relevant therapeutic target in AD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
