<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ion Channel | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/ion-channel/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/ion-channel/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Ion Channel</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Ion Channel</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/ion-channel/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Suppression of PD-L1 release from small extracellular vesicles promotes systemic anti-tumor immunity by targeting ORAI1 calcium channels</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36482876/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36482876/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blockade of immune checkpoints as a strategy of cancer cells to overcome the immune response has received ample attention in cancer research recently. In particular, expression of PD-L1 by various cancer cells has become a paradigm in this respect. Delivery of PD-L1 to its site of action occurs either by local diffusion, or else by transport via small extracellular vesicles (sEVs, commonly referred to as exosomes). Many steps of sEVs formation, their packaging with PD-L1 and their release into the extracellular space have been studied in detail. The likely dependence of release on Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt;-signaling, however, has received little attention. This is surprising, since the intracellular Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt;-concentration is known as a prominent regulator of many secretory processes. Here, we report on the roles of three Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt;-dependent proteins in regulating release of PD-L1-containing sEVs, as well as on the growth of tumors in mouse models. We show that sEVs release in cancer cell lines is Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt;-dependent and the knockdown of the gene coding the Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt;-channel protein ORAI1 reduces Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt;-signals and release of sEVs. Consequently, the T cell response is reinvigorated and tumor progression in mouse models is retarded. Furthermore, analysis of protein expression patterns in samples from human cancer tissue shows that the ORAI1 gene is significantly upregulated. Such upregulation is identified as an unfavorable prognostic factor for survival of patients with non-small-cell lung cancer. We show that reduced Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt;-signaling after knockdown of ORAI1 gene also compromises the activity of melanophilin and Synaptotagmin-like protein 2, two proteins, which are important for correct localization of secretory organelles within cancer cells and their transport to sites of exocytosis. Thus, the Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt;-channel ORAI1 and Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt;-dependent proteins of the secretion pathway emerge as important targets for understanding and manipulating immune checkpoint blockade by PD-L1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
