<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ion Channel | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/ion-channel/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/ion-channel/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Ion Channel</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Ion Channel</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/ion-channel/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>DNA topoisomerase 2-associated proteins PATL1 and PATL2 regulate the biogenesis of hERG K&#43; channels</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36608291/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36608291/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The human ether-a-go-go-related gene (hERG) K&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; channel conducts a rapidly activating delayed rectifier K&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; current (I&lt;sub&gt;Kr&lt;/sub&gt;), which is essential for normal electrical activity of the heart. Precise regulation of hERG channel biogenesis is critical for serving its physiological functions, and deviations from the regulation result in human diseases. However, the mechanism underlying the precise regulation of hERG channel biogenesis remains elusive. Here, by using forward genetic screen, we found that PATR-1, the &lt;em&gt;Caenorhabditis elegans&lt;/em&gt; homolog of the yeast DNA topoisomerase 2-associated protein PAT1, is a critical regulator for the biogenesis of UNC-103, the ERG K&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; channel in &lt;em&gt;C. elegans&lt;/em&gt;. A loss-of-function mutation in patr-1 down-regulates the expression level of UNC-103 proteins and suppresses the phenotypic defects resulted from a gain-of-function mutation in the unc-103 gene. Furthermore, downregulation of PATL1 and PATL2, the human homologs of PAT1, decreases protein levels and the current density of native hERG channels in SH-SY5Y cells and human-induced pluripotent stem cell-derived cardiomyocytes (hiPSC-CMs). Knockdown of PATL1 and PATL2 elongates the duration of action potentials in hiPSC-CMs, suggesting that PATL1 and PATL2 affect the function of hERG channels and hence electrophysiological characteristics in the human heart. Further studies found that PATL1 and PATL2 interact with TFIIE, a general transcription factor required for forming the RNA polymerase II preinitiation complex, and dual-luciferase reporter assays indicated that PATL1 and PATL2 facilitate the transcription of hERG mRNAs. Together, our study discovers that evolutionarily conserved DNA topoisomerase 2-associated proteins regulate the biogenesis of hERG channels via a transcriptional mechanism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The sodium channel subunit SCNN1B suppresses colorectal cancer via suppression of active c-Raf and MAPK signaling cascade</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36564468/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36564468/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The incidence of colorectal cancer (CRC) is rising worldwide. Here, we identified SCNN1B as an outlier down-regulated in CRC and it functions as a tumor suppressor. SCNN1B mRNA and protein expression were down-regulated in primary CRC and CRC cells. In a tissue microarray cohort (N = 153), SCNN1B protein was an independent prognostic factor for favorable outcomes in CRC. Ectopic expression of SCNN1B in CRC cell lines suppressed cell proliferation, induced apoptosis, and cell cycle arrest, and suppressed cell migration in vitro. Xenograft models validated tumor suppressive function of SCNN1B in vivo. Mechanistically, Gene Set Enrichment Analysis (GSEA) showed that SCNN1B correlates with KRAS signaling. Consistently, MAPK qPCR and kinase arrays revealed that SCNN1B suppressed MAPK signaling. In particular, SCNN1B overexpression suppressed p-MEK/p-ERK expression and SRE-mediated transcription activities, confirming blockade of Ras-Raf-MEK-ERK cascade. Mechanistically, SCNN1B did not affect KRAS activation, instead impairing activation of c-Raf by inducing its inhibitory phosphorylation and targeting active c-Raf for degradation. The ectopic expression of c-Raf fully rescued cell proliferation and colony formation in SCNN1B-overexpressing CRC cells, confirming c-Raf as the principal molecular target of SCNN1B. In summary, we identified SCNN1B as a tumor suppressor by functioning as a c-Raf antagonist, which in turn suppressed oncogenic MEK-ERK signaling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emerging roles of mechanosensitive ion channels in acute lung injury/acute respiratory distress syndrome</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/36539808/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/36539808/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acute lung injury/acute respiratory distress syndrome (ALI/ARDS) is a devastating respiratory disorder with high rates of mortality and morbidity, but the detailed underlying mechanisms of ALI/ARDS remain largely unknown. Mechanosensitive ion channels (MSCs), including epithelial sodium channel (ENaC), Piezo channels, transient receptor potential channels (TRPs), and two-pore domain potassium ion (K2P) channels, are highly expressed in lung tissues, and the activity of these MSCs can be modulated by mechanical forces (e.g., mechanical ventilation) and other stimuli (e.g., LPS, hyperoxia). Dysfunction of MSCs has been found in various types of ALI/ARDS, and MSCs play a key role in regulating alveolar fluid clearance, alveolar epithelial/endothelial barrier function, the inflammatory response and surfactant secretion in ALI/ARDS lungs. Targeting MSCs exerts therapeutic effects in the treatment of ALI/ARDS. In this review, we summarize the structure and functions of several well-recognized MSCs, the role of MSCs in the pathogenesis of ALI/ARDS and recent advances in the pharmacological and molecular modulation of MSCs in the treatment of ALI/ARDS. According to the current literature, targeting MSCs might be a very promising therapeutic approach against ALI/ARDS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Suppression of PD-L1 release from small extracellular vesicles promotes systemic anti-tumor immunity by targeting ORAI1 calcium channels</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36482876/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36482876/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blockade of immune checkpoints as a strategy of cancer cells to overcome the immune response has received ample attention in cancer research recently. In particular, expression of PD-L1 by various cancer cells has become a paradigm in this respect. Delivery of PD-L1 to its site of action occurs either by local diffusion, or else by transport via small extracellular vesicles (sEVs, commonly referred to as exosomes). Many steps of sEVs formation, their packaging with PD-L1 and their release into the extracellular space have been studied in detail. The likely dependence of release on Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt;-signaling, however, has received little attention. This is surprising, since the intracellular Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt;-concentration is known as a prominent regulator of many secretory processes. Here, we report on the roles of three Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt;-dependent proteins in regulating release of PD-L1-containing sEVs, as well as on the growth of tumors in mouse models. We show that sEVs release in cancer cell lines is Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt;-dependent and the knockdown of the gene coding the Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt;-channel protein ORAI1 reduces Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt;-signals and release of sEVs. Consequently, the T cell response is reinvigorated and tumor progression in mouse models is retarded. Furthermore, analysis of protein expression patterns in samples from human cancer tissue shows that the ORAI1 gene is significantly upregulated. Such upregulation is identified as an unfavorable prognostic factor for survival of patients with non-small-cell lung cancer. We show that reduced Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt;-signaling after knockdown of ORAI1 gene also compromises the activity of melanophilin and Synaptotagmin-like protein 2, two proteins, which are important for correct localization of secretory organelles within cancer cells and their transport to sites of exocytosis. Thus, the Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt;-channel ORAI1 and Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt;-dependent proteins of the secretion pathway emerge as important targets for understanding and manipulating immune checkpoint blockade by PD-L1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Liquiritigenin protects against myocardial ischemic by inhibiting oxidative stress, apoptosis, and L-type Ca2&#43; channels</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35747908/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35747908/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Liquiritigenin (Lq) offers cytoprotective effects against various cardiac injuries, but its beneficial effects on myocardial ischemic (MI) injury and the related mechanisms remain unclear. In the in vivo study, an animal model of MI was induced by intraperitoneal injection of isoproterenol (Iso, 85 mg/kg). ECG, heart rate, serum levels of CK and CK-MB, histopathological changes, and reactive oxygen species (ROS) levels were all measured. In vitro, H9c2 cells were divided into four groups and treated for 24 hr with liquiritigenin (30 μmol/L and 100 μmol/L) followed with CoCl&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; (800 μmol/L) for another 24 hr. Cell viability, apoptosis, mitochondrial membrane potential, and intracellular Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt; concentration ([Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt; ]&lt;sub&gt;i&lt;/sub&gt;) were then assessed. The L-type Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt; current (I&lt;sub&gt;Ca-L&lt;/sub&gt;) was detected using a patch clamp technique on isolated rat ventricular myocytes. The myocyte contraction and Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt; transients were measured using an IonOptix detection system. The remarkable cardiac injury and generation of intracellular ROS induced by Iso were alleviated via treatment with Lq. CoCl&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; administration induced cell apoptosis, mitochondrial dysfunction, and Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt; overload in H9c2; Lq reduces these deleterious effects of CoCl&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;. Meanwhile, Lq blocked I&lt;sub&gt;Ca-L&lt;/sub&gt; in a dose-dependent manner. The half-maximal inhibitory concentration of Lq was 110.87 μmol/L. Lq reversibly reduced the amplitude of cell contraction as well as the Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt; transients. The results show that Lq protects against MI injury by antioxidation, antiapoptosis, counteraction mitochondrial dysfunction, and inhibition of I&lt;sub&gt;Ca-L&lt;/sub&gt;, thus damping intracellular Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CaMK4 Promotes Acute Lung Injury Through NLRP3 Inflammasome Activation in Type II Alveolar Epithelial Cell</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35734175/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35734175/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Type II alveolar epithelial cell (AEC II), in addition to its roles in maintaining lung homeostasis, takes an active role in inflammatory response during acute lung injury (ALI). Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt;/calmodulin-dependent protein kinase IV (CaMK4) activated by Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt;/calmodulin signaling, has been implicated in immune responses. This study was to investigate the roles of CaMK4 in the development of ALI and the underlying mechanisms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; CaMK4 inhibitor KN-93 was used to investigate the effects of CaMK4 on NLRP3 inflammasome activation. The effects of KN-93 on disease development of lipopolysaccharide (LPS)-induced ALI were also evaluated. The role of CaMK4 on NLRP3 inflammasome activation was explored in human AEC II cell line A549 using KN-93 or CaMK4 siRNA. NLRP3 inflammasome activation was measured by histology immunofluorescence and Western blot. IL-1β and IL-18 were measured by ELISA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; Phosphorylation of CaMK4 and the expression of NLRP3 and Caspase-1 p20 were increased in the lungs of LPS-induced ALI mice, which was suppressed by KN-93 as measured by Western blot. Further, the activation of NLRP3 inflammasome was detected in AEC II from patients with acute respiratory distress syndrome (ARDS) and LPS-induced ALI mice. In vitro, inhibition or silencing CaMK4 in AEC II significantly inhibited NLRP3 inflammasome activation, resulting in reduced IL-1β production. The inhibition of NLRP3 inflammasome and decreased IL-1β/IL-18 production by KN-93 led to reduced inflammatory infiltration and ameliorated lung injury in LPS-induced ALI mice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/em&gt; CaMK4 controls the activation of NLRP3 inflammasome in AEC II during LPS-induced ALI. CaMK4 inhibition could be a novel therapeutic approach for the treatment of ALI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Non-invasive imaging of ion concentration distribution around cell spheroids by electrical impedance tomographic sensor printed on circuit board under temporal compensation by ion transport impedance model</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35671699/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35671699/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A non-invasive imaging called as PCB-EIT imaging has been proposed in order to image spatio-temporal ion concentration distribution around cell spheroids in 0.1 s of temporal resolution by a newly developed electrical impedance tomographic sensor printed on circuit board (PCB-EIT sensor). To realize the high temporal resolution in PCB-EIT imaging, the temporal compensation by the ion transport impedance model interpolating the extracted resistance of extracellular solution &lt;em&gt;R&lt;sub&gt;ex&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/em&gt; obtained from the Cole-Cole equation is employed. To confirm the performance of PCB-EIT imaging, the ion concentration distribution around three cell spheroid types (GFP type (GFPT), Histone type (HT) and wild type (WT)) which are electrically different due to green fluorescent protein expressed in cytoplasm and nucleus of MRC-5. As a result, spatio-temporal ion concentration distributions due to ion transport from cell spheroid are successfully reconstructed by PCB-EIT imaging. The images by PCB-EIT imaging are validated with those by fluorescence ratio imaging within the distribution error &lt;em&gt;ε&lt;sub&gt;dis&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/em&gt; of 0.046 ± 0.0038 in maximum. For an evaluation of the ion diffusivity &lt;em&gt;D&lt;sub&gt;m&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/em&gt; of each cell spheroid type by the mass transfer simulation based on Fick&amp;rsquo;s law, &lt;em&gt;D&lt;sub&gt;m&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/em&gt; of GFPT shows the highest value among the three cell types in the earlier time range from 4 s, while &lt;em&gt;D&lt;sub&gt;m&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/em&gt; of HT shows the highest one in the time range from 15 s, which indicates that PCB-EIT imaging is able to evaluate the ion transport characteristics of each cell type.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inhibition of BKCa channels protects neonatal hearts against myocardial ischemia and reperfusion injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35393410/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35393410/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BK&lt;sub&gt;Ca&lt;/sub&gt; channels are large-conductance calcium and voltage-activated potassium channels that are heterogeneously expressed in a wide array of cells. Activation of BK&lt;sub&gt;Ca&lt;/sub&gt; channels present in mitochondria of adult ventricular cardiomyocytes is implicated in cardioprotection against ischemia-reperfusion (IR) injury. However, the BK&lt;sub&gt;Ca&lt;/sub&gt; channel&amp;rsquo;s activity has never been detected in the plasma membrane of adult ventricular cardiomyocytes. In this study, we report the presence of the BK&lt;sub&gt;Ca&lt;/sub&gt; channel in the plasma membrane and mitochondria of neonatal murine and rodent cardiomyocytes, which protects the heart on inhibition but not activation. Furthermore, K+ currents measured in neonatal cardiomyocyte (NCM) was sensitive to iberiotoxin (IbTx), suggesting the presence of BK&lt;sub&gt;Ca&lt;/sub&gt; channels in the plasma membrane. Neonatal hearts subjected to IR when post-conditioned with NS1619 during reoxygenation increased the myocardial infarction whereas IbTx reduced the infarct size. In agreement, isolated NCM also presented increased apoptosis on treatment with NS1619 during hypoxia and reoxygenation, whereas IbTx reduced TUNEL-positive cells. In NCMs, activation of BK&lt;sub&gt;Ca&lt;/sub&gt; channels increased the intracellular reactive oxygen species post HR injury. Electrophysiological characterization of NCMs indicated that NS1619 increased the beat period, field, and action potential duration, and decreased the conduction velocity and spike amplitude. In contrast, IbTx had no impact on the electrophysiological properties of NCMs. Taken together, our data established that inhibition of plasma membrane BK&lt;sub&gt;Ca&lt;/sub&gt; channels in the NCM protects neonatal heart/cardiomyocytes from IR injury. Furthermore, the functional disparity observed towards the cardioprotective activity of BK&lt;sub&gt;Ca&lt;/sub&gt; channels in adults compared to neonatal heart could be attributed to their differential localization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
