<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Phagocytosis | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/phagocytosis/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/phagocytosis/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Phagocytosis</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Phagocytosis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/phagocytosis/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chlorogenic acid enhances alveolar macrophages phagocytosis in acute respiratory distress syndrome by activating G protein-coupled receptor 37 (GPR 37)</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36194973/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36194973/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Impaired alveolar macrophages phagocytosis can contribute to pathogenesis of acute respiratory distress syndrome (ARDS) and negatively impacts clinical outcomes. Chlorogenic acid (CGA) is a naturally occurring polyphenolic compound with potential anti-inflammatory and antioxidant bioactivities. Studies have shown that CGA plays a protective role in ARDS, however, the precise protective mechanism of CGA against ARDS, is still unclear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Purpose&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The aim of this study was to investigate whether CGA enhances alveolar macrophages phagocytosis to attenuate lung injury during ARDS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;RAW264.7 cells were stimulated with lipopolysaccharides (100 μg/ml for 24 h) and treated with CGA (100, 200, and 400 μM CGA for 1 h) to measure pro-inflammatory cytokine levels, GPR37 expression and macrophages phagocytosis. Mouse models of ARDS induced by cecal ligation and perforation (CLP) surgery were treated with CGA (100 or 200 mg/kg) to investigate lung inflammatory injury and alveolar macrophages phagocytosis. Computational modeling was performed to examine potential binding sites of G protein-coupled receptor 37 (GPR37) with CGA, and the results were validated by interfering with the binding sites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Result&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;In vitro&lt;/em&gt;, CGA notably ameliorated inflammatory response and increased phagocytosis in lipopolysaccharides-induced RAW264.7 cells. &lt;em&gt;In vivo&lt;/em&gt;, CGA administration significantly alleviated lung inflammatory injury, decreased the bacteria load in the lung, promoted alveolar macrophages phagocytosis and improved the survival rate in mice with CLP-induced ARDS. Moreover, CGA markedly upregulated the expression of GPR37 &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;in vitro&lt;/em&gt;. However, the protective effect of CGA against ARDS were reversed after silencing the expression of GPR37.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CGA has a protective effect against ARDS and may enhance alveolar macrophages phagocytosis and attenuate lung inflammatory injury by upregulating GPR37 expression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alveolar macrophage-derived NRP2 curtails lung injury while boosting host defense in bacterial pneumonia</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35435271/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35435271/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clearance of airway intruders by immune cells is required to resolve infectious pneumonia. However, the molecular mechanisms underlying this process remain elusive. Here, we demonstrated that alveolar macrophage (AM)-derived neuropilin 2 (NRP2) plays an essential role in controlling severe pneumonia by enhancing microbial clearance. Mice with conditional deletion of the &lt;em&gt;NRP2&lt;/em&gt; gene in AM had persistent bacteria, uncontrolled neutrophil influx, and decreased survival during &lt;em&gt;Escherichia coli&lt;/em&gt;-induced pneumonia. &lt;em&gt;In vitro&lt;/em&gt; assays demonstrated that NRP2 could bind to CD11b&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt;Ly6G&lt;sup&gt;lo/+&lt;/sup&gt; neutrophils and promote their capacities in phagocytosis and killing of bacteria, which is partially contributed to the increased expression of &lt;em&gt;TLR4&lt;/em&gt; and TNF-α. These findings collectively revealed that AM-derived NRP2 protects the lungs from unwanted injury by promoting the clearance of invading pathogens. This study might provide a promising diagnostic biomarker and therapeutic target for severe pneumonia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Squeezing in a Meal: Myosin Functions in Phagocytosis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/31836280/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/31836280/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Phagocytosis is a receptor-mediated, actin-dependent process of internalization of large extracellular particles, such as pathogens or apoptotic cells. Engulfment of phagocytic targets requires the activity of myosins, actin-dependent molecular motors, which perform a variety of functions at distinct steps during phagocytosis. By applying force to actin filaments, the plasma membrane, and intracellular proteins and organelles, myosins can generate contractility, directly regulate actin assembly to ensure proper phagocytic internalization, and translocate phagosomes or other cargo to appropriate cellular locations. Recent studies using engineered microenvironments and phagocytic targets have demonstrated how altering the actomyosin cytoskeleton affects phagocytic behavior. Here, we discuss how studies using genetic and biochemical manipulation of myosins, force measurement techniques, and live-cell imaging have advanced our understanding of how specific myosins function at individual steps of phagocytosis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
