<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Herpesvirus | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/herpesvirus/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/herpesvirus/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Herpesvirus</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Herpesvirus</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/herpesvirus/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Degradation of HDAC10 by autophagy promotes IRF3-mediated antiviral innate immune responses</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36538592/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36538592/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Histone deacetylases (HDACs) play important roles in immunity and inflammation. Through functional screening, we identified HDAC10 as an inhibitor of the type I interferon (IFN) response mediated by interferon regulatory factor 3 (IRF3). HDAC10 abundance was decreased in mouse macrophages in response to innate immune stimuli and was reduced in peripheral blood mononuclear cells (PBMCs) from patients with systemic lupus erythematosus (SLE) compared with that in PBMCs from healthy donors. Deficiency in HDAC10 in mouse embryonic fibroblasts and in mice promoted the expression of genes encoding type I IFNs and of IFN-stimulated genes (ISGs), leading to enhanced antiviral responses in vitro and in vivo. HDAC10 bound in a deacetylase-independent manner to IRF3 in uninfected cells to inhibit the phosphorylation of IRF3 at Ser&lt;sup&gt;396&lt;/sup&gt; by TANK-binding kinase 1 (TBK1). Upon viral infection, HDAC10 was targeted for autophagy-mediated degradation through its interaction with LC3-II. Consequently, IRF3 phosphorylation was increased, which resulted in enhanced type I IFN production and antiviral responses. Our findings identify a potential target for improving host defense responses against pathogen infection and for treating autoimmune disease.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Herpes Simplex Virus 1-Induced Ferroptosis Contributes to Viral Encephalitis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36507835/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36507835/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Herpes simplex virus 1 (HSV-1) is a DNA virus belonging to the family Herpesviridae. HSV-1 infection causes severe neurological disease in the central nervous system (CNS), including encephalitis. Ferroptosis is a nonapoptotic form of programmed cell death that contributes to different neurological inflammatory diseases. However, whether HSV-1 induces ferroptosis in the CNS and the role of ferroptosis in viral pathogenesis remain unclear. Here, we demonstrate that HSV-1 induces ferroptosis, as hallmarks of ferroptosis, including Fe&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt; overload, reactive oxygen species (ROS) accumulation, glutathione (GSH) depletion, lipid peroxidation, and mitochondrion shrinkage, are observed in HSV-1-infected cultured human astrocytes, microglia cells, and murine brains. Moreover, HSV-1 infection enhances the E3 ubiquitin ligase Keap1 (Kelch-like ECH-related protein 1)-mediated ubiquitination and degradation of nuclear factor E2-related factor 2 (Nrf2), a transcription factor that regulates the expression of antioxidative genes, thereby disturbing cellular redox homeostasis and promoting ferroptosis. Furthermore, HSV-1-induced ferroptosis is tightly associated with the process of viral encephalitis in a mouse model, and the ferroptosis-activated upregulation of prostaglandin-endoperoxide synthase 2 (PTGS2) and prostaglandin E2 (PGE&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;) plays an important role in HSV-1-caused inflammation and encephalitis. Importantly, the inhibition of ferroptosis by a ferroptosis inhibitor or a proteasome inhibitor to suppress Nrf2 degradation effectively alleviated HSV-1 encephalitis. Together, our findings demonstrate the interaction between HSV-1 infection and ferroptosis and provide novel insights into the pathogenesis of HSV-1 encephalitis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Importance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ferroptosis is a nonapoptotic form of programmed cell death that contributes to different neurological inflammatory diseases. However, whether HSV-1 induces ferroptosis in the CNS and the role of ferroptosis in viral pathogenesis remain unclear. In the current study, we demonstrate that HSV-1 infection induces ferroptosis, as Fe&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt; overload, ROS accumulation, GSH depletion, lipid peroxidation, and mitochondrion shrinkage, all of which are hallmarks of ferroptosis, are observed in human cultured astrocytes, microglia cells, and murine brains infected with HSV-1. Moreover, HSV-1 infection enhances Keap1-dependent Nrf2 ubiquitination and degradation, which results in substantial reductions in the expression levels of antiferroptotic genes downstream of Nrf2, thereby disturbing cellular redox homeostasis and promoting ferroptosis. Furthermore, HSV-1-induced ferroptosis is tightly associated with the process of viral encephalitis in a mouse model, and the ferroptosis-activated upregulation of PTGS2 and PGE2 plays an important role in HSV-1-caused inflammation and encephalitis. Importantly, the inhibition of ferroptosis by either a ferroptosis inhibitor or a proteasome inhibitor to suppress HSV-1-induced Nrf2 degradation effectively alleviates HSV-1-caused neuro-damage and inflammation in infected mice. Overall, our findings uncover the interaction between HSV-1 infection and ferroptosis, shed novel light on the physiological impacts of ferroptosis on the pathogenesis of HSV-1 infection and encephalitis, and provide a promising therapeutic strategy to treat this important infectious disease with a worldwide distribution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An HSV-1-H129 amplicon tracer system for rapid and efficient monosynaptic anterograde neural circuit tracing</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36496505/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36496505/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Monosynaptic viral tracers are essential tools for dissecting neuronal connectomes and for targeted delivery of molecular sensors and effectors. Viral toxicity and complex multi-injection protocols are major limiting application barriers. To overcome these barriers, we developed an anterograde monosynaptic H129&lt;sub&gt;Amp&lt;/sub&gt; tracer system based on HSV-1 strain H129. The H129&lt;sub&gt;Amp&lt;/sub&gt; tracer system consists of two components: an H129-dTK-T2-pac&lt;sup&gt;Flox&lt;/sup&gt; helper which assists H129&lt;sub&gt;Amp&lt;/sub&gt; tracer&amp;rsquo;s propagation and transneuronal monosynaptic transmission. The shared viral features of tracer/helper allow for simultaneous single-injection and subsequent high expression efficiency from multiple-copy of expression cassettes in H129&lt;sub&gt;Amp&lt;/sub&gt; tracer. These improvements of H129&lt;sub&gt;Amp&lt;/sub&gt; tracer system shorten experiment duration from 28-day to 5-day for fast-bright monosynaptic tracing. The lack of toxic viral genes in the H129&lt;sub&gt;Amp&lt;/sub&gt;tracer minimizes toxicity in postsynaptic neurons, thus offering the potential for functional anterograde mapping and long-term tracer delivery of genetic payloads. The H129&lt;sub&gt;Amp&lt;/sub&gt; tracer system is a powerful tracing tool for revealing neuronal connectomes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MITA oligomerization upon viral infection is dependent on its N-glycosylation mediated by DDOST</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36449507/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36449507/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therapeutics that discriminate between the genetic makeup of normal cells and tumour cells are valuable for treating and understanding cancer. Small molecules with oncogene-selective lethality may reveal novel functions of oncoproteins and enable the creation of more selective drugs. Here we describe the mechanism of action of the selective anti-tumour agent erastin, involving the RAS-RAF-MEK signalling pathway functioning in cell proliferation, differentiation and survival. Erastin exhibits greater lethality in human tumour cells harbouring mutations in the oncogenes HRAS, KRAS or BRAF. Using affinity purification and mass spectrometry, we discovered that erastin acts through mitochondrial voltage-dependent anion channels (VDACs)&amp;ndash;a novel target for anti-cancer drugs. We show that erastin treatment of cells harbouring oncogenic RAS causes the appearance of oxidative species and subsequent death through an oxidative, non-apoptotic mechanism. RNA-interference-mediated knockdown of VDAC2 or VDAC3 caused resistance to erastin, implicating these two VDAC isoforms in the mechanism of action of erastin. Moreover, using purified mitochondria expressing a single VDAC isoform, we found that erastin alters the permeability of the outer mitochondrial membrane. Finally, using a radiolabelled analogue and a filter-binding assay, we show that erastin binds directly to VDAC2. These results demonstrate that ligands to VDAC proteins can induce non-apoptotic cell death selectively in some tumour cells harbouring activating mutations in the RAS-RAF-MEK pathway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tegument protein UL21 of alpha-herpesvirus inhibits the innate immunity by triggering CGAS degradation through TOLLIP-mediated selective autophagy</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36343628/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36343628/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alpha-herpesvirus causes lifelong infections and serious diseases in a wide range of hosts and has developed multiple strategies to counteract the host defense. Here, we demonstrate that the tegument protein UL21 (unique long region 21) in pseudorabies virus (PRV) dampens type I interferon signaling by triggering the degradation of CGAS (cyclic GMP-AMP synthase) through the macroautophagy/autophagy-lysosome pathway. Mechanistically, the UL21 protein scaffolds the E3 ligase UBE3C (ubiquitin protein ligase E3C) to catalyze the K27-linked ubiquitination of CGAS at Lys384, which is recognized by the cargo receptor TOLLIP (toll interacting protein) and degraded in the lysosome. Additionally, we show that the N terminus of UL21 in PRV is dominant in destabilizing CGAS-mediated innate immunity. Moreover, viral tegument protein UL21 in herpes simplex virus type 1 (HSV-1) also displays the conserved inhibitory mechanisms. Furthermore, by using PRV, we demonstrate the roles of UL21 in degrading CGAS to promote viral infection in vivo. Altogether, these findings describe a distinct pathway where alpha-herpesvirus exploits TOLLIP-mediated selective autophagy to evade host antiviral immunity, highlighting a new interface of interplay between the host and DNA virus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The E3 ubiquitin ligase ARIH1 promotes antiviral immunity and autoimmunity by inducing mono-ISGylation and oligomerization of cGAS</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36217001/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36217001/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The cytosolic DNA sensor cyclic GMP-AMP synthase (cGAS) plays a critical role in antiviral immunity and autoimmunity. The activity and stability of cGAS are fine-tuned by post-translational modifications. Here, we show that ariadne RBR E3 ubiquitin protein ligase 1 (ARIH1) catalyzes the mono-ISGylation and induces the oligomerization of cGAS, thereby promoting antiviral immunity and autoimmunity. Knockdown or knockout of ARIH1 significantly inhibits herpes simplex virus 1 (HSV-1)- or cytoplasmic DNA-induced expression of type I interferons (IFNs) and proinflammatory cytokines. Consistently, tamoxifen-treated ER-Cre;Arih1&lt;sup&gt;fl/fl&lt;/sup&gt; mice and Lyz2-Cre; Arih1&lt;sup&gt;fl/fl&lt;/sup&gt; mice are hypersensitive to HSV-1 infection compared with the controls. In addition, deletion of ARIH1 in myeloid cells alleviates the autoimmune phenotypes and completely rescues the autoimmune lethality caused by TREX1 deficiency. Mechanistically, HSV-1- or cytosolic DNA-induced oligomerization and activation of cGAS are potentiated by ISGylation at its K187 residue, which is catalyzed by ARIH1. Our findings thus reveal an important role of ARIH1 in innate antiviral and autoimmune responses and provide insight into the post-translational regulation of cGAS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Single cell analysis of PANoptosome cell death complexes through an expansion microscopy method</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36169732/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36169732/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In response to infection or sterile insults, inflammatory programmed cell death is an essential component of the innate immune response to remove infected or damaged cells. PANoptosis is a unique innate immune inflammatory cell death pathway regulated by multifaceted macromolecular complexes called PANoptosomes, which integrate components from other cell death pathways. Growing evidence shows that PANoptosis can be triggered in many physiological conditions, including viral and bacterial infections, cytokine storms, and cancers. However, PANoptosomes at the single cell level have not yet been fully characterized. Initial investigations have suggested that key pyroptotic, apoptotic, and necroptotic molecules including the inflammasome adaptor protein ASC, apoptotic caspase-8 (CASP8), and necroptotic RIPK3 are conserved components of PANoptosomes. Here, we optimized an immunofluorescence procedure to probe the highly dynamic multiprotein PANoptosome complexes across various innate immune cell death-inducing conditions. We first identified and validated antibodies to stain endogenous mouse ASC, CASP8, and RIPK3, without residual staining in the respective knockout cells. We then assessed the formation of PANoptosomes across innate immune cell death-inducing conditions by monitoring the colocalization of ASC with CASP8 and/or RIPK3. Finally, we established an expansion microscopy procedure using these validated antibodies to image the organization of ASC, CASP8, and RIPK3 within the PANoptosome. This optimized protocol, which can be easily adapted to study other multiprotein complexes and other cell death triggers, provides confirmation of PANoptosome assembly in individual cells and forms the foundation for a deeper molecular understanding of the PANoptosome complex and PANoptosis to facilitate therapeutic targeting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Methionine metabolism controls the B cell EBV epigenome and viral latency</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36070681/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36070681/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Methionine metabolism is critical for Epstein-Barr virus B cell latency&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Extensive crosstalk enables methionine metabolism to control the EBV epigenome&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Methionine restriction also impairs EBV-driven human B cell immortalization&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dietary methionine restriction unmasks EBV antigens in Burkitt xenografts &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Epstein-Barr virus (EBV) subverts host epigenetic pathways to switch between viral latency programs, colonize the B cell compartment, and reactivate. Within memory B cells, the reservoir for lifelong infection, EBV genomic DNA and histone methylation marks restrict gene expression. But this epigenetic strategy also enables EBV-infected tumors, including Burkitt lymphomas, to evade immune detection. Little is known about host cell metabolic pathways that support EBV epigenome landscapes. We therefore used amino acid restriction, metabolomic, and CRISPR approaches to identify that an abundant methionine supply and interconnecting methionine and folate cycles maintain Burkitt EBV gene silencing. Methionine restriction, or methionine cycle perturbation, hypomethylated EBV genomes and de-repressed latent membrane protein and lytic gene expression. Methionine metabolism also shaped EBV latency gene regulation required for B cell immortalization. Dietary methionine restriction altered murine Burkitt xenograft metabolomes and de-repressed EBV immunogens &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt;. These results highlight epigenetic/immunometabolism crosstalk supporting the EBV B cell life cycle and suggest therapeutic approaches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Monocyte Signature Associated with Herpes Simplex Virus Reactivation and Neurological Recovery after Brain Injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35486851/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35486851/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rationale:&lt;/em&gt; Brain injury induces systemic immunosuppression, increasing the risk of viral reactivations and altering neurological recovery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Objectives:&lt;/em&gt; To determine if systemic immune alterations and lung replication of herpesviridae are associated and can help predict outcomes after brain injury.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; We collected peripheral blood mononuclear cells in patients with severe brain injury requiring invasive mechanical ventilation. We systematically searched for respiratory herpes simplex virus (HSV) replications in tracheal aspirates. We also performed chromatin immunoprecipitation sequencing, RNA-sequencing, and in vitro functional assays of monocytes and CD4 T cells collected on Day 1 to characterize the immune response to severe acute brain injury. The primary outcome was the Glasgow Outcome Scale Extended at 6 months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Measurements and Main Results:&lt;/em&gt; In 344 patients with severe brain injury, lung HSV reactivations were observed in 39% of the 232 patients seropositive for HSV and independently associated with poor neurological recovery at 6 months (hazard ratio, 1.90; 95% confidence interval, 1.08-3.57). Weighted gene coexpression network analyses of the transcriptomic response of monocytes to brain injury defined a module of 721 genes, including PD-L1 and CD80, enriched for the binding DNA motif of the transcriptional factor Zeb2 and whose ontogenic analyses revealed decreased IFN-γ-mediated and antiviral response signaling pathways. This monocyte signature was preserved in a validation cohort and predicted the neurological outcome at 6 months with good accuracy (area under the curve, 0.786; 95% confidence interval, 0.593-0.978).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; A specific monocyte signature is associated with HSV reactivation and predicts poor recovery after brain injury. The alterations of the immune control of herpesviridae replication are understudied and represent a novel therapeutic target.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ly6Chi monocytes balance regulatory and cytotoxic CD4 T cell responses to control virus-induced immunopathology</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35857578/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35857578/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gammaherpesviruses (γHVs) have coevolved with their host, leading to a remarkably high infection prevalence and establishment of latency. The lifelong persistence of γHVs in hosts appears to broadly shape host immunity, and we show here that pulmonary infection with Murid herpesvirus 4 (MuHV-4), a mouse γHV, drives the recruitment of Ly6C&lt;sup&gt;hi&lt;/sup&gt; monocytes (MOs) into the airway, thereby modulating the host immune response. The absence of Ly6C&lt;sup&gt;hi&lt;/sup&gt; MOs is associated with severe virus-induced immunopathology and the systemic release of inflammatory mediators. Mechanistically, MuHV-4-imprinted MOs recruit CD4 T cells to the airways and trigger immunosuppressive signaling pathways through the PD-L1/PD-1 axis, thereby dampening the deleterious activation of cytotoxic CD4 T cells. These results uncover a role for Ly6C&lt;sup&gt;hi&lt;/sup&gt; MOs in modulating CD4 T cell functions and reveal pathways that could be targeted therapeutically to reduce detrimental immunopathological responses associated with respiratory viral infections.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Insights on the cGAS-STING Signaling Pathway During Herpesvirus Infections</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/35844623/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/35844623/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Herpesviruses belong to large double-stranded DNA viruses. They are under a wide range of hosts and establish lifelong infection, which creates a burden on human health and animal health. Innate immunity is the host&amp;rsquo;s innate defense ability. Activating the innate immune signaling pathway and producing type I interferon is the host&amp;rsquo;s first line of defense against infectious pathogens. Emerging evidence indicates that the cGAS-STING signaling pathway plays an important role in the innate immunity in response to herpesvirus infections. In parallel, because of the constant selective pressure imposed by host immunity, herpesvirus also evolves to target the cGAS-STING signaling pathway to inhibit or escape the innate immune responses. In the current review, we insight on the classical cGAS-STING signaling pathway. We describe the activation of cGAS-STING signaling pathway during herpesvirus infections and strategies of herpesvirus targeting this pathway to evade host antiviral response. Furthermore, we outline the immunotherapy boosting cGAS-STING signaling pathway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>KSHV episome tethering sites on host chromosomes and regulation of latency-lytic switch by CHD4</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35545047/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35545047/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;KSHV episomes tether to host chromosomes at CHD4 enriched regions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CHD4-LANA complex binds to the PAN RNA promoter and terminal repeat regions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The viral long non-coding RNA sequesters CHD4 from KSHV genomes during reactivation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CHD4 facilitates KSHV to establish latency and inhibits reactivation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kaposi sarcoma-associated herpesvirus (KSHV) establishes a latent infection in the cell nucleus, but where KSHV episomal genomes are tethered and the mechanisms underlying KSHV lytic reactivation are unclear. Here, we study the nuclear microenvironment of KSHV episomes and show that the KSHV latency-lytic replication switch is regulated via viral long non-coding (lnc)RNA-CHD4 (chromodomain helicase DNA binding protein 4) interaction. KSHV episomes localize with CHD4 and ADNP proteins, components of the cellular ChAHP complex. The CHD4 and ADNP proteins occupy the 5&amp;rsquo;-region of the highly inducible lncRNAs and terminal repeats of the KSHV genome together with latency-associated nuclear antigen (LANA). Viral lncRNA binding competes with CHD4 DNA binding, and KSHV reactivation sequesters CHD4 from the KSHV genome, which is also accompanied by detachment of KSHV episomes from host chromosome docking sites. We propose a model in which robust KSHV lncRNA expression determines the latency-lytic decision by regulating LANA/CHD4 binding to KSHV episomes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Combined protein and nucleic acid imaging reveals virus-dependent B cell and macrophage immunosuppression of tissue microenvironments</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35447093/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35447093/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Development of a method (PANINI) for multiplexed nucleic acid and protein imaging&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Identification of orchestrated immune events in response to SIV infection&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IL-10 levels in B cells and macrophages correlate with immunosuppression&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tissue microenvironmental cues can influence SIV viral transcription state&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Understanding the mechanisms of HIV tissue persistence necessitates the ability to visualize tissue microenvironments where infected cells reside; however, technological barriers limit our ability to dissect the cellular components of these HIV reservoirs. Here, we developed protein and nucleic acid in situ imaging (PANINI) to simultaneously quantify DNA, RNA, and protein levels within these tissue compartments. By coupling PANINI with multiplexed ion beam imaging (MIBI), we measured over 30 parameters simultaneously across archival lymphoid tissues from healthy or simian immunodeficiency virus (SIV)-infected nonhuman primates. PANINI enabled the spatial dissection of cellular phenotypes, functional markers, and viral events resulting from infection. SIV infection induced IL-10 expression in lymphoid B cells, which correlated with local macrophage M2 polarization. This highlights a potential viral mechanism for conditioning an immunosuppressive tissue environment for virion production. The spatial multimodal framework here can be extended to decipher tissue responses in other infectious diseases and tumor biology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Systematic optimization of host-directed therapeutic targets and preclinical validation of repositioned antiviral drugs</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35238349/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35238349/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inhibition of host protein functions using established drugs produces a promising antiviral effect with excellent safety profiles, decreased incidence of resistant variants and favorable balance of costs and risks. Genomic methods have produced a large number of robust host factors, providing candidates for identification of antiviral drug targets. However, there is a lack of global perspectives and systematic prioritization of known virus-targeted host proteins (VTHPs) and drug targets. There is also a need for host-directed repositioned antivirals. Here, we integrated 6140 VTHPs and grouped viral infection modes from a new perspective of enriched pathways of VTHPs. Clarifying the superiority of nonessential membrane and hub VTHPs as potential ideal targets for repositioned antivirals, we proposed 543 candidate VTHPs. We then presented a large-scale drug-virus network (DVN) based on matching these VTHPs and drug targets. We predicted possible indications for 703 approved drugs against 35 viruses and explored their potential as broad-spectrum antivirals. &lt;em&gt;In vitro&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt; tests validated the efficacy of bosutinib, maraviroc and dextromethorphan against human herpesvirus 1 (HHV-1), hepatitis B virus (HBV) and influenza A virus (IAV). Their drug synergy with clinically used antivirals was evaluated and confirmed. The results proved that low-dose dextromethorphan is better than high-dose in both single and combined treatments. This study provides a comprehensive landscape and optimization strategy for druggable VTHPs, constructing an innovative and potent pipeline to discover novel antiviral host proteins and repositioned drugs, which may facilitate their delivery to clinical application in translational medicine to combat fatal and spreading viral infections.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interferon-Induced Transmembrane Proteins Inhibit Infection by the Kaposi&#39;s Sarcoma-Associated Herpesvirus and the Related Rhesus Monkey Rhadinovirus in a Cell-Specific Manner</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34933450/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34933450/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The interferon-induced transmembrane proteins (IFITMs) are broad-spectrum antiviral proteins that inhibit the entry of enveloped viruses. We analyzed the effect of IFITMs on the gamma-2 herpesviruses Kaposi&amp;rsquo;s sarcoma-associated herpesvirus (KSHV) and the closely related rhesus monkey rhadinovirus (RRV). We used CRISPR/Cas9-mediated gene knockout to generate A549 cells, human foreskin fibroblasts (HFF), and human umbilical vein endothelial cells (HUVEC) with combined IFITM1/2/3 knockout and identified IFITMs as cell-dependent inhibitors of KSHV and RRV infection in A549 cells and HFF but not HUVEC. IFITM overexpression revealed IFITM1 as the relevant IFITM that inhibits KSHV and RRV infection. Fluorescent KSHV particles did not pronouncedly colocalize with IFITM-positive compartments. However, we found that KSHV and RRV glycoprotein-mediated cell-cell fusion is enhanced upon IFITM1/2/3 knockout. Taken together, we identified IFITM1 as a cell-dependent restriction factor of KSHV and RRV that acts at the level of membrane fusion. Of note, our results indicate that recombinant IFITM overexpression may lead to results that are not representative for the situation at endogenous levels. Strikingly, we observed that the endotheliotropic KSHV circumvents IFITM-mediated restriction in HUVEC despite high IFITM expression, while influenza A virus (IAV) glycoprotein-driven entry into HUVEC is potently restricted by IFITMs even in the absence of interferon. Mechanistically, we found that KSHV colocalizes less with IFITM1 and IFITM2 in HUVEC than in A549 cells immediately after attachment, potentially contributing to the observed difference in restriction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Importance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;IFITM proteins are the first line of defense against infection by many pathogens and may also have therapeutic importance, as they, among other effectors, mediate the antiviral effect of interferons. Neither their function against herpesviruses nor their mechanism of action is well understood. We report here that in some cells but not in, for example, primary umbilical vein endothelial cells, IFITM1 restricts KSHV and RRV and that, mechanistically, this is likely effected by reducing the fusogenicity of the cell membrane. Further, we demonstrate potent inhibition of IAV glycoprotein-driven infection of cells of extrapulmonary origin by high constitutive IFITM expression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>STING-Mediated Interferon Induction by Herpes Simplex Virus 1 Requires the Protein Tyrosine Kinase Syk</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34933455/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34933455/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The nature and the intensity of innate immune response to virus infection determine the course of pathogenesis in the host. Among the many pathogen-associated molecular pattern recognition receptors, STING, an endoplasmic reticulum (ER)-associated protein, plays a pivotal role in triggering responses to microbial or cellular cytoplasmic DNA. Herpes simplex virus 1 (HSV-1), a common human pathogen, activates STING signaling, and the resultant induction of type I interferon causes inhibition of virus replication. In this context, we have observed that phosphorylation of Tyr245 of STING by epidermal growth factor receptor kinase is necessary for interferon induction. Here, we report that phosphorylation of Tyr240 by the tyrosine kinase Syk is essential for all signaling activities of STING. Our analysis showed that upon ligand-binding, STING dimerizes and interacts with membrane-bound EGFR, which autophosphorylates and provides the platform for the recruitment of cytoplasmic Syk to the signaling complex and its activation. Activated Syk phosphorylates Tyr240 of STING, followed by phosphorylation of Tyr245 by epidermal growth factor receptor (EGFR). Pharmacological or genetic ablation of Syk activity resulted in an arrest of STING in the ER compartment and a complete block of gene induction. Consequently, in the absence of Syk, HSV-1 could not induce interferon, and it replicated more robustly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Importance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The innate immune response to virus infection leads to interferon production and inhibition of viral replication. STING, an ER-bound protein, mediates such a response to cytoplasmic cellular or microbial DNA. HSV-1, a DNA virus, activates STING, and it replicates more efficiently in the absence of STING signaling. We demonstrate that phosphorylation of Tyr240 of STING by the protein tyrosine kinase Syk is essential for STING-mediated gene induction. To signal, ligand-activated STING recruits two kinases, Syk and EGFR, which phosphorylate Tyr240 and Tyr245, respectively. The dependence of STING signaling on Syk has broad significance, because STING plays a major role in many microbial, mitochondrial, and autoimmune diseases as well as in cancer development and therapy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>gp96 Is Critical for both Human Herpesvirus 6A (HHV-6A) and HHV-6B Infections</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32295911/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32295911/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Human herpesviruses 6A and 6B (HHV-6A and HHV-6B, respectively) are two virus species in the betaherpesvirus subfamily that exhibit T cell tropism. CD46 and CD134 are the cellular receptors for HHV-6A and HHV-6B, respectively. Interestingly, the efficiency of HHV-6A/6B entry is different among different types of target cells despite similar receptor expression levels on these cells. Here, we found that the cellular factor gp96 (also known as glucose-regulated protein 94, GRP94) is expressed on the cell surface and interacts with viral glycoprotein Q1 (gQ1) during virus entry. gp96 cell surface expression levels are associated with the efficiency of HHV-6A and HHV-6B entry into target cells. Both loss-of-function and gain-of-function experiments indicated that gp96 plays an important role in HHV-6 infection. Our findings provide new insight into the HHV-6 entry process and might suggest novel therapeutic targets for HHV-6 infection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Importance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although new clinical importance has been revealed for human herpesviruses 6A (HHV-6A) and 6B, much is still unknown about the life cycles of these viruses in target cells. We identified a novel cellular factor, gp96, that is critical for both HHV-6A and -6B entry into host cells. As gp96 can function as an adjuvant in vaccine development for both infectious agents and cancers, it can be a potential therapeutic target for infection by these two viruses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>hnRNPA2B1 Associated with Recruitment of RNA into Exosomes Plays a Key Role in Herpes Simplex Virus 1 Release from Infected Cells</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32295924/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32295924/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;hnRNPA2B1, an abundant cellular protein, has been reported to recruit RNAs bearing a specific sequence (EXO motif) into exosomes. We characterized an exosome population averaging 100 ± 50 nm in diameter and containing a defined set of constitutive exosome markers. This population packages microRNAs (miRNAs) and can be directed to block targeted gene expression in a dose-dependent fashion. The objective of this study was to characterize the role of hnRNPA2B1 in the recruitment of miRNA. We report the following four key findings. (i) hnRNPA2B1 is not a component of exosomes produced in HEp-2 or HEK293T cells. Hence, hnRNPA2B1 carries its cargo, at most, to the site of exosome assembly, but it is not itself incorporated into exosomes. (ii) The accumulation of exosomes produced by cells in which the gene encoding hnRNPA2B1 has been knocked out (ΔhnRNPA2B1 cells) was reduced 3-fold. (iii) In uninfected HEp-2 cells, hnRNPA2B1 is localized in the nucleus. In cells infected with herpes simplex virus 1 (HSV-1), hnRNPA2B1 was quantitatively exported to the cytoplasm and at least a fraction of hnRNPA2B1 colocalized with a Golgi marker. (iv) Lastly, in ΔhnRNPA2B1 cells, there was a 2- to 3-fold reduction in virus yield but a significant (&amp;gt;10-fold) reduction in HSV-1 released through the apical surface into the extracellular environment. The absence of hnRNPA2B1 had no significant impact on the basolateral export of HSV-1 from infected to uninfected cells by direct cell-to-cell contact. The results suggest that hnRNPA2B1 plays a key role in the transport of enveloped virus from its site of assembly to the extracellular environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Importance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this report, we show that hnRNPA2B1 is not a component of exosomes produced in HEp-2 or HEK293T cells. In herpes simplex virus 1 (HSV-1)-infected cells, hnRNPA2B1 was quantitatively translocated from the nucleus into the cytoplasm. In infected ΔhnRNPA2B1 cells, Golgi-dependent transport of virus from the apical surface to the extracellular medium was significantly reduced. In essence, this report supports the hypothesis that hnRNPA2B1 plays a key role in the egress of exosomes and HSV-1 from infected cells.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>USP29 maintains the stability of cGAS and promotes cellular antiviral responses and autoimmunity</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32457395/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32457395/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Erratum in:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Author Correction: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nature.com/articles/s41422-020-0368-8&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;USP29 maintains the stability of cGAS and promotes cellular antiviral responses and autoimmunity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cyclic GMP-AMP synthase (cGAS) is an essential sensor of cytosolic DNA and critically mediates innate immune responses and autoimmunity. Modulating the activity and stability of cGAS provides potential strategies for treating viral or autoimmune diseases. Here, we report that ubiquitin-specific protease 29 (USP29) deubiquitinates and stabilizes cGAS and promotes cellular antiviral responses and autoimmunity. Knockdown or knockout of USP29 severely impairs Herpes simplex virus 1 (HSV-1)- or cytosolic DNA-induced expression of type I interferons (IFNs) and proinflammatory cytokines. Consistently, Usp29m/m mice produce decreased type I IFNs and proinflammatory cytokines after HSV-1 infection and are hypersensitive to HSV-1 infection compared to the wild-type littermates. In addition, genetic ablation of USP29 in Trex1-/- mice eliminated the detectable pathological and molecular autoimmune phenotypes. Mechanistically, USP29 constitutively interacts with cGAS, deconjugates K48-linked polyubiquitin chains from cGAS and stabilizes cGAS in uninfected cells or after HSV-1 infection. Reconstitution of cGAS into Usp29-/- cells fully rescues type I IFN induction and cellular antiviral responses after HSV-1 infection. Our findings thus reveal a critical role of USP29 in the innate antiviral responses against DNA viruses and autoimmune diseases and provide insight into the regulation of cGAS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integrative functional genomics decodes herpes simplex virus 1</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32341360/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32341360/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The predicted 80 open reading frames (ORFs) of herpes simplex virus 1 (HSV-1) have been intensively studied for decades. Here, we unravel the complete viral transcriptome and translatome during lytic infection with base-pair resolution by computational integration of multi-omics data. We identify a total of 201 transcripts and 284 ORFs including all known and 46 novel large ORFs. This includes a so far unknown ORF in the locus deleted in the FDA-approved oncolytic virus Imlygic. Multiple transcript isoforms expressed from individual gene loci explain translation of the vast majority of ORFs as well as N-terminal extensions (NTEs) and truncations. We show that NTEs with non-canonical start codons govern the subcellular protein localization and packaging of key viral regulators and structural proteins. We extend the current nomenclature to include all viral gene products and provide a genome browser that visualizes all the obtained data from whole genome to single-nucleotide resolution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Infection-Induced Peroxisome Biogenesis Is a Metabolic Strategy for Herpesvirus Replication</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/30269970/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/30269970/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Viral proteins have evolved to target cellular organelles and usurp their functions for virus replication. Despite the knowledge of these critical functions for several organelles, little is known about peroxisomes during infection. Peroxisomes are primarily metabolic organelles with important functions in lipid metabolism. Here, we discovered that the enveloped viruses human cytomegalovirus (HCMV) and herpes simplex virus type 1 (HSV-1) induce the biogenesis of and unique morphological changes to peroxisomes to support their replication. Targeted proteomic quantification revealed a global virus-induced upregulation of peroxisomal proteins. Mathematical modeling and microscopy structural analysis show that infection triggers peroxisome growth and fission, leading to increased peroxisome numbers and irregular disc-like structures. HCMV-induced peroxisome biogenesis increased the phospholipid plasmalogen, thereby enhancing virus production. Peroxisome regulation and dependence were not observed for the non-enveloped adenovirus. Our findings uncover a role of peroxisomes in viral pathogenesis, with likely implications for multiple enveloped viruses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cell autonomous regulation of herpes and influenza virus infection by the circadian clock</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/27528682/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/27528682/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Viruses are intracellular pathogens that hijack host cell machinery and resources to replicate. Rather than being constant, host physiology is rhythmic, undergoing circadian (∼24 h) oscillations in many virus-relevant pathways, but whether daily rhythms impact on viral replication is unknown. We find that the time of day of host infection regulates virus progression in live mice and individual cells. Furthermore, we demonstrate that herpes and influenza A virus infections are enhanced when host circadian rhythms are abolished by disrupting the key clock gene transcription factor Bmal1. Intracellular trafficking, biosynthetic processes, protein synthesis, and chromatin assembly all contribute to circadian regulation of virus infection. Moreover, herpesviruses differentially target components of the molecular circadian clockwork. Our work demonstrates that viruses exploit the clockwork for their own gain and that the clock represents a novel target for modulating viral replication that extends beyond any single family of these ubiquitous pathogens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
