<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Herpesvirus | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/herpesvirus/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/herpesvirus/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Herpesvirus</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Herpesvirus</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/herpesvirus/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>MITA oligomerization upon viral infection is dependent on its N-glycosylation mediated by DDOST</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36449507/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36449507/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therapeutics that discriminate between the genetic makeup of normal cells and tumour cells are valuable for treating and understanding cancer. Small molecules with oncogene-selective lethality may reveal novel functions of oncoproteins and enable the creation of more selective drugs. Here we describe the mechanism of action of the selective anti-tumour agent erastin, involving the RAS-RAF-MEK signalling pathway functioning in cell proliferation, differentiation and survival. Erastin exhibits greater lethality in human tumour cells harbouring mutations in the oncogenes HRAS, KRAS or BRAF. Using affinity purification and mass spectrometry, we discovered that erastin acts through mitochondrial voltage-dependent anion channels (VDACs)&amp;ndash;a novel target for anti-cancer drugs. We show that erastin treatment of cells harbouring oncogenic RAS causes the appearance of oxidative species and subsequent death through an oxidative, non-apoptotic mechanism. RNA-interference-mediated knockdown of VDAC2 or VDAC3 caused resistance to erastin, implicating these two VDAC isoforms in the mechanism of action of erastin. Moreover, using purified mitochondria expressing a single VDAC isoform, we found that erastin alters the permeability of the outer mitochondrial membrane. Finally, using a radiolabelled analogue and a filter-binding assay, we show that erastin binds directly to VDAC2. These results demonstrate that ligands to VDAC proteins can induce non-apoptotic cell death selectively in some tumour cells harbouring activating mutations in the RAS-RAF-MEK pathway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The E3 ubiquitin ligase ARIH1 promotes antiviral immunity and autoimmunity by inducing mono-ISGylation and oligomerization of cGAS</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36217001/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36217001/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The cytosolic DNA sensor cyclic GMP-AMP synthase (cGAS) plays a critical role in antiviral immunity and autoimmunity. The activity and stability of cGAS are fine-tuned by post-translational modifications. Here, we show that ariadne RBR E3 ubiquitin protein ligase 1 (ARIH1) catalyzes the mono-ISGylation and induces the oligomerization of cGAS, thereby promoting antiviral immunity and autoimmunity. Knockdown or knockout of ARIH1 significantly inhibits herpes simplex virus 1 (HSV-1)- or cytoplasmic DNA-induced expression of type I interferons (IFNs) and proinflammatory cytokines. Consistently, tamoxifen-treated ER-Cre;Arih1&lt;sup&gt;fl/fl&lt;/sup&gt; mice and Lyz2-Cre; Arih1&lt;sup&gt;fl/fl&lt;/sup&gt; mice are hypersensitive to HSV-1 infection compared with the controls. In addition, deletion of ARIH1 in myeloid cells alleviates the autoimmune phenotypes and completely rescues the autoimmune lethality caused by TREX1 deficiency. Mechanistically, HSV-1- or cytosolic DNA-induced oligomerization and activation of cGAS are potentiated by ISGylation at its K187 residue, which is catalyzed by ARIH1. Our findings thus reveal an important role of ARIH1 in innate antiviral and autoimmune responses and provide insight into the post-translational regulation of cGAS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>gp96 Is Critical for both Human Herpesvirus 6A (HHV-6A) and HHV-6B Infections</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32295911/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32295911/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Human herpesviruses 6A and 6B (HHV-6A and HHV-6B, respectively) are two virus species in the betaherpesvirus subfamily that exhibit T cell tropism. CD46 and CD134 are the cellular receptors for HHV-6A and HHV-6B, respectively. Interestingly, the efficiency of HHV-6A/6B entry is different among different types of target cells despite similar receptor expression levels on these cells. Here, we found that the cellular factor gp96 (also known as glucose-regulated protein 94, GRP94) is expressed on the cell surface and interacts with viral glycoprotein Q1 (gQ1) during virus entry. gp96 cell surface expression levels are associated with the efficiency of HHV-6A and HHV-6B entry into target cells. Both loss-of-function and gain-of-function experiments indicated that gp96 plays an important role in HHV-6 infection. Our findings provide new insight into the HHV-6 entry process and might suggest novel therapeutic targets for HHV-6 infection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Importance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although new clinical importance has been revealed for human herpesviruses 6A (HHV-6A) and 6B, much is still unknown about the life cycles of these viruses in target cells. We identified a novel cellular factor, gp96, that is critical for both HHV-6A and -6B entry into host cells. As gp96 can function as an adjuvant in vaccine development for both infectious agents and cancers, it can be a potential therapeutic target for infection by these two viruses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>hnRNPA2B1 Associated with Recruitment of RNA into Exosomes Plays a Key Role in Herpes Simplex Virus 1 Release from Infected Cells</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32295924/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32295924/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;hnRNPA2B1, an abundant cellular protein, has been reported to recruit RNAs bearing a specific sequence (EXO motif) into exosomes. We characterized an exosome population averaging 100 ± 50 nm in diameter and containing a defined set of constitutive exosome markers. This population packages microRNAs (miRNAs) and can be directed to block targeted gene expression in a dose-dependent fashion. The objective of this study was to characterize the role of hnRNPA2B1 in the recruitment of miRNA. We report the following four key findings. (i) hnRNPA2B1 is not a component of exosomes produced in HEp-2 or HEK293T cells. Hence, hnRNPA2B1 carries its cargo, at most, to the site of exosome assembly, but it is not itself incorporated into exosomes. (ii) The accumulation of exosomes produced by cells in which the gene encoding hnRNPA2B1 has been knocked out (ΔhnRNPA2B1 cells) was reduced 3-fold. (iii) In uninfected HEp-2 cells, hnRNPA2B1 is localized in the nucleus. In cells infected with herpes simplex virus 1 (HSV-1), hnRNPA2B1 was quantitatively exported to the cytoplasm and at least a fraction of hnRNPA2B1 colocalized with a Golgi marker. (iv) Lastly, in ΔhnRNPA2B1 cells, there was a 2- to 3-fold reduction in virus yield but a significant (&amp;gt;10-fold) reduction in HSV-1 released through the apical surface into the extracellular environment. The absence of hnRNPA2B1 had no significant impact on the basolateral export of HSV-1 from infected to uninfected cells by direct cell-to-cell contact. The results suggest that hnRNPA2B1 plays a key role in the transport of enveloped virus from its site of assembly to the extracellular environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Importance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this report, we show that hnRNPA2B1 is not a component of exosomes produced in HEp-2 or HEK293T cells. In herpes simplex virus 1 (HSV-1)-infected cells, hnRNPA2B1 was quantitatively translocated from the nucleus into the cytoplasm. In infected ΔhnRNPA2B1 cells, Golgi-dependent transport of virus from the apical surface to the extracellular medium was significantly reduced. In essence, this report supports the hypothesis that hnRNPA2B1 plays a key role in the egress of exosomes and HSV-1 from infected cells.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>USP29 maintains the stability of cGAS and promotes cellular antiviral responses and autoimmunity</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32457395/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32457395/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Erratum in:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Author Correction: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nature.com/articles/s41422-020-0368-8&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;USP29 maintains the stability of cGAS and promotes cellular antiviral responses and autoimmunity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cyclic GMP-AMP synthase (cGAS) is an essential sensor of cytosolic DNA and critically mediates innate immune responses and autoimmunity. Modulating the activity and stability of cGAS provides potential strategies for treating viral or autoimmune diseases. Here, we report that ubiquitin-specific protease 29 (USP29) deubiquitinates and stabilizes cGAS and promotes cellular antiviral responses and autoimmunity. Knockdown or knockout of USP29 severely impairs Herpes simplex virus 1 (HSV-1)- or cytosolic DNA-induced expression of type I interferons (IFNs) and proinflammatory cytokines. Consistently, Usp29m/m mice produce decreased type I IFNs and proinflammatory cytokines after HSV-1 infection and are hypersensitive to HSV-1 infection compared to the wild-type littermates. In addition, genetic ablation of USP29 in Trex1-/- mice eliminated the detectable pathological and molecular autoimmune phenotypes. Mechanistically, USP29 constitutively interacts with cGAS, deconjugates K48-linked polyubiquitin chains from cGAS and stabilizes cGAS in uninfected cells or after HSV-1 infection. Reconstitution of cGAS into Usp29-/- cells fully rescues type I IFN induction and cellular antiviral responses after HSV-1 infection. Our findings thus reveal a critical role of USP29 in the innate antiviral responses against DNA viruses and autoimmune diseases and provide insight into the regulation of cGAS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integrative functional genomics decodes herpes simplex virus 1</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32341360/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32341360/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The predicted 80 open reading frames (ORFs) of herpes simplex virus 1 (HSV-1) have been intensively studied for decades. Here, we unravel the complete viral transcriptome and translatome during lytic infection with base-pair resolution by computational integration of multi-omics data. We identify a total of 201 transcripts and 284 ORFs including all known and 46 novel large ORFs. This includes a so far unknown ORF in the locus deleted in the FDA-approved oncolytic virus Imlygic. Multiple transcript isoforms expressed from individual gene loci explain translation of the vast majority of ORFs as well as N-terminal extensions (NTEs) and truncations. We show that NTEs with non-canonical start codons govern the subcellular protein localization and packaging of key viral regulators and structural proteins. We extend the current nomenclature to include all viral gene products and provide a genome browser that visualizes all the obtained data from whole genome to single-nucleotide resolution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Infection-Induced Peroxisome Biogenesis Is a Metabolic Strategy for Herpesvirus Replication</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/30269970/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/30269970/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Viral proteins have evolved to target cellular organelles and usurp their functions for virus replication. Despite the knowledge of these critical functions for several organelles, little is known about peroxisomes during infection. Peroxisomes are primarily metabolic organelles with important functions in lipid metabolism. Here, we discovered that the enveloped viruses human cytomegalovirus (HCMV) and herpes simplex virus type 1 (HSV-1) induce the biogenesis of and unique morphological changes to peroxisomes to support their replication. Targeted proteomic quantification revealed a global virus-induced upregulation of peroxisomal proteins. Mathematical modeling and microscopy structural analysis show that infection triggers peroxisome growth and fission, leading to increased peroxisome numbers and irregular disc-like structures. HCMV-induced peroxisome biogenesis increased the phospholipid plasmalogen, thereby enhancing virus production. Peroxisome regulation and dependence were not observed for the non-enveloped adenovirus. Our findings uncover a role of peroxisomes in viral pathogenesis, with likely implications for multiple enveloped viruses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cell autonomous regulation of herpes and influenza virus infection by the circadian clock</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/27528682/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/27528682/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Viruses are intracellular pathogens that hijack host cell machinery and resources to replicate. Rather than being constant, host physiology is rhythmic, undergoing circadian (∼24 h) oscillations in many virus-relevant pathways, but whether daily rhythms impact on viral replication is unknown. We find that the time of day of host infection regulates virus progression in live mice and individual cells. Furthermore, we demonstrate that herpes and influenza A virus infections are enhanced when host circadian rhythms are abolished by disrupting the key clock gene transcription factor Bmal1. Intracellular trafficking, biosynthetic processes, protein synthesis, and chromatin assembly all contribute to circadian regulation of virus infection. Moreover, herpesviruses differentially target components of the molecular circadian clockwork. Our work demonstrates that viruses exploit the clockwork for their own gain and that the clock represents a novel target for modulating viral replication that extends beyond any single family of these ubiquitous pathogens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
