<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Bone/Joint | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/bone/joint/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/bone/joint/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Bone/Joint</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Bone/Joint</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/bone/joint/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>A progeroid syndrome caused by a deep intronic variant in TAPT1 is revealed by RNA/SI-NET sequencing</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36652330/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36652330/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Exome sequencing has introduced a paradigm shift for the identification of germline variations responsible for Mendelian diseases. However, non-coding regions, which make up 98% of the genome, cannot be captured. The lack of functional annotation for intronic and intergenic variants makes RNA-seq a powerful companion diagnostic. Here, we illustrate this point by identifying six patients with a recessive Osteogenesis Imperfecta (OI) and neonatal progeria syndrome. By integrating homozygosity mapping and RNA-seq, we delineated a deep intronic TAPT1 mutation (c.1237-52 G&amp;gt;A) that segregated with the disease. Using SI-NET-seq, we document that TAPT1&amp;rsquo;s nascent transcription was not affected in patients&amp;rsquo; fibroblasts, indicating instead that this variant leads to an alteration of pre-mRNA processing. Predicted to serve as an alternative splicing branchpoint, this mutation enhances TAPT1 exon 12 skipping, creating a protein-null allele. Additionally, our study reveals dysregulation of pathways involved in collagen and extracellular matrix biology in disease-relevant cells. Overall, our work highlights the power of transcriptomic approaches in deciphering the repercussions of non-coding variants, as well as in illuminating the molecular mechanisms of human diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gut commensal Parabacteroides distasonis alleviates inflammatory arthritis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36604114/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36604114/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Objective:&lt;/em&gt; Gut microbiota dysbiosis is closely linked to the pathogenesis of rheumatoid arthritis (RA). We aimed to identify potential probiotic gut microbes that can ameliorate the development of RA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Design:&lt;/em&gt; Microbiota profiling in patients with RA and healthy individuals was investigated via 16S rDNA bacterial gene sequencing and shotgun metagenomics. Collagen-induced arthritic mice and TNF-α transgenic mice were used to evaluate the roles of the gut commensal &lt;em&gt;Parabacteroides distasonis&lt;/em&gt; in RA. The effects of &lt;em&gt;P. distasonis&lt;/em&gt;-derived microbial metabolites on the differentiation of CD4&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T cells and macrophage polarisation were also investigated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; The relative abundance of &lt;em&gt;P. distasonis&lt;/em&gt; in new-onset patients with RA and patients with RA with history of the disease was downregulated and this decrease was negatively correlated with Disease Activity Score-28 (DAS28). Oral treatment of arthritic mice with live &lt;em&gt;P. distasonis&lt;/em&gt; (LPD) considerably ameliorated RA pathogenesis. LPD-derived lithocholic acid (LCA), deoxycholic acid (DCA), isolithocholic acid (isoLCA) and 3-oxolithocholic acid (3-oxoLCA) had similar and synergistic effects on the treatment of RA. In addition to directly inhibiting the differentiation of Th17 cells, 3-oxoLCA and isoLCA were identified as TGR5 agonists that promoted the M2 polarisation of macrophages. A specific synthetic inhibitor of bile salt hydrolase attenuated the antiarthritic effects of LPD by reducing the production of these four bile acids. The natural product ginsenoside Rg2 exhibited its anti-RA effects by promoting the growth of &lt;em&gt;P. distasonis&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;P. distasonis&lt;/em&gt; and ginsenoside Rg2 might represent probiotic and prebiotic agents in the treatment of RA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generation of bioactive MSC-EVs for bone tissue regeneration by tauroursodeoxycholic acid treatment</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36586671/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36586671/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Extracellular vesicles (EVs) are nano-sized carriers that reflect the parent cell&amp;rsquo;s information and are known to mediate cell-cell communication. In order to overcome the disadvantages of mesenchymal stem cells (MSCs) in cell therapy, such as unexpected differentiation leading to tumorization, immune rejection, and other side effects, EVs derived from MSCs (MSC-EVs) with the tissue regenerative function have been studied as new cell-free therapeutics. However, therapeutic applications of EVs require overcoming several challenges. First, the production efficiency of MSC-EVs should be increased at least as much as the quantity of them are required to their clinical application; second, MSC-EVs needs to show various functionality further, thereby increasing tissue regeneration efficiency. In this study, we treated tauroursodeoxycholic acid (TUDCA), a biological derivative known to regulate cholesterol, to MSCs and investigated whether TUDCA treatment would be able to increase EV production efficiency and tissue regenerative capacity of EVs. Indeed, it appears that TUDCA priming to MSC increases the yield of MSC-EVs &amp;gt;2 times by reducing the cellular cholesterol level in MSCs and increasing the exocytosis-related CAV1 expression. Interestingly, it was found that the EVs derived from TUDCA-primed MSCs (T-EV) contained higher amounts of anti-inflammatory cytokines (IL1RN, IL6, IL10, and IL11) and osteogenic proteins (ALP, RUNX2, BMP2, BMPR1, and BMPR2) than those in control MSC-EVs (C-EV). Besides, it was shown that T-EV not only regulated M1/M2 macrophages differentiation of monocytes, also effectively increased the osteogenic differentiation of MSCs as well as bone tissue regeneration in a bone defect rat model. Based on these results, it is concluded that TUDCA treatment to MSC as a new approach endows EV with high-yield production and functionality. Thus, we strongly believe T-EV would be a powerful therapeutic material for bone tissue regeneration and potentially could be expanded to other types of tissue regeneration for clinical applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gut microbiome dysregulation drives bone damage in broiler tibial dyschondroplasia by disrupting glucose homeostasis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36596826/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36596826/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tibial dyschondroplasia (TD) with multiple incentives is a metabolic skeletal disease that occurs in fast-growing broilers. Perturbations in the gut microbiota (GM) have been shown to affect bone homoeostasis, but the mechanisms by which GM modulates bone metabolism in TD broilers remain unknown. Here, using a broiler model of TD, we noted elevated blood glucose (GLU) levels in TD broilers, accompanied by alterations in the pancreatic structure and secretory function and damaged intestinal barrier function. Importantly, faecal microbiota transplantation (FMT) of gut microbes from normal donors rehabilitated the GM and decreased the elevated GLU levels in TD broilers. A high GLU level is a predisposing factor to bone disease, suggesting that GM dysbiosis-mediated hyperglycaemia might be involved in bone regulation. 16S rRNA gene sequencing and short-chain fatty acid analysis revealed that the significantly increased level of the metabolite butyric acid derived from the genera &lt;em&gt;Blautia&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Coprococcus&lt;/em&gt; regulated GLU levels in TD broilers by binding to GPR109A in the pancreas. Tibial studies showed reduced expression of vascular regulatory factors (including PI3K, AKT and VEFGA) based on transcriptomics analysis and reduced vascular distribution, contributing to nonvascularization of cartilage in the proximal tibial growth plate of TD broilers with elevated GLU levels. Additionally, treatment with the total flavonoids from Rhizoma drynariae further validated the improvement in bone homoeostasis in TD broilers by regulating GLU levels through the regulation of GM to subsequently improve intestinal and pancreatic function. These findings clarify the critical role of GM-mediated changes in GLU levels via the gut–pancreas axis in bone homoeostasis in TD chickens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transcript shortening via alternative polyadenylation promotes gene expression during fracture healing</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36596777/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36596777/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maturation of the 3&amp;rsquo; end of almost all eukaryotic messenger RNAs (mRNAs) requires cleavage and polyadenylation. Most mammalian mRNAs are polyadenylated at different sites within the last exon, generating alternative polyadenylation (APA) isoforms that have the same coding region but distinct 3&amp;rsquo; untranslated regions (UTRs). The 3&amp;rsquo;UTR contains motifs that regulate mRNA metabolism; thus, changing the 3&amp;rsquo;UTR length via APA can significantly affect gene expression. Endochondral ossification is a central process in bone healing, but the impact of APA on gene expression during this process is unknown. Here, we report the widespread occurrence of APA, which impacts multiple pathways that are known to participate in bone healing. Importantly, the progression of endochondral ossification involves global 3&amp;rsquo;UTR shortening, which is coupled with an increased abundance of shortened transcripts relative to other transcripts; these results highlight the role of APA in promoting gene expression during endochondral bone formation. Our mechanistic studies of transcripts that undergo APA in the fracture callus revealed an intricate regulatory network in which APA enhances the expression of the collagen, type I, alpha 1 (Col1a1) and Col1a2 genes, which encode the 2 subunits of the abundantly expressed protein collagen 1. APA exerts this effect by shortening the 3&amp;rsquo;UTRs of the Col1a1 and Col1a2 mRNAs, thus removing the binding sites of miR-29a-3p, which would otherwise strongly promote the degradation of both transcripts. Taken together, our study is the first to characterize the crucial roles of APA in regulating the 3&amp;rsquo;UTR landscape and modulating gene expression during fracture healing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Targeting SOST using a small-molecule compound retards breast cancer bone metastasis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36581888/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36581888/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Breast cancer metastasis to the bone can be exacerbated by osteoporosis, is associated with poor long-term survival, and has limited therapeutic options. Sclerostin (SOST) is an endogenous inhibitor of bone formation, and an attractive target for treatment of osteoporosis. However, it is unclear whether SOST can be used as a therapeutic target for bone metastases of breast cancer, and whether small molecule compounds that target SOST in breast cancer cells can inhibit breast cancer bone metastasis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; SOST expression in 442 breast cancer tissues was characterized by immunohistochemistry and statistically analyzed for the association with breast cancer bone metastases. Bone metastatic breast cancer SCP2 cells were induced for SOST silencing or overexpression and their bone metastatic behaviors were tested in vitro and in vivo. To identify potential therapeutics, we screened inhibitors of the interaction of SOST with STAT3 from a small chemical molecule library and tested the inhibitory effects of one inhibitor on breast cancer growth and bone metastasis in vitro and in vivo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; We found that up-regulated SOST expression was associated with breast cancer bone metastases and worse survival of breast cancer patients. SOST silencing significantly reduced the bone metastatic capacity of SCP2 cells. SOST interacted with STAT3 to enhance the TGF-β/KRAS signaling, increasing both tumor growth and bone metastasis. Treatment with one lead candidate, S6, significantly inhibited the growth of breast-cancer organoids and bone metastasis in mice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; Our findings highlight a new class of potential therapeutics for treatment of bone metastasis in breast cancer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Regulation of bone homeostasis by MERTK and TYRO3</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36509738/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36509738/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The fine equilibrium of bone homeostasis is maintained by bone-forming osteoblasts and bone-resorbing osteoclasts. Here, we show that TAM receptors MERTK and TYRO3 exert reciprocal effects in osteoblast biology: Osteoblast-targeted deletion of MERTK promotes increased bone mass in healthy mice and mice with cancer-induced bone loss, whereas knockout of TYRO3 in osteoblasts shows the opposite phenotype. Functionally, the interaction of MERTK with its ligand PROS1 negatively regulates osteoblast differentiation via inducing the VAV2-RHOA-ROCK axis leading to increased cell contractility and motility while TYRO3 antagonizes this effect. Consequently, pharmacologic MERTK blockade by the small molecule inhibitor R992 increases osteoblast numbers and bone formation in mice. Furthermore, R992 counteracts cancer-induced bone loss, reduces bone metastasis and prolongs survival in preclinical models of multiple myeloma, breast- and lung cancer. In summary, MERTK and TYRO3 represent potent regulators of bone homeostasis with cell-type specific functions and MERTK blockade represents an osteoanabolic therapy with implications in cancer and beyond.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>STAT3/mitophagy axis coordinates macrophage NLRP3 inflammasome activation and inflammatory bone loss</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36502520/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36502520/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Signal transducer and activator of transcription 3 (STAT3), a cytokine-responsive transcription factor, is known to play a role in immunity and bone remodeling. However, whether and how STAT3 impacts macrophage NLR family pyrin domain containing 3 (NLRP3) inflammasome activation associated with inflammatory bone loss remains unknown. Here, STAT3 signaling is hyperactivated in macrophages in the context of both non-sterile and sterile inflammatory osteolysis, and this was highly correlated with the cleaved interleukin-1β (IL-1β) expression pattern. Strikingly, pharmacological inhibition of STAT3 markedly blocks macrophage NLRP3 inflammasome activation in vitro, thereby relieving inflammatory macrophage-amplified osteoclast formation and bone resorptive activity. Mechanistically, STAT3 inhibition in macrophages triggers PTEN-induced kinase 1 (PINK1)-dependent mitophagy that eliminates dysfunctional mitochondria, reverses mitochondrial membrane potential collapse, and inhibits mitochondrial reactive oxygen species release, thus inactivating the NLRP3 inflammasome. In vivo, STAT3 inhibition effectively protects mice from both infection-induced periapical lesions and aseptic titanium particle-mediated calvarial bone erosion with potent induction of PINK1 and downregulation of inflammasome activation, macrophage infiltration, and osteoclast formation. This study reveals the regulatory role of the STAT3/mitophagy axis at the osteo-immune interface and highlights a potential therapeutic intervention to prevent inflammatory bone loss.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Injectable MMP1-sensitive microspheres with spatiotemporally controlled exosome release promote neovascularized bone healing</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36481504/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36481504/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bone marrow mesenchymal stromal cell-derived exosomes (BMSC-Exos) can recruit stem cells for bone repair, with neovessels serving as the main migratory channel for stem cells to the injury site. However, existing exosome (Exo) delivery strategies cannot reach the angiogenesis phase following bone injury. To that end, an enzyme-sensitive Exo delivery material that responds to neovessel formation during the angiogenesis phase was designed in the present study to achieve spatiotemporally controlled Exo release. Herein, matrix metalloproteinase-1 (MMP1) was found to be highly expressed in neovascularized bone; as a result, we proposed an injectable MMP1-sensitive hydrogel microspheres (KGE) made using a microfluidic chip prepared by mixing self-assembling peptide (KLDL-MMP1), GelMA, and BMSC-Exos. The results revealed that KGE microspheres had a uniform diameter of 50-70 μm, ideal for minimally invasive injection and could release exosomes in response to MMP1 expression. In vitro experiments demonstrated that KGE had less cytotoxicity and could promote the migration and osteodifferentiation of BMSCs. Furthermore, in vivo experiments confirmed that KGE could promote bone repair during angiogenesis by recruiting CD90+ stem cells via neovessels. Collectively, our results suggest that injectable enzyme-responsive KGE microspheres could be a promising Exo-secreting material for accelerating neovascularized bone healing. STATEMENT OF SIGNIFICANCE: Exosomes can spread through blood vessels and activate stem cells to participate in bone repair, but under normal circumstances, exosomes lacking sustained-release delivery materials cannot be maintained until the angiogenesis phase. In this study, we found that MMP1 was highly expressed in neovascularized bone, then we proposed an MMP1-sensitive injectable microsphere that carries exosomes and responds temporally and spatially to neovascularization, which maximizes the ability of exosomes to recruit stem cells. Different from previous strategies that focus on promoting angiogenesis to accelerate bone healing, this is a brand new delivery strategy that is stimuli-responsive to neovessel formation. In addition, the preparation of self-assembled peptide microspheres by a microfluidic chip is also proposed for the first time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Do Extracellular Vesicles Play a Key Role in the Maintenance of Bone Homeostasis and Regeneration? A Comprehensive Review of Literature</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/36419718/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/36419718/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The maintenance of bone homeostasis includes both bone resorption by osteoclasts and bone formation by osteoblasts. These two processes are in dynamic balance to maintain a constant amount of bone for accomplishing its critical functions in daily life. Multiple cell type communications are involved in these two complex and continuous processes. In recent decades, an increasing number of studies have shown that osteogenic and osteoclastic extracellular vesicles play crucial roles in regulating bone homeostasis through paracrine, autosecretory and endocrine signaling. Elucidating the functional roles of extracellular vesicles in the maintenance of bone homeostasis may contribute to the design of new strategies for bone regeneration. Hence, we review the recent understandings of the classification, production process, extraction methods, structure, contents, functions and applications of extracellular vesicles in bone homeostasis. We highlight the contents of various bone-derived extracellular vesicles and their interactions with different cells in the bone microenvironment during bone homeostasis. We also summarize the recent advances in EV-loaded biomaterial scaffolds for bone regeneration and repair.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exosome modification to better alleviates endoplasmic reticulum stress induced chondrocyte apoptosis and osteoarthritis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36370754/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36370754/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Osteoarthritis (OA) is characterized by cartilage matrix degeneration and chondrocyte apoptosis. Prolonged endoplasmic reticulum (ER) stress participates in chondrocyte apoptosis and cartilage degeneration in OA progression. miR-486-5p could suppress the apoptosis of nucleus pulposus cells and cardiomyocyte, yet whether miR-486-5p modified exosomes could modulate ER stress and apoptosis of chondrocytes remain unknown. We validated the increased inflammation and ER stress in OA synovium and cartilage, and the inhibition of ER stress could attenuate the IL-1β induced chondrocyte apoptosis. Administration of exogenous miR-486-5p could inhibit the ER stress, alleviate chondrocytes apoptosis and promote matrix regeneration. In comparison with direct administration of miR-486-5p and miR-486-5p overexpressing ADSCs, miR-486-5p modified exosomes indicated a better effect in modulating chondrocyte homeostasis. MiR-486-5p containing exosomes could also regulate macrophage polarization. Our IVIS imaging data validated that intraarticular injection of miR-486-5p containing exosomes could sustain for at least 7 days. MiR-486-5p containing exosomes showed a better effect on alleviating rats OA compared with direct administration of miR-486-5p and miR-486-5p overexpressing ADSCs. Our data demonstrated that miR-486-5p modified exosomes have a better effect on alleviating chondrocyte apoptosis and osteoarthritis. This study provides evidence of this efficient strategy of exosomal miRNA delivery and the miRNA-based therapy for OA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gasdermin D maintains bone mass by rewiring the endo-lysosomal pathway of osteoclastic bone resorption</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36243012/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36243012/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gasdermin D (GSDMD)-mediated pyroptosis induces immunogenic cell death and promotes inflammation. However, the functions of GSDMD in tissue homeostasis remain unclear. Here, we identify a physiological function of GSDMD in osteoclasts via a non-lytic p20-generated protein, which prevents bone loss to maintain bone homeostasis. In the late stage of RANKL-induced osteoclastogenesis, GSDMD underwent cleavage, which is dependent on RIPK1 and caspase-8/-3, to yield this p20 product. Gsdmd-deficient osteoclasts showed normal differentiation but enhanced bone resorption with excessive lysosomal activity. Mice with complete or myeloid-specific Gsdmd deletion exhibited increased trabecular bone loss and more severe aging/ovariectomy-induced osteoporosis. GSDMD p20 was preferentially localized to early endosomes and limited endo-lysosomal trafficking and maturation, relying on its oligomerization and control of phosphoinositide conversion by binding to phosphatidylinositol 3-phosphate (PI(3)P). We have thus identified an anti-osteoclastic function of GSDMD as a checkpoint for lysosomal maturation and secretion and linked this to bone homeostasis and endosome-lysosome biology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A neuronal action of sirtuin 1 suppresses bone mass in young and aging mice</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36194488/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36194488/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The various functions of the skeleton are influenced by extracellular cues, hormones, and neurotransmitters. One type of neuronal regulation favors bone mass accrual by inhibiting sympathetic nervous system (SNS) activity. This observation raises questions about the transcriptional mechanisms regulating catecholamine synthesis. Using a combination of genetic and pharmacological studies, we found that the histone deacetylase sirtuin 1 (SIRT1) is a transcriptional modulator of the neuronal control of bone mass. Neuronal SIRT1 reduced bone mass by increasing SNS signaling. SIRT1 did so by increasing expression of monoamine oxidase A (MAO-A), a SIRT1 target that reduces brain serotonin levels by inducing its catabolism and by suppressing tryptophan hydroxylase 2 (Tph2) expression and serotonin synthesis in the brain stem. SIRT1 upregulated brain catecholamine synthesis indirectly through serotonin, but did not directly affect dopamine β hydroxylase (Dbh) expression in the locus coeruleus. These results help us to understand skeletal changes associated with selective serotonin reuptake inhibitors (SSRIs) and may have implications for treating skeletal and metabolic diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Targeting FoxO transcription factors with HDAC inhibitors for the treatment of osteoarthritis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36109140/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36109140/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Objectives:&lt;/em&gt; Osteoarthritis (OA) features ageing-related defects in cellular homeostasis mechanisms in articular cartilage. These defects are associated with suppression of forkhead box O (FoxO) transcription factors. FoxO1 or FoxO3 deficient mice show early onset OA while FoxO1 protects against oxidative stress in chondrocytes and promotes expression of autophagy genes and the essential joint lubricant proteoglycan 4 (PRG4). The objective of this study was to identify small molecules that can increase FoxO1 expression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; We constructed a reporter cell line with FoxO1 promoter sequences and performed high-throughput screening (HTS) of the Repurposing, Focused Rescue and Accelerated Medchem (ReFRAME) library . Hits from the HTS were validated and function was assessed in human chondrocytes, meniscus cells and synoviocytes and following administration to mice. The most promising hit, the histone deacetylase inhibitor (HDACI) panobinostat was tested in a murine OA model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; Among the top hits were HDACI and testing in human chondrocytes, meniscus cells and synoviocytes showed that panobinostat was the most promising compound as it increased the expression of autophagy genes and PRG4 while suppressing the basal and IL-1β induced expression of inflammatory mediators and extracellular matrix degrading enzymes. Intraperitoneal administration of panobinostat also suppressed the expression of mediators of OA pathogenesis induced by intra-articular injection of IL-1β. In a murine OA model, panobinostat reduced the severity of histological changes in cartilage, synovium and subchondral bone and improved pain behaviours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/em&gt; Panobinostat has a clinically relevant activity profile and is a candidate for OA symptom and structure modification.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Propionate and butyrate attenuate macrophage pyroptosis and osteoclastogenesis induced by CoCrMo alloy particles</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35996168/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35996168/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Wear particles-induced osteolysis is a major long-term complication after total joint arthroplasty. Up to now, there is no effective treatment for wear particles-induced osteolysis except for the revision surgery, which is a heavy psychological and economic burden to patients. A metabolite of gut microbiota, short chain fatty acids (SCFAs), has been reported to be beneficial for many chronic inflammatory diseases. This study aimed to investigate the therapeutic effect of SCFAs on osteolysis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; A model of inflammatory osteolysis was established by applying CoCrMo alloy particles to mouse calvarium. After two weeks of intervention, the anti-inflammatory effects of SCFAs on wear particle-induced osteolysis were evaluated by Micro-CT analysis and immunohistochemistry staining. In vitro study, lipopolysaccharide (LPS) primed bone marrow-derived macrophages (BMDMs) and Tohoku Hospital Pediatrics-1 (THP-1) macrophages were stimulated with CoCrMo particles to activate inflammasome in the presence of acetate (C2), propionate (C3), and butyrate (C4). Western blotting, Enzyme-linked immunosorbent assay, and immunofluorescence were used to detect the activation of NLRP3 inflammasome. The effects of SCFAs on osteoclasts were evaluate by qRT-PCR, Western blotting, immunofluorescence, and tartrate-resistant acid phosphatase (TRAP) staining. Additionally, histone deacetylase (HDAC) inhibitors, agonists of GPR41, GPR43, and GPR109A were applied to confirm the underlying mechanism of SCFAs on the inflammasome activation of macrophages and osteoclastogenesis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; C3 and C4 but not C2 could alleviate wear particles-induced osteolysis with fewer bone erosion pits (P &amp;lt; 0.001), higher level of bone volume to tissue volume (BV/TV, P &amp;lt; 0.001), bone mineral density (BMD, P &amp;lt; 0.001), and a lower total porosity (P &amp;lt; 0.001). C3 and C4 prevented CoCrMo alloy particles-induced ASC speck formation and nucleation-induced oligomerization, suppressing the cleavage of caspase-1 (P &amp;lt; 0.05) and IL-1β (P &amp;lt; 0.05) stimulated by CoCrMo alloy particles. C3 and C4 also inhibited the generation of Gasdermin D-N-terminal fragment (GSDMD-NT) to regulate pyroptosis. Besides, C3 and C4 have a negative impact on osteoclast differentiation (P &amp;lt; 0.05) and its function (P &amp;lt; 0.05), affecting the podosome arrangement and morphologically normal podosome belts formation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/em&gt; Our work showed that C3 and C4 are qualified candidates for the treatment of wear particle-induced osteolysis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Circular RNA circFIRRE drives osteosarcoma progression and metastasis through tumorigenic-angiogenic coupling</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35986280/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35986280/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Disappointing clinical efficacy of standard treatment has been proven in refractory metastatic osteosarcoma, and the emerging anti-angiogenic regimens are still in the infantile stage. Thus, there is an urgent need to develop novel therapeutic approach for osteosarcoma lung metastasis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;circFIRRE was selected from RNA-sequencing of 4 matched osteosarcoma and adjacent samples. The expression of circFIRRE was verified in clinical osteosarcoma samples and cell lines via quantitative real-time polymerase chain reaction (RT-qPCR). The effect of circFIRRE was investigated in cell lines in vitro models, ex vivo models and in vivo xenograft tumor models, including proliferation, invasion, migration, metastasis and angiogenesis. Signaling regulatory mechanism was evaluated by RT-qPCR, Western blot, RNA pull-down and dual-luciferase reporter assays.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article, a novel circular RNA, circFIRRE (hsa_circ_0001944) was screened out and identified from RNA-sequencing, and was upregulated in both osteosarcoma cell lines and tissues. Clinically, aberrantly upregulated circFIRRE portended higher metastatic risk and worse prognosis in osteosarcoma patients. Functionally, in vitro, ex vivo and in vivo experiments demonstrated that circFIRRE could drive primary osteosarcoma progression and lung metastasis by inducing both tumor cells and blood vessels, we call as “tumorigenic-angiogenic coupling”. Mechanistically, upregulated circFIRRE was induced by transcription factor YY1, and partially boosted the mRNA and protein level of LUZP1 by sponging miR-486-3p and miR-1225-5p.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We identified circFIRRE as a master regulator in the tumorigenesis and angiogenesis of osteosarcoma, which could be purposed as a novel prognostic biomarker and therapeutic target for refractory osteosarcoma.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extracellular histones aggravate autoimmune arthritis by lytic cell death</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36032105/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36032105/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although recent studies have demonstrated a proinflammatory effect of extracellular histones in sepsis via endothelial cytotoxicity, little is known about their contribution to autoimmune arthritis. Therefore, we investigated the role of extracellular histones in autoimmune arthritis and their cytotoxic effect on synoviocytes and macrophages. We measured histones in the synovial fluid of patients with rheumatoid arthritis (RA) and evaluated arthritis severity in a serum-transfer arthritis (STA) mouse model with intraperitoneal histone injection. Histone-induced cytotoxicity was measured using SYTOX green staining in the synoviocyte cell line MH7A and macrophages differentiated from the monocytic cell line THP-1, and the production of damage-associated molecular patterns (DAMPs) was measured by HMGB1 and ATP. Furthermore, we performed RNA-seq analysis of THP-1 cells stimulated with H2B-α1 peptide or with its citrullinated form. The levels of histones were elevated in RA synovial fluid, and histones aggravated arthritis in the STA model. Histones induced cytotoxicity and DAMP production in synoviocytes and macrophages. Chondroitin sulfate reduced histone-induced cytotoxicity, while lipopolysaccharides aggravated cytotoxicity. Moreover, the cytotoxicity decreased when the arginines in H2B-α1 were replaced with citrullines, which demonstrated its electrostatic nature. In transcriptome analysis, H2B-α1 changed the gene expression pattern of THP-1 cells involving chemokines, interleukin-1, -4, -10, -13, and toll-like receptor (TLR) signaling pathways. Extracellular histones were increased in RA synovial fluid and aggravated synovitis in STA. They induced lytic cell death through electrostatic interaction with synoviocytes and macrophages, leading to the secretion of DAMPs. These findings suggest that histones play a central role in autoimmune arthritis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Circular RNA circNFKB1 promotes osteoarthritis progression through interacting with ENO1 and sustaining NF-κB signaling</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35945200/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35945200/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inflammatory cytokines-induced activation of the nuclear factor κB (NF-κB) pathway plays a critical role in the pathogenesis of osteoarthritis (OA). Circular RNA (circRNA) has been identified as important epigenetic factor in numerous diseases. However, the biological roles of inflammation-related circRNAs in regulating OA pathogenesis remain elusive. Here, we revealed circRNA expression profiles in human primary chondrocytes with interleukin-1β (IL-1β) stimulation by circRNA sequencing. We identified a highly upregulated circRNA, termed as circNFKB1 in inflamed chondrocytes and osteoarthritic cartilage. As a circRNA derived from exon 2-5 of NFKB1, circNFKB1 is located in both cytoplasm and nucleus of chondrocytes. Furthermore, knockdown of circNFKB1 inhibited extracellular matrix (ECM) catabolism and rescued IL-1β impaired ECM anabolism whereas ectopic expression of circNFKB1 significantly promoted chondrocytes degradation in vitro. Moreover, intraarticular injection of adenovirus-circNFKB1 in mouse joints triggered spontaneous cartilage loss and OA development. Mechanistically, circNFKB1 interacted with α-enolase (ENO1), regulated the expression of its parental gene NFKB1 and sustained the activation of NF-κB signaling pathway in chondrocytes. Therefore, this study highlights a novel ENO1-interacting circNFKB1 in OA pathogenesis, and provides valuable insights into understanding the regulatory mechanism of NF-κB signaling in chondrocytes and a promising therapeutic target for the treatment of OA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dynamic changes in O-GlcNAcylation regulate osteoclast differentiation and bone loss via nucleoporin 153</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35879285/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35879285/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bone mass is maintained by the balance between osteoclast-induced bone resorption and osteoblast-triggered bone formation. In inflammatory arthritis such as rheumatoid arthritis (RA), however, increased osteoclast differentiation and activity skew this balance resulting in progressive bone loss. O-GlcNAcylation is a posttranslational modification with attachment of a single O-linked β-D-N-acetylglucosamine (O-GlcNAc) residue to serine or threonine residues of target proteins. Although O-GlcNAcylation is one of the most common protein modifications, its role in bone homeostasis has not been systematically investigated. We demonstrate that dynamic changes in O-GlcNAcylation are required for osteoclastogenesis. Increased O-GlcNAcylation promotes osteoclast differentiation during the early stages, whereas its downregulation is required for osteoclast maturation. At the molecular level, O-GlcNAcylation affects several pathways including oxidative phosphorylation and cell-cell fusion. TNFα fosters the dynamic regulation of O-GlcNAcylation to promote osteoclastogenesis in inflammatory arthritis. Targeted pharmaceutical or genetic inhibition of O-GlcNAc transferase (OGT) or O-GlcNAcase (OGA) arrests osteoclast differentiation during early stages of differentiation and during later maturation, respectively, and ameliorates bone loss in experimental arthritis. Knockdown of NUP153, an O-GlcNAcylation target, has similar effects as OGT inhibition and inhibits osteoclastogenesis. These findings highlight an important role of O-GlcNAcylation in osteoclastogenesis and may offer the potential to therapeutically interfere with pathologic bone resorption.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>N6-Methyladenosine-induced miR-143-3p promotes intervertebral disc degeneration by regulating SOX5</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35878746/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35878746/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Intervertebral disc degeneration is the basic cause of lumbocrural pain, which not only causes pain and but also serious economic burdens on patients. Increasingly more evidence has shown that tumor necrosis factor-α (TNF-α) is involved in the pathological process of intervertebral disc degeneration, but the specific molecular mechanism is still unclear. This study investigated the potential mechanism and function of methyltransferase-like 3 (METTL3)/miR-143-3p/SOX5 regulatory axis in nucleus pulposus cells under the action of TNF-α. Human nucleus pulposus cells were treated with TNF-α to construct an in vitro model of intervertebral disc degeneration. Flow cytometry, quantitative reverse-transcription PCR (RT-qPCR), Western blot (WB) and luciferase assays were used to identify the mechanism of action of miR-143-3p in the course of intervertebral disc degeneration in vitro and the downstream targeted regulatory molecules. The role of miR-143-3p in intervertebral disc degeneration was also validated by in vivo. RT-qPCR, WB, coimmunoprecipitation (Co-IP) and flow cytometry were used to verify the regulatory effect of METTL3 on miR-143-3p maturation. RT-qPCR and WB were adopted to detect differences in METTL3, miR-143-3p and SOX5 expression in human nucleus pulposus tissue. miR-143-3p in nucleus pulposus cells was involved in the regulation of extracellular matrix metabolism and apoptosis after TNF-α stimulation, and intervertebral disc degeneration was relieved by effectively regulating miR-143-3p expression. Subsequent experiments showed that the downstream direct target gene of miR-143-3p was SOX5 and that miR-143-3p negatively regulated the expression of SOX5. In addition, METTL3 promoted miR-143-3p maturation, and METTL3 and miR-143-3p were significantly upregulated in degenerative nucleus pulposus, an effect that was significantly negatively correlated with low SOX5 expression. In conclusion, TNF-α upregulates METTL3, METTL3 promotes miR-143-3p maturation, and miR-143-3p inhibits the transcriptional activity of SOX5 through targeted binding, thereby inducing intervertebral disc degeneration. The inhibition of METTL3 or miR-143-3p expression may be an effective way to treat intervertebral disc degeneration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anti-inflammatory protective effect of ADAMTS-13 in murine arthritis models</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35875933/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35875933/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Patients with rheumatoid arthritis (RA) have frequent thrombotic events with endothelial dysfunction. Von Willebrand factor (VWF) has been shown to bind neutrophil extracellular traps (NETs) and NETs are part of RA etiology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Objectives:&lt;/em&gt; This study aims to elucidate whether this prothrombotic status exacerbates inflammation in arthritis. Here we focus on the involvement of A Disintegrin And Metalloprotease with ThromboSpondin type 1 motif, member 13 (ADAMTS-13), an enzyme cleaving VWF and its effect on NET deposition and RA development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; We evaluated the influence of the Adamts13 gene and recombinant human ADAMTS-13 (rhADAMTS-13) on arthritis in the mouse models of collagen-induced arthritis (CIA). We also assessed VWF and NETs in synovial tissue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; Several &lt;em&gt;Adamts13&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; mice developed arthritis, while &lt;em&gt;Adamts13&lt;sup&gt;+/+&lt;sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; siblings did not. Synovial tissue from &lt;em&gt;Adamts13&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; showed accumulation of NETs. Treatment of DBA/1 J mice, an arthritis-susceptible strain, with well-tolerated doses of rhADAMT13 reduced arthritis incidence and alleviated the severity of arthritis. Mice treated with rhADAMT13 presented less serum interleukin 6 and less bone erosion determined by micro-computed tomography. The effects on arthritis severity were observed both when administering rhADAMTS-13 prophylactically and also when given after arthritis has developed. In both conditions, rhADAMTS-13 reduced VWF and NET deposition on proliferated synovial tissue evaluated by immunoblotting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; Our results demonstrate the inhibitory role of &lt;em&gt;Adamts13&lt;/em&gt; in murine arthritis and the effectiveness of rhADAMTS-13 treatment. Additionally, this study suggests that deposition of VWF in the synovium and subsequent pathogenic NET retention promotes arthritis. Treatment with rhADAMTS-13 provides a potential therapeutic approach targeting inflammation and pro-thrombotic state in arthritis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Histone demethylase JMJD3 downregulation protects against aberrant force-induced osteoarthritis through epigenetic control of NR4A1</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35831280/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35831280/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Osteoarthritis (OA) is a prevalent joint disease with no effective treatment strategies. Aberrant mechanical stimuli was demonstrated to be an essential factor for OA pathogenesis. Although multiple studies have detected potential regulatory mechanisms underlying OA and have concentrated on developing novel treatment strategies, the epigenetic control of OA remains unclear. Histone demethylase JMJD3 has been reported to mediate multiple physiological and pathological processes, including cell differentiation, proliferation, autophagy, and apoptosis. However, the regulation of JMJD3 in aberrant force-related OA and its mediatory effect on disease progression are still unknown. In this work, we confirmed the upregulation of JMJD3 in aberrant force-induced cartilage injury in vitro and in vivo. Functionally, inhibition of JMJD3 by its inhibitor, GSK-J4, or downregulation of JMJD3 by adenovirus infection of sh-JMJD3 could alleviate the aberrant force-induced chondrocyte injury. Mechanistic investigation illustrated that aberrant force induces JMJD3 expression and then demethylates H3K27me3 at the NR4A1 promoter to promote its expression. Further experiments indicated that NR4A1 can regulate chondrocyte apoptosis, cartilage degeneration, extracellular matrix degradation, and inflammatory responses. In vivo, anterior cruciate ligament transection (ACLT) was performed to construct an OA model, and the therapeutic effect of GSK-J4 was validated. More importantly, we adopted a peptide-siRNA nanoplatform to deliver si-JMJD3 into articular cartilage, and the severity of joint degeneration was remarkably mitigated. Taken together, our findings demonstrated that JMJD3 is flow-responsive and epigenetically regulates OA progression. Our work provides evidences for JMJD3 inhibition as an innovative epigenetic therapy approach for joint diseases by utilizing p5RHH-siRNA nanocomplexes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NIR-driven polydopamine-based nanoenzymes as ROS scavengers to suppress osteoarthritis progression</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/mtnano.2022.100240/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/mtnano.2022.100240/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The excessive reactive oxygen species (ROS) is always associated with the degradation of cartilage matrix during osteoarthritis (OA). The development of novel nanoenzymes with excellent ROS scavenging ability and biosafety shows great potentials for improving OA treatment. Herein a novel functional polydopamine (P) loading with ultrasmall Pt and Cu nanoparticles (P@Pt@Cu) was developed to act as nanoenzymes to scavenge ROS for OA treatment, wherein the excellent catalytic activities of Pt and Cu were employed. Results showed that P@Pt@Cu simultaneously presented obvious enzyme-mimicking properties like superoxide dismutase, catalase, and glutathione peroxidase, leading to excellent antioxidant and anti-inflammatory activities in H2O2 stimulated chondrocytes and OA joints with low cytotoxicity, leading to significant alleviation of OA progression. Besides, near infrared stimulation strengthened the antioxidant and anti-inflammation ability of P@Pt@Cu, resulting in the most prominent therapeutic effects. The proposed polydopamine-based nanoenzymes inspired a novel therapeutic strategy for OA therapy in clinic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intraarticularly injectable silk hydrogel microspheres with enhanced mechanical and structural stability to attenuate osteoarthritis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35660867/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35660867/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A silk fibroin (silk) hydrogel was prepared by using diglycidyl ether (BDDE), a chemical crosslinker commonly used to generate Food and Drug Administration (FDA)-approved hyaluronic acid (HA) medical products. The silk/BDDE hydrogels exhibited high elasticity (compressive modulus of 166 ± 15.0 kPa), anti-fatigue properties, and stable structure and mechanical strength in aqueous solution. Chemical crosslinking was conducted in a high concentration (9.3 M) of lithium bromide (LiBr) solution, a salt that is commonly used to dissolve degummed silk fibers during silk solubilization. The unfolded and extended structure of silk molecules with these reaction conditions, as well as the unique ionic environment provided by LiBr facilitated a high degree of crosslinking in the hydrogel. Similar hydrogels were not obtained when the silk was dissolved in other silk fiber-dissolving reagents (——, Ajisawa&amp;rsquo;s, formic acid (FA)/LiBr, FA/CaCl&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; solutions), likely because partially folded silk structures and the ionic conditions with these reagents were less favorable for the crosslinking reaction. Based on these findings, silk/BDDE hydrogel spheres were prepared using an oil/water (o/w) emulsification method and biocompatibility and biodegradation were evaluated in vivo, along with other silk gel control systems (e.g., enzyme-catalyzed di-tyrosine and pulverized silk/BDDE gel particles with irregular shapes). Histological and immunohistochemical analyses demonstrated that the silk/BDDE hydrogel spheres were biocompatible and served as a bio-lubricant to treat osteoarthritis (OA). The intra-articular injection of the gel spheres reduced pain as measured with OA rats, reduced cartilage damage and resisted the digestive environment in the articular cavity for extended time frames (&amp;gt;4 weeks), suggesting utility for pain relief and sustained drug release for future OA treatments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Autophagic LC3&#43; calcified extracellular vesicles initiate cartilage calcification in osteoarthritis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35544558/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35544558/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pathological cartilage calcification plays an important role in osteoarthritis progression but in which the origin of calcified extracellular vesicles (EVs) and their effects remain unknown. Here, we demonstrate that pathological cartilage calcification occurs in the early stage of the osteoarthritis in which the calcified EVs are closely involved. Autophagosomes carrying the minerals are released in EVs, and calcification is induced by those autophagy-regulated calcified EVs. Autophagy-derived microtubule-associated proteins 1A/1B light chain 3B (LC3)-positive EVs are the major population of calcified EVs that initiate pathological calcification. Release of LC3-positive calcified EVs is caused by blockage of the autophagy flux resulted from histone deacetylase 6 (HDAC6)-mediated microtubule destabilization. Inhibition of HDAC6 activity blocks the release of the LC3-positive calcified EVs by chondrocytes and effectively reverses the pathological calcification and degradation of cartilage. The present work discovers that calcified EVs derived from autophagosomes initiate pathological cartilage calcification in osteoarthritis, with potential therapeutic targeting implication.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Construction of a magnesium hydroxide/graphene oxide/hydroxyapatite composite coating on Mg-Ca-Zn-Ag alloy to inhibit bacterial infection and promote bone regeneration</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35415306/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35415306/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A Mg(OH)&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;/GO/HA composite coating with high bonding strength was constructed on the surface of Mg–Ca–Zn–Ag alloy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The outer HA layer with excellent osteogenic activity recovered the high corrosion resistance of inner Mg(OH)&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; layer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Mg(OH)&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;/GO/HA composite coating promoted new bone regeneration significantly under both normal and infected conditions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The improved corrosion resistance, osteogenic activity, and antibacterial ability are the key factors for promoting the large-scale clinical application of magnesium (Mg)-based implants. In the present study, a novel nanocomposite coating composed of inner magnesium hydroxide, middle graphene oxide, and outer hydroxyapatite (Mg(OH)&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;/GO/HA) is constructed on the surface of Mg-0.8Ca-5Zn-1.5Ag by a combined strategy of hydrothermal treatment, electrophoretic deposition, and electrochemical deposition. The results of material characterization and electrochemical corrosion test showed that all the three coatings have high bonding strength, hydrophilicity and corrosion resistance. In vitro studies show that Mg(OH)&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; indeed improves the antibacterial activity of the substrate. The next GO and GO/HA coating procedures both promote the osteogenic differentiation of MC3T3-E1 cells and show no harm to the antibacterial activity of Mg(OH)&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; coating, but the latter exhibits the best promoting effect. In vivo studies demonstrate that the Mg alloy with the composite coating not only ameliorates osteolysis induced by bacterial invasion but also promotes bone regeneration under both normal and infected conditions. The current study provides a promising surface modification strategy for developing multifunctional Mg-based implants with good corrosion resistance, antibacterial ability and osteogenic activity to enlarge their biomedical applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Targeting macrophagic SHP2 for ameliorating osteoarthritis via TLR signaling</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35865095/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35865095/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therapeutics that discriminate between the genetic makeup of normal cells and tumour cells are valuable for treating and understanding cancer. Small molecules with oncogene-selective lethality may reveal novel functions of oncoproteins and enable the creation of more selective drugs. Here we describe the mechanism of action of the selective anti-tumour agent erastin, involving the RAS-RAF-MEK signalling pathway functioning in cell proliferation, differentiation and survival. Erastin exhibits greater lethality in human tumour cells harbouring mutations in the oncogenes HRAS, KRAS or BRAF. Using affinity purification and mass spectrometry, we discovered that erastin acts through mitochondrial voltage-dependent anion channels (VDACs)&amp;ndash;a novel target for anti-cancer drugs. We show that erastin treatment of cells harbouring oncogenic RAS causes the appearance of oxidative species and subsequent death through an oxidative, non-apoptotic mechanism. RNA-interference-mediated knockdown of VDAC2 or VDAC3 caused resistance to erastin, implicating these two VDAC isoforms in the mechanism of action of erastin. Moreover, using purified mitochondria expressing a single VDAC isoform, we found that erastin alters the permeability of the outer mitochondrial membrane. Finally, using a radiolabelled analogue and a filter-binding assay, we show that erastin binds directly to VDAC2. These results demonstrate that ligands to VDAC proteins can induce non-apoptotic cell death selectively in some tumour cells harbouring activating mutations in the RAS-RAF-MEK pathway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intestinal butyrate-metabolizing species contribute to autoantibody production and bone erosion in rheumatoid arthritis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35148177/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35148177/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The imbalance between pathogenic and beneficial species of the intestinal microbiome and metabolism in rheumatoid arthritis (RA) remains unclarified. Here, using shotgun-based metagenome sequencing for a treatment-naïve patient cohort and a &amp;ldquo;quasi-paired cohort&amp;rdquo; method, we observed a deficiency of butyrate-producing species and an overwhelming number of butyrate consumers in RA patients. These outcomes mainly occurred in patients with positive ACPA, with a mean AUC of 0.94. This panel was also validated in established RA with an AUC of 0.986 in those with joint deformity. In addition, we showed that butyrate promoted T&lt;sub&gt;regs&lt;/sub&gt;, while suppressing T&lt;sub&gt;convs&lt;/sub&gt; and osteoclasts, due to potentiation of the reduction in HDAC expression and down-regulation of proinflammatory cytokine genes. Dietary butyrate supplementation conferred anti-inflammatory benefits in a mouse model by rebalancing T&lt;sub&gt;FH&lt;/sub&gt; cells and T&lt;sub&gt;regs&lt;/sub&gt;, as well as reducing antibody production. These findings reveal the critical role of butyrate-metabolizing species and suggest the potential of butyrate-based therapies for RA patients.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Procalcitonin is expressed in osteoblasts and limits bone resorption through inhibition of macrophage migration during intermittent PTH treatment</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35087025/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35087025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Intermittent injections of parathyroid hormone (iPTH) are applied clinically to stimulate bone formation by osteoblasts, although continuous elevation of parathyroid hormone (PTH) primarily results in increased bone resorption. Here, we identified &lt;em&gt;Calca&lt;/em&gt;, encoding the sepsis biomarker procalcitonin (ProCT), as a novel target gene of PTH in murine osteoblasts that inhibits osteoclast formation. During iPTH treatment, mice lacking ProCT develop increased bone resorption with excessive osteoclast formation in both the long bones and axial skeleton. Mechanistically, ProCT inhibits the expression of key mediators involved in the recruitment of macrophages, representing osteoclast precursors. Accordingly, ProCT arrests macrophage migration and causes inhibition of early but not late osteoclastogenesis. In conclusion, our results reveal a potential role of osteoblast-derived ProCT in the bone microenvironment that is required to limit bone resorption during iPTH.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nanotopography Sequentially Mediates Human Mesenchymal Stem Cell-Derived Small Extracellular Vesicles for Enhancing Osteogenesis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34935354/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34935354/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Engineered small extracellular vesicles (sEVs) are used as tools to enhance therapeutic efficacy. However, such application of sEVs is associated with several issues, including high costs and a high risk of tumorigenesis. Nanotopography has a greater influence on bone-related cell behaviors. However, whether nanotopography specifically mediate sEV content to perform particular biological functions remains unclear. Here, we demonstrate that selective nanotopography may be used to sequentially mediate human bone mesenchymal stem cell (hBMSC) sEVs to enhance the therapeutic efficacy of hBMSCs-EVs for osteogenesis. We subjected sEVs harvested from hBMSCs cultured on polished titanium plates (Ti) or nanotopographical titanium plates (Ti4) after 7, 14, and 21 d for RNA sequencing, and we found that there was no significant difference in sEV-miRNA expression after 7 d. Differentially expressed osteogenic-related microRNAs were founded after 14 days, and KEGG analysis indicated that the main microRNAs were associated with osteogenesis-related pathways, such as TGF-beta, AMPK, and FoxO. A significant difference was found in sEV-miRNAs expression after 21 d. We loaded sEV secreted from hBMSCs cultured on Ti4 after 21 d on 3D-printed porous PEEK scaffolds with poly dopamine (PDA) and found that such scaffolds showed superior osteogenic ability after 6- and 12-weeks. Here, we demonstrate the alkali- and heat-treated nanotopography with the ability of stimulating osteogenic differentiation of hBMSC can induce the secretion of pro-osteogenesis sEV, and we also found that sEVs meditate osteogenesis through miRNA. Thus, whether nanotopography has the ability to regulate other contents of sEVs such as proteins for enhancing osteogenesis needs further research. These findings may help us use nanotopography to extract sEVs for other biomedical applications, including cancer therapy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sympathetic Neurostress Drives Osteoblastic Exosomal MiR-21 Transfer to Disrupt Bone Homeostasis and Promote Osteopenia</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35312228/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35312228/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Innervation and extracellular vesicle secretion co-exist in the local tissue microenvironment for message transfer, but whether they are interconnected to regulate organ homeostasis remains unknown. Sympatho-adrenergic activation is implicated in stress-induced depression and leads to bone loss, but the mechanisms and therapeutics are incompletely elucidated. Here, it is revealed that sympathetic neurostress through the β1/2 -adrenergic receptor (β1/2-AR) signaling triggers the transcription response of a microRNA, miR-21, in osteoblasts, which is transferred to osteoclast progenitors via exosomes for dictating osteoclastogenesis. After confirming that miR-21 deficiency retards the β1/2-AR agonist isoproterenol (ISO)-induced osteopenia, it is shown that the pharmacological inhibition of exosome release by two clinically-relevant drugs, dimethyl amiloride and omeprazole, suppresses osteoblastic miR-21 transfer and ameliorates bone loss under both ISO and chronic variable stress (CVS)-induced depression conditions. A targeted delivery approach to specifically silence osteoblastic miR-21 is further applied, which is effective in rescuing the bone remodeling balance and ameliorating ISO- and CVS-induced osteopenias. These results decipher a previously unrecognized paradigm that neural cues drive exosomal microRNA communication to regulate organ homeostasis and help to establish feasible strategies to counteract bone loss under psychological stresses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clinical remission of rheumatoid arthritis in a multicenter real-world study in Asia-Pacific region</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34528015/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34528015/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Clinical remission is an attainable goal for Rheumatoid Arthritis (RA). However, data on RA remission rates from multinational studies in the Asia-Pacific region are limited. We conducted a cross-sectional multicentric study to evaluate the clinical remission status and the related factors in RA patients in the Asia-Pacific region.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; RA patients receiving standard care were enrolled consecutively from 17 sites in 11 countries from APLAR RA SIG group. Data were collected on-site by rheumatologists with a standardized case-report form. Remission was analyzed by different definitions including disease activity score using 28 joints (DAS28) based on ESR and CRP, clinical disease activity index (CDAI), simplified disease activity index (SDAI), Boolean remission definition, and clinical deep remission (CliDR). Logistic regression was used to determine related factors of remission.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Findings:&lt;/em&gt; A total of 2010 RA patients was included in the study, the overall remission rates were 62•3% (DAS28-CRP), 35•5% (DAS28-ESR), 30•8% (CDAI), 26•5% (SDAI), 24•7% (Boolean), and 17•1% (CliDR), respectively, and varied from countries to countries in the Asia-Pacific region. Biological and targeted synthetic disease-modifying antirheumatic drugs (b/tsDMARDs) prescription rate was low (17•9%). Compared to patients in non-remission, patients in remission had higher rates of b/tsDMARDs usage and lower rates of GC usage. The favorable related factors were male sex, younger age, fewer comorbidities, fewer extra-articular manifestations (EAM), and use of b/tsDMARDs, while treatment with GC was negatively related to remission.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Interpretation:&lt;/em&gt; Remission rates were low and varied in the Asia-Pacific region. Treatment with b/tsDMARDs and less GC usage were related to higher remission rate. There is an unmet need for RA remission in the Asia-Pacific region.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Circ_0008542 in osteoblast exosomes promotes osteoclast-induced bone resorption through m6A methylation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34145224/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34145224/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With an increasing aging society, China is the world&amp;rsquo;s fastest growing markets for oral implants. Compared with traditional oral implants, immediate implants cause marginal bone resorption and increase the failure rate of osseointegration, but the mechanism is still unknown. Therefore, it is important to further study mechanisms of tension stimulus on osteoblasts and osteoclasts at the early stage of osseointegration to promote rapid osseointegration around oral implants. The results showed that exosomes containing circ_0008542 from MC3T3-E1 cells with prolonged tensile stimulation promoted osteoclast differentiation and bone resorption. Circ_0008542 upregulated Tnfrsf11a (RANK) gene expression by acting as a miR-185-5p sponge. Meanwhile, the circ_0008542 1916-1992 bp segment exhibited increased m6A methylation levels. Inhibiting the RNA methyltransferase METTL3 or overexpressing the RNA demethylase ALKBH5 reversed osteoclast differentiation and bone resorption induced by circ_0008542. Injection of circ_0008542 + ALKBH5 into the tail vein of mice reversed the same effects in vivo. Site-directed mutagenesis study demonstrated that 1956 bp on circ_0008542 is the m6A functional site with the abovementioned biological functions. In conclusion, the RNA methylase METTL3 acts on the m6A functional site of 1956 bp in circ_0008542, promoting competitive binding of miRNA-185-5p by circ_0008542, and leading to an increase in the target gene RANK and the initiation of osteoclast bone absorption. In contrast, the RNA demethylase ALKBH5 inhibits the binding of circ_0008542 with miRNA-185-5p to correct the bone resorption process. The potential value of this study provides methods to enhance the resistance of immediate implants through use of exosomes releasing ALKBH5.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Circular RNA AFF4 modulates osteogenic differentiation in BM-MSCs by activating SMAD1/5 pathway through miR-135a-5p/FNDC5/Irisin axis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34145212/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34145212/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bone marrow-derived mesenchymal stem cells (BM-MSCs), the common progenitor cells of adipocytes and osteoblasts, have been recognized as the key mediator during bone formation. Herein, our study aim to investigate molecular mechanisms underlying circular RNA (circRNA) AFF4 (circ_AFF4)-regulated BM-MSCs osteogenesis. BM-MSCs were characterized by FACS, ARS, and ALP staining. Expression patterns of circ_AFF4, miR-135a-5p, FNDC5/Irisin, SMAD1/5, and osteogenesis markers, including ALP, BMP4, RUNX2, Spp1, and Colla1 were detected by qRT-PCR, western blot, or immunofluorescence staining, respectively. Interactions between circ_AFF4 and miR-135a-5p, FNDC5, and miR-135a-5p were analyzed using web tools including TargetScan, miRanda, and miRDB, and further confirmed by luciferase reporter assay and RNA pull-down. Complex formation between Irisin and Integrin αV was verified by Co-immunoprecipitation. To further verify the functional role of circ_AFF4 in vivo during bone formation, we conducted animal experiments harboring circ_AFF4 knockdown, and born samples were evaluated by immunohistochemistry, hematoxylin and eosin, and Masson staining. Circ_AFF4 was upregulated upon osteogenic differentiation induction in BM-MSCs, and miR-135a-5p expression declined as differentiation proceeds. Circ_AFF4 knockdown significantly inhibited osteogenesis potential in BM-MSCs. Circ_AFF4 stimulated FNDC5/Irisin expression through complementary binding to its downstream target molecule miR-135a-5p. Irisin formed an intermolecular complex with Integrin αV and activated the SMAD1/5 pathway during osteogenic differentiation. Our work revealed that circ_AFF4, acting as a sponge of miR-135a-5p, triggers the promotion of FNDC5/Irisin via activating the SMAD1/5 pathway to induce osteogenic differentiation in BM-MSCs. These findings gained a deeper insight into the circRNA-miRNA regulatory system in the bone marrow microenvironment and may improve our understanding of bone formation-related diseases at physiological and pathological levels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
