<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mendelian Randomization | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/mendelian-randomization/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/mendelian-randomization/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Mendelian Randomization</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Mendelian Randomization</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/mendelian-randomization/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>FinnGen provides genetic insights from a well-phenotyped isolated population</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36653562/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36653562/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Population isolates such as those in Finland benefit genetic research because deleterious alleles are often concentrated on a small number of low-frequency variants (0.1% ≤ minor allele frequency &amp;lt; 5%). These variants survived the founding bottleneck rather than being distributed over a large number of ultrarare variants. Although this effect is well established in Mendelian genetics, its value in common disease genetics is less explored. FinnGen aims to study the genome and national health register data of 500,000 Finnish individuals. Given the relatively high median age of participants (63 years) and the substantial fraction of hospital-based recruitment, FinnGen is enriched for disease end points. Here we analyse data from 224,737 participants from FinnGen and study 15 diseases that have previously been investigated in large genome-wide association studies (GWASs). We also include meta-analyses of biobank data from Estonia and the United Kingdom. We identified 30 new associations, primarily low-frequency variants, enriched in the Finnish population. A GWAS of 1,932 diseases also identified 2,733 genome-wide significant associations (893 phenome-wide significant (PWS), &lt;em&gt;P&lt;/em&gt; &amp;lt; 2.6 × 10&lt;sup&gt;-11&lt;/sup&gt;) at 2,496 (771 PWS) independent loci with 807 (247 PWS) end points. Among these, fine-mapping implicated 148 (73 PWS) coding variants associated with 83 (42 PWS) end points. Moreover, 91 (47 PWS) had an allele frequency of &amp;lt;5% in non-Finnish European individuals, of which 62 (32 PWS) were enriched by more than twofold in Finland. These findings demonstrate the power of bottlenecked populations to find entry points into the biology of common diseases through low-frequency, high impact variants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mono- and biallelic variant effects on disease at biobank scale</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36653560/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36653560/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Identifying causal factors for Mendelian and common diseases is an ongoing challenge in medical genetics. Population bottleneck events, such as those that occurred in the history of the Finnish population, enrich some homozygous variants to higher frequencies, which facilitates the identification of variants that cause diseases with recessive inheritance. Here we examine the homozygous and heterozygous effects of 44,370 coding variants on 2,444 disease phenotypes using data from the nationwide electronic health records of 176,899 Finnish individuals. We find associations for homozygous genotypes across a broad spectrum of phenotypes, including known associations with retinal dystrophy and novel associations with adult-onset cataract and female infertility. Of the recessive disease associations that we identify, 13 out of 20 would have been missed by the additive model that is typically used in genome-wide association studies. We use these results to find many known Mendelian variants whose inheritance cannot be adequately described by a conventional definition of dominant or recessive. In particular, we find variants that are known to cause diseases with recessive inheritance with significant heterozygous phenotypic effects. Similarly, we find presumed benign variants with disease effects. Our results show how biobanks, particularly in founder populations, can broaden our understanding of complex dosage effects of Mendelian variants on disease.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Circulating Proteins Influencing Psychiatric Disease: A Mendelian Randomization Study</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36280454/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36280454/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; There is a pressing need for novel drug targets for psychiatric disorders. Circulating proteins are potential candidates because they are relatively easy to measure and modulate and play important roles in signaling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; We performed two-sample Mendelian randomization analyses to estimate the associations between circulating protein abundances and risk of 10 psychiatric disorders. Genetic variants associated with 1611 circulating protein abundances identified in 6 large-scale proteomic studies were used as genetic instruments. Effects of the circulating proteins on psychiatric disorders were estimated by Wald ratio or inverse variance-weighted ratio tests. Horizontal pleiotropy, colocalization, and protein-altering effects were examined to validate the assumptions of Mendelian randomization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; Nine circulating protein-to-disease associations withstood multiple sensitivity analyses. Among them, 2 circulating proteins had associations replicated in 3 proteomic studies. A 1 standard deviation increase in the genetically predicted circulating TIMP4 level was associated with a reduced risk of anorexia nervosa (minimum odds ratio [OR] = 0.83; 95% CI, 0.76-0.91) and bipolar disorder (minimum OR = 0.88; 95% CI, 0.82-0.94). A 1 standard deviation increase in the genetically predicted circulating ESAM level was associated with an increased risk of schizophrenia (maximum OR = 1.32; 95% CI, 1.22-1.43). In addition, 58 suggestive protein-to-disease associations warrant validation with observational or experimental evidence. For instance, a 1 standard deviation increase in the ERLEC1-201-to-ERLEC1-202 splice variant ratio was associated with a reduced risk of schizophrenia (OR = 0.94; 95% CI, 0.90-0.97).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; Prioritized circulating proteins appear to influence the risk of psychiatric disease and may be explored as intervention targets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Circulating insulin-like growth factors and Alzheimer disease: A mendelian randomization study</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/29282328/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/29282328/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Objective:&lt;/em&gt; To examine whether genetically predicted variation in circulating insulin-like growth factor 1 (IGF1) or its binding protein, IGFBP3, are associated with risk of Alzheimer disease (AD), using a mendelian randomization study design.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; We first examined disease risk by genotypes of 9 insulin-like growth factor (IGF)-related single nucleotide polymorphisms (SNPs) using published summary genome-wide association statistics from the International Genomics of Alzheimer&amp;rsquo;s Project (IGAP; n = 17,008 cases; 37,154 controls). We then assessed whether any SNP-disease results replicated in an independent sample derived from the Swedish Twin Registry (n = 984 cases; 10,304 controls).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; Meta-analyses of SNP-AD results did not suggest that variation in IGF1, IGFBP3, or the molar ratio of these affect AD risk. Only one SNP appeared to affect AD risk in IGAP data. This variant is located in the gene &lt;em&gt;FOXO3&lt;/em&gt;, implicated in human longevity. In a meta-analysis of both IGAP and secondary data, the odds ratio of AD per &lt;em&gt;FOXO3&lt;/em&gt; risk allele was 1.04 (95% confidence interval 1.01-1.08; &lt;em&gt;p&lt;/em&gt; = 0.008).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; These findings suggest that circulating IGF1 and IGFBP3 are not important determinants of AD risk. &lt;em&gt;FOXO3&lt;/em&gt; function may influence AD development via pathways that are independent of IGF signaling (&lt;em&gt;i.e.&lt;/em&gt;, pleiotropic actions).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
