<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cell Communication | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/cell-communication/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/cell-communication/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Cell Communication</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Cell Communication</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/cell-communication/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Methods for inference and analysis of cell-cell communication</title>
      <link>https://example.com/blog/2023-01-02-infer-anal-ccc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/blog/2023-01-02-infer-anal-ccc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cellphonedb.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CellPhoneDB&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a publicly available repository of curated receptors, ligands and their interactions. Subunit architecture is included for both ligands and receptors, representing heteromeric complexes accurately. This is crucial, as cell-cell communication relies on multi-subunit protein complexes that go beyond the binary representation used in most databases and studies. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cellphonedb.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CellPhoneDB&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; integrates existing datasets that pertain to cellular communication and new manually reviewed information. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cellphonedb.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CellPhoneDB&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; utilises information from the following data bases: UniProt, Ensembl, PDB, the IMEx consortium, IUPHAR. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cellphonedb.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CellPhoneDB&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; can be used to search for a particular ligand/receptor or interrogate your own single-cell transcriptomics data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Reference(s):&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/34857954/&#34;&gt;Mapping the temporal and spatial dynamics of the human endometrium in vivo and in vitro&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/32103204/&#34;&gt;CellPhoneDB: Inferring cell-cell communication from combined expression of multi-subunit receptor-ligand complexes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Research into the Human Connectome has exploded since the original Human Connectome Project grants were awarded by the NIH in 2011. Over the next decade, we expect to see dozens of new projects at institutions around the world researching aspects of how age, growth, disease, and other factors can affect the ever-changing connections in the human brain. The &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.humanconnectome.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Connectome Coordination Facility (CCF)&lt;/a&gt; has been chartered to help coordinate these myriad research projects, harmonize their data, and facilitate the distribution and dissemination of results. The CCF has three primary aims:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Run a “data acquisition help desk,” to facilitate in the collection of HCP-style data for optimal comparability.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Maintain and expand the HCP informatics infrastructure, to host and distribute connectome data from multiple studies on &lt;a href=&#34;https://db.humanconnectome.org/app/template/Login.vm&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ConnectomeDB&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and Amazon Web Services.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Serve as a “harmonization center,” to make data from multiple studies and institutions as comparable as possible.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The goal of &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/arc85/celltalker&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;celltalker&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is to infer putative ligand and receptor interactions from single-cell RNAseq data. This is accomplished by evaluating known cognate ligand/receptor interactions across groups of cells. Interactions are scored by jointly weighting the expression levels of ligands and receptors, and significance is evaluated by comparing to a background distribution of scrambled ligands and receptors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Coolgenome/iTALK&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;iTALK&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is an R toolkit for characterizing and illustrating intercellular communication, developed and maintained by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mdanderson.org/research/departments-labs-institutes/labs/linghua-wang-laboratory.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Linghua Wang Lab&lt;/a&gt; at the University of Texas MD Anderson Cancer Center. &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Coolgenome/iTALK&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;iTALK&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; can be used to visualize the complexity, diversity and dynamics of cell-cell communication in a wide range of biological processes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Reference(s):&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/italk/&#34;&gt;iTALK: an R Package to Characterize and Illustrate Intercellular Communication&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Recent development of high throughput single-cell sequencing technologies has made it cost-effective to profile thousands of cells from a complex sample. Examining ligand and receptor expression patterns in the cell types identified from these datasets allows prediction of cell-to-cell communication at the level of niches, tissues and organism-wide. Here, we developed &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/forrest-lab/NATMI/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NATMI (Network Analysis Toolkit for Multicellular Interactions)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, a Python-based toolkit for multi-cellular communication network construction and network analysis of multispecies single-cell and bulk gene expression and proteomic data. &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/forrest-lab/NATMI/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NATMI&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; uses connectomeDB2020 (the most up-to-date manually curated ligand-receptor interaction list) and user supplied gene expression tables with cell type labels to predict and visualize cell-to-cell communication networks. By interrogating the Tabula Muris cell atlas we demonstrate the utility of &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/forrest-lab/NATMI/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NATMI&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; to identify cellular communities and the key ligands and receptors involved. Notably, we confirm our previous predictions from bulk data that autocrine signalling is a major feature of cell-to-cell communication networks and for the first time ever show a substantial potential for self-signalling of individual cells through hundreds of co-expressed ligand-receptor pairs. Lastly, we identify age related changes in intercellular communication between the mammary gland of 3 and 18-month-old mice in the Tabula Muris dataset. &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/forrest-lab/NATMI/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NATMI&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and our updated ligand-receptor lists are freely available to the research community.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fast, flexible and easy-to-use command-line tool to construct cell-to-cell communication networks from user-supplied multi-omics data (single-cell and bulk) in a variety of species.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Python-based (software requirements), but no additional coding in python is required. After the analysis is finished, results can be viewed directly or imported to other software of choice such as, for example, R or excel.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Built on connectomeDB2020 (default), but users can also add and interrogate their own interactions in any species or explore existing Tabula Muris, Tabula Muris Senis and FANTOM5 cell atlas datastets.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Reference(s):&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/33024107/&#34;&gt;Predicting cell-to-cell communication networks using NATMI&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cellchat.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CellChat Explorer&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; contains two major components: (a) Ligand-Receptor Interaction Explorer that allows easy exploration of our ligand-receptor interaction database, and (b) Cell-Cell Communication Atlas Explorer that allows easy exploration of the cell-cell communications for any given scRNA-seq dataset that has been processed by &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/sqjin/CellChat&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;R toolkit CellChat&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Reference(s):&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/33597522/&#34;&gt;Inference and analysis of cell-cell communication using CellChat&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/SCA-IRCM&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SingleCellSignalR&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a R package to study Cell Signaling Using Single Cell RNAseq Data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Reference(s):&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/32196115/&#34;&gt;SingleCellSignalR: inference of intercellular networks from single-cell transcriptomics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The goal of &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/saeyslab/nichenetr&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NicheNet&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is to study intercellular communication from a computational perspective. &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/saeyslab/nichenetr&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NicheNet&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; uses human or mouse gene expression data of interacting cells as input and combines this with a prior model that integrates existing knowledge on ligand-to-target signaling paths. This allows to predict ligand-receptor interactions that might drive gene expression changes in cells of interest.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Reference(s):&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/31819264/&#34;&gt;NicheNet: modeling intercellular communication by linking ligands to target genes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/blog/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Blog &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comparison of methods and resources for cell-cell communication inference from single-cell RNA-Seq data</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35680885/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35680885/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The growing availability of single-cell data, especially transcriptomics, has sparked an increased interest in the inference of cell-cell communication. Many computational tools were developed for this purpose. Each of them consists of a resource of intercellular interactions prior knowledge and a method to predict potential cell-cell communication events. Yet the impact of the choice of resource and method on the resulting predictions is largely unknown. To shed light on this, we systematically compare 16 cell-cell communication inference resources and 7 methods, plus the consensus between the methods’ predictions. Among the resources, we find few unique interactions, a varying degree of overlap, and an uneven coverage of specific pathways and tissue-enriched proteins. We then examine all possible combinations of methods and resources and show that both strongly influence the predicted intercellular interactions. Finally, we assess the agreement of cell-cell communication methods with spatial colocalisation, cytokine activities, and receptor protein abundance and find that predictions are generally coherent with those data modalities. To facilitate the use of the methods and resources described in this work, we provide LIANA, a LIgand-receptor ANalysis frAmework as an open-source interface to all the resources and methods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comprehensive insight into endothelial progenitor cell-derived extracellular vesicles as a promising candidate for disease treatment</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/35672766/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/35672766/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Endothelial progenitor cells (EPCs), which are a type of stem cell, have been found to have strong angiogenic and tissue repair capabilities. Extracellular vesicles (EVs) contain many effective components, such as cellular proteins, microRNAs, messenger RNAs, and long noncoding RNAs, and can be secreted by different cell types. The functions of EVs depend mainly on their parent cells. Many researchers have conducted functional studies of EPC-derived EVs (EPC-EVs) and showed that they exhibit therapeutic effects on many diseases, such as cardiovascular disease, acute kidney injury, acute lung injury, and sepsis. In this review article, we comprehensively summarized the biogenesis and functions of EPCs and EVs and the potent role of EPC-EVs in the treatment of various diseases. Furthermore, the current problems and future prospects have been discussed, and further studies are needed to compare the therapeutic effects of EVs derived from various stem cells, which will contribute to the accelerated translation of these applications in a clinical setting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mapping the temporal and spatial dynamics of the human endometrium in vivo and in vitro</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34857954/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34857954/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The endometrium, the mucosal lining of the uterus, undergoes dynamic changes throughout the menstrual cycle in response to ovarian hormones. We have generated dense single-cell and spatial reference maps of the human uterus and three-dimensional endometrial organoid cultures. We dissect the signaling pathways that determine cell fate of the epithelial lineages in the lumenal and glandular microenvironments. Our benchmark of the endometrial organoids reveals the pathways and cell states regulating differentiation of the secretory and ciliated lineages both in vivo and in vitro. In vitro downregulation of WNT or NOTCH pathways increases the differentiation efficiency along the secretory and ciliated lineages, respectively. We utilize our cellular maps to deconvolute bulk data from endometrial cancers and endometriotic lesions, illuminating the cell types dominating in each of these disorders. These mechanistic insights provide a platform for future development of treatments for common conditions including endometriosis and endometrial carcinoma.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inference and analysis of cell-cell communication using CellChat</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33597522/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33597522/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Understanding global communications among cells requires accurate representation of cell-cell signaling links and effective systems-level analyses of those links. We construct a database of interactions among ligands, receptors and their cofactors that accurately represent known heteromeric molecular complexes. We then develop &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/sqjin/CellChat&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CellChat&lt;/a&gt;, a tool that is able to quantitatively infer and analyze intercellular communication networks from single-cell RNA-sequencing (scRNA-seq) data. &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/sqjin/CellChat&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CellChat&lt;/a&gt; predicts major signaling inputs and outputs for cells and how those cells and signals coordinate for functions using network analysis and pattern recognition approaches. Through manifold learning and quantitative contrasts, &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/sqjin/CellChat&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CellChat&lt;/a&gt; classifies signaling pathways and delineates conserved and context-specific pathways across different datasets. Applying &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/sqjin/CellChat&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CellChat&lt;/a&gt; to mouse and human skin datasets shows its ability to extract complex signaling patterns. Our versatile and easy-to-use toolkit &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/sqjin/CellChat&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CellChat&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cellchat.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;a web-based Explorer&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; will help discover novel intercellular communications and build cell-cell communication atlases in diverse tissues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Predicting cell-to-cell communication networks using NATMI</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33024107/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33024107/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Development of high throughput single-cell sequencing technologies has made it cost-effective to profile thousands of cells from diverse samples containing multiple cell types. To study how these different cell types work together, here we develop &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/forrest-lab/NATMI/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NATMI (Network Analysis Toolkit for Multicellular Interactions)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/forrest-lab/NATMI/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NATMI&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; uses &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.humanconnectome.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;connectomeDB2020&lt;/a&gt; (a database of 2293 manually curated ligand-receptor pairs with literature support) to predict and visualise cell-to-cell communication networks from single-cell (or bulk) expression data. Using multiple published single-cell datasets we demonstrate how &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/forrest-lab/NATMI/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NATMI&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; can be used to identify (i) the cell-type pairs that are communicating the most (or most specifically) within a network, (ii) the most active (or specific) ligand-receptor pairs active within a network, (iii) putative highly-communicating cellular communities and (iv) differences in intercellular communication when profiling given cell types under different conditions. Furthermore, analysis of the Tabula Muris (organism-wide) atlas confirms our previous prediction that autocrine signalling is a major feature of cell-to-cell communication networks, while also revealing that hundreds of ligands and their cognate receptors are co-expressed in individual cells suggesting a substantial potential for self-signalling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Classical and Nonclassical Intercellular Communication in Senescence and Ageing</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/32505550/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/32505550/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Intercellular communication is a key feature in physiological and pathological conditions. We hypothesize that several means of intercellular communication occur either simultaneously or in succession.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The most studied means of intercellular communication are soluble factors. However, important alternative means are emerging.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Senescent cells are highly proactive and communicate with neighboring cells via various means of intercellular communication including but not limited to the senescence-associated secretory phenotype (SASP).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Most studies of pharmacological drugs preventing the release of soluble factors oversee the influence of these drugs on other means of communication.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Intercellular communication refers to the different ways through which cells communicate with each other and transfer a variety of messages. These communication methods involve a number of different processes that occur individually or simultaneously, which change depending on the physiological or pathological context. The best characterized means of intercellular communication is the release of soluble factors that affect the function of neighboring cells. However, there are many other ways by which cells can communicate with each other. Here, we review the different means of intercellular communication including soluble factors in the context of senescence, ageing, and age-related diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SingleCellSignalR: inference of intercellular networks from single-cell transcriptomics</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32196115/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32196115/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Single-cell transcriptomics offers unprecedented opportunities to infer the ligand-receptor (LR) interactions underlying cellular networks. We introduce a new, curated LR database and a novel regularized score to perform such inferences. For the first time, we try to assess the confidence in predicted LR interactions and show that our regularized score outperforms other scoring schemes while controlling false positives. &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/SCA-IRCM&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SingleCellSignalR&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is implemented as an open-access R package accessible to entry-level users and available from &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/SCA-IRCM&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;. Analysis results come in a variety of tabular and graphical formats. For instance, we provide a unique network view integrating all the intercellular interactions, and a function relating receptors to expressed intracellular pathways. A detailed comparison of related tools is conducted. Among various examples, we demonstrate &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/SCA-IRCM&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SingleCellSignalR&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; on mouse epidermis data and discover an oriented communication structure from external to basal layers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CellPhoneDB: inferring cell-cell communication from combined expression of multi-subunit ligand-receptor complexes</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32103204/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32103204/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cell-cell communication mediated by ligand-receptor complexes is critical to coordinating diverse biological processes, such as development, differentiation and inflammation. To investigate how the context-dependent crosstalk of different cell types enables physiological processes to proceed, we developed &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cellphonedb.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CellPhoneDB&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, a novel repository of ligands, receptors and their interactions. In contrast to other repositories, our database takes into account the subunit architecture of both ligands and receptors, representing heteromeric complexes accurately. We integrated our resource with a statistical framework that predicts enriched cellular interactions between two cell types from single-cell transcriptomics data. Here, we outline the structure and content of our repository, provide procedures for inferring cell-cell communication networks from single-cell RNA sequencing data and present a practical step-by-step guide to help implement the protocol. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cellphonedb.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CellPhoneDB&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; v.2.0 is an updated version of our resource that incorporates additional functionalities to enable users to introduce new interacting molecules and reduces the time and resources needed to interrogate large datasets. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cellphonedb.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CellPhoneDB&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; v.2.0 is publicly available, both as code and as a user-friendly web interface; it can be used by both experts and researchers with little experience in computational genomics. In our protocol, we demonstrate how to evaluate meaningful biological interactions with &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cellphonedb.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CellPhoneDB&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; v.2.0 using published datasets. This protocol typically takes ~2 h to complete, from installation to statistical analysis and visualization, for a dataset of ~10 GB, 10,000 cells and 19 cell types, and using five threads.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NicheNet: modeling intercellular communication by linking ligands to target genes</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/31819264/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/31819264/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Computational methods that model how gene expression of a cell is influenced by interacting cells are lacking. We present &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/saeyslab/nichenetr&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;NicheNet&lt;/a&gt;, a method that predicts ligand-target links between interacting cells by combining their expression data with prior knowledge on signaling and gene regulatory networks. We applied &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/saeyslab/nichenetr&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;NicheNet&lt;/a&gt; to tumor and immune cell microenvironment data and demonstrate that &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/saeyslab/nichenetr&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;NicheNet&lt;/a&gt; can infer active ligands and their gene regulatory effects on interacting cells.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>iTALK: an R Package to Characterize and Illustrate Intercellular Communication</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/italk/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/italk/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Crosstalk between tumor cells and other cells within the tumor microenvironment (TME) plays a crucial role in tumor progression, metastases, and therapy resistance. We present &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Coolgenome/iTALK&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;iTALK&lt;/a&gt;, a computational approach to characterize and illustrate intercellular communication signals in the multicellular tumor ecosystem using single-cell RNA sequencing data. &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Coolgenome/iTALK&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;iTALK&lt;/a&gt; can in principle be used to dissect the complexity, diversity, and dynamics of cell-cell communication from a wide range of cellular processes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
