<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Apoptosis | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/apoptosis/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/apoptosis/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Apoptosis</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Apoptosis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/apoptosis/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>RAGE inhibition alleviates lipopolysaccharides-induced lung injury via directly suppressing autophagic apoptosis of type II alveolar epithelial cells</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36691012/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36691012/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Advanced glycation end product receptor (RAGE) acts as a receptor of pro-inflammatory ligands and is highly expressed in alveolar epithelial cells (AECs). Autophagy in AECs has received much attention recently. However, the roles of autophagy and RAGE in the pathogenesis of acute lung injury remain unclear. Therefore, this study aimed to explore whether RAGE activation signals take part in the dysfunction of alveolar epithelial barrier through autophagic death.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; Acute lung injury animal models were established using C57BL/6 and Ager gene knockout (Ager -/- mice) mice in this study. A549 cells and primary type II alveolar epithelial (ATII) cells were treated with siRNA to reduce Ager gene expression. Autophagy was inhibited by 3-methyladenine (3-MA). Lung injury was assessed by histopathological examination. Cell viability was estimated by cell counting kit-8 (CCK-8) assay. The serum and bronchoalveolar lavage fluid (BALF) levels of interleukin (IL)-6, IL-8 and soluble RAGE (sRAGE) were evaluated by Enzyme-linked immunosorbent assay (ELISA). The involvement of RAGE signals, autophagy and apoptosis was assessed using western blots, immunohistochemistry, immunofluorescence, transmission electron microscopy and TUNEL test.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; The expression of RAGE was promoted by lipopolysaccharide (LPS), which was associated with activation of autophagy both in mice lung tissues and A549 cells as well as primary ATII cells. sRAGE in BALF was positively correlated with IL-6 and IL-8 levels. Compared with the wild-type mice, inflammation and apoptosis in lung tissues were alleviated in Ager-/- mice. Persistently activated autophagy contributed to cell apoptosis, whereas the inhibition of autophagy by 3-MA protected lungs from damage. In addition, Ager knockdown inhibited LPS-induced autophagy activation and attenuated lung injury. In vitro, knockdown of RAGE significantly suppressed the activation of LPS-induced autophagy and apoptosis of A549 and primary ATII cells. Furthermore, RAGE activated the downstream STAT3 signaling pathway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/em&gt; RAGE plays an essential role in the pathogenesis of ATII cells injury. Our results suggested that RAGE inhibition alleviated LPS-induced lung injury by directly suppressing autophagic apoptosis of alveolar epithelial cells.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Protective effect of soloxolone derivatives in carrageenan- and LPS-driven acute inflammation: Pharmacological profiling and their effects on key inflammation-related processes</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36640672/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36640672/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Soloxolone derivatives (SDs) effectively ameliorate carrageenan-induced inflammation and LPS-stimulated ALI in mice.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SDs suppress the expression of key inflammatory genes in inflamed sites and the functional activity of murine macrophages.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SDs inhibit macrophage NO production by both suppression of Nos2 expression and probable direct interaction with iNOS.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Soloxolone methyl (SM) displays cytoprotective effect on inflamed pneumocytes and does not affect their ALI-driven EMT.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SM directly inhibits the activity of thrombin involved in the regulation of inflammation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The anti-inflammatory potential of three cyanoenone-containing triterpenoids, including soloxolone methyl (SM), soloxolone (S) and its novel derivative bearing at the C-30 amidoxime moiety (SAO), was studied in murine models of acute inflammation. It was found that the compounds effectively suppressed the development of carrageenan-induced paw edema and peritonitis as well as lipopolysaccharide (LPS)-driven acute lung injury (ALI) with therapeutic outcomes comparable with that of the reference drugs indomethacin and dexamethasone. Non-immunogenic carrageenan-stimulated inflammation was more sensitive to the transformation of C-30 of SM compared with immunogenic LPS-induced inflammation: the anti-inflammatory properties of the studied compounds against carrageenan-induced paw edema and peritonitis decreased in the order of SAO &amp;gt; S &amp;gt; &amp;gt; SM, whereas the efficiency of these triterpenoids against LPS-driven ALI was similar (SAO ≈ S ≈ SM). Further studies demonstrated that soloxolone derivatives significantly inhibited a range of immune-related processes, including granulocyte influx and the expression of key pro-inflammatory cytokines and chemokines in the inflamed sites as well as the functional activity of macrophages. Moreover, SM was found to prevent inflammation-associated apoptosis of A549 pneumocytes and effectively inhibited the protease activity of thrombin (IC50 = 10.3 µM) tightly associated with rodent inflammatome. Taken together, our findings demonstrate that soloxolone derivatives can be considered as novel promising anti-inflammatory drug candidates with multi-targeted mechanism of action.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tea leaf-derived exosome-like nanotherapeutics retard breast tumor growth by pro-apoptosis and microbiota modulation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36600299/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36600299/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While several artificial nanodrugs have been approved for clinical treatment of breast tumor, their long-term applications are restricted by unsatisfactory therapeutic outcomes, side reactions and high costs. Conversely, edible plant-derived natural nanotherapeutics (NTs) are source-widespread and cost-effective, which have been shown remarkably effective in disease treatment. Herein, we extracted and purified exosome-like NTs from tea leaves (TLNTs), which had an average diameter of 166.9 nm and a negative-charged surface of - 28.8 mV. These TLNTs contained an adequate slew of functional components such as lipids, proteins and pharmacologically active molecules. In vitro studies indicated that TLNTs were effectively internalized by breast tumor cells (4T1 cells) and caused a 2.5-fold increase in the amount of intracellular reactive oxygen species (ROS) after incubation for 8 h. The high levels of ROS triggered mitochondrial damages and arrested cell cycles, resulting in the apoptosis of tumor cells. The mouse experiments revealed that TLNTs achieved good therapeutic effects against breast tumors regardless of intravenous injection and oral administration through direct pro-apoptosis and microbiota modulation. Strikingly, the intravenous injection of TLNTs, not oral administration, yielded obvious hepatorenal toxicity and immune activation. These findings collectively demonstrate that TLNTs can be developed as a promising oral therapeutic platform for the treatment of breast cancer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Circadian regulator BMAL1::CLOCK promotes cell proliferation in hepatocellular carcinoma by controlling apoptosis and cell cycle</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36595671/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36595671/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hepatocellular carcinoma (HCC) remains a global health challenge whose incidence is growing worldwide. Previous evidence strongly supported the notion that the circadian clock controls physiological homeostasis of the liver and plays a key role in hepatocarcinogenesis. Despite the progress, cellular and molecular mechanisms underpinning this HCC-clock crosstalk remain unknown. Addressing this knowledge gap, we show here that although the human HCC cells Hep3B, HepG2, and Huh7 displayed variations in circadian rhythm profiles, all cells relied on the master circadian clock transcription factors, BMAL1 and CLOCK, for sustained cell growth. Down-regulating &lt;em&gt;Bmal1&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;Clock&lt;/em&gt; in the HCC cells induced apoptosis and arrested cell cycle at the G&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;/M phase. Mechanistically, we found that inhibiting &lt;em&gt;Bmal1&lt;/em&gt;/&lt;em&gt;Clock&lt;/em&gt; induced dysregulation of the cell cycle regulators &lt;em&gt;Wee1&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;p21&lt;/em&gt; which cooperatively contribute to tumor cell death. &lt;em&gt;Bmal1&lt;/em&gt;/&lt;em&gt;Clock&lt;/em&gt; knockdown caused downregulation of &lt;em&gt;Wee1&lt;/em&gt; that led to apoptosis activation and upregulation of &lt;em&gt;p21&lt;/em&gt; which arrested the cell cycle at the G&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;/M phase. Collectively, our results suggest that the circadian clock regulators BMAL1 and CLOCK promote HCC cell proliferation by controlling &lt;em&gt;Wee1&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;p21&lt;/em&gt; levels, thereby preventing apoptosis and cell cycle arrest. Our findings shed light on cellular impact of the clock proteins for maintaining HCC oncogenesis and provide proof-of-principle for developing cancer therapy based on modulation of the circadian clock.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chimeric efferocytic receptors improve apoptotic cell clearance and alleviate inflammation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36563662/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36563662/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Design of chimeric receptors for efferocytosis (CHEF) to enhance efferocytosis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Boosting efferocytosis via CHEF attenuates multiple inflammatory insults &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Protein folding and misfolded protein degradation are rate-limiting steps in efferocytosis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CHEF expression can improve outcomes in ongoing disease&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our bodies turn over billions of cells daily via apoptosis and are in turn cleared by phagocytes via the process of &amp;ldquo;efferocytosis.&amp;rdquo; Defects in efferocytosis are now linked to various inflammatory diseases. Here, we designed a strategy to boost efferocytosis, denoted &amp;ldquo;chimeric receptor for efferocytosis&amp;rdquo; (CHEF). We fused a specific signaling domain within the cytoplasmic adapter protein ELMO1 to the extracellular phosphatidylserine recognition domains of the efferocytic receptors BAI1 or TIM4, generating BELMO and TELMO, respectively. CHEF-expressing phagocytes display a striking increase in efferocytosis. In mouse models of inflammation, BELMO expression attenuates colitis, hepatotoxicity, and nephrotoxicity. In mechanistic studies, BELMO increases ER-resident enzymes and chaperones to overcome protein-folding-associated toxicity, which was further validated in a model of ER-stress-induced renal ischemia-reperfusion injury. Finally, TELMO introduction after onset of kidney injury significantly reduced fibrosis. Collectively, these data advance a concept of chimeric efferocytic receptors to boost efferocytosis and dampen inflammation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mitochondria-localized lncRNA HITT inhibits fusion by attenuating formation of mitofusin-2 homo- or heterotypic complexes</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36567017/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36567017/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Long non-coding RNAs (lncRNAs) are emerging as essential players in multiple biological processes. Mitochondrial dynamics, comprising the continuous cycle of fission and fusion, are required for healthy mitochondria that function properly. Despite long-term recognition of its significance in cell-fate control, the mechanism underlying mitochondrial fusion is not completely understood, particularly regarding the involvement of lncRNAs. Here, we show that the lncRNA HITT (HIF-1α inhibitor at translation level), can specifically localize in mitochondria. Cells expressing higher levels of HITT contain fragmented mitochondria. Conversely, we show that HITT knockdown cells have more tubular mitochondria than is present in control cells. Mechanistically, we demonstrate HITT directly binds mitofusin-2 (MFN2), a core component that mediates mitochondrial outer membrane fusion, by the &lt;em&gt;in vitro&lt;/em&gt; RNA pull-down and UV-cross-linking RNA-IP (CLIP) assays. In doing so, we found HITT disturbs MFN2 homo- or heterotypic complex formation, attenuating mitochondrial fusion. Under stress conditions, such as ultraviolet radiation, we in addition show HITT stability increases as a consequence of MiR-205 downregulation, inhibiting MFN2-mediated fusion and leading to apoptosis. Overall, our data provide significant insights into the roles of organelle (mitochondria)-specific resident lncRNAs in regulating mitochondrial fusion, and also reveal how such a mechanism controls cellular sensitivity to UV radiation-induced apoptosis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PANoptosis-like cell death in ischemia/reperfusion injury of retinal neurons</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35900430/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35900430/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We screened small molecules to identify two compounds, which we named RSL3 and RSL5, that have increased lethality in the presence of oncogenic RAS. Counter screening with biologically active compounds defined aspects of the mechanism of action for RSL3 and RSL5, such as a nonapoptotic, MEK-dependent, and iron-dependent oxidative cell death. Erastin, a previously reported compound with RAS-selective lethality, showed similar properties. RNA interference experiments targeting voltage-dependent anion channel 3 (VDAC3), a target of erastin, demonstrated that RSL5 is a scaffold that acts through VDACs to activate the observed pathway. RSL3 activated a similar death mechanism but in a VDAC-independent manner. We found that cells transformed with oncogenic RAS have increased iron content relative to their normal cell counterparts through upregulation of transferrin receptor 1 and downregulation of ferritin heavy chain 1 and ferritin light chain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>H3K27 tri-demethylase JMJD3 inhibits macrophage apoptosis by promoting ADORA2A in lipopolysaccharide-induced acute lung injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36456564/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36456564/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acute lung injury (ALI) is a common critical disease, which is characterized by an uncontrolled, acute inflammatory response, diffuse lung damage and ultimately directly deteriorates into acute respiratory distress syndrome. The number of pro-inflammatory macrophages is related to the severity of ALI. Up-regulation of lipopolysaccharide (LPS)-activated macrophage apoptosis can reduce the pro-inflammatory reactions. Jumonji domain-containing protein D3 (JMJD3)-mediated histone 3 lysine 27 trimethylation (H3K27me3) demethylation may promote the pro-inflammatory response of macrophages under LPS stimulation. However, the mechanism of JMJD3 affecting macrophage apoptosis is still not clear. To explore this gap in knowledge, the ALI mice model with intratracheal administration of LPS and RAW264.7 cells with LPS stimulation were used as in vivo and in vitro experiments. The expression of JMJD3 and H3K27me3 and their cellular localization were analysed in lung tissue. Apoptosis was evaluated using TUNEL staining and flow cytometry. Expression of H3K27me3, ADORA2A and C/EBPβ were compared among different treatments and chromatin immunoprecipitation was performed to investigate the regulatory relationship. Our study showed that JMJD3 expression was upregulated in LPS-induced ALI mice and RAW264.7 cells. JMJD3-indued H3K27me3 demethylation inhibited caspase-3 cleavage by upregulating ADORA2A to decrease LPS-stimulated macrophage apoptosis and promoted the inflammatory reaction. This H3K27me3 demethylation also increased C/EBPβ expression, which may enhance ADORA2A expression further. Besides, inhibiting ADORA2A can also promote LPS-limited macrophage apoptosis. Moreover, the inhibition of JMJD3 in vivo and in vitro relieved the inhibition of macrophage apoptosis thus leading to the resolution of the inflammation. JMJD3 might inhibit macrophage apoptosis by promoting ADORA2A expression in LPS-induced ALI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amorphous silica nanoparticles caused lung injury through the induction of epithelial apoptosis via ROS/Ca2&#43;/DRP1-mediated mitochondrial fission signaling</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36441139/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36441139/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The adverse effects of amorphous silica nanoparticles (SiNPs) exposure on the respiratory system were increasingly recognized, however, its potential pathogenesis still remains not fully elucidated. So, this study aimed to explore its effects on pulmonary injury, and to investigate related mechanisms. Histological investigations illustrated SiNPs triggered the lung injury, mainly manifested as alveolar structure destruction, collagen deposition, and mitochondrial ultrastructural injury. In particular, SiNPs greatly enhanced pulmonary ROS and TUNEL positive rate in lungs, both of which were positively correlated with lung impairments. Further, the underlying mechanisms were investigated in cultured human bronchial epithelial cells (16HBE). Consistent with the &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt; findings, SiNPs caused the impairments on mitochondrial structure, as well as the activation of ROS generation and oxidative injury. Upon SiNPs stimuli, mitochondrial respiration was greatly inhibited, while Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt; overload in cytosol and mitochondria owing to ER calcium release was noticed, resulting in mitochondrial-dependent epithelial apoptosis. More importantly, mitochondrial dynamics was imbalanced toward a fission type, as evidenced by upregulated DRP1 and its phosphorylation at Ser616 (DRP1&lt;sup&gt;s616&lt;/sup&gt;), while downregulated DRP1&lt;sup&gt;s637&lt;/sup&gt;, and also MFN1, MFN2. Mechanistic investigations revealed that the activation of ROS/Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt; signaling promoted DRP1-mediated mitochondrial fission by SiNPs, forming a vicious cycle, and ultimately contributing to apoptosis in 16HBE. In summary, our results disclosed SiNPs caused pulmonary injury through the induction of epithelial apoptosis via a ROS/Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt;/DRP1-mediated mitochondrial fission axis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SENP1 prevents steatohepatitis by suppressing RIPK1-driven apoptosis and inflammation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36414671/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36414671/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Activation of RIPK1-driven cell death and inflammation play important roles in the progression of nonalcoholic steatohepatitis (NASH). However, the mechanism underlying RIPK1 activation in NASH remains unclear. Here we identified SENP1, a SUMO-specific protease, as a key endogenous inhibitor of RIPK1. SENP1 is progressively reduced in proportion to NASH severity in patients. Hepatocyte-specific SENP1-knockout mice develop spontaneous NASH-related phenotypes in a RIPK1 kinase-dependent manner. We demonstrate that SENP1 deficiency sensitizes cells to RIPK1 kinase-dependent apoptosis by promoting RIPK1 activation following TNFα stimulation. Mechanistically, SENP1 deSUMOylates RIPK1 in TNF-R1 signaling complex (TNF-RSC), keeping RIPK1 in check. Loss of SENP1 leads to SUMOylation of RIPK1, which re-orchestrates TNF-RSC and modulates the ubiquitination patterns and activity of RIPK1. Notably, genetic inhibition of RIPK1 effectively reverses disease progression in hepatocyte-specific SENP1-knockout male mice with high-fat-diet-induced nonalcoholic fatty liver. We propose that deSUMOylation of RIPK1 by SENP1 provides a pathophysiologically relevant cell death-restricting checkpoint that modulates RIPK1 activation in the pathogenesis of nonalcoholic steatohepatitis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exosome modification to better alleviates endoplasmic reticulum stress induced chondrocyte apoptosis and osteoarthritis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36370754/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36370754/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Osteoarthritis (OA) is characterized by cartilage matrix degeneration and chondrocyte apoptosis. Prolonged endoplasmic reticulum (ER) stress participates in chondrocyte apoptosis and cartilage degeneration in OA progression. miR-486-5p could suppress the apoptosis of nucleus pulposus cells and cardiomyocyte, yet whether miR-486-5p modified exosomes could modulate ER stress and apoptosis of chondrocytes remain unknown. We validated the increased inflammation and ER stress in OA synovium and cartilage, and the inhibition of ER stress could attenuate the IL-1β induced chondrocyte apoptosis. Administration of exogenous miR-486-5p could inhibit the ER stress, alleviate chondrocytes apoptosis and promote matrix regeneration. In comparison with direct administration of miR-486-5p and miR-486-5p overexpressing ADSCs, miR-486-5p modified exosomes indicated a better effect in modulating chondrocyte homeostasis. MiR-486-5p containing exosomes could also regulate macrophage polarization. Our IVIS imaging data validated that intraarticular injection of miR-486-5p containing exosomes could sustain for at least 7 days. MiR-486-5p containing exosomes showed a better effect on alleviating rats OA compared with direct administration of miR-486-5p and miR-486-5p overexpressing ADSCs. Our data demonstrated that miR-486-5p modified exosomes have a better effect on alleviating chondrocyte apoptosis and osteoarthritis. This study provides evidence of this efficient strategy of exosomal miRNA delivery and the miRNA-based therapy for OA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bclaf1 regulates c-FLIP expression and protects cells from TNF-induced apoptosis and tissue injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34693625/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34693625/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TNF stimulation generates pro-survival signals through activation of NF-κB that restrict the build-in death signaling triggered by TNF. The competition between TNF-induced survival and death signals ultimately determines the fate of a cell. Here, we report the identification of Bclaf1 as a novel component of the anti-apoptotic program of TNF. Bclaf1 depletion in multiple cells sensitizes cells to TNF-induced apoptosis but not to necroptosis. Bclaf1 exerts its anti-apoptotic function by promoting the transcription of CFLAR, a caspase 8 antagonist, downstream of NF-κB activation. Bclaf1 binds to the p50 subunit of NF-κB, which is required for Bclaf1 to stimulate CFLAR transcription. Finally, in Bclaf1 siRNA administered mice, TNF-induced small intestine injury is much more severe than in control mice with aggravated signs of apoptosis and pyroptosis. These results suggest Bclaf1 is a key regulator in TNF-induced apoptosis, both in vitro and in vivo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Naringenin attenuates inflammation, apoptosis, and ferroptosis in silver nanoparticle-induced lung injury through a mechanism associated with Nrf2/HO-1 axis: In vitro and in vivo studies</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36306867/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36306867/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the wide application of silver nanoparticles (AgNPs), their potential damage to human health needs to be investigated. Lung is one of the main target organs after inhalation of AgNPs. Naringenin has been reported to have anti-inflammatory and anti-oxidative properties. This study aims to evaluate the protective effects of naringenin against AgNPs-induced lung injury and determine the underlying mechanism. In in vivo experiments, AgNPs were intratracheally instilled into ICR mice (l mg/kg) to establish a lung injury model. These mice were then treated with naringenin by oral gavage (25, 50, 100 mg/kg) for three days. Naringenin treatment decreased the levels of white blood cells, neutrophils, and lymphocytes in the blood, ameliorated lung injury, suppressed the release of pro-inflammatory cytokines, normalized ferroptotic markers and prevented oxidative stress with elevating Nrf2 and HO-1 protein expressions in lung. In in vitro experiments, BEAS-2B cells were firstly treated with AgNPs (320 μg/mL) and then naringenin (25, 50, and 100 μM), respectively. Naringenin attenuated AgNPs-induced oxidative stress and inflammatory response. Moreover, naringenin attenuated AgNPs-induced apoptosis with modulated low BAX, CytC, cleaved Caspase9, cleaved Caspase3 but high Bcl2. Furthermore, naringenin effectively decreased ferroptotic markers and increased the protein expressions of Nrf2 and HO-1, as well as increased the nuclear translocation of Nrf2. Importantly, the anti-apoptotic and anti-ferroptotic effects of naringenin in BEAS-2B cells were found to be at least partially Nrf2-dependent. These results indicated that naringenin exerted anti-inflammation, anti-apoptosis, and anti-ferroptosis effects and protected against AgNPs-induced lung injury at least partly via activating Nrf2/HO-1 signaling pathway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Splicing factor BUD31 promotes ovarian cancer progression through sustaining the expression of anti-apoptotic BCL2L12</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36271053/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36271053/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dysregulated expression of splicing factors has important roles in cancer development and progression. However, it remains a challenge to identify the cancer-specific splicing variants. Here we demonstrate that spliceosome component BUD31 is increased in ovarian cancer, and its higher expression predicts worse prognosis. We characterize the BUD31-binding motif and find that BUD31 preferentially binds exon-intron regions near splicing sites. Further analysis reveals that BUD31 inhibition results in extensive exon skipping and a reduced production of long isoforms containing full coding sequence. In particular, we identify &lt;em&gt;BCL2L12&lt;/em&gt;, an anti-apoptotic BCL2 family member, as one of the functional splicing targets of BUD31. BUD31 stimulates the inclusion of exon 3 to generate full-length &lt;em&gt;BCL2L12&lt;/em&gt; and promotes ovarian cancer progression. Knockdown of BUD31 or splice-switching antisense oligonucleotide treatment promotes exon 3 skipping and results in a truncated isoform of &lt;em&gt;BCL2L12&lt;/em&gt; that undergoes nonsense-mediated mRNA decay, and the cells subsequently undergo apoptosis. Our findings reveal BUD31-regulated exon inclusion as a critical factor for ovarian cancer cell survival and cancer progression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sulforaphane alleviated vascular remodeling in hypoxic pulmonary hypertension via inhibiting inflammation and oxidative stress</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36220525/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36220525/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hypoxic pulmonary hypertension (HPH) is a cardiopulmonary disease featured by pulmonary vascular remodeling, which is due to abnormal proliferation of pulmonary artery smooth muscle cells (PASMCs) and dysfunction of endothelial cells (ECs). Sulforaphane (SFN) is a natural isothiocyanate extracted from cruciferous vegetables with promising anti-inflammatory and anti-oxidative activities. This study aimed to explore the effect and mechanism of SFN on HPH. Male mice were exposed to persistent chronic hypoxia for 4 weeks to induce HPH. The results demonstrated that SFN repressed the increased right ventricular systolic pressure (RVSP) and attenuated the right ventricular hypertrophy and pulmonary arteries remodeling in HPH mice. In particular, after SFN treatment, the CD68 positive cells in lung sections were reduced; TNF-α and IL-6 levels in lungs and serum declined; activation of NF-κB in PASMCs was inhibited in response to hypoxia. Besides, SFN enhanced the superoxide dismutase (SOD) activity in serum, SOD2 expression, total glutathione levels, and GSH/GSSG ratio in PASMCs, along with a decrease in malondialdehyde (MDA) contents in serum and ROS production in PASMCs after hypoxia exposure. Notably, SFN, as an Nrf2 activator, reversed the reduction in Nrf2 expression in hypoxic PASMCs. In vitro, SFN treatment inhibited hyperproliferation and promoted apoptosis of PASMCs under hypoxia conditions. SFN also prevented the apoptosis of pulmonary microvascular ECs caused by hypoxia. Therefore, these data suggested that SFN could significantly restrain the inflammation and oxidative stress, thereby inhibiting PASMCs proliferation, promoting PASMCs apoptosis, and reversing hypoxia injury in ECs to improve pulmonary vascular remodeling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Molecular mechanism of RIPK1 and caspase-8 in homeostatic type I interferon production and regulation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36198273/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36198273/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Caspase-8 regulates tonic type I IFN in homeostasis through the RIPK1-TBK1 axis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Caspase-8 inhibits the interaction between RIPK1 and TBK1 to regulate type I IFN&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When caspase-8 is absent, RIPK1 drives pathogenic IFN production and lymphadenopathy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RIPK1-mediated IFN leads to natural viral resistance when caspase-8 is absent&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Type I interferons (IFNs) are essential innate immune proteins that maintain tissue homeostasis through tonic expression and can be upregulated to drive antiviral resistance and inflammation upon stimulation. However, the mechanisms that inhibit aberrant IFN upregulation in homeostasis and the impacts of tonic IFN production on health and disease remain enigmatic. Here, we report that caspase-8 negatively regulates type I IFN production by inhibiting the RIPK1-TBK1 axis during homeostasis across multiple cell types and tissues. When caspase-8 is deleted or inhibited, RIPK1 interacts with TBK1 to drive elevated IFN production, leading to heightened resistance to norovirus infection in macrophages but also early onset lymphadenopathy in mice. Combined deletion of caspase-8 and RIPK1 reduces the type I IFN signaling and lymphadenopathy, highlighting the critical role of RIPK1 in this process. Overall, our study identifies a mechanism to constrain tonic type I IFN during homeostasis which could be targeted for infectious and inflammatory diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fibroblast growth factor 10 attenuates chronic obstructive pulmonary disease by protecting against glycocalyx impairment and endothelial apoptosis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36183124/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36183124/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; The defects and imbalance in lung repair and structural maintenance contribute to the pathogenesis of chronic obstructive pulmonary diseases (COPD), yet the molecular mechanisms that regulate lung repair process are so far incompletely understood. We hypothesized that cigarette smoking causes glycocalyx impairment and endothelial apoptosis in COPD, which could be repaired by the stimulation of fibroblast growth factor 10 (FGF10)/FGF receptor 1 (FGFR1) signaling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; We used immunostaining (immunohistochemical [IHC] and immunofluorescence [IF]) and enzyme-linked immunosorbent assay (ELISA) to detect the levels of glycocalyx components and endothelial apoptosis in animal models and in patients with COPD. We used the murine emphysema model and in vitro studies to determine the protective and reparative role of FGF10/FGFR1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; Exposure to cigarette smoke caused endothelial glycocalyx impairment and emphysematous changes in murine models and human specimens. Pretreatment of FGF10 attenuated the development of emphysema and the shedding of glycocalyx components induced by CSE &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt;. However, FGF10 did not attenuate the emphysema induced by endothelial-specific killing peptide CGSPGWVRC-GG-&lt;sub&gt;D&lt;/sub&gt;(KLAKLAK)&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;. Mechanistically, FGF10 alleviated smoke-induced endothelial apoptosis and glycocalyx repair through FGFR1/ERK/SOX9/HS6ST1 signaling &lt;em&gt;in vitro&lt;/em&gt;. FGF10 was shown to repair pulmonary glycocalyx injury and endothelial apoptosis, and attenuate smoke-induced COPD through FGFR1 signaling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; Our results suggest that FGF10 may serve as a potential therapeutic strategy against COPD via endothelial repair and glycocalyx reconstitution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lycopene attenuates the inflammation and apoptosis in aristolochic acid nephropathy by targeting the Nrf2 antioxidant system</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36198206/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36198206/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lycopene improves renal dysfunction in mice with aristolochic acid nephropathy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lycopene inhibits oxidative stress, inflammation, and apoptosis in the kidney of mice with aristolochic acid nephropathy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Activation of Nrf2 antioxidant signaling pathway is critical to inhibit the development of renal inflammatory response.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lycopene activates the Nrf2 antioxidant system and then inhibits apoptosis.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lycopene (LYC) is a carotenoid, has antioxidant properties. This study investigated whether lycopene attenuates aristolochic acids (AAs) -induced chronic kidney disease. In this experiment, lycopene was used to intervene C57BL/6 mice with renal injury induced by aristolochic acid exposure. The histomorphological changes and serological parameters of the kidney were measured in order to assess the alleviating effect of lycopene on renal injury in aristolochic acid nephropathy. In vitro and in vivo experiments were carried out to verify the main mechanism of action and drug targets of lycopene in improving aristolochic acid nephropathy (AAN) and by various experimental methods such as ELISA, immunohistochemistry, immunofluorescence, Western-blot and qRT-PCR. The results showed that oxidative stress injury was induced in the kidney of mice after AAI exposure, resulting in inflammatory response and tubular epithelial cell apoptosis. The results showed that the Nrf2/HO-1 antioxidant signaling pathway was inhibited after AAI exposure. AAI induces oxidative stress injury in the kidney, which ultimately leads to inflammation and tubular epithelial cell apoptosis. After LYC intervened in the body, it activated Nrf2 nuclear translocation and its downstream HO-1 and NQO1 antioxidant signaling pathways. LYC inhibited ROS production by renal tubular epithelial cells, and alleviated mitochondrial damage. LYC further modulated the TNF-α/NF-κB signaling cascade, thereby reduced the accumulation of inflammatory factors in the renal interstitium. Moreover, LYC was able to up-regulate the expression of Bcl-2, down-regulate Bax expression and inhibit the activation of cleaved forms of Caspase-9 and Caspase-3, which finally attenuated the apoptosis of the mitochondrial pathway induced by AAI exposure. It was concluded that lycopene was able to activate the Nrf2 antioxidant signaling pathway to maintain the homeostasis of renal oxidative stress and ultimately attenuated renal inflammatory response and apoptosis. These results suggested that lycopene can be used as a drug to relieve AAN.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Liang-Ge decoction ameliorates acute lung injury in septic model rats through reducing inflammatory response, oxidative stress, apoptosis, and modulating host metabolism</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36188538/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36188538/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Liang-Ge decoction (LG) has been used in the treatment of early stage of spesis and can ameliorate sepsis-associated lung injury. However, the mechanism of LG on sepsis-associated lung injury remains unknown. In this study, we established a rat model of sepsis-associated lung injury using the cecal ligation and puncture (CLP) method, and investigated the therapeutic effects of LG on lung injury in rats with sepsis. In addition, the anti-inflammatory, anti-oxidative and anti-apoptotic effects of LG on sepsis-associated lung injury model rats were evaluated. Besides, untargeted metabolomics was used to investigate the regulation of metabolites in rats with sepsis-associated lung injury after LG treatment. Our results showed that LG could decrease the wet/dry (W/D) ratio in lung and the total cell count and total protein concentration in bronchoalveolar lavage fluid (BALF) in septic model rats. Hematoxylin and eosin (HE) staining showed that LG reduced the infiltration of pro-inflammatory cells in lung. In addition, LG treatmment down-regulated the gene and protein expression of pro-inflammatory cytokins in lung tissue and BALF. The activities of superoxide dismutase (SOD) and glutathione peroxidase (GSH-Px) were increased and the level of methane dicarboxylic aldehyde (MDA) was decreased in lung tissue homogenate in septic model rats after LG treament. Moreover, the numbers of apoptotic cells in lung were reduced and the activity of lactic dehydrogenase (LDH) in BALF was decreased in septic model rats after LG treament. Untargeted metabolomics analysis showed that LG treatment affected the levels of 23 metabolites in lung in septic model rats such as citric acid, methionine, threonine, alpha-ketoglutaric acid, and inositol, these metabolites were associated with the glycine, serine and threonine metabolism, cysteine and methionine metabolism, inositol phosphate metabolism and citrate cycle (TCA cycle) pathways. In conclusion, our study demonstrated the therapeutic effetcts of LG on sepsis-associated lung injury model rats. Moreover, LG could inhibit the inflammatory response, oxidative stress, apoptosis and regulate metabolites related to glycine, serine and threonine metabolism, cysteine and methionine metabolism, inositol phosphate metabolism and TCA cycle in lung in sepsis-associated lung injury model rats.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Regulator of calcineurin 1 deletion attenuates mitochondrial dysfunction and apoptosis in acute kidney injury through JNK/Mff signaling pathway</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36071051/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36071051/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ischemia-reperfusion (I/R) induced acute kidney injury (AKI), characterized by excessive mitochondrial damage and cell apoptosis, remains a clinical challenge. Recent studies suggest that regulator of calcineurin 1 (RCAN1) regulates mitochondrial function in different cell types, but the underlying mechanisms require further investigation. Herein, we aim to explore whether RCAN1 involves in mitochondrial dysfunction in AKI and the exact mechanism. In present study, AKI was induced by I/R and cisplatin in RCAN1flox/flox mice and mice with renal tubular epithelial cells (TECs)-specific deletion of RCAN1. The role of RCAN1 in hypoxia-reoxygenation (HR) and cisplatin-induced injury in human renal proximal tubule epithelial cell line HK-2 was also examined by overexpression and knockdown of RCAN1. Mitochondrial function was assessed by transmission electron microscopy, JC-1 staining, MitoSOX staining, ATP production, mitochondrial fission and mitophagy. Apoptosis was detected by TUNEL assay, Annexin V-FITC staining and Western blotting analysis of apoptosis-related proteins. It was found that protein expression of RCAN1 was markedly upregulated in I/R- or cisplatin-induced AKI mouse models, as well as in HR models in HK-2 cells. RCAN1 deficiency significantly reduced kidney damage, mitochondrial dysfunction, and cell apoptosis, whereas RCAN1 overexpression led to the opposite phenotypes. Our in-depth mechanistic exploration demonstrated that RCAN1 increases the phosphorylation of mitochondrial fission factor (Mff) by binding to downstream c-Jun N-terminal kinase (JNK), then promotes dynamin related protein 1 (Drp1) migration to mitochondria, ultimately leads to excessive mitochondrial fission of renal TECs. In conclusion, our study suggests that RCAN1 could induce mitochondrial dysfunction and apoptosis by activating the downstream JNK/Mff signaling pathway. RCAN1 may be a potential therapeutic target for conferring protection against I/R- or cisplatin-AKI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Diacerein attenuate LPS-induced acute lung injury via inhibiting ER stress and apoptosis: Impact on the crosstalk between SphK1/S1P, TLR4/NFκB/STAT3, and NLRP3/IL-1β signaling pathways</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36055546/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36055546/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Aims:&lt;/em&gt; Acute lung injury (ALI) is a life-threatening clinical problem with high mortality rate and limited treatments or preventive options that represents a major challenge for clinicians. Diacerein (DIA) is a multi-target anthraquinone derivative with potent anti-inflammatory action. The aim of this study is to assess the protective effect of DIA and its potential molecular targets against lipopolysaccharide (LPS)-induced ALI in rats.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Materials and methods:&lt;/em&gt; Adult male Sprague-Dawley rats were orally administrated DIA (50 mg/kg) for 5 consecutive days followed by a single intraperitoneal injection of LPS (5mg/kg).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Key findings:&lt;/em&gt; DIA mitigated oxidative lung injury in LPS-challenged rats via significantly decreasing lung wet/dry (W/D) ratio, inflammatory cells infiltration, and lipid peroxidation, with concomitant elevation in enzymatic and non-enzymatic antioxidant levels in lung tissue. Likewise, DIA alleviated endoplasmic reticulum stress and markedly halted inflammation triggered by LPS challenge in pulmonary tissue by suppressing NLRP3/IL-1β and TLR4/NF-κB signaling with parallel decrease in proinflammatory cytokine levels. Interestingly, DIA down regulated Sphk1/S1P axis, reduced GSK-3β and STAT3 proteins expression, and markedly decreased caspase-3 besides increasing Bcl-2 levels in lung tissue of LPS-challenged animals. These biochemical findings was simultaneously associated with marked improvement in histological alterations of lung tissue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Significance:&lt;/em&gt; These findings verify the protective effect of DIA against LPS-induced ALI through targeting oxidative stress, endoplasmic reticulum stress, and apoptosis. Importantly, DIA halted the hyperinflammatory state triggered by LPS via multi-faceted inhibitory effect on different signaling pathways, hence DIA could potentially reduce mortality in patients with ALI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anti-Fibrotic Effect of SDF-1β Overexpression in Bleomycin-Injured Rat Lung</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36145551/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36145551/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rational:&lt;/em&gt; Idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis (IPF) is a progressive interstitial lung disease and is associated with high mortality due to a lack of effective treatment. Excessive deposition of the extracellular matrix by activated myofibroblasts in the alveolar space leads to scar formation that hinders gas exchange. Therefore, selectively removing activated myofibroblasts with the aim to repair and remodel fibrotic lungs is a promising approach. Stromal-derived growth factor (SDF-1) is known to stimulate cellular signals which attract stem cells to the site of injury for tissue repair and remodeling. Here, we investigate the effect of overexpression of SDF-1β on lung structure using the bleomycin-injured rat lung model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; Intratracheal administration of bleomycin was performed in adult male rats (F344). Seven days later, in vivo electroporation-mediated gene transfer of either SDF-1β or the empty vector was performed. Animals were sacrificed seven days after gene transfer and histology, design-based stereology, flow cytometry, and collagen measurement were performed on the tissue collected. For in vitro experiments, lung fibroblasts obtained from IPF patients were used.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; Seven days after SDF-1β gene transfer to bleomycin-injured rat lungs, reduced total collagen, reduced collagen fibrils, improved histology and induced apoptosis of myofibroblasts were observed. Furthermore, it was revealed that TNF-α mediates SDF-1β-induced apoptosis of myofibroblasts; moreover, SDF-1β overexpression increased alveolar epithelial cell numbers and proliferation in vivo and also induced their migration in vitro.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; Our study demonstrates a new antifibrotic mechanism of SDF-1β overexpression and suggests SDF-1β as a potential new approach for the treatment of lung fibrosis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lentinan-functionalized selenium nanoparticles induce apoptosis and cell cycle arrest in human colon carcinoma HCT-116 cells</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36082027/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36082027/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Selenium nanoparticles (SeNPs) have gained extensive attention for their excellent biological activity and low toxicity. However, SeNPs are extremely liable to aggregate into non-bioactive or gray elemental selenium, which limits their application in the biomedicine field. This study aimed to prepare stable SeNPs by using lentinan (LNT) as a template and evaluate its anti-colon cancer activity. The average particle diameter of obtained lentinan-selenium nanoparticles (LNT-SeNPs) was approximately 59 nm and presented zero-valent, amorphous, and spherical structures. The monodisperse SeNPs were stabilized by LNT through hydrogen bonding interactions. LNT-SeNPs solution remained highly stable at 4°C for at least 8 weeks. The stability of LNT-SeNPs solution sharply decreased under high temperature and strong acidic conditions. LNT-SeNPs showed no obvious cytotoxic effect on normal cells (IEC-6) but significantly inhibited the proliferation of five colon cancer cells (HCT-116, HT-29, Caco-2, SW620, and CT26). Among them, LNT-SeNPs exhibited the highest sensitivity toward HCT-116 cells with an IC50 value of 7.65 μM. Also, LNT-SeNPs displayed better cancer cell selectivity than sodium selenite and selenomethionine. Moreover, LNT-SeNPs promoted apoptosis of HCT-116 cells through activating mitochondria-mediated apoptotic pathway. Meanwhile, LNT-SeNPs induced cell cycle arrest at G0/G1 phase in HCT-116 cells via modulation of cell cycle regulatory proteins. The results of this study indicated that LNT-SeNPs possessed strong potential application in the treatment of colorectal cancer (CRC).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UBXD8 mediates mitochondria-associated degradation to restrain apoptosis and mitophagy</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35979733/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35979733/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The hexameric AAA-ATPase valosin-containing protein (VCP) is essential for mitochondrial protein quality control. How VCP is recruited to mammalian mitochondria remains obscure. Here we report that UBXD8, an ER- and lipid droplet-localized VCP adaptor, also localizes to mitochondria and locally recruits VCP. UBXD8 associates with mitochondrial and ER ubiquitin E3 ligases and targets their substrates for degradation. Remarkably, both mitochondria- and ER-localized UBXD8 can degrade mitochondrial and ER substrates in cis and in trans. UBXD8 also associates with the TOM complex but is dispensable for translocation-associated degradation. UBXD8 knockout impairs the degradation of the pro-survival protein Mcl1 but surprisingly sensitizes cells to apoptosis and mitochondrial stresses. UBXD8 knockout also hyperactivates mitophagy. We identify pro-apoptotic BH3-only proteins Noxa, Bik, and Bnip3 as novel UBXD8 substrates and determine that UBXD8 inhibits apoptosis via degrading Noxa and restrains mitophagy via degrading Bnip3. Collectively, our characterizations reveal UBXD8 as the major mitochondrial adaptor of VCP and unveil its role in apoptosis and mitophagy regulation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cangma Huadu granules attenuate H1N1 virus-induced severe lung injury correlated with repressed apoptosis and altered gut microbiome</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36090063/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36090063/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Severe influenza A virus infection leads to overwhelming inflammatory responses and cellular apoptosis, which causes lung injury and contributes to high mortality and morbidity. The gut microbiome altered in response to the infection might influence the disease progression and the treatment outcome. Cangma Huadu (CMHD) granules, an in-hospital preparation of traditional Chinese medicine, have been shown to be favorable in the clinical treatment of influenza. However, the effects and mechanisms of CMHD granules on severe influenza pneumonia and its mechanisms are not well-known. In this study, a lethal influenza A (H1N1) A/Puerto Rico/8/34 virus (PR8)-infected mice model was established, and the 16S ribosomal RNA (16S rRNA) V3-V4 region sequencing of the intestinal microbiome was conducted. We revealed that the oral administration of CMHD granules protects mice against higher mortality, enhanced weight loss, overwhelmed interferon-γ concentration, lung viral titers, and severe lung pathological injury in PR8-infected mice. CMHD granules&amp;rsquo; administration downregulated the levels of interleukin (IL)-1β, tumor necrosis factor-α, and malondialdehyde, while it upregulated the levels of IL-10, superoxide dismutase, and glutathione peroxidase. Subsequently, it decreased the protein ratio of B-cell lymphoma-2/Bcl-2-associated X and the expression of cleaved caspase-3. The diversity and compositions of the gut microbes were altered profoundly after the administration of CMHD granules in PR8-infected mice. A higher abundance of &lt;em&gt;Bifidobacterium&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Parasutterella&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Bacteroides&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Faecalibaculum&lt;/em&gt; was observed in the CMHD group, and a higher abundance of &lt;em&gt;Lactobacillus&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Turicibacter&lt;/em&gt; was observed in the positive drug Ribavirin group. The linear discriminant analysis effect size also revealed a higher proportion of &lt;em&gt;Bacteroides&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Bifidobacterium_pseudolongum&lt;/em&gt; characterized in the CMHD group. These results demonstrated that CMHD granules are a promising strategy for managing severe influenza and attenuating severe lung damage via reducing viral titer, inflammatory responses, and oxidative stress. The mechanisms are involved in repressed Bcl-2-regulated apoptosis and altered composition and diversity of the gut microbiome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Identification of programmed cell death-related gene signature and associated regulatory axis in cerebral ischemia/reperfusion injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35991562/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35991562/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Numerous studies have suggested that programmed cell death (PCD) pathways play vital roles in cerebral ischemia/reperfusion (I/R) injury. However, the specific mechanisms underlying cell death during cerebral I/R injury have yet to be completely clarified. There is thus a need to identify the PCD-related gene signatures and the associated regulatory axes in cerebral I/R injury, which should provide novel therapeutic targets against cerebral I/R injury.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; We analyzed transcriptome signatures of brain tissue samples from mice subjected to middle cerebral artery occlusion/reperfusion (MCAO/R) and matched controls, and identified differentially expressed genes related to the three types of PCD(apoptosis, pyroptosis, and necroptosis). We next performed functional enrichment analysis and constructed PCD-related competing endogenous RNA (ceRNA) regulatory networks. We also conducted hub gene analysis to identify hub nodes and key regulatory axes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; Fifteen PCD-related genes were identified. Functional enrichment analysis showed that they were particularly associated with corresponding PCD-related biological processes, inflammatory response, and reactive oxygen species metabolic processes. The apoptosis-related ceRNA regulatory network was constructed, which included 24 long noncoding RNAs (lncRNAs), 41 microRNAs (miRNAs), and 4 messenger RNAs (mRNAs); the necroptosis-related ceRNA regulatory network included 16 lncRNAs, 20 miRNAs, and 6 mRNAs; and the pyroptosis-related ceRNA regulatory network included 15 lncRNAs, 18 miRNAs, and 6 mRNAs. Hub gene analysis identified hub nodes in each PCD-related ceRNA regulatory network and seven key regulatory axes in total, namely, lncRNA Malat1/miR-181a-5p/Mapt, lncRNA Malat1/miR-181b-5p/Mapt, lncRNA Neat1/miR-181a-5p/Mapt, and lncRNA Neat1/miR-181b-5p/Mapt for the apoptosis-related ceRNA regulatory network; lncRNA Neat1/miR-181a-5p/Tnf for the necroptosis-related ceRNA regulatory network; lncRNA Malat1/miR-181c-5p/Tnf for the pyroptosis-related ceRNA regulatory network; and lncRNAMalat1/miR-181a-5p for both necroptosis-related and pyroptosis-related ceRNA regulatory networks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/em&gt; The results of this study supported the hypothesis that these PCD pathways (apoptosis, necroptosis, pyroptosis, and PANoptosis) and crosstalk among them might be involved in ischemic stroke and that the key nodes and regulatory axes identified in this study might play vital roles in regulating the above processes. This may offer new insights into the potential mechanisms underlying cell death during cerebral I/R injury and provide new therapeutic targets for neuroprotection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LncRNA RMRP Contributes to the Development and Progression of Spinal Cord Injury by Regulating miR-766-5p/FAM83A Axis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35902548/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35902548/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spinal cord injury (SCI) is known as a central nervous system disorder. Previous studies suggested that long-non-coding RNA RMRP (LncRNA RMRP) was abnormally expressed in SCI, but the potential underlying mechanism remains to be further explored. To explore the regulatory roles of LncRNA RMRP/miR-766-5p/FAM83A axis in SCI. Spinal T9 hemisection was performed on healthy adult male Sprague Dawley (SD) rats to establish the SCI rat models. The expressions of LncRNA RMRP in spinal cord of rats in different groups were examined by RT-qPCR. Moreover, AGE1.HN and PC12 cells were treated with hypoxic condition, and expression of LncRNA RMRP was examined by RT-qPCR methods. Furthermore, hypoxic PC12 cells were transfected with LncRNA RMRP OE, and the cell viability, proliferation, and apoptosis were examined. Next, the direct targeting relationship between LncRNA RMRP and miR-766-5p, as well as miR-766-5p and FAM83A, was confirmed by dual-luciferase reporter and RNA pull-down assays. Finally, the effects of LncRNA RMRP/miR-766-5p/FAM83A axis on cell viability, proliferation, and apoptosis were examined. LncRNA RMRP was downregulated in SCI rats and over-expression of LncRNA RMRP alleviated the SCI condition. LncRNA RMRP over-expression increased the viability and proliferation, and inhibited the apoptosis of hypoxic PC12 cells in vitro. miR-766-5p was confirmed as a target of LncRNA RMRP, and FAM83A was confirmed as a target of miR-766-5p. LncRNA RMRP could regulate the proliferation and apoptosis of hypoxic PC12 cells via regulating miR-766-5p/FAM83A axis in vitro. LncRNA RMRP may contribute to the pathogenesis of SCI via regulating miR-766-5p/FAM83A axis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The EGFR/ErbB inhibitor neratinib modifies the neutrophil phosphoproteome and promotes apoptosis and clearance by airway macrophages</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35967296/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35967296/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dysregulated neutrophilic inflammation can be highly destructive in chronic inflammatory diseases due to prolonged neutrophil lifespan and continual release of histotoxic mediators in inflamed tissues. Therapeutic induction of neutrophil apoptosis, an immunologically silent form of cell death, may be beneficial in these diseases, provided that the apoptotic neutrophils are efficiently cleared from the tissue. Previous research in our group identified ErbB inhibitors as able to induce neutrophil apoptosis and reduce neutrophilic inflammation both &lt;em&gt;in vitro&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt;. Here, we extend that work using a clinical ErbB inhibitor, neratinib, which has the potential to be repurposed in inflammatory diseases. We show that neratinib reduces neutrophilic migration o an inflammatory site in zebrafish larvae. Neratinib upregulates efferocytosis and reduces the number of persisting neutrophil corpses in mouse models of acute, but not chronic, lung injury, suggesting that the drug may have therapeutic benefits in acute inflammatory settings. Phosphoproteomic analysis of human neutrophils shows that neratinib modifies the phosphorylation of proteins regulating apoptosis, migration, and efferocytosis. This work identifies a potential mechanism for neratinib in treating acute lung inflammation by upregulating the clearance of dead neutrophils and, through examination of the neutrophil phosphoproteome, provides important insights into the mechanisms by which this may be occurring.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Colchicine improves severe acute pancreatitis-induced acute lung injury by suppressing inflammation, apoptosis and oxidative stress in rats</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36076491/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36076491/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Inflammation, apoptosis and oxidative stress play critical roles in severe acute pancreatitis (SAP).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Colchicine (COL) mitigates severe acute pancreatitis-associated lung injury (SAP-ALI) in rats model.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Colchicine limits inflammation, apoptosis and oxidative stress in SAP-ALI.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Inflammation, apoptosis and oxidative stress contribute to the development of severe acute pancreatitis-associated acute lung injury (SAP-ALI). Currently, there is no curative treatment for SAP-ALI in the clinic. This study investigated the potential therapeutic role and mechanisms of colchicine in a rat model of SAP-ALI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; Male Sprague-Dawley rats were randomized and administrated intragastrically with vehicle saline or colchicine (0.5 mg/kg/day) for seven days, followed by injecting sodium taurocholate to induce SAP-ALI. Together with a healthy control group of rats, their pancreatic and lung tissues and plasma samples were collected for histology, enzyme-linked immunosorbent assay (ELISA), immunoblot, immunohistochemistry, and immunofluorescence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; Compared with the sham controls, the SAP group of rats with vehicle saline treatment displayed severe damages, inflammation with many neutrophil and macrophage infiltrates in pancreatic and lung tissues, accompanied by elevated levels of plasma interleukin-1β (IL-1β), IL-6 and tumor necrosis factor (TNF)-α, which were significantly mitigated in colchicine-treated SAP + COL group of rats. Furthermore, colchicine treatment significantly attenuated nuclear factor kappa-B (NF-κB)-p65, signal transducer and activator of transcription 3 (STAT3) and protein kinase B (AKT) phosphorylation, reduced inducible nitric oxide synthase (iNOS) and 4-Hydroxynonenal expression, ROS production and cell apoptosis by decreasing caspase-3 cleavage, Bax expression, but increasing Bcl-2, nuclear factor erythroid 2-related factor 2 (Nrf2) and heme oxygenase-1 (HO-1) expression in pancreatic and lung tissues, relative to the SAP group of rats.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/em&gt; Colchicine treatment significantly mitigated the severity of SAP-ALI by inhibiting inflammation, oxidative stress and cell apoptosis in rats.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Long non-coding RNA (lncRNA): A potential therapeutic target in acute lung injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/35873025/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/35873025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acute Lung Injury (ALI) and its severe form Acute Respiratory Distress Syndrome (ARDS) are the major cause of ICU death worldwide. ALI/ARDS is characterized by severe hypoxemia and inflammation that leads to poor lung compliance. Despite many advances in understanding and management, ALI/ARDS is still causing significant morbidity and mortality. Long non-coding RNA (lncRNA) is a fast-growing topic in lung inflammation and injury. lncRNA is a class of non-coding RNA having a length of more than 200 nucleotides. It has been a center of research for understanding the pathophysiology of various diseases in the past few years. Multiple studies have shown that lncRNAs are abundant in acute lung injury/injuries in mouse models and cell lines. By targeting these long non-coding RNAs, many investigators have demonstrated the alleviation of ALI in various mouse models. Therefore, lncRNAs show great promise as a therapeutic target in ALI. This review provides the current state of knowledge about the relationship between lncRNAs in various biological processes in acute lung injury and its use as a potential therapeutic target.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Structural integrity is essential for the protective effect of mitochondrial transplantation against UV-induced cell death</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35905626/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35905626/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mitochondrial transplantation exhibits protective effect on UV-induced cell death.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The mitochondrial components, such as ATP and mtDNA, are not the key factors of mitochondrial transplantation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mitochondria structural integrity is crucial in the radiation resistance of mitochondrial transplantation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mitochondrial transplantation (MT) is a new technology developed in recent years, which injects healthy mitochondria directly into damaged tissues or blood vessels to play a therapeutic role. This technology has been studied in many animal models of various diseases including myocardial ischemia, cerebral stroke, liver and lung injury, and even has been successfully used in the treatment of childhood heart disease. MT can quickly improve tissue function within a few minutes after injection. The speed with which MT improves tissue function is frequently questioned, for it is hard to understand how the whole mitochondrion transports to the damaged sites, enters cells and functions within such a short period of time. Are there small molecules of mitochondrial component responsible for the function of MT? To test this hypothesis, we established an ultra-violet (UV)-irradiated HeLa cell model. The results of colony formation, sulforhodamine B (SRB), and Hoechst 33342/PI double staining assay strongly indicated that MT exhibited a significant protective effect against UV irradiation damage. The UV irradiation-induced cell cycle arresting at S phase, apoptosis, mitochondrial membrane potential (MMP) decreasing, and the related apoptosis signaling factors p-IKKα, p-p65, I-κB and the activation of caspase3 were all reversed by MT treatments to some extent. The mechanisms of MT were evaluated through comparing the effect of thermal inactivation, ultrasonic crushing, and repeated freezing and thawing treatments on MT function. These results denied the above hypothesis that mitochondrial component may be responsible for MT, excluded the function of ATP, mtDNA and other small molecules, and indicated that the mitochondria structural integrity is essential. We also evaluated the effect of Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt; concentrations (1 and 1.8 mM) on MT, and the results showed no effect was found in this UV-irradiated HeLa cell model. Our data support a potent anti-UV irradiation effect of MT, and that structural integrity of the mitochondria is critical for its function.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Class IIa histone deacetylase inhibition ameliorates acute kidney injury by suppressing renal tubular cell apoptosis and enhancing autophagy and proliferation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35935816/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35935816/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Expression and function of histone deacetylases (HDACs) vary with cell types and pathological conditions. Our recent studies showed that pharmacological targeting class IIa HDACs attenuated renal fibrosis, but the effect of class IIa HDAC inhibition on acute kidney injury (AKI) remains unknown. In this study, we found that four class IIa HDACs (4, 5, 7, 9) were highly expressed in the kidney of folic acid (FA) and ischemia/reperfusion (I/R)-induced AKI in mice. Administration of TMP269, a potent and selective class IIa HDAC inhibitor, improved renal function and reduced tubular cell injury and apoptosis, with concomitant suppression of HDAC4 and elevation of acetyl-histone H3. Mechanistical studies showed that TMP269 treatment inhibited FA and I/R-induced caspase-3 cleavage, Bax expression and p53 phosphorylation. Conversely, TMP269 administration preserved expression of E-cadherin, BMP7, Klotho and Bcl-2 in injured kidneys. Moreover, TMP269 was effective in promoting cellular autophagy as indicated by increased expression of Atg7, beclin-1, and LC3II, and promoted renal tubular cell proliferation as shown by increased number of proliferating cell nuclear antigen-positive cells and expression of cyclin E. Finally, blocking class IIa HDACs inhibited FA-and I/R-induced phosphorylation of extracellular signal-regulated kinases 1 and 2, and p38, two signaling pathways associated with the pathogenesis of AKI. Collectively, these results suggest that pharmacological inhibition of class IIa HDACs protects against AKI through ameliorating apoptosis, enhancing autophagy and promoting proliferation of renal tubular cells by targeting multiple signaling pathways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inhaled Pro-Efferocytic Nanozymes Promote Resolution of Acute Lung Injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35859230/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35859230/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acute lung injury (ALI) is a significant contributor to the morbidity and mortality of sepsis. Characterized by uncontrolled inflammation and excessive inflammatory cells infiltration in lung, ALI has been exacerbated by impaired efferocytosis (clearance of apoptotic cells by macrophages). Through specific receptor recognition and activation of downstream signaling, efferocytic macrophages promote resolution of inflammation by efficiently engulfing dying cells, avoiding the consequent release of cellular inflammatory contents. Here, inspired by the intrinsic recovery mechanism of efferocytosis, an apoptotic cell membrane (ACM) coated antioxidant nanozyme (AOzyme) is engineered, thus obtaining an inhalable pro-efferocytic nanozyme (AOzyme@ACM). Notably, AOzyme@ACM can efficiently increase apoptotic cell removal by combing enhanced macrophages recognition of &amp;ldquo;eat me&amp;rdquo; signals through apoptotic body mimicking and scavenge of intracellular excessive reactive oxygen species (ROS), a significant barrier for efferocytosis. AOzyme@ACM can significantly inhibit inflammatory response, promote pro-resolving (M2) phenotype transition of macrophage, and alleviate ALI in endotoxemia mice compared with AOzyme group. By addressing the critical factor in the pathogenesis of sepsis-related ALI through restoring efferocytosis activity, the ACM-based antioxidant nanozyme in this study is envisioned to provide a promising strategy to treat this complex and challenging disease.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Autophagy promotes GSDME-mediated pyroptosis via intrinsic and extrinsic apoptotic pathways in cobalt chloride-induced hypoxia reoxygenation-acute kidney injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35863214/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35863214/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cobalt ions induced more serious damage in the reoxygenation stage in HRI.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CoCl&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; induced GSDME-mediated pyroptosis in the HRI-AKI model.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CoCl&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;-activated GSDME was cleaved via the intrinsic and extrinsic apoptotic pathways in HRI-AKI.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CoCl&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;-elevated autophagy promoted the induction of apoptosis and GSDME-mediated pyroptosis in HRI-AKI.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cobalt is a transition element that abundantly exists in the environment. Besides direct hypoxia stress, cobalt ions indirectly induce hypoxia-reoxygenation injury (HRI), the main cause of acute kidney injury (AKI), a life-threatening clinical syndrome characterized by the necrosis of the proximal tubular epithelial cells (PTECs) and inflammation. Pyroptosis, a type of inflammatory programmed cell death, might play an essential role in HRI-AKI. However, whether pyroptosis is involved in cobalt chloride (CoCl&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;)-induced HRI-AKI remains unknown. Autophagy is a cellular biological process maintaining cell homeostasis that is involved in cell damage in AKI, yet the underlying regulatory mechanism of autophagy on pyroptosis has not been fully understood. In this study, the in vitro and in vivo models of CoCl&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;-induced HRI-AKI were established with HK-2 cell line and C57BL/6J mouse. Pyroptosis-related markers were detected with western blotting and immunofluorescence assays, and results showed that gasdermin E (GSDME)-mediated pyroptosis was involved in the cell damage in HRI-AKI. Specific chemical inhibitors of caspase 3, caspase 8, and caspase 9 significantly inhibited GSDME-mediated pyroptosis, verifying that GSDME-mediated pyroptosis was induced via the activation of caspase 3/8/9. The western blotting and immunofluorescence assays were adopted to detect the accumulation of the autophagosomes, and results suggested that HRI increased the autophagic level. The effects of autophagy on apoptosis and pyroptosis were evaluated using lentivirus transfection assays to knock down autophagy-specific genes atg5 and fip200, and results demonstrated that autophagy induced GSDME-mediated pyroptosis via apoptotic pathways in HRI-AKI. Our results revealed the involvement of GSDME-mediated pyroptosis in CoCl&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;-induced HRI-AKI and promoted the understanding of the regulatory mechanism of GSDME cleavage. Our study might provide a potential therapeutic target for HRI-AKI, and will be helpful for the risk evaluation of cobalt exposure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inhibition of polycomb repressive complex 2 by targeting EED protects against cisplatin-induced acute kidney injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35734954/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35734954/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Polycomb repressive complex 2 (PRC2) is a multicomponent complex with methyltransferase activity that catalyzes trimethylation of histone H3 at lysine 27 (H3K27me3). Interaction of the epigenetic reader protein EED with EZH2, a catalytic unit of PRC, allosterically stimulates PRC2 activity. In this study, we investigated the role and underlying mechanism of the PRC2 in acute kidney injury (AKI) by using EED226, a highly selective PRC2 inhibitor, to target EED. Administration of EED226 improved renal function, attenuated renal pathological changes, and reduced renal tubular cell apoptosis in a murine model of cisplatin-induced AKI. In cultured renal epithelial cells, treatment with either EED226 or EED siRNA also ameliorated cisplatin-induced apoptosis. Mechanistically, EED226 treatment inhibited cisplatin-induced phosphorylation of p53 and FOXO3a, two transcriptional factors contributing to apoptosis, and preserved expression of Sirtuin 3 and PGC1α, two proteins associated with mitochondrial protection in vivo and in vitro. EED226 was also effective in enhancing renal tubular cell proliferation, suppressing expression of multiple inflammatory cytokines, and reducing infiltration of macrophages to the injured kidney. These data suggest that inhibition of the PRC2 activity by targeting EED can protect against cisplatin-induced AKI by promoting the survival and proliferation of renal tubular cells and inhibiting inflammatory response.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Liquiritigenin protects against myocardial ischemic by inhibiting oxidative stress, apoptosis, and L-type Ca2&#43; channels</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35747908/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35747908/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Liquiritigenin (Lq) offers cytoprotective effects against various cardiac injuries, but its beneficial effects on myocardial ischemic (MI) injury and the related mechanisms remain unclear. In the in vivo study, an animal model of MI was induced by intraperitoneal injection of isoproterenol (Iso, 85 mg/kg). ECG, heart rate, serum levels of CK and CK-MB, histopathological changes, and reactive oxygen species (ROS) levels were all measured. In vitro, H9c2 cells were divided into four groups and treated for 24 hr with liquiritigenin (30 μmol/L and 100 μmol/L) followed with CoCl&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; (800 μmol/L) for another 24 hr. Cell viability, apoptosis, mitochondrial membrane potential, and intracellular Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt; concentration ([Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt; ]&lt;sub&gt;i&lt;/sub&gt;) were then assessed. The L-type Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt; current (I&lt;sub&gt;Ca-L&lt;/sub&gt;) was detected using a patch clamp technique on isolated rat ventricular myocytes. The myocyte contraction and Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt; transients were measured using an IonOptix detection system. The remarkable cardiac injury and generation of intracellular ROS induced by Iso were alleviated via treatment with Lq. CoCl&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; administration induced cell apoptosis, mitochondrial dysfunction, and Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt; overload in H9c2; Lq reduces these deleterious effects of CoCl&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;. Meanwhile, Lq blocked I&lt;sub&gt;Ca-L&lt;/sub&gt; in a dose-dependent manner. The half-maximal inhibitory concentration of Lq was 110.87 μmol/L. Lq reversibly reduced the amplitude of cell contraction as well as the Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt; transients. The results show that Lq protects against MI injury by antioxidation, antiapoptosis, counteraction mitochondrial dysfunction, and inhibition of I&lt;sub&gt;Ca-L&lt;/sub&gt;, thus damping intracellular Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Innate Immune Cell Death in Neuroinflammation and Alzheimer&#39;s Disease</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/35741014/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/35741014/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alzheimer&amp;rsquo;s disease (AD) is a neurodegenerative disorder molecularly characterized by the formation of amyloid β (Aβ) plaques and type 2 microtubule-associated protein (Tau) abnormalities. Multiple studies have shown that many of the brain&amp;rsquo;s immunological cells, specifically microglia and astrocytes, are involved in AD pathogenesis. Cells of the innate immune system play an essential role in eliminating pathogens but also regulate brain homeostasis and AD. When activated, innate immune cells can cause programmed cell death through multiple pathways, including pyroptosis, apoptosis, necroptosis, and PANoptosis. The cell death often results in the release of proinflammatory cytokines that propagate the innate immune response and can eliminate Aβ plaques and aggregated Tau proteins. However, chronic neuroinflammation, which can result from cell death, has been linked to neurodegenerative diseases and can worsen AD. Therefore, the innate immune response must be tightly balanced to appropriately clear these AD-related structural abnormalities without inducing chronic neuroinflammation. In this review, we discuss neuroinflammation, innate immune responses, inflammatory cell death pathways, and cytokine secretion as they relate to AD. Therapeutic strategies targeting these innate immune cell death mechanisms will be critical to consider for future preventive or palliative treatments for AD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Caloric restriction reduces the pro-inflammatory eicosanoid 20-hydroxyeicosatetraenoic acid to protect from acute kidney injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35654224/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35654224/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acute kidney injury is a frequent complication in the clinical setting and associated with significant morbidity and mortality. Preconditioning with short-term caloric restriction is highly protective against kidney injury in rodent ischemia reperfusion injury models. However, the underlying mechanisms are unknown hampering clinical translation. Here, we examined the molecular basis of caloric restriction-mediated protection to elucidate the principles of kidney stress resistance. Analysis of an RNAseq dataset after caloric restriction identified Cyp4a12a, a cytochrome exclusively expressed in male mice, to be strongly downregulated after caloric restriction. Kidney ischemia reperfusion injury robustly induced acute kidney injury in male mice and this damage could be markedly attenuated by pretreatment with caloric restriction. In females, damage was significantly less pronounced and preconditioning with caloric restriction had only little effect. Tissue concentrations of the metabolic product of Cyp4a12a, 20-hydroxyeicosatetraenoic acid (20-HETE), were found to be significantly reduced by caloric restriction. Conversely, intraperitoneal supplementation of 20-HETE in preconditioned males partly abrogated the protective potential of caloric restriction. Interestingly, this effect was accompanied by a partial reversal of caloric restriction&amp;ndash;induced changes in protein but not RNA expression pointing towards inflammation, endoplasmic reticulum stress and lipid metabolism. Thus, our findings provide an insight into the mechanisms underlying kidney protection by caloric restriction. Hence, understanding the mediators of preconditioning is an important prerequisite for moving towards translation to the clinical setting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Design and synthesis of highly TRAIL expression HDAC inhibitors based on ONC201 to promote apoptosis of colorectal cancer</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35649291/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35649291/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Erratum in:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Corrigendum to &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0223523422004706&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Design and synthesis of highly TRAIL expression HDAC inhibitors based on ONC201 to promote apoptosis of colorectal cancer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; [Eur. J. Med. Chem. 238 (2022) 1-20/114484].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Compound IIc is a novel and effective highly TRAIL-sensitive HDAC inhibitors.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IIc mediated HCT-116 cell apoptosis through the TRAIL-induced apoptosis signaling pathway.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IIc showed good antitumor efficacy in HCT-116 xenograft model.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Activation of the TRAIL proapoptotic pathway can promote cancer cell apoptosis. Histone deacetylases (HDACs) also are promising drug targets for cancers, and their synergistic effect with TRAIL can improve the inhibitory effect on cancer cells. Therefore, the development of highly TRAIL-sensitive HDAC inhibitors might be a promising strategy for the treatment of cancers. We synthesized a series of HDAC inhibitors by introducing effective fragments sensitive to TRAIL. Compound IIc showed good inhibitory activity against HDAC1 and HCT116 cells and showed higher sensitivity to activating the expression of the TRAIL protein and promoting the apoptosis of HCT-116 cells compared with ONC201. The inhibitory activity of compound IIc (25 mg/kg) in the HCT-116 xenograft model was significantly greater than those of the positive control drugs (ONC201, chidamide). These findings suggested that development of highly TRAIL-sensitive HDAC inhibitors as colorectal tumor cancer drugs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Down-regulated miR-146a expression with increased neutrophil extracellular traps and apoptosis formation in autoimmune-mediated diffuse alveolar hemorrhage</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36028828/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36028828/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Increasing evidences have suggested an important role of microRNAs (miRNAs) in regulating cell death processes including NETosis and apoptosis. Dysregulated expression of miRNAs and increased formation of neutrophil extracellular traps (NETs) and apoptosis participate in autoimmune-mediated diffuse alveolar hemorrhage (DAH), mostly associated with pulmonary capillaritis in systemic lupus erythematosus (SLE) patients. In particular, besides the inhibition of apoptosis, miR-146a can control innate and acquired immune responses, and regulate the toll-like receptor pathway through targeting TRAF6 to reduce the expression of pro-inflammatory cytokines/chemokines like IL-8, a NETosis inducer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; Expression of miR-146a, TRAF6 and NETs were examined in peripheral blood neutrophils (PBNs) and lung tissues from SLE-associated DAH patients, and in neutrophils and pristane-induced DAH lung tissues from C57BL/6 mice. To assess NETs formation, we examined NETosis-related DNAs morphology and crucial mediators including protein arginine deiminase 4 and citrullinated Histone 3. Expression of miR-146a and its endogenous RNA SNHG16 were studied in HL-60 promyelocytic cells and MLE-12 alveolar cells during NETosis and apoptosis processes, respectively. MiR-146a-overexpressed and CRISPR-Cas13d-mediated SNHG16-silenced HL-60 cells were investigated for NETosis. MiR-146a-overexpressed MLE-12 cells were analyzed for apoptosis. Pristane-injected mice received intra-pulmonary miR-146a delivery to evaluate therapeutic efficacy in DAH.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; In DAH patients, there were down-regulated miR-146a levels with increased TRAF6 expression and PMA/LPS-induced NETosis in PBNs, and down-regulated miR-146a levels with increased TRAF6, high-mobility group box 1 (HMGB1), IL-8, NETs and apoptosis expression in lung tissues. HMGB1-stimulated mouse neutrophils had down-regulated miR-146a levels with increased TRAF6, IL-8 and NETs expression. PMA-stimulated HL-60 cells had down-regulated miR-146a levels with enhanced NETosis. MiR-146a-overexpressed or SNHG16-silenced HL-60 cells showed reduced NETosis. Apoptotic MLE-12 cells had down-regulated miR-146a expression and increased HMGB1 release, while miR-146a-overexpressed MLE-12 cells showed reduced apoptosis and HMGB1 production. There were down-regulated miR-146a levels with increased TRAF6, HMGB1, IL-8, NETs and apoptosis expression in mouse DAH lung tissues. Intra-pulmonary miR-146a delivery could suppress DAH by reducing TRAF6, IL-8, NETs and apoptosis expression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; Our results demonstrate firstly down-regulated pulmonary miR-146a levels with increased TRAF6 and IL-8 expression and NETs and apoptosis formation in autoimmune-mediated DAH, and implicate a therapeutic potential of intra-pulmonary miR-146a delivery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HCMV-miR-US33-5p promotes apoptosis of aortic vascular smooth muscle cells by targeting EPAS1/SLC3A2 pathway</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35596131/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35596131/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; In patients with acute aortic dissection (AAD), increased vascular smooth muscle cell (VSMC) apoptosis has been found. Human cytomegalovirus (HCMV)-miR-US33-5p was significantly increased in the plasma of patients with AAD. However, the roles of miR-US33-5p in human aortic VSMC (HA-VSMC) apoptosis remain to be elucidated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; In the current study, cell apoptosis was analyzed by flow cytometry, cell proliferation by CCK-8 assay, and differentially expressed genes by RNA sequencing. Luciferase reporter assay was used for binding analysis between miR-US33-5p and endothelial PAS domain protein 1 (EPAS1), and EPAS1 and amino acid transporter heavy chain, member 2 (SLC3A2). The enrichment degree of SLC3A2 promoter DNA was analyzed by chromatin immunoprecipitation assay. Quantitative reverse-transcription polymerase chain reaction (qRT-PCR) and immunoblotting were performed for measuring messenger RNA (mRNA) and protein levels, respectively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; It was found that HCMV infection inhibited proliferation but promoted HA-VSMC apoptosis by upregulating HCMV-miR-US33-5p. Transfection of HCMV-miR-US33-5p mimics the significant effect on several signaling pathways including integrin signaling as shown in the RNA sequencing data. Western blotting analysis confirmed that HCMV-miR-US33-5p mimics suppression of the activity of key factors of the integrin signal pathway including FAK, AKT, CAS, and Rac. Mechanistic study showed that HCMV-miR-US33-5p bound to the 3&amp;rsquo;-untranslated region of EPAS1 to suppress its expression, leading to suppression of SLC3A2 expression, which ultimately promoted cell apoptosis and inhibited cell proliferation. This was confirmed by the findings that silencing EPAS1 significantly reduced the SLC3A2 expression and inhibited proliferation and key factors of integrin signal pathway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; HCMV-miR-US33-5p suppressed proliferation, key factors of integrin signal pathway, and EPAS1/SLC3A2 expression, but promoted HA-VSMC apoptosis. These findings highlighted the importance of HCMV-miR-US33-5p/EPAS1/SCL3A2 signaling and may provide new insights into therapeutic strategies for AAD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evolving Concepts in Endothelial Pathobiology of Pulmonary Arterial Hypertension</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/35582968/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/35582968/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pulmonary arterial hypertension (PAH) is a deadly disease, characterized by increased vascular resistance, pulmonary arteriolar loss, and occlusive arterial remodeling, leading to eventual right heart failure. Evidence increasingly points to the pulmonary endothelium as a central actor in PAH. Endothelial cell apoptosis can result directly in distal lung arteriolar pruning and indirectly in the formation of complex and occlusive arterial lesions, reflecting an imbalance between endothelial injury and repair in the development and progression of PAH. Many of the mutations implicated in PAH are in genes, which are predominantly, or solely, expressed in endothelial cells, and the endothelium is a major target for therapeutic interventions to restore BMP signaling. We explore how arterial pruning can promote the emergence of occlusive arterial remodeling mediated by ongoing endothelial injury secondary to hemodynamic perturbation and pathological increases in luminal shear stress. The emerging role of endothelial cell senescence is discussed in the transition from reversible to irreversible arterial remodeling in advanced PAH, and we review the sometimes conflicting evidence that female sex hormones can both protect or promote vascular changes in disease. Finally, we explore the contribution of the endothelium to metabolic changes and the altered inflammatory and immune state in the PAH lung, focusing on the role of excessive TGFβ signaling. Given the complexity of the endothelial pathobiology of PAH, we anticipate that emerging technologies that allow the study of molecular events at a single cell level will provide answers to many of the questions raised in this review.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DEAD/H-Box Helicases in Immunity, Inflammation, Cell Differentiation, and Cell Death and Disease</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/35626643/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/35626643/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DEAD/H-box proteins are the largest family of RNA helicases in mammalian genomes, and they are present in all kingdoms of life. Since their discovery in the late 1980s, DEAD/H-box family proteins have been a major focus of study. They have been found to play central roles in RNA metabolism, gene expression, signal transduction, programmed cell death, and the immune response to bacterial and viral infections. Aberrant functions of DEAD/H-box proteins have been implicated in a wide range of human diseases that include cancer, neurodegeneration, and inherited genetic disorders. In this review, we provide a historical context and discuss the molecular functions of DEAD/H-box proteins, highlighting the recent discoveries linking their dysregulation to human diseases. We will also discuss the state of knowledge regarding two specific DEAD/H-box proteins that have critical roles in immune responses and programmed cell death, DDX3X and DDX58, also known as RIG-I. Given their importance in homeostasis and disease, an improved understanding of DEAD/H-box protein biology and protein-protein interactions will be critical for informing strategies to counteract the pathogenesis associated with several human diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It&#39;s All in the PAN: Crosstalk, Plasticity, Redundancies, Switches, and Interconnectedness Encompassed by PANoptosis Underlying the Totality of Cell Death-Associated Biological Effects</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/35563804/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/35563804/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The innate immune system provides the first line of defense against cellular perturbations. Innate immune activation elicits inflammatory programmed cell death in response to microbial infections or alterations in cellular homeostasis. Among the most well-characterized programmed cell death pathways are pyroptosis, apoptosis, and necroptosis. While these pathways have historically been defined as segregated and independent processes, mounting evidence shows significant crosstalk among them. These molecular interactions have been described as &amp;lsquo;crosstalk&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;plasticity&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;redundancies&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;molecular switches&amp;rsquo;, and more. Here, we discuss the key components of cell death pathways and note several examples of crosstalk. We then explain how the diverse descriptions of crosstalk throughout the literature can be interpreted through the lens of an integrated inflammatory cell death concept, PANoptosis. The totality of biological effects in PANoptosis cannot be individually accounted for by pyroptosis, apoptosis, or necroptosis alone. We also discuss PANoptosomes, which are multifaceted macromolecular complexes that regulate PANoptosis. We consider the evidence for PANoptosis, which has been mechanistically characterized during influenza A virus, herpes simplex virus 1, Francisella novicida, and Yersinia infections, as well as in response to altered cellular homeostasis, in inflammatory diseases, and in cancers. We further discuss the role of IRF1 as an upstream regulator of PANoptosis and conclude by reexamining historical studies which lend credence to the PANoptosis concept. Cell death has been shown to play a critical role in infections, inflammatory diseases, neurodegenerative diseases, cancers, and more; therefore, having a holistic understanding of cell death is important for identifying new therapeutic strategies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cineole alleviates the BPA-inhibited NETs formation by regulating the p38 pathway-mediated programmed cell death</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35483150/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35483150/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;BPA inhibited the release of NETs by inducing necroptosis and apoptosis.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CIN can alleviate the oxidative stress and programmed cell death induced by BPA.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CIN via p38 pathway alleviates BPA-induced neutrophil injury.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enriched the research on toxicology of BPA and detoxification mechanism of CIN.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bisphenol A (BPA) is an endocrine disruptor, that can cause immune dysfunction. Cineole (CIN) has that effect of regulating immune function and resist oxidation. Neutrophil extracellular traps (NETs) are one of the ways to resist pathogen invasion. In order to explore the effects of BPA and CIN on the release of chicken NETs and the antagonistic effect of CIN, take chicken peripheral blood neutrophils as object of study, grouping as NC, CIN, BPA + CIN and BPA. SEM, flow cytometry, RT-PCR, Western-blot and other methods were used to detect related indicators. The results showed that BPA inhibited the activities of GPX, SOD and CAT, increased the contents of MDA and NO, increased the activity of iNOS. BPA exposure inhibited the expression of myeloperoxidase (MPO), neutrophil elastase (NE) and histone, and inhibited the release of NETs. BPA activated downstream apoptosis and necroptosis through the p38 mitogen-activated protein kinase (p38-MAPK) pathway, which increased the expression of cytochrome C (CytC), bcl-2 associated K protein gene (bak), cysteinyl aspartate specific proteinase 3 (caspase-3), cysteinyl aspartate specific proteinase 9 (caspase-9), receptor-interacting protein kinase 1 (RIPK1), receptor-interacting protein kinase 1 (RIPK3) and mixed lineage kinase domain-like protein (MLKL), decreased the expression of B-cell lymphoma-2 (bcl-2). However, the co-exposure of CIN and BPA partially recovered the release of NETs, alleviated BPA-induced oxidative stress, and inhibited the activation of p38-MAPK pathway, necroptosis, and mitochondrial apoptosis pathway. These results indicated that CIN modulated p38 pathway alleviated BPA-induced neutrophil necroptosis and apoptosis, and increased NETs formation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cyclin-dependent kinase 4-related tubular epithelial cell proliferation is regulated by Paired box gene 2 in kidney ischemia-reperfusion injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35483529/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35483529/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paired box 2 (Pax2) is a transcription factor essential for kidney development and is reactivated in proximal tubular epithelial cells (PTECs) during recovery from kidney injury. However, the role of Pax2 in this process is still unknown. Here the role of Pax2 reactivation during injury was examined in the proliferation of PTECs using an ischemia-reperfusion injury (IRI) mouse model. Kidney proximal tubule-specific Pax2 conditional knockout mice were generated by mating kidney androgen-regulated protein-Cre and Pax2 flox mice. The degree of cell proliferation and fibrosis was assessed and a Pax2 inhibitor (EG1) was used to evaluate the role of Pax2 in the hypoxic condition of cultured PTECs (O2 5%, 24 hours). The number of Pax2-positive cells and Pax2 mRNA increased after IRI. Sirius red staining indicated that the area of interstitial fibrosis was significantly larger in knockout mice 14 days after IRI. The number of Ki-67-positive cells (an index of proliferation) was significantly lower in knockout than in wild-type mice after IRI, whereas the number of TUNEL-positive cells (an index of apoptotic cells) was significantly higher in knockout mice four days after IRI. Expression analyses of cell cycle-related genes showed that cyclin-dependent kinase 4 (CDK4) was significantly less expressed in the Pax2 knockout mice. In vitro data showed that the increase in CDK4 mRNA and protein expression induced by hypoxia was attenuated by EG1. Thus, Pax2 reactivation may be involved in PTEC proliferation by activating CDK4, thereby limiting kidney fibrosis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crosstalk between lncRNAs in the apoptotic pathway and therapeutic targets in cancer</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/35597701/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/35597701/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The assertion that a significant portion of the mammalian genome has not been translated and that non-coding RNA accounts for over half of polyadenylate RNA have received much attention. In recent years, increasing evidence proposes non-coding RNAs (ncRNAs) as new regulators of various cellular processes, including cancer progression and nerve damage. Apoptosis is a type of programmed cell death critical for homeostasis and tissue development. Cancer cells often have inhibited apoptotic pathways. It has recently been demonstrated that up/down-regulation of various lncRNAs in certain types of tumors shapes cancer cells&amp;rsquo; response to apoptotic stimuli. This review discusses the most recent studies on lncRNAs and apoptosis in healthy and cancer cells. In addition, the role of lncRNAs as novel targets for cancer therapy is reviewed here. Finally, since it has been shown that lncRNA expression is associated with specific types of cancer, the potential for using lncRNAs as biomarkers is also discussed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>circHECTD1 attenuates apoptosis of alveolar epithelial cells in acute lung injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35440759/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35440759/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Circular RNAs (circRNAs) play important roles in many lung diseases. This study aimed to investigate the role of circHECTD1 in acute lung injury (ALI). The mouse and cell models of ALI were induced by lipopolysaccharide (LPS). The apoptosis of alveolar epithelial cells (AECs) was detected by flow cytometry. The relationships between circHECTD1, miRNAs, and target genes were assessed by RNA pull-down, luciferase reporter gene, and RNA-FISH assays. circHECTD1 was downregulated in LPS-induced human and mouse AECs (HBE and MLE-12). The knockdown of circHECTD1 increased the apoptotic rates and the expressions of miR-136 and miR-320a, while its overexpression caused opposite effects in LPS-induced HBE and MLE-12 cells. Mechanistically, circHECTD1 bound to miR-320a and miR-136. miR-320a targeted PIK3CA and mediated the effect of circHECTD1 on PIK3CA expression. miR-136 targeted Sirt1 and mediated the effect of circHECTD1 on Sirt1 expression. Silencing PIK3CA and/or Sirt1 reversed the effect of circHECTD1 overexpression on the apoptosis of LPS-induced HBE and MLE-12 cells. In vivo, overexpression of circHECTD1 alleviated the LPS-induced ALI of mice. Our findings suggested that circHECTD1 inhibits the apoptosis of AECs through miR-320a/PIK3CA and miR-136/Sirt1 pathways in LPS-induced ALI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Geraniol Ameliorates Doxorubicin-Mediated Kidney Injury through Alteration of Antioxidant Status, Inflammation, and Apoptosis: Potential Roles of NF-κB and Nrf2/Ho-1</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35458182/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35458182/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Doxorubicin-mediated kidney impairment is a serious problem in cancer treatment. Accordingly, this work investigated the ability of geraniol to modulate doxorubicin-induced kidney damage using a rat model. Rats were randomly assigned to four groups: control, doxorubicin (20 mg/kg, intraperitoneal, i.p.), doxorubicin plus 100 mg/kg of geraniol, and doxorubicin plus 200 mg/kg of geraniol. A single doxorubicin injection triggered kidney impairment, as evidenced by the altered serum creatinine, blood urea nitrogen, and albumin values; it also caused histological changes in the kidney architecture. Additionally, doxorubicin enhanced lipid peroxidation while lowering reduced glutathione, catalase activity, and the expression of glutathione peroxidase and superoxide dismutase. Interestingly, pre-treatment with geraniol rescued doxorubicin-induced alterations in kidney antioxidant parameters, enzymatic activity, and the expression of inflammatory and apoptosis-mediating gene and proteins. Moreover, prophylactic treatment with geraniol preserved most kidney histological characteristics in a dose-dependent manner. These findings support that geraniol could protect against doxorubicin-mediated kidney dysfunction. However, further research is needed to clarify the mechanisms of geraniol&amp;rsquo;s protective effects against doxorubicin-mediated kidney dysfunction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Filamentous GLS1 promotes ROS-induced apoptosis upon glutamine deprivation via insufficient asparagine synthesis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35381197/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35381197/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GLS1 orchestrates glutaminolysis and promotes cell proliferation when glutamine is abundant by regenerating TCA cycle intermediates and supporting redox homeostasis. CB-839, an inhibitor of GLS1, is currently under clinical investigation for a variety of cancer types. Here, we show that GLS1 facilitates apoptosis when glutamine is deprived. Mechanistically, the absence of exogenous glutamine sufficiently reduces glutamate levels to convert dimeric GLS1 to a self-assembled, extremely low-Km filamentous polymer. GLS1 filaments possess an enhanced catalytic activity, which further depletes intracellular glutamine. Functionally, filamentous GLS1-dependent glutamine scarcity leads to inadequate synthesis of asparagine and mitogenome-encoded proteins, resulting in ROS-induced apoptosis that can be rescued by asparagine supplementation. Physiologically, we observed GLS1 filaments in solid tumors and validated the tumor-suppressive role of constitutively active, filamentous GLS1 mutants K320A and S482C in xenograft models. Our results change our understanding of GLS1 in cancer metabolism and suggest the therapeutic potential of promoting GLS1 filament formation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chrysin Ameliorates Influenza Virus Infection in the Upper Airways by Repressing Virus-Induced Cell Cycle Arrest and Mitochondria-Dependent Apoptosis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35432374/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35432374/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chrysin has been proven to possess antiviral properties, but the precise underlying anti-influenza mechanism and its anti-influenza efficacy in vivo are largely unclear. In this study, we investigated the involvement of chrysin in the blockade of cell cycle and apoptosis in distinct cell lines subjected to two H1N1 influenza A virus (IAV) strains, as well as its anti-IAV activity in vivo. Here, we found an early unidentified finding that chrysin strongly impeded IAV replication through a mechanism that was autonomous of innate antiviral immune activation and viral protein interaction. Surprisingly, chrysin can suppress IAV-induced cell cycle arrest in the G0/G1 phase by downregulating the expression levels of P53 and P21 while promoting Cyclin D1/CDK4 and Cyclin E1/CDK2 activation. Furthermore, chrysin dramatically inhibited the IAV-triggered mitochondrial apoptotic pathway by altering the balance of Bax/Bcl-xl and reducing caspase-9 and caspase-3 activation. Accumulated reactive oxygen species (ROS) reduction may contribute to the inhibitory role of chrysin in cell cycle arrest and apoptosis following IAV infection. Notably, chrysin preferably inhibited IAV replication in the upper respiratory tract, indicating that it might be a promising drug for restraining the spread of respiratory viruses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>m6A mRNA modification maintains colonic epithelial cell homeostasis via NF-κB-mediated antiapoptotic pathway</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35333576/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35333576/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Colonic mucosal barrier dysfunction is one of the major causes of inflammatory bowel disease (IBD). However, the mechanisms underlying mucosal barrier dysfunction are poorly understood. N6-methyladenosine (m6A) mRNA modification is an important modulator of epitranscriptional regulation of gene expression, participating in multiple physiological and pathological processes. However, the function of m6A modification in colonic epithelial cells and stem cells is unknown. Here, we show that m6A modification is essential for maintaining the homeostatic self-renewal in colonic stem cells. Specific deletion of the methyltransferase 14 (Mettl14) gene in mouse colon resulted in colonic stem cell apoptosis, causing mucosal barrier dysfunction and severe colitis. Mechanistically, we revealed that Mettl14 restricted colonic epithelial cell death by regulating the stability of Nfkbia mRNA and modulating the NF-κB pathway. Our results identified a previously unidentified role for m6A modification in colonic epithelial cells and stem cells, suggesting that m6A modification may be a potential therapeutic target for IBD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inhibition of lung microbiota-derived proapoptotic peptides ameliorates acute exacerbation of pulmonary fibrosis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35322016/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35322016/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis is an incurable disease of unknown etiology. Acute exacerbation of idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis is associated with high mortality. Excessive apoptosis of lung epithelial cells occurs in pulmonary fibrosis acute exacerbation. We recently identified corisin, a proapoptotic peptide that triggers acute exacerbation of pulmonary fibrosis. Here, we provide insights into the mechanism underlying the processing and release of corisin. Furthermore, we demonstrate that an anticorisin monoclonal antibody ameliorates lung fibrosis by significantly inhibiting acute exacerbation in the human transforming growth factorβ1 model and acute lung injury in the bleomycin model. By investigating the impact of the anticorisin monoclonal antibody in a general model of acute lung injury, we further unravel the potential of corisin to impact such diseases. These results underscore the role of corisin in the pathogenesis of acute exacerbation of pulmonary fibrosis and acute lung injury and provide a novel approach to treating this incurable disease.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Epithelial LIF signaling limits apoptosis and lung injury during bacterial pneumonia</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35137631/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35137631/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During bacterial pneumonia, alveolar epithelial cells are critical for maintaining gas exchange and providing antimicrobial as well as pro-immune properties. We previously demonstrated that leukemia inhibitory factor (LIF), an IL-6 family cytokine, is produced by type II alveolar epithelial cells (ATII) and is critical for tissue protection during bacterial pneumonia. However, the target cells and mechanisms of LIF-mediated protection remain unknown. Here, we demonstrate that antibody-induced LIF blockade remodels the lung epithelial transcriptome in association with increased apoptosis. Based on these data, we performed pneumonia studies using a novel mouse model in which LIFR (the unique receptor for LIF) is absent in lung epithelium. Although LIFR is expressed on the surface of epithelial cells, its absence only minimally contributed to tissue protection during pneumonia. Single-cell RNA-sequencing (scRNAseq) was conducted to identify adult murine lung cell types most prominently expressing &lt;em&gt;Lifr&lt;/em&gt;, revealing endothelial cells, mesenchymal cells, and ATIIs as major sources of &lt;em&gt;Lifr&lt;/em&gt;. Sequencing data indicated that ATII cells were significantly impacted by pneumonia, with additional differences observed in response to LIF neutralization, including but not limited to gene programs related to cell death, injury, and inflammation. Overall, our data suggest that LIF signaling on epithelial cells alters responses in this cell type during pneumonia. However, our results also suggest separate and perhaps more prominent roles of LIFR in other cell types, such as endothelial cells or mesenchymal cells, which provide grounds for future investigation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GSPE Protects against Bleomycin-Induced Pulmonary Fibrosis in Mice via Ameliorating Epithelial Apoptosis through Inhibition of Oxidative Stress</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35355866/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35355866/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis (IPF) is a chronic, progressive interstitial lung disease of unknown cause which leads to alveolar epithelial cell apoptosis followed by basement membrane disruption and accumulation of extracellular matrix, destroying the lung architecture. Oxidative stress is involved in the development of alveolar injury, inflammation, and fibrosis. Oxidative stress-mediated alveolar epithelial cell (AEC) apoptosis is suggested to be a key process in the pathogenesis of IPF. Therefore, the present study investigated whether grape seed proanthocyanidin extract (GSPE) could inhibit the development of pulmonary fibrosis via ameliorating epithelial apoptosis through the inhibition of oxidative stress. We found that GSPE significantly ameliorated the histological changes and the level of collagen deposition in bleomycin (BLM)-induced lungs. Moreover, GSPE attenuated lung inflammation by reducing the total number of cells in bronchoalveolar lavage (BAL) fluid and decreasing the expression of IL-6. We observed that the levels of H2O2 leading to oxidative stress were increased following BLM instillation, which significantly decreased with GSPE treatment both in vivo and in vitro. These findings showed that GSPE attenuated BLM-induced epithelial apoptosis in the mouse lung and A549 alveolar epithelial cell through the inhibition of oxidative stress. Furthermore, GSPE could attenuate mitochondrial-associated cell apoptosis via decreasing the Bax/Bcl-2 ratio. The present study demonstrates that GSPE could ameliorate bleomycin-induced pulmonary fibrosis in mice via inhibition of epithelial apoptosis through the inhibition of oxidative stress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PINK1/Parkin-mediated mitophagy is activated to protect against AFB1-induced kidney damage in mice</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35304092/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35304092/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aflatoxin B&lt;sub&gt;1&lt;/sub&gt; (AFB&lt;sub&gt;1&lt;/sub&gt;) is a toxic food pollutant that has extensive deleterious impacts on the kidney. Oxidative stress represents the primary mechanism of AFB&lt;sub&gt;1&lt;/sub&gt; nephrotoxicity and can also cause mitochondrial damage. Damaged mitochondria can trigger apoptosis leading to kidney injury. PINK1/Parkin-mediated mitophagy can alleviate mitochondrial injury to maintain cellular homeostasis, however, its role in AFB&lt;sub&gt;1&lt;/sub&gt;-induced kidney damage is unknown. To investigate the effect of PINK1/Parkin-mediated mitophagy on kidney impairment triggered by AFB&lt;sub&gt;1&lt;/sub&gt;, 40 male wild-type (WT) C57BL/6N mice were first assigned to 4 groups and orally exposed to AFB&lt;sub&gt;1&lt;/sub&gt; at 0, 0.5, 0.75, and 1 mg/kg body weight (BW) for 28 days. The results revealed that AFB&lt;sub&gt;1&lt;/sub&gt; induced kidney damage, oxidative stress, mitochondrial damage, apoptosis and activated PINK1/Parkin-mediated mitophagy with a dose-dependent effect. Then, 20 male WT C57BL/6N mice and 20 male Parkin knockout (Parkin&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt;) C57BL/6N mice were assigned to 4 groups and orally exposed to AFB&lt;sub&gt;1&lt;/sub&gt; at 0, 1, 0, and 1 mg/kg BW for 28 days. The results revealed that Parkin&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt; suppressed mitophagy and exacerbated kidney damage, oxidative stress, mitochondrial damage, and apoptosis under AFB&lt;sub&gt;1&lt;/sub&gt; exposure. The aforementioned evidences demonstrate that PINK1/Parkin-mediated mitophagy is activated by AFB&lt;sub&gt;1&lt;/sub&gt; and protects against kidney damage in mice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fengreqing Oral Liquid Exerts Anti-Inflammatory Effects by Promoting Apoptosis and Inhibiting PI3K/AKT and NF-κB Signaling Pathways</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35370749/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35370749/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fengreqing oral liquid (FOL), a Chinese patent drug frequently used in clinical practice in China, is effective in treating inflammatory diseases of the upper respiratory tract such as colds and flu. However, its anti-inflammatory effects and mechanisms remain to be elucidated. In this study, the anti-inflammatory effects of FOL and its mechanisms on PI3K/AKT and NF-κB signaling pathways in LPS-induced RAW264.7 cells were explored, as well as the regulatory effect of FOL on apoptosis. In addition, the potential of FOL for the treatment of acute lung injury was explored in LPS-induced ALI mice. The results showed that treatment with FOL significantly reduced the levels of interleukin 1β (IL-1β), interleukin 6 (IL-6), nitric oxide (NO), and tumor necrosis factor α (TNF-α) in the supernatant of LPS-induced RAW264.7 cells, and also significantly reduced the phosphorylated protein levels of PI3K and AKT in the PI3K/AKT signaling pathway and also protein levels of NF-κB p50, phosphorylated NF-κB p65, and IκBα in the NF-κB signaling pathway. In addition, the results showed that FOL induced apoptosis in LPS-induced RAW264.7 cells at the level of 80%-90%, and significantly increased the protein expression levels of the pro-apoptotic Bax and cleaved-caspase-3. In LPS-induced ALI mice, FOL administration showed inhibition of IL-1β, IL-6, and TNF-α in Bronchoalveolar lavage fluid (BALF) and decreased protein expression levels of PI3K, AKT, NF-κB p50, and NF-κB p65, and elevated protein expression levels of Bax and cleaved-caspase-3 significantly. These results suggest that FOL may exert anti-inflammatory effects by inhibiting the PI3K/AKT signaling pathway to promote apoptosis and leading to attenuated activation of the NF-κB signaling pathway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Molecular Mechanism of Long Non-Coding RNA (LncRNA) Regulation of Notch Signaling in Glucose-Induced Apoptosis of Human Retinal Vascular Endothelial Cell</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35715905/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35715905/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Diabetes, a global health concern, affects the health of more than 500 million adults. The absence of Notch protein can cause an imbalance in the retinal vascular environment and cause retinal vascular disease. Long noncoding RNA (lncRNA) is known to be involved in the regulation of many signaling pathways. We hope to understand the specific mechanism of apoptosis in retinal vascular endothelial cells (RVECs) by exploring the regulatory effect of lncRNA on the Notch pathway. In this study, we found that RVECs treated with glucose showed increased levels of Notch transcript and protein expression. The lentiviral interference with Notch RNAi reversed this response. When Notch activity decreased, oxidative stress also decreased, accompanied by increased levels of Caspase-9 and Caspase-3 and an increased rate of apoptosis. Therefore, we believe that Notch is involved in the development of diabetic retinopathy and loss of expression promotes apoptosis of human RVECs. By inhibiting the Notch pathway, lncRNA promotes apoptosis of human RVECs in a high-glucose environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Phosphorylated NFS1 weakens oxaliplatin-based chemosensitivity of colorectal cancer by preventing PANoptosis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35221331/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35221331/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Metabolic enzymes have an indispensable role in metabolic reprogramming, and their aberrant expression or activity has been associated with chemosensitivity. Hence, targeting metabolic enzymes remains an attractive approach for treating tumors. However, the influence and regulation of cysteine desulfurase (NFS1), a rate-limiting enzyme in iron-sulfur (Fe-S) cluster biogenesis, in colorectal cancer (CRC) remain elusive. Here, using an in vivo metabolic enzyme gene-based clustered regularly interspaced short palindromic repeats (CRISPR)-Cas9 library screen, we revealed that loss of NFS1 significantly enhanced the sensitivity of CRC cells to oxaliplatin. In vitro and in vivo results showed that NFS1 deficiency synergizing with oxaliplatin triggered PANoptosis (apoptosis, necroptosis, pyroptosis, and ferroptosis) by increasing the intracellular levels of reactive oxygen species (ROS). Furthermore, oxaliplatin-based oxidative stress enhanced the phosphorylation level of serine residues of NFS1, which prevented PANoptosis in an S293 phosphorylation-dependent manner during oxaliplatin treatment. In addition, high expression of NFS1, transcriptionally regulated by MYC, was found in tumor tissues and was associated with poor survival and hyposensitivity to chemotherapy in patients with CRC. Overall, the findings of this study provided insights into the underlying mechanisms of NFS1 in oxaliplatin sensitivity and identified NFS1 inhibition as a promising strategy for improving the outcome of platinum-based chemotherapy in the treatment of CRC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amelioration of Endotoxin-Induced Acute Lung Injury and Alveolar Epithelial Cells Apoptosis by Simvastatin Is Associated with Up-Regulation of Survivin/NF-kB/p65 Pathway</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35269738/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35269738/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Disruption of the alveolar-endothelial barrier caused by inflammation leads to the progression of septic acute lung injury (ALI). In the present study, we investigated the beneficial effects of simvastatin on the endotoxin lipopolysaccharide (LPS)-induced ALI and its related mechanisms. A model of ALI was induced within experimental sepsis developed by intraperitoneal injection of a single non-lethal LPS dose after short-term simvastatin pretreatment (10-40 mg/kg orally). The severity of the lung tissue inflammatory injury was expressed as pulmonary damage scores (PDS). Alveolar epithelial cell apoptosis was confirmed by TUNEL assay (DNA fragmentation) and expressed as an apoptotic index (AI), and immunohistochemically for cleaved caspase-3, cytochrome C, and anti-apoptotic Bcl-xL, an inhibitor of apoptosis, survivin, and transcriptional factor, NF-kB/p65. Severe inflammatory injury of pulmonary parenchyma (PDS 3.33 ± 0.48) was developed after the LPS challenge, whereas simvastatin significantly and dose-dependently protected lung histology after LPS (&lt;em&gt;p&lt;/em&gt; &amp;lt; 0.01). Simvastatin in a dose of 40 mg/kg showed the most significant effects in amelioration alveolar epithelial cells apoptosis, demonstrating this as a marked decrease of AI (&lt;em&gt;p&lt;/em&gt; &amp;lt; 0.01 vs. LPS), cytochrome C, and cleaved caspase-3 expression. Furthermore, simvastatin significantly enhanced the expression of Bcl-xL and survivin. Finally, the expression of survivin and its regulator NF-kB/p65 in the alveolar epithelium was in strong positive correlation across the groups. Simvastatin could play a protective role against LPS-induced ALI and apoptosis of the alveolar-endothelial barrier. Taken together, these effects were seemingly mediated by inhibition of caspase 3 and cytochrome C, a finding that might be associated with the up-regulation of cell-survival survivin/NF-kB/p65 pathway and Bcl-xL.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Knockdown of receptor interacting protein 140 (RIP140) alleviated lipopolysaccharide-induced inflammation, apoptosis and permeability in pulmonary microvascular endothelial cells by regulating C-terminal binding protein 2 (CTBP2)</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35113002/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35113002/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main pathological feature of acute lung injury (ALI) is pulmonary edema caused by increased permeability of pulmonary microvascular endothelial cells (PMVECs). LPS was has been confirmed to lead to cell damage and barrier dysfunction in PMVECs. Furthermore, receptor interacting protein 140 (RIP140) was discovered to be increased in LPS-induced human pulmonary microvascular endothelial cells (HPMECs), but the mechanism of RIP140 on LPS-induced HPMECs has not been investigated. In this study, an acute lung injury model was constructed in LPS-induced HPMECs. After RIP140 was downregulated, inflammation, apoptosis and cell permeability levels were detected by RT-qPCR, TUNEL staining and FITC-Dextran, respectively. Western blotting was used to detect the protein levels of related factors. The binding of RIP140 and C-terminal binding protein 2 (CTBP2) was predicted by database and verified by Co-IP. Subsequently, CTBP2 overexpression was transfected into cells and the above experiments were performed again. The results showed that inflammation, apoptosis and permeability levels of LPS-induced HPMECs were remarkably increased compared to the untreated control group. However, these levels were suppressed after RIP140 was silenced compared to the LPS-induced HPMECs group. Notably, the Co-IP study demonstrated that RIP140 and CTBP2 interacted with each other. Moreover, CTBP2 overexpression reversed the inhibitory effects of RIP140 silencing on LPS-induced inflammation, apoptosis and permeability levels in HPMECs. Together, the study found that interference of RIP140 could alleviate LPS-induced inflammation, apoptosis and permeability in HPMECs by regulating CTBP2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Long non-coding RNA growth arrest specific 5 is downregulated in sepsis-ALI and inhibits apoptosis by up-regulating miR-146a</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35112981/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35112981/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Long non-coding RNA (lncRNA) growth arrest specific 5 (GAS5) and microRNA (miR)-146a both have inhibitory effects on LPS-induced inflammation, suggesting the crosstalk between them. In this study, the expression of GAS5 and miR-146a in patients with sepsis-induced acute lung injury (sepsis-ALI), sepsis patients without obvious complications (sepsis) and healthy controls were studied by RT-qPCR. The role of GAS5 in the expression and methylation of miR-146a in human bronchial epithelial cells (HBEpCs) were studied by RT-qPCR and methylation-specific PCR (MSP), respectively. Cell apoptosis was analyzed by flow cytometry. We found that GAS5 and miR-146a were downregulated in sepsis-ALI and the expression of these two were correlated. LPS induced the downregulation of GAS5 and miR-146a in HBEpCs. In HBEpCs, overexpression of GAS5 increased the expression levels of miR-146a and reduced the methylation of miR-146a gene. Under lipopolysaccharide (LPS) treatment, overexpression of GAS5 and miR-146a decreased the apoptotic rate of HBEpCs. Moreover, the combined overexpression of GAS5 and miR-146a showed stronger effects. Therefore, GAS5 is downregulated in sepsis-ALI and inhibits cell apoptosis by up-regulating the expression of miR-146a.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Long noncoding RNA EIF1AX-AS1 promotes endometrial cancer cell apoptosis by affecting EIF1AX mRNA stabilization</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35080085/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35080085/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Long noncoding RNAs (lncRNAs) have been found to play an important role in the occurrence and development of endometrial carcinoma (EC). Here, using RNA sequencing analysis, we systemically screened and identified the lncRNA eukaryotic translation initiation factor 1A, X-linked (EIF1AX)-AS1, which is aberrantly downregulated in clinical EC tissues and closely correlated with tumor type. &lt;em&gt;EIF1AX-AS1&lt;/em&gt; markedly inhibited EC cell proliferation and promoted apoptosis in vitro and in vivo. Mechanistically, &lt;em&gt;EIF1AX-AS1&lt;/em&gt; interacts with &lt;em&gt;EIF1AX&lt;/em&gt; mRNA and poly C binding protein 1 (PCBP1), which promote &lt;em&gt;EIF1AX&lt;/em&gt; mRNA degradation. Intriguingly, by interacting with internal ribosome entry site-related protein Y-box binding protein 1 (YBX-1), EIF1AX promotes c-Myc translation through the internal ribosome entry site pathway. c-Myc promotes &lt;em&gt;EIF1AX&lt;/em&gt; transcription and thus forms a feed-forward loop to regulate EC cell proliferation. Taken together, these data reveal new insights into the biology driving EC proliferation and highlights the potential of lncRNAs as biomarkers for prognosis and future therapeutic targets for cancer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A novel nordihydroguaiaretic acid analog, compound 3a, alleviates acute lung injury by exerting antiapoptotic and antiinflammatory effects</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35085517/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35085517/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acute lung injury (ALI) is a continuum of pulmonary changes caused by various lung insults. Previously, we synthesized a series of nordihydroguaiaretic acid analogs; of these, compound 3a exhibited excellent antioxidant capacity in a murine model of middle cerebral artery occlusion. However, it remains unclear whether compound 3a can modulate lipopolysaccharide (LPS)-induced ALI. ALI was induced via tracheal LPS administration, and the pathological changes were assessed. The level of inflammation was verified by immunofluorescence and immunohistochemical analyses. Apoptosis was measured by terminal deoxynucleotidyl transferase dUTP nick-end labeling assays and Western blotting. Changes in the levels of mitogen-activated protein kinase (MAPK)/nuclear factor-κB (NF-κB) pathway proteins were assessed by immunofluorescence assays and Western blotting. In vitro, RAW 264.7 cells were treated with compound 3a prior to LPS challenge, and the intracellular level of inflammation was assessed by quantitative PCR (qPCR). Relevant proteins were detected via immunofluorescence assays and Western blotting. Mice developed extensive lung inflammation by 24 h after LPS challenge. Histological examination revealed signs typical of ALI. Preadministration of compound 3a markedly ameliorated the histopathological changes and reduced fluid exudation into the alveolar space. Compound 3a also greatly reduced the levels of inflammation and apoptosis both in vivo and in vitro. Moreover, compound 3a markedly reduced phosphorylation of MAPK/NF-κB pathway-related proteins and p65 translocation, consistent with the in vitro observations. In summary, administration of compound 3a prior to LPS suppressed ALI via inhibition of the MAPK/NF-κB pathway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Platelets Derived Transthyretin Participate in The Development of Sepsis Associated Acute Kidney Injury by Inducing Oxidative Stress and Apoptosis of Renal Tubular Epithelial Cells</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35081075/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35081075/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The pathophysiology of sepsis-associated acute kidney injury (S-AKI) is not well elucidated. Platelets have been reported to play a critical role in the pathogenesis of AKI, but the true mechanism remains unknown. Herein, we established a mouse model of S-AKI by cecal ligation and puncture (CLP). Ticagrelor was given 24 h before and after CLP by gastric gavage. Platelets were isolated and analyzed by the label-free proteome approach to identify platelet-derived damage-associated molecular patterns (DAMPs). Our results demonstrated that, among all differentially expressed proteins (DEPs), platelet-derived transthyretin (TTR) exerted effects in S-AKI. To examine the direct effects of platelet TTR on human renal proximal tubule epithelial (HK2) cells damage, platelets were co-cultured with HK2 cells. The results indicated that platelet TTR can cause reactive oxygen species production and apoptosis in HK2 cells. Further research found that platelet TTR can also result in increased levels of mRNA and protein for protein kinase B (AKT), phosphatidylinositol 3-kinase (PI3K), and extracellular regulated protein kinase (ERK), as analyzed by real-time quantitative polymerase chain reaction (RT-qPCR) and western blotting. In conclusion, platelet-derived TTR may be one kind of DAMPs that plays an important role in the development of S-AKI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Macrophage interferon regulatory factor 4 deletion ameliorates aristolochic acid nephropathy via reduced migration and increased apoptosis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35025763/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35025763/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aristolochic acid (AA) is the causative nephrotoxic alkaloid in AA nephropathy, which results in a tubulointerstitial fibrosis. AA causes direct proximal tubule damage as well as an influx of macrophages, although the role of macrophages in pathogenesis is poorly understood. Here, we demonstrate that AA directly stimulates migration, inflammation, and ROS production in macrophages &lt;em&gt;ex vivo&lt;/em&gt;. Cells lacking interferon regulatory factor 4 (IRF4), a known regulator of macrophage migration and phenotype, had a reduced migratory response, though effects on ROS production and inflammation were preserved or increased relative to WT cells. Macrophage-specific IRF4-knockout mice were protected from both acute and chronic kidney effects of AA administration based on functional and histological analysis. Renal macrophages from kidneys of AA-treated macrophage-specific IRF4-knockout mice demonstrated increased apoptosis and ROS production compared with WT controls, indicating that AA directly polarizes macrophages to a promigratory and proinflammatory phenotype. However, knockout mice had reduced renal macrophage abundance following AA administration. While macrophages lacking IRF4 can adopt a proinflammatory phenotype upon AA exposure, their inability to migrate to the kidney and increased rates of apoptosis upon infiltration provide protection from AA &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt;. These results provide evidence of direct AA effects on macrophages in AA nephropathy and add to the growing body of evidence that supports a key role of IRF4 in modulating macrophage function in kidney injury.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Salidroside prevents PM2.5-induced BEAS-2B cell apoptosis via SIRT1-dependent regulation of ROS and mitochondrial function</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35026589/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35026589/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PM2.5 induces BEAS-2B cell apoptosis through mitochondrial pathway.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Salidroside inhibits BEAS-2B cell apoptosis induced by PM2.5 through improving the production of ROS and the damage of mitochondrial.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The activation of SIRT1 plays a key role in the protective effect of Sal on PM2.5 induced apoptosis of BEAS-2B cells.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PM2.5 is a harmful air pollutant currently threatening public health. It has been closely linked to increased morbidity of bronchial asthma and lung cancer worldwide. Salidroside (Sal), an active component extracted from Rhodiola rosea, has been reported to ameliorate the progression of asthma. However, there are few studies on the protective effect of salidroside on PM2.5-induced bronchial epithelial cell injury, and the related molecular mechanism is not clear. Here, we aimed to explore the protective effect and related mechanism of Sal on PM2.5 bronchial injury. We chose 50 μg/mL PM2.5 for 24 h as a PM2.5-induced cell damage model. After that BEAS-2B cells were pretreated with 40, 80, 160 µM Sal for 24 h and then exposed to 50 μg/mL PM2.5 for 24 h. We found that Sal pretreatment significantly inhibited the decrease of cell viability induced by PM2.5. Sal was effective in preventing PM2.5-induced apoptotic features, including Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt; overload, the cleavages of caspase 3, and the increases in levels of caspase 9 and Bcl-2-associated X protein (Bax), ultimately, Sal significantly inhibited PM2.5-induced apoptosis. Sal improved mitochondrial membrane potential, inhibited the release of cytochrome c from the mitochondria to cytoplasm. Sal alleviated ROS production, decreased the level of MDA, prevented the reduction of CAT, SOD and GSH-Px and increased the expression of NF-E2-related factor 2 (Nrf2), HO-1 and superoxide dismutase 1 (SOD1) in cells exposed to PM2.5. Furthermore, Sal improved the decrease of SIRT1 and PGC-1 α expression levels caused by PM2.5. In addition, inhibition of SIRT1 by EX527 (SIRT1 inhibitor) reversed the protective effects of Sal, including the decrease of ROS level, the increase of membrane potential level and the decrease of apoptosis level. Thus, Sal may be regarded as a potential drug to prevent PM2.5-induced apoptosis of bronchial epithelial cells and other diseases with similar pathological&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PTX3 alleviates hard metal-induced acute lung injury through potentiating efferocytosis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34995911/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34995911/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;WC-Co exposure induces inflammatory response and apoptosis both in vivo and in vitro.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;WC-Co stimulation increases PTX3 expression in vivo and the trend is paralleled with the lung inflammation severity.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Apoptotic cells exhibited higher levels of PTX3 on the surface of the membrane after WC-Co treatment.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PTX3 on the surface of apoptotic cells membrane efficiently facilitates efferocytosis.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prolonged exposure to hard metal dust results in hard metal lung disease (HMLD) characterized by respiratory symptoms. Understanding the pathogenesis and pathological process of HMLD would be helpful for its early diagnosis and treatment. In this study, we established a mouse model of hard metal-induced acute lung injury through one-time intratracheal instillation of WC-Co dust suspension. We found that WC-Co treatment damaged the lungs of mice, leading to increased production of IL-1β, TNF-α, IL-6 and IL-18, inflammatory cells infiltration and apoptosis. In vitro, WC-Co induced cytotoxicity, inflammatory response and apoptosis in macrophages (PMA-treated THP-1) and epithelial cells (A549) in a dose-dependent manner. Moreover, RNA-sequence and validation experiments verified that Pentraxin 3 (PTX3), an important mediator in the regulation of inflammation, was elevated both in vivo and in vitro induced by WC-Co. Functional experiments confirmed the PTX3, which was located on the membrane of apoptotic cells, promoted macrophage efferocytosis efficiently. This progress could help block the lung inflammation and contribute to the rapid recovery of WC-Co-induced acute lung injury. These observations provide a further understanding of the molecular mechanism of WC-Co-induced pulmonary injury and disclose PTX3 as a new potential therapeutic approach to relieve WC-Co-induced acute lung injury via efferocytosis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TNF-α Induces Neutrophil Apoptosis Delay and Promotes Intestinal Ischemia-Reperfusion-Induced Lung Injury through Activating JNK/FoxO3a Pathway</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35003520/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35003520/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Intestinal ischemia is a common clinical critical illness. Intestinal ischemia-reperfusion (IIR) leads to acute lung injury (ALI), but the causative factors of ALI are unknown. The aim of this study was to reveal the causative factors and mechanisms of IIR-induced lung injury.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; A mouse model of IIR was developed using C57BL/6 mice, followed by detection of lung injury status and plasma levels of inflammatory factors in sham-operated mice and model mice. Some model mice were treated with a tumor necrosis factor-α (TNF-α) inhibitor lenalidomide (10 mg/kg), followed by observation of lung injury status through hematoxylin and eosin staining and detection of neutrophil infiltration levels through naphthol esterase and Ly6G immunohistochemical staining. Additionally, peripheral blood polymorphonuclear neutrophils (PMNs) were cultured &lt;em&gt;in vitro&lt;/em&gt; and then stimulated by TNF-α to mimic &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt; inflammatory stimuli; this TNF-α stimulation was also performed on PMNs after knockdown of FoxO3a or treatment with the c-Jun N-terminal kinase (JNK) inhibitor SP600125. PMN apoptosis after stimulation was detected using flow cytometry. Finally, the role of PMN apoptosis in IIR-induced lung injury was evaluated in vivo by detecting the ALI status in the model mice administered with ABT-199, a Bcl-2 inhibitor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; IIR led to pulmonary histopathological injury and increased lung water content, which were accompanied by increased plasma levels of inflammatory factors, with the TNF-α plasma level showing the most pronounced increase. Inhibition of TNF-α led to effective reduction of lung tissue injury, especially that of the damaging infiltration of PMNs in the lung. &lt;em&gt;In vitro&lt;/em&gt; knockdown of FoxO3a or inhibition of JNK activity could inhibit TNF-α-induced PMN apoptosis. Further &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt; experiments revealed that ABT-199 effectively alleviated lung injury and decreased inflammation levels by promoting PMN apoptosis during IIR-induced lung injury.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/em&gt; TNF-α activates the JNK/FoxO3a pathway to induce a delay in PMN apoptosis, which promotes IIR-induced lung injury.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Astragaloside IV pre-treatment attenuates PM2.5-induced lung injury in rats: Impact on autophagy, apoptosis and inflammation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35026504/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35026504/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Autophagy flux inhibition is a critical mechanism of PM2.5-induced lung toxicity in rats.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PM2.5 triggered pulmonary inflammation by tipping the balance between autophagy and apoptosis.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Astragaloside IV increased autophagic flux and inhibited apoptosis and inflammation by activation of the AMPK/mTOR signaling pathway in a PM2.5-induced rat lung toxicity model.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Fine particulate matter (PM2.5) with an aerodynamic diameter of less than 2.5 μm, exerts serious lung toxicity. At present, effective prevention measures and treatment modalities for pulmonary toxicity caused by PM2.5 are lacking. Astragaloside IV (AS-IV) is a natural product that has received increasing attention from researchers for its unique biological functions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Purpose:&lt;/em&gt; To investigate the protective effects of AS-IV on PM2.5-induced pulmonary toxicity and identify its potential mechanisms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; The rat model of PM2.5-induced lung toxicity was created by intratracheal instillation of PM2.5 dust suspension. The investigation was performed with AS-IV or in combination with autophagic flux inhibitor (Chloroquine) or AMP-sensitive protein kinase (AMPK)-specific inhibitor (Compound C). Apoptosis was detected by terminal deoxy-nucleotidyl transferase dUTP nick end labeling (TUNEL) and western blotting. Autophagy was detected by immunofluorescence staining, autophagic flux measurement, western blotting, and transmission electron microscopy. The AMPK/mTOR pathway was analyzed by western blotting. Inflammation was analyzed by western blotting and suspension array.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; AS-IV prevented histopathological injury, inflammation, autophagy dysfunction, apoptosis, and changes in AMPK levels induced by PM2.5. AS-IV increased autophagic flux and inhibited apoptosis and inflammation by activating the AMPK/ mammalian target of rapamycin (mTOR) pathway. However, AS-IV had no protective effect on PM2.5-induced lung injury following treatment with Compound C or Chloroquine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/em&gt; AS-IV prevented PM2.5-induced lung toxicity by restoring the balance among autophagy, apoptosis, and inflammation in rats by activating the AMPK/mTOR signaling pathway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Long non-coding RNA MALAT1 modulates myocardial ischemia-reperfusion injury through the PI3K/Akt/eNOS pathway by sponging miRNA-133a-3p to target IGF1R expression</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34968461/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34968461/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The mechanism of myocardial ischemia-reperfusion injury (MIRI) is a complex pathophysiological process that can lead to poor patient outcomes. Although LncRNA metastasis-associated lung adenocarcinoma transcript 1 (MALAT1) is reported to be highly expressed in myocardial ischemia reperfusion (IR) injury, the specific mechanism remains largely unknown. This study aimed to elucidate the roles and possible mechanism of MALAT1 in myocardial IR injury. IR model was established in rats by ligation of the anterior descending artery in vivo, and H9c2 and HL-1 cells were treated by hypoxia/reoxygenation (HR) to construct the model in vitro. The small interfering RNA (siRNA) for MALAT1 and miR-133a-3p mimics, inhibitor was used to transfect the cells. The expression of MALAT1, miR-133a-3p in MIRI were evaluated using real-time quantitative polymerase chain reaction (qRT-PCR)，immunohistochemistry (IHC) and western blot (WB). Relationships between MALAT1, insulin-like growth factor 1 receptor (IGF1R) with miR-133a-3p were confirmed by luciferase reporter assay. Annexin V-FITC/PI double-labeled flow cytometry, terminal dexynucleotidyl transferase-mediated dUTP nick end labeling (TUNEL), Cell Counting Kit-8 (CCK-8), serum creatine kinase MB (CK-MB), and lactate dehydrogenase (LDH) were evaluated to examine the impact of MALAT1 on MIRI. Our results revealed that MALAT1 was highly expressed, while miR-133a-3p and IGF1R were repressed in IR and HR groups. Knockdown of MALAT1 alleviate the pro-apoptotic effect and myocardial injury in vitro and in vivo. Systematically, MALAT1 may serve as a sponge for miR-133a-3p to suppress IGF1R, which a direct target of miR-133a-3p, then inhibit the PI3K/Akt/eNOS survival pathway. Mechanistically, our study demonstrated that MALAT1 regulates PI3K/Akt/eNOS signaling via miR-133a-3p. In summary, these results suggest that MALAT1 and miR-133a-3p play important roles in MIRI. MALAT1 regulates miR-133a-3p /IGF1R axis. These results show light on the underlying mechanisms of MIRI and provide potential therapeutic targets for MIRI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the molecular mechanisms of the inhibition of acrolein-induced BEAS-2B cytotoxicity by luteolin using network pharmacology and cell biology technology</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34958803/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34958803/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acrolein is a highly reactive unsaturated hazardous air pollutant, which is extremely irritating to the respiratory tract. Luteolin, an active flavonoid compound, possesses multiple biological activities. The purpose of this study was to evaluate the mechanism of the inhibition of acrolein-induced human bronchial epithelial (BEAS-2B) cells cytotoxicity by luteolin using network pharmacology and cell biology technology. Firstly, network pharmacology results indicated that oxidative stress processes might play an important role in luteolin inhibiting lung injury. Next, it was verified at the cellular level. Reactive oxygen species (ROS) generation increased, glutathione (GSH) level decreased after exposure to acrolein. MAPK signaling pathways were activated, which activated downstream IκBα/NF-κB signaling pathways. Meanwhile, acrolein caused oxidative DNA damage and double-strand breaks, induced DNA damage response (DDR) and apoptosis. These adverse effects were significantly reversed by luteolin, which inhibited the activation of MAPK/IκBα/NF-κB and DDR pathways, and reduced the ratio of Bax/Bcl-2. Moreover, luteolin also had a similar effect to antioxidant N-acetyl cysteine (NAC) in the regulation of signaling transduction mechanisms, which indicated that the regulation of oxidative stress played an important role in the process. These results provide an experimental basis for elucidating the molecular mechanisms of the inhibition of acrolein-induced BEAS-2B cytotoxicity with luteolin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From pyroptosis, apoptosis and necroptosis to PANoptosis: A mechanistic compendium of programmed cell death pathways</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/34504660/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/34504660/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pyroptosis, apoptosis and necroptosis are the most genetically well-defined programmed cell death (PCD) pathways, and they are intricately involved in both homeostasis and disease. Although the identification of key initiators, effectors and executioners in each of these three PCD pathways has historically delineated them as distinct, growing evidence has highlighted extensive crosstalk among them. These observations have led to the establishment of the concept of PANoptosis, defined as an inflammatory PCD pathway regulated by the PANoptosome complex with key features of pyroptosis, apoptosis and/or necroptosis that cannot be accounted for by any of these PCD pathways alone. In this review, we provide a brief overview of the research history of pyroptosis, apoptosis and necroptosis. We then examine the intricate crosstalk among these PCD pathways to discuss the current evidence for PANoptosis. We also detail the molecular evidence for the assembly of the PANoptosome complex, a molecular scaffold for contemporaneous engagement of key molecules from pyroptosis, apoptosis, and/or necroptosis. PANoptosis is now known to be critically involved in many diseases, including infection, sterile inflammation and cancer, and future discovery of novel PANoptotic components will continue to broaden our understanding of the fundamental processes of cell death and inform the development of new therapeutics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Artemether confers neuroprotection on cerebral ischemic injury through stimulation of the Erk1/2-P90rsk-CREB signaling pathway</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34303216/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34303216/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Artemether conferred neuroprotection in a middle cerebral artery occlusion (MCAO) animal model.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Artemether conferred neuroprotection on oxygen-glucose deprivation/reperfusion-induced cell injury model.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Artemether promoted the activation of Erk1/2-P90&lt;sup&gt;rsk&lt;/sup&gt;-CREB signaling pathway &lt;em&gt;in vitro&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ischemic stroke is one of the leading causes of death and disability among adults. Despite the economic burden of the disease, available treatment options are still very limited. With the exception of anti-thrombolytics and hypothermia, current therapies fail to reduce neuronal injury, neurological deficits and mortality rates, suggesting that the development of novel and more effective therapies against ischemic stroke is urgent. In the present study, we found that artemether, which has been used in the clinic as an anti-malarial drug, was able to improve the neurological deficits, attenuate the infarction volume and the brain water content in a middle cerebral artery occlusion (MCAO) animal model. Furthermore, artemether treatment significantly suppressed cell apoptosis, stimulated cell proliferation and promoted the phosphorylation of extracellular signal-regulated kinase 1/2 (ERK1/2), P90&lt;sup&gt;rsk&lt;/sup&gt; and cAMP responsive element-binding protein (CREB). Artemether protective effect was attenuated by PD98059, an ERK1/2 inhibitor, administration. Similarly, in oxygen-glucose deprivation/reperfusion (OGD/RP) cell models, artemether pre-treatment induced the suppression of the intracellular ROS, the down-regulation of LDH activity, the reduction of caspase 3 activity and of the apoptosis cell rate and reversed the decrease of mitochondrial membrane potential. As with MCAO animal model, artemether promoted the activation of Erk1/2-P90&lt;sup&gt;rsk&lt;/sup&gt;-CREB signaling pathway. This effect was blocked by the inhibition or knock-down of ERK1/2. The present study provides evidences of the neuroprotective effect of artemether unravelling its potential as a new therapeutic candidate for the prevention and treatment of stroke.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Suppression of mitochondrial ROS by prohibitin drives glioblastoma progression and therapeutic resistance</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34140524/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34140524/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Low levels of reactive oxygen species (ROS) are crucial for maintaining cancer stem cells (CSCs) and their ability to resist therapy, but the ROS regulatory mechanisms in CSCs remains to be explored. Here, we discover that prohibitin (PHB) specifically regulates mitochondrial ROS production in glioma stem-like cells (GSCs) and facilitates GSC radiotherapeutic resistance. We find that PHB is upregulated in GSCs and is associated with malignant gliomas progression and poor prognosis. PHB binds to peroxiredoxin3 (PRDX3), a mitochondrion-specific peroxidase, and stabilizes PRDX3 protein through the ubiquitin-proteasome pathway. Knockout of PHB dramatically elevates ROS levels, thereby inhibiting GSC self-renewal. Importantly, deletion or pharmacological inhibition of PHB potently slows tumor growth and sensitizes tumors to radiotherapy, thus providing significant survival benefits in GSC-derived orthotopic tumors and glioblastoma patient-derived xenografts. These results reveal a selective role of PHB in mitochondrial ROS regulation in GSCs and suggest that targeting PHB improves radiotherapeutic efficacy in glioblastoma.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GPR34-mediated sensing of lysophosphatidylserine released by apoptotic neutrophils activates type 3 innate lymphoid cells to mediate tissue repair</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34107271/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34107271/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Neutrophils migrate rapidly to damaged tissue and play critical roles in host defense and tissue homeostasis. Here we investigated the mechanisms whereby neutrophils participate in tissue repair. In an intestinal epithelia injury model, neutrophil depletion exacerbated colitis and associated with reduced interleukin (IL)-22 and limited activation of type 3 innate lymphoid cells (ILC3s). Co-culture with neutrophils activated ILC3s in a manner dependent on neutrophil apoptosis. Metabolomic analyses revealed that lysophosphatidylserine (LysoPS) from apoptotic neutrophils directly stimulated ILC3 activation. ILC3-specific deletion of Gpr34, encoding the LysoPS receptor GPR34, or inhibition of downstream PI3K-AKT or ERK suppressed IL-22 production in response to apoptotic neutrophils. Gpr34&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt; mice exhibited compromised ILC3 activation and tissue repair during colon injury, and neutrophil depletion abrogated these defects. GPR34 deficiency in ILC3s limited IL-22 production and tissue repair in vivo in settings of colon and skin injury. Thus, GPR34 is an ILC3-expressed damage-sensing receptor that triggers tissue repair upon recognition of dying neutrophils.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Delivering Antisense Oligonucleotides across the Blood-Brain Barrier by Tumor Cell-Derived Small Apoptotic Bodies</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34258157/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34258157/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The blood-brain barrier (BBB) is the most restrictive and complicated barrier that keeps most biomolecules and drugs from the brain. An efficient brain delivery strategy is urgently needed for the treatment of brain diseases. Based on the studies of brain-targeting extracellular vesicles (EVs), the potential of using small apoptotic bodies (sABs) from brain metastatic cancer cells for brain-targeting drug delivery is explored. It is found that anti-TNF-α antisense oligonucleotide (ASO) combined with cationic konjac glucomannan (cKGM) can be successfully loaded into sABs via a transfection/apoptosis induction process and that the sABs generated by B16F10 cells have an extraordinarily high brain delivery efficiency. Further studies suggest that ASO-loaded sABs (sCABs) are transcytosed by b. End3 (brain microvascular endothelial cells, BMECs) to penetrate the BBB, which is mediated by CD44v6, and eventually taken up by microglial cells in the brain. In a Parkinson&amp;rsquo;s disease (PD) mouse model, sCABs dramatically ameliorate PD symptoms via the anti-inflammatory effect of ASO. This study suggests that sABs from brain metastatic cancer cells are excellent carriers for brain-targeted delivery, as they have not only an extraordinary delivery efficiency but also a much higher scale-up production potential than other EVs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Structural insight into the molecular mechanism of p53-mediated mitochondrial apoptosis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33863900/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33863900/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tumor suppressor p53 is mutated in approximately half of all human cancers. p53 can induce apoptosis through mitochondrial membrane permeabilization by interacting with and antagonizing the anti-apoptotic proteins BCL-xL and BCL-2. However, the mechanisms by which p53 induces mitochondrial apoptosis remain elusive. Here, we report a 2.5 Å crystal structure of human p53/BCL-xL complex. In this structure, two p53 molecules interact as a homodimer, and bind one BCL-xL molecule to form a ternary complex with a 2:1 stoichiometry. Mutations at the p53 dimer interface or p53/BCL-xL interface disrupt p53/BCL-xL interaction and p53-mediated apoptosis. Overall, our current findings of the bona fide structure of p53/BCL-xL complex reveal the molecular basis of the interaction between p53 and BCL-xL, and provide insight into p53-mediated mitochondrial apoptosis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Long noncoding RNAs (lncRNAs) in human lymphomas</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/35685474/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/35685474/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lymphomas are a diverse group of haematologic malignancies, which occur in infection-fighting cells of the lymphatic system. Long non-coding RNAs (lncRNAs) are non-coding RNAs, which have recently received significant attention as the main mediators of gene expression. In this review, we summarize the current knowledge on lncRNAs involved in lymphomas, their molecular functions, as well as their potential clinical value. Relevant literature was identified by a PubMed search of English language papers using the following terms: Lymphoma, LncRNA, leukemia, proliferation, apoptosis, and prognosis. LncRNAs are imperative for lymphoma carcinogenesis through affecting apoptosis, cell proliferation, invasion, and response to chemotherapy. The expression level of lncRNAs can affect chemotherapy-induced apoptosis. Taken together, lncRNA dysregulation in lymphoma cells is not only an epiphenomenon but also lncRNA transcription is critically related to the initiation and progression of lymphomas. Aberrant expression of lncRNAs can lead to the transformation of normal lymphocytes into lymphoma cells.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>microRNA-199a-3p inhibits hepatic apoptosis and hepatocarcinogenesis by targeting PDCD4</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33099584/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33099584/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hepatic apoptosis and the initiated liver inflammation play the initial roles in inflammation-induced hepatocarcinogenesis. Molecular mechanisms underlying the regulation of hepatocyte apoptosis and their roles in hepatocarcinogenesis have attracted much attention. A set of microRNAs (miRNAs) have been determined to be dysregulated in hepatocellular carcinoma (HCC) and participated in cancer progression, however, the roles of these dysregulated miRNAs in carcinogenesis are still poorly understood. We previously analyzed the dysregulated miRNAs in HCC using high-throughput sequencing, and found that miR-199a/b-3p was abundantly expressed in human normal liver while markedly decreased in HCC, which promotes HCC progression. Whether miR-199a/b-3p participates in HCC carcinogenesis is still unknown up to now. Hence, we focused on the role and mechanism of miR-199a/b-3p in hepatocarcinogenesis in this study. Hepatic miR-199a/b-3p was determined to be expressed by miR-199a-2 gene in mice, and we constructed miR-199a-2 knockout and hepatocyte-specific miR-199a-2 knockout mice. Diethylnitrosamine (DEN)-induced hepatocarcinogenesis were markedly increased by hepatocyte-specific miR-199a-3p knockout, which is mediated by the enhanced hepatocyte apoptosis and hepatic injury by DEN administration. In acetaminophen (APAP)-induced acute hepatic injury model, hepatocyte-specific miR-199a-3p knockout also aggravated hepatic apoptosis. By proteomic screening and reporter gene validation, we identified and verified that hepatic programed cell death 4 (PDCD4), which promotes apoptosis, was directly targeted by miR-199a-3p. Furthermore, we confirmed that miR-199a-3p-suppressed hepatocyte apoptosis and hepatic injury by targeting and suppressing PDCD4. Thus, hepatic miR-199a-3p inhibits hepatocyte apoptosis and hepatocarcinogenesis, and decreased miR-199a-3p in hepatocytes may aggravate hepatic injury and HCC development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The PANoptosome: A Deadly Protein Complex Driving Pyroptosis, Apoptosis, and Necroptosis (PANoptosis)</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/32582562/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/32582562/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Programmed cell death is regulated by evolutionarily conserved pathways that play critical roles in development and the immune response. A newly recognized pathway for proinflammatory programmed cell death called PANoptosis is controlled by a recently identified cytoplasmic multimeric protein complex named the PANoptosome. The PANoptosome can engage, in parallel, three key modes of programmed cell death-pyroptosis, apoptosis, and necroptosis. The PANoptosome components have been implicated in a wide array of human diseases including autoinflammatory diseases, neurodegenerative diseases, cancer, microbial infections, and metabolic diseases. Here, we review putative components of the PANoptosome and present a phylogenetic analysis of their molecular domains and interaction motifs that support complex assembly. We also discuss genetic data that suggest PANoptosis is coordinated by scaffolding and catalytic functions of the complex components and propose mechanistic models for PANoptosome assembly. Overall, this review presents potential mechanisms governing PANoptosis based on evolutionary analysis of the PANoptosome components.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Identification of the PANoptosome: A Molecular Platform Triggering Pyroptosis, Apoptosis, and Necroptosis (PANoptosis)</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32547960/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32547960/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Programmed cell death plays crucial roles in organismal development and host defense. Recent studies have highlighted mechanistic overlaps and extensive, multifaceted crosstalk between pyroptosis, apoptosis, and necroptosis, three programmed cell death pathways traditionally considered autonomous. The growing body of evidence, in conjunction with the identification of molecules controlling the concomitant activation of all three pathways by pathological triggers, has led to the development of the concept of PANoptosis. During PANoptosis, inflammatory cell death occurs through the collective activation of pyroptosis, apoptosis, and necroptosis, which can circumvent pathogen-mediated inhibition of individual death pathways. Many of the molecular details of this emerging pathway are unclear. Here, we describe the activation of PANoptosis by bacterial and viral triggers and report protein interactions that reveal the formation of a PANoptosome complex. Infection of macrophages with influenza A virus, vesicular stomatitis virus, Listeria monocytogenes, or Salmonella enterica serovar Typhimurium resulted in robust cell death and the hallmarks of PANoptosis activation. Combined deletion of the PANoptotic components caspase-1 (CASP1), CASP11, receptor-interacting serine/threonine-protein kinase 3 (RIPK3), and CASP8 largely protected macrophages from cell death induced by these pathogens, while deletion of individual components provided reduced or no protection. Further, molecules from the pyroptotic, apoptotic, and necroptotic cell death pathways interacted to form a single molecular complex that we have termed the PANoptosome. Overall, our study identifies pathogens capable of activating PANoptosis and the formation of a PANoptosome complex.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Caspase-8 is the molecular switch for apoptosis, necroptosis and pyroptosis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/31748744/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/31748744/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Caspase-8 is the initiator caspase of extrinsic apoptosis and inhibits necroptosis mediated by RIPK3 and MLKL. Accordingly, caspase-8 deficiency in mice causes embryonic lethality, which can be rescued by deletion of either &lt;em&gt;Ripk3&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;Mlkl&lt;/em&gt;. Here we show that the expression of enzymatically inactive CASP8(C362S) causes embryonic lethality in mice by inducing necroptosis and pyroptosis. Similar to &lt;em&gt;Casp8&lt;sup&gt;−/−&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; mice, &lt;em&gt;Casp8&lt;sup&gt;C362S/C362S&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; mouse embryos died after endothelial cell necroptosis leading to cardiovascular defects. MLKL deficiency rescued the cardiovascular phenotype but unexpectedly caused perinatal lethality in &lt;em&gt;Casp8&lt;sup&gt;C362S/C362S&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; mice, indicating that CASP8(C362S) causes necroptosis-independent death at later stages of embryonic development. Specific loss of the catalytic activity of caspase-8 in intestinal epithelial cells induced intestinal inflammation similar to intestinal epithelial cell-specific &lt;em&gt;Casp8&lt;/em&gt; knockout mice. Inhibition of necroptosis by additional deletion of &lt;em&gt;Mlkl&lt;/em&gt; severely aggravated intestinal inflammation and caused premature lethality in &lt;em&gt;Mlkl&lt;/em&gt; knockout mice with specific loss of caspase-8 catalytic activity in intestinal epithelial cells. Expression of CASP8(C362S) triggered the formation of ASC specks, activation of caspase-1 and secretion of IL-1β. Both embryonic lethality and premature death were completely rescued in &lt;em&gt;Casp8&lt;sup&gt;C362S/C362S&lt;/sup&gt;Mlkl&lt;sup&gt;−/−&lt;/sup&gt;Asc&lt;sup&gt;−/−&lt;/sup&gt;sup&amp;gt;&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;Casp8&lt;sup&gt;C362S/C362S&lt;/sup&gt;Mlkl&lt;sup&gt;−/−&lt;/sup&gt;Casp1&lt;sup&gt;−/−&lt;/sup&gt;sup&amp;gt;&lt;/em&gt; mice, indicating that the activation of the inflammasome promotes CASP8(C362S)-mediated tissue pathology when necroptosis is blocked. Therefore, caspase-8 represents the molecular switch that controls apoptosis, necroptosis and pyroptosis, and prevents tissue damage during embryonic development and adulthood.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Coming Decade of Cell Death Research: Five Riddles</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/31100266/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/31100266/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Active cell death, in its many forms, is a fundamental biological process. Studies over the past several decades have explored the functions and consequences of cellular demise and elucidated several of the key cell death pathways. Here, I pose five questions, or riddles, that might provide a guide to the next decade of cell death research. Focusing mainly on four types of active cell death (apoptosis, necroptosis, pyroptosis, and ferroptosis) mainly in mammals, this Perspective explores the possible research directions that might answer these riddles, or at least prompt new ones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
