<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Apoptosis | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/apoptosis/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/apoptosis/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Apoptosis</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Apoptosis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/apoptosis/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mitochondria-localized lncRNA HITT inhibits fusion by attenuating formation of mitofusin-2 homo- or heterotypic complexes</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36567017/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36567017/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Long non-coding RNAs (lncRNAs) are emerging as essential players in multiple biological processes. Mitochondrial dynamics, comprising the continuous cycle of fission and fusion, are required for healthy mitochondria that function properly. Despite long-term recognition of its significance in cell-fate control, the mechanism underlying mitochondrial fusion is not completely understood, particularly regarding the involvement of lncRNAs. Here, we show that the lncRNA HITT (HIF-1α inhibitor at translation level), can specifically localize in mitochondria. Cells expressing higher levels of HITT contain fragmented mitochondria. Conversely, we show that HITT knockdown cells have more tubular mitochondria than is present in control cells. Mechanistically, we demonstrate HITT directly binds mitofusin-2 (MFN2), a core component that mediates mitochondrial outer membrane fusion, by the &lt;em&gt;in vitro&lt;/em&gt; RNA pull-down and UV-cross-linking RNA-IP (CLIP) assays. In doing so, we found HITT disturbs MFN2 homo- or heterotypic complex formation, attenuating mitochondrial fusion. Under stress conditions, such as ultraviolet radiation, we in addition show HITT stability increases as a consequence of MiR-205 downregulation, inhibiting MFN2-mediated fusion and leading to apoptosis. Overall, our data provide significant insights into the roles of organelle (mitochondria)-specific resident lncRNAs in regulating mitochondrial fusion, and also reveal how such a mechanism controls cellular sensitivity to UV radiation-induced apoptosis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PANoptosis-like cell death in ischemia/reperfusion injury of retinal neurons</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35900430/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35900430/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We screened small molecules to identify two compounds, which we named RSL3 and RSL5, that have increased lethality in the presence of oncogenic RAS. Counter screening with biologically active compounds defined aspects of the mechanism of action for RSL3 and RSL5, such as a nonapoptotic, MEK-dependent, and iron-dependent oxidative cell death. Erastin, a previously reported compound with RAS-selective lethality, showed similar properties. RNA interference experiments targeting voltage-dependent anion channel 3 (VDAC3), a target of erastin, demonstrated that RSL5 is a scaffold that acts through VDACs to activate the observed pathway. RSL3 activated a similar death mechanism but in a VDAC-independent manner. We found that cells transformed with oncogenic RAS have increased iron content relative to their normal cell counterparts through upregulation of transferrin receptor 1 and downregulation of ferritin heavy chain 1 and ferritin light chain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SENP1 prevents steatohepatitis by suppressing RIPK1-driven apoptosis and inflammation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36414671/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36414671/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Activation of RIPK1-driven cell death and inflammation play important roles in the progression of nonalcoholic steatohepatitis (NASH). However, the mechanism underlying RIPK1 activation in NASH remains unclear. Here we identified SENP1, a SUMO-specific protease, as a key endogenous inhibitor of RIPK1. SENP1 is progressively reduced in proportion to NASH severity in patients. Hepatocyte-specific SENP1-knockout mice develop spontaneous NASH-related phenotypes in a RIPK1 kinase-dependent manner. We demonstrate that SENP1 deficiency sensitizes cells to RIPK1 kinase-dependent apoptosis by promoting RIPK1 activation following TNFα stimulation. Mechanistically, SENP1 deSUMOylates RIPK1 in TNF-R1 signaling complex (TNF-RSC), keeping RIPK1 in check. Loss of SENP1 leads to SUMOylation of RIPK1, which re-orchestrates TNF-RSC and modulates the ubiquitination patterns and activity of RIPK1. Notably, genetic inhibition of RIPK1 effectively reverses disease progression in hepatocyte-specific SENP1-knockout male mice with high-fat-diet-induced nonalcoholic fatty liver. We propose that deSUMOylation of RIPK1 by SENP1 provides a pathophysiologically relevant cell death-restricting checkpoint that modulates RIPK1 activation in the pathogenesis of nonalcoholic steatohepatitis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exosome modification to better alleviates endoplasmic reticulum stress induced chondrocyte apoptosis and osteoarthritis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36370754/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36370754/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Osteoarthritis (OA) is characterized by cartilage matrix degeneration and chondrocyte apoptosis. Prolonged endoplasmic reticulum (ER) stress participates in chondrocyte apoptosis and cartilage degeneration in OA progression. miR-486-5p could suppress the apoptosis of nucleus pulposus cells and cardiomyocyte, yet whether miR-486-5p modified exosomes could modulate ER stress and apoptosis of chondrocytes remain unknown. We validated the increased inflammation and ER stress in OA synovium and cartilage, and the inhibition of ER stress could attenuate the IL-1β induced chondrocyte apoptosis. Administration of exogenous miR-486-5p could inhibit the ER stress, alleviate chondrocytes apoptosis and promote matrix regeneration. In comparison with direct administration of miR-486-5p and miR-486-5p overexpressing ADSCs, miR-486-5p modified exosomes indicated a better effect in modulating chondrocyte homeostasis. MiR-486-5p containing exosomes could also regulate macrophage polarization. Our IVIS imaging data validated that intraarticular injection of miR-486-5p containing exosomes could sustain for at least 7 days. MiR-486-5p containing exosomes showed a better effect on alleviating rats OA compared with direct administration of miR-486-5p and miR-486-5p overexpressing ADSCs. Our data demonstrated that miR-486-5p modified exosomes have a better effect on alleviating chondrocyte apoptosis and osteoarthritis. This study provides evidence of this efficient strategy of exosomal miRNA delivery and the miRNA-based therapy for OA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bclaf1 regulates c-FLIP expression and protects cells from TNF-induced apoptosis and tissue injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34693625/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34693625/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TNF stimulation generates pro-survival signals through activation of NF-κB that restrict the build-in death signaling triggered by TNF. The competition between TNF-induced survival and death signals ultimately determines the fate of a cell. Here, we report the identification of Bclaf1 as a novel component of the anti-apoptotic program of TNF. Bclaf1 depletion in multiple cells sensitizes cells to TNF-induced apoptosis but not to necroptosis. Bclaf1 exerts its anti-apoptotic function by promoting the transcription of CFLAR, a caspase 8 antagonist, downstream of NF-κB activation. Bclaf1 binds to the p50 subunit of NF-κB, which is required for Bclaf1 to stimulate CFLAR transcription. Finally, in Bclaf1 siRNA administered mice, TNF-induced small intestine injury is much more severe than in control mice with aggravated signs of apoptosis and pyroptosis. These results suggest Bclaf1 is a key regulator in TNF-induced apoptosis, both in vitro and in vivo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UBXD8 mediates mitochondria-associated degradation to restrain apoptosis and mitophagy</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35979733/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35979733/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The hexameric AAA-ATPase valosin-containing protein (VCP) is essential for mitochondrial protein quality control. How VCP is recruited to mammalian mitochondria remains obscure. Here we report that UBXD8, an ER- and lipid droplet-localized VCP adaptor, also localizes to mitochondria and locally recruits VCP. UBXD8 associates with mitochondrial and ER ubiquitin E3 ligases and targets their substrates for degradation. Remarkably, both mitochondria- and ER-localized UBXD8 can degrade mitochondrial and ER substrates in cis and in trans. UBXD8 also associates with the TOM complex but is dispensable for translocation-associated degradation. UBXD8 knockout impairs the degradation of the pro-survival protein Mcl1 but surprisingly sensitizes cells to apoptosis and mitochondrial stresses. UBXD8 knockout also hyperactivates mitophagy. We identify pro-apoptotic BH3-only proteins Noxa, Bik, and Bnip3 as novel UBXD8 substrates and determine that UBXD8 inhibits apoptosis via degrading Noxa and restrains mitophagy via degrading Bnip3. Collectively, our characterizations reveal UBXD8 as the major mitochondrial adaptor of VCP and unveil its role in apoptosis and mitophagy regulation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Filamentous GLS1 promotes ROS-induced apoptosis upon glutamine deprivation via insufficient asparagine synthesis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35381197/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35381197/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GLS1 orchestrates glutaminolysis and promotes cell proliferation when glutamine is abundant by regenerating TCA cycle intermediates and supporting redox homeostasis. CB-839, an inhibitor of GLS1, is currently under clinical investigation for a variety of cancer types. Here, we show that GLS1 facilitates apoptosis when glutamine is deprived. Mechanistically, the absence of exogenous glutamine sufficiently reduces glutamate levels to convert dimeric GLS1 to a self-assembled, extremely low-Km filamentous polymer. GLS1 filaments possess an enhanced catalytic activity, which further depletes intracellular glutamine. Functionally, filamentous GLS1-dependent glutamine scarcity leads to inadequate synthesis of asparagine and mitogenome-encoded proteins, resulting in ROS-induced apoptosis that can be rescued by asparagine supplementation. Physiologically, we observed GLS1 filaments in solid tumors and validated the tumor-suppressive role of constitutively active, filamentous GLS1 mutants K320A and S482C in xenograft models. Our results change our understanding of GLS1 in cancer metabolism and suggest the therapeutic potential of promoting GLS1 filament formation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>m6A mRNA modification maintains colonic epithelial cell homeostasis via NF-κB-mediated antiapoptotic pathway</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35333576/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35333576/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Colonic mucosal barrier dysfunction is one of the major causes of inflammatory bowel disease (IBD). However, the mechanisms underlying mucosal barrier dysfunction are poorly understood. N6-methyladenosine (m6A) mRNA modification is an important modulator of epitranscriptional regulation of gene expression, participating in multiple physiological and pathological processes. However, the function of m6A modification in colonic epithelial cells and stem cells is unknown. Here, we show that m6A modification is essential for maintaining the homeostatic self-renewal in colonic stem cells. Specific deletion of the methyltransferase 14 (Mettl14) gene in mouse colon resulted in colonic stem cell apoptosis, causing mucosal barrier dysfunction and severe colitis. Mechanistically, we revealed that Mettl14 restricted colonic epithelial cell death by regulating the stability of Nfkbia mRNA and modulating the NF-κB pathway. Our results identified a previously unidentified role for m6A modification in colonic epithelial cells and stem cells, suggesting that m6A modification may be a potential therapeutic target for IBD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From pyroptosis, apoptosis and necroptosis to PANoptosis: A mechanistic compendium of programmed cell death pathways</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/34504660/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/34504660/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pyroptosis, apoptosis and necroptosis are the most genetically well-defined programmed cell death (PCD) pathways, and they are intricately involved in both homeostasis and disease. Although the identification of key initiators, effectors and executioners in each of these three PCD pathways has historically delineated them as distinct, growing evidence has highlighted extensive crosstalk among them. These observations have led to the establishment of the concept of PANoptosis, defined as an inflammatory PCD pathway regulated by the PANoptosome complex with key features of pyroptosis, apoptosis and/or necroptosis that cannot be accounted for by any of these PCD pathways alone. In this review, we provide a brief overview of the research history of pyroptosis, apoptosis and necroptosis. We then examine the intricate crosstalk among these PCD pathways to discuss the current evidence for PANoptosis. We also detail the molecular evidence for the assembly of the PANoptosome complex, a molecular scaffold for contemporaneous engagement of key molecules from pyroptosis, apoptosis, and/or necroptosis. PANoptosis is now known to be critically involved in many diseases, including infection, sterile inflammation and cancer, and future discovery of novel PANoptotic components will continue to broaden our understanding of the fundamental processes of cell death and inform the development of new therapeutics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GPR34-mediated sensing of lysophosphatidylserine released by apoptotic neutrophils activates type 3 innate lymphoid cells to mediate tissue repair</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34107271/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34107271/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Neutrophils migrate rapidly to damaged tissue and play critical roles in host defense and tissue homeostasis. Here we investigated the mechanisms whereby neutrophils participate in tissue repair. In an intestinal epithelia injury model, neutrophil depletion exacerbated colitis and associated with reduced interleukin (IL)-22 and limited activation of type 3 innate lymphoid cells (ILC3s). Co-culture with neutrophils activated ILC3s in a manner dependent on neutrophil apoptosis. Metabolomic analyses revealed that lysophosphatidylserine (LysoPS) from apoptotic neutrophils directly stimulated ILC3 activation. ILC3-specific deletion of Gpr34, encoding the LysoPS receptor GPR34, or inhibition of downstream PI3K-AKT or ERK suppressed IL-22 production in response to apoptotic neutrophils. Gpr34&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt; mice exhibited compromised ILC3 activation and tissue repair during colon injury, and neutrophil depletion abrogated these defects. GPR34 deficiency in ILC3s limited IL-22 production and tissue repair in vivo in settings of colon and skin injury. Thus, GPR34 is an ILC3-expressed damage-sensing receptor that triggers tissue repair upon recognition of dying neutrophils.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Structural insight into the molecular mechanism of p53-mediated mitochondrial apoptosis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33863900/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33863900/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tumor suppressor p53 is mutated in approximately half of all human cancers. p53 can induce apoptosis through mitochondrial membrane permeabilization by interacting with and antagonizing the anti-apoptotic proteins BCL-xL and BCL-2. However, the mechanisms by which p53 induces mitochondrial apoptosis remain elusive. Here, we report a 2.5 Å crystal structure of human p53/BCL-xL complex. In this structure, two p53 molecules interact as a homodimer, and bind one BCL-xL molecule to form a ternary complex with a 2:1 stoichiometry. Mutations at the p53 dimer interface or p53/BCL-xL interface disrupt p53/BCL-xL interaction and p53-mediated apoptosis. Overall, our current findings of the bona fide structure of p53/BCL-xL complex reveal the molecular basis of the interaction between p53 and BCL-xL, and provide insight into p53-mediated mitochondrial apoptosis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>microRNA-199a-3p inhibits hepatic apoptosis and hepatocarcinogenesis by targeting PDCD4</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33099584/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33099584/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hepatic apoptosis and the initiated liver inflammation play the initial roles in inflammation-induced hepatocarcinogenesis. Molecular mechanisms underlying the regulation of hepatocyte apoptosis and their roles in hepatocarcinogenesis have attracted much attention. A set of microRNAs (miRNAs) have been determined to be dysregulated in hepatocellular carcinoma (HCC) and participated in cancer progression, however, the roles of these dysregulated miRNAs in carcinogenesis are still poorly understood. We previously analyzed the dysregulated miRNAs in HCC using high-throughput sequencing, and found that miR-199a/b-3p was abundantly expressed in human normal liver while markedly decreased in HCC, which promotes HCC progression. Whether miR-199a/b-3p participates in HCC carcinogenesis is still unknown up to now. Hence, we focused on the role and mechanism of miR-199a/b-3p in hepatocarcinogenesis in this study. Hepatic miR-199a/b-3p was determined to be expressed by miR-199a-2 gene in mice, and we constructed miR-199a-2 knockout and hepatocyte-specific miR-199a-2 knockout mice. Diethylnitrosamine (DEN)-induced hepatocarcinogenesis were markedly increased by hepatocyte-specific miR-199a-3p knockout, which is mediated by the enhanced hepatocyte apoptosis and hepatic injury by DEN administration. In acetaminophen (APAP)-induced acute hepatic injury model, hepatocyte-specific miR-199a-3p knockout also aggravated hepatic apoptosis. By proteomic screening and reporter gene validation, we identified and verified that hepatic programed cell death 4 (PDCD4), which promotes apoptosis, was directly targeted by miR-199a-3p. Furthermore, we confirmed that miR-199a-3p-suppressed hepatocyte apoptosis and hepatic injury by targeting and suppressing PDCD4. Thus, hepatic miR-199a-3p inhibits hepatocyte apoptosis and hepatocarcinogenesis, and decreased miR-199a-3p in hepatocytes may aggravate hepatic injury and HCC development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The PANoptosome: A Deadly Protein Complex Driving Pyroptosis, Apoptosis, and Necroptosis (PANoptosis)</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/32582562/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/32582562/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Programmed cell death is regulated by evolutionarily conserved pathways that play critical roles in development and the immune response. A newly recognized pathway for proinflammatory programmed cell death called PANoptosis is controlled by a recently identified cytoplasmic multimeric protein complex named the PANoptosome. The PANoptosome can engage, in parallel, three key modes of programmed cell death-pyroptosis, apoptosis, and necroptosis. The PANoptosome components have been implicated in a wide array of human diseases including autoinflammatory diseases, neurodegenerative diseases, cancer, microbial infections, and metabolic diseases. Here, we review putative components of the PANoptosome and present a phylogenetic analysis of their molecular domains and interaction motifs that support complex assembly. We also discuss genetic data that suggest PANoptosis is coordinated by scaffolding and catalytic functions of the complex components and propose mechanistic models for PANoptosome assembly. Overall, this review presents potential mechanisms governing PANoptosis based on evolutionary analysis of the PANoptosome components.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Identification of the PANoptosome: A Molecular Platform Triggering Pyroptosis, Apoptosis, and Necroptosis (PANoptosis)</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32547960/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32547960/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Programmed cell death plays crucial roles in organismal development and host defense. Recent studies have highlighted mechanistic overlaps and extensive, multifaceted crosstalk between pyroptosis, apoptosis, and necroptosis, three programmed cell death pathways traditionally considered autonomous. The growing body of evidence, in conjunction with the identification of molecules controlling the concomitant activation of all three pathways by pathological triggers, has led to the development of the concept of PANoptosis. During PANoptosis, inflammatory cell death occurs through the collective activation of pyroptosis, apoptosis, and necroptosis, which can circumvent pathogen-mediated inhibition of individual death pathways. Many of the molecular details of this emerging pathway are unclear. Here, we describe the activation of PANoptosis by bacterial and viral triggers and report protein interactions that reveal the formation of a PANoptosome complex. Infection of macrophages with influenza A virus, vesicular stomatitis virus, Listeria monocytogenes, or Salmonella enterica serovar Typhimurium resulted in robust cell death and the hallmarks of PANoptosis activation. Combined deletion of the PANoptotic components caspase-1 (CASP1), CASP11, receptor-interacting serine/threonine-protein kinase 3 (RIPK3), and CASP8 largely protected macrophages from cell death induced by these pathogens, while deletion of individual components provided reduced or no protection. Further, molecules from the pyroptotic, apoptotic, and necroptotic cell death pathways interacted to form a single molecular complex that we have termed the PANoptosome. Overall, our study identifies pathogens capable of activating PANoptosis and the formation of a PANoptosome complex.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Caspase-8 is the molecular switch for apoptosis, necroptosis and pyroptosis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/31748744/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/31748744/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Caspase-8 is the initiator caspase of extrinsic apoptosis and inhibits necroptosis mediated by RIPK3 and MLKL. Accordingly, caspase-8 deficiency in mice causes embryonic lethality, which can be rescued by deletion of either &lt;em&gt;Ripk3&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;Mlkl&lt;/em&gt;. Here we show that the expression of enzymatically inactive CASP8(C362S) causes embryonic lethality in mice by inducing necroptosis and pyroptosis. Similar to &lt;em&gt;Casp8&lt;sup&gt;−/−&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; mice, &lt;em&gt;Casp8&lt;sup&gt;C362S/C362S&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; mouse embryos died after endothelial cell necroptosis leading to cardiovascular defects. MLKL deficiency rescued the cardiovascular phenotype but unexpectedly caused perinatal lethality in &lt;em&gt;Casp8&lt;sup&gt;C362S/C362S&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; mice, indicating that CASP8(C362S) causes necroptosis-independent death at later stages of embryonic development. Specific loss of the catalytic activity of caspase-8 in intestinal epithelial cells induced intestinal inflammation similar to intestinal epithelial cell-specific &lt;em&gt;Casp8&lt;/em&gt; knockout mice. Inhibition of necroptosis by additional deletion of &lt;em&gt;Mlkl&lt;/em&gt; severely aggravated intestinal inflammation and caused premature lethality in &lt;em&gt;Mlkl&lt;/em&gt; knockout mice with specific loss of caspase-8 catalytic activity in intestinal epithelial cells. Expression of CASP8(C362S) triggered the formation of ASC specks, activation of caspase-1 and secretion of IL-1β. Both embryonic lethality and premature death were completely rescued in &lt;em&gt;Casp8&lt;sup&gt;C362S/C362S&lt;/sup&gt;Mlkl&lt;sup&gt;−/−&lt;/sup&gt;Asc&lt;sup&gt;−/−&lt;/sup&gt;sup&amp;gt;&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;Casp8&lt;sup&gt;C362S/C362S&lt;/sup&gt;Mlkl&lt;sup&gt;−/−&lt;/sup&gt;Casp1&lt;sup&gt;−/−&lt;/sup&gt;sup&amp;gt;&lt;/em&gt; mice, indicating that the activation of the inflammasome promotes CASP8(C362S)-mediated tissue pathology when necroptosis is blocked. Therefore, caspase-8 represents the molecular switch that controls apoptosis, necroptosis and pyroptosis, and prevents tissue damage during embryonic development and adulthood.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Coming Decade of Cell Death Research: Five Riddles</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/31100266/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/31100266/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Active cell death, in its many forms, is a fundamental biological process. Studies over the past several decades have explored the functions and consequences of cellular demise and elucidated several of the key cell death pathways. Here, I pose five questions, or riddles, that might provide a guide to the next decade of cell death research. Focusing mainly on four types of active cell death (apoptosis, necroptosis, pyroptosis, and ferroptosis) mainly in mammals, this Perspective explores the possible research directions that might answer these riddles, or at least prompt new ones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
