<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Glutathionylation | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/glutathionylation/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/glutathionylation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Glutathionylation</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Glutathionylation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/glutathionylation/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>LanCLs add glutathione to dehydroamino acids generated at phosphorylated sites in the proteome</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33932340/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33932340/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enzyme-mediated damage repair or mitigation, while common for nucleic acids, is rare for proteins. Examples of protein damage are elimination of phosphorylated Ser/Thr to dehydroalanine/dehydrobutyrine (Dha/Dhb) in pathogenesis and aging. Bacterial LanC enzymes use Dha/Dhb to form carbon-sulfur linkages in antimicrobial peptides, but the functions of eukaryotic LanC-like (LanCL) counterparts are unknown. We show that LanCLs catalyze the addition of glutathione to Dha/Dhb in proteins, driving irreversible C-glutathionylation. Chemo-enzymatic methods were developed to site-selectively incorporate Dha/Dhb at phospho-regulated sites in kinases. In human MAPK-MEK1, such &amp;ldquo;elimination damage&amp;rdquo; generated aberrantly activated kinases, which were deactivated by LanCL-mediated C-glutathionylation. Surveys of endogenous proteins bearing damage from elimination (the eliminylome) also suggest it is a source of electrophilic reactivity. LanCLs thus remove these reactive electrophiles and their potentially dysregulatory effects from the proteome. As knockout of LanCL in mice can result in premature death, repair of this kind of protein damage appears important physiologically.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Decreased Expression of the Host Long-Noncoding RNA-GM Facilitates Viral Escape by Inhibiting the Kinase activity TBK1 via S-glutathionylation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33326766/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33326766/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Viruses have evolved multiple strategies to evade elimination by the immune system. Here we examined the contribution of host long noncoding RNAs (lncRNAs) in viral immune evasion. By functional screening of lncRNAs whose expression decreased upon viral infection of macrophages, we identified a lncRNA (lncRNA-GM, Gene Symbol: AK189470.1) that promoted type I interferon (IFN-I) production and inhibited viral replication. Deficiency of lncRNA-GM in mice increased susceptibility to viral infection and impaired IFN-I production. Mechanistically, lncRNA-GM bound to glutathione S-transferase M1 (GSTM1) and blocked GSTM1 interaction with the kinase TBK1, reducing GSTM1-mediated S-glutathionylation of TBK1. Decreased S-glutathionylation enhanced TBK1 activity and downstream production of antiviral mediators. Viral infection reprogrammed intracellular glutathione metabolism and furthermore, an oxidized glutathione mimetic could inhibit TBK1 activity and promote viral replication. Our findings reveal regulation of TBK1 by S-glutathionylation and provide insight into the viral mediated metabolic changes that impact innate immunity and viral evasion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
