<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Vesicular Stomatitis Virus | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/vesicular-stomatitis-virus/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/vesicular-stomatitis-virus/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Vesicular Stomatitis Virus</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Vesicular Stomatitis Virus</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/vesicular-stomatitis-virus/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Engineered MARCH8-Resistant Vesicular Stomatitis Virus Glycoprotein Enhances Lentiviral Vector Transduction</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33678011/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33678011/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lentiviral vectors are one of the most commonly used viral delivery systems for gene therapy. Vesicular stomatitis virus-G envelope glycoprotein (VSV G)-pseudotyped lentiviral vectors have been widely used in clinical studies for treatment of virus infections and genetic deficient diseases. However, the efficiency of lentiviral vector transduction has been long recognized as a limiting factor in clinical gene therapy application, especially in transducing hematopoietic stem cells. MARCH8 (membrane-associated RING-CH 8), an E3 ubiquitin ligase, has been reported to target and downregulate VSV G. Results in this study show that MARCH8 induces ubiquitination and lysosome degradation of VSV G, and knockout of MARCH8 in virus-producing cells increases lentiviral vector transduction by elevating the level of VSV G protein. We then engineered VSV G mutant that has the lysine residues in the cytoplasmic domain substituted for arginine, and showed that this G mutant resists degradation by MARCH8, and allows the enhancement of transduction efficiency of lentiviral vector particles than the parental VSV G protein. This engineered VSV G mutant thus further advances the lentiviral vector system as a powerful tool in gene therapy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TRIM24 facilitates antiviral immunity through mediating K63-linked TRAF3 ubiquitination</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32324863/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32324863/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ubiquitination is an essential mechanism in the control of antiviral immunity upon virus infection. Here, we identify a series of ubiquitination-modulating enzymes that are modulated by vesicular stomatitis virus (VSV). Notably, TRIM24 is down-regulated through direct transcriptional suppression induced by VSV-activated IRF3. Reducing or ablating TRIM24 compromises type I IFN (IFN-I) induction upon RNA virus infection and thus renders mice more sensitive to VSV infection. Mechanistically, VSV infection induces abundant TRIM24 translocation to mitochondria, where TRIM24 binds with TRAF3 and directly mediates K63-linked TRAF3 ubiquitination at K429/K436. This modification of TRAF3 enables its association with MAVS and TBK1, which consequently activates downstream antiviral signaling. Together, these findings establish TRIM24 as a critical positive regulator in controlling the activation of antiviral signaling and describe a previously unknown mechanism of TRIM24 function.The predicted 80 open reading frames (ORFs) of herpes simplex virus 1 (HSV-1) have been intensively studied for decades. Here, we unravel the complete viral transcriptome and translatome during lytic infection with base-pair resolution by computational integration of multi-omics data. We identify a total of 201 transcripts and 284 ORFs including all known and 46 novel large ORFs. This includes a so far unknown ORF in the locus deleted in the FDA-approved oncolytic virus Imlygic. Multiple transcript isoforms expressed from individual gene loci explain translation of the vast majority of ORFs as well as N-terminal extensions (NTEs) and truncations. We show that NTEs with non-canonical start codons govern the subcellular protein localization and packaging of key viral regulators and structural proteins. We extend the current nomenclature to include all viral gene products and provide a genome browser that visualizes all the obtained data from whole genome to single-nucleotide resolution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ZFYVE1 negatively regulates MDA5- but not RIG-I-mediated innate antiviral response</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32251420/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32251420/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The retinoic acid-inducible gene-I (RIG-I)-like receptors (RLRs), including RIG-I and melanoma differentiation-associated gene 5 (MDA5), sense cytoplasmic viral RNA and initiate innate antiviral responses. How RIG-I and MDA5 are differentially regulated remains enigmatic. In this study, we identified the guanylate-binding protein (GBP) and zinc-finger FYVE domain-containing protein ZFYVE1 as a negative regulator of MDA5- but not RIG-I-mediated innate antiviral responses. ZFYVE1-deficiency promoted MDA5- but not RIG-I-mediated transcription of downstream antiviral genes. Comparing to wild-type mice, &lt;em&gt;Zfyve1&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; mice were significantly protected from lethality induced by encephalomyocarditis virus (EMCV) that is sensed by MDA5, whereas &lt;em&gt;Zfyve1&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Zfyve1&lt;sup&gt;+/+&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; mice were comparable to death induced by vesicular stomatitis virus (VSV) that is sensed by RIG-I. Mechanistically, ZFYVE1 interacted with MDA5 but not RIG-I. ZFYVE1 bound to viral RNA and decreased the ligand binding and oligomerization of MDA5. These findings suggest that ZFYVE1 acts as a specific negative regulator of MDA5-mediated innate immune responses by inhibiting its ligand binding and oligomerization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Recognition of an Inducible Host lncRNA by RIG-I Feedback Restricts Innate Immune Response</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/29706547/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/29706547/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The innate RNA sensor RIG-I is critical in the initiation of antiviral type I interferons (IFNs) production upon recognition of &amp;ldquo;non-self&amp;rdquo; viral RNAs. Here, we identify a host-derived, IFN-inducible long noncoding RNA, lnc-Lsm3b, that can compete with viral RNAs in the binding of RIG-I monomers and feedback inactivate the RIG-I innate function at late stage of innate response. Mechanistically, binding of lnc-Lsm3b restricts RIG-I protein&amp;rsquo;s conformational shift and prevents downstream signaling, thereby terminating type I IFNs production. Multivalent structural motifs and long-stem structure are critical features of lnc-Lsm3b for RIG-I binding and inhibition. These data reveal a non-canonical self-recognition mode in the regulation of immune response and demonstrate an important role of an inducible &amp;ldquo;self&amp;rdquo; lncRNA acting as a potent molecular decoy actively saturating RIG-I binding sites to restrict the duration of &amp;ldquo;non-self&amp;rdquo; RNA-induced innate immune response and maintaining immune homeostasis, with potential utility in inflammatory disease management.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
