<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Microbiology | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/microbiology/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/microbiology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Microbiology</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Microbiology</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/microbiology/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Summary of microbiome databases</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tool/2022-07-10-db-microbiome/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/tool/2022-07-10-db-microbiome/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.dsmz.de/collection/catalogue/microorganisms/special-groups-of-organisms/dzif-sammlung/maus-mikrobiomliste&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;mouse intestinal Bacterial Collection (miBC)&lt;/a&gt;  is an initiative from the RTWH Aachen (Prof. Thomas Clavel) and the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.dsmz.de/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Leibniz-Institute DSMZ-German Collection of Microorganisms and Cell Cultures&lt;/a&gt;. It is supported by Collaborative Research Centre (CRC) 1371 and CRC1382 and by the German Federal Ministry of Science and Education through the German Center of Infection Research (DZIF). This collection includes bacterial strains isolated from the intestine of mice. They have been taxonomically described and are all publicly available. This well-curated resource was built to increase our knowledge of cultured diversity within the mouse gut microbiota and to support scientists with their own research by providing multiple strains representing a broad phylogenetic diversity to be used for functional experiments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://bio-annotation.cn/gutMDisorder/home.dhtml&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;gutMDisorder&lt;/a&gt; is a comprehensive resource for associations between gut microbes and phenotypes or interventions in Human and Mouse, derived from manual literature extraction and raw data reprocessing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Microbiome and its metabolites are closely associated with human health and diseases. However, it is challenging to understand the complex interplay between microbiome and metabolites. &lt;a href=&#34;http://metorigin.met-bioinformatics.cn/home/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;MetOrigin&lt;/a&gt; is a bioinformatics tool, aiming to identify which bacteria and how they participate in certain metabolic reactions, helping us to understand where metabolites come from: host, bacteria, or both?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://gmrepo.humangut.info/home&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;GMrepo&lt;/a&gt; is a curated database of consistently annotated human gut metagenomes. So far &lt;a href=&#34;https://gmrepo.humangut.info/home&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;GMrepo&lt;/a&gt; contains 71,642 human gut runs/samples from 353 projects; they are associated with 132 human phenotypes. Its main features include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;extensive manual curation of meta-data of gut samples/runs,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;grouping samples/runs according to their associated human phenotypes (i.e. health and diseases),&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;graphical selectors enabling easy and efficient access to all our collected data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently numerous studies have identified that the perturbations in the gut microbiome were associated with human health, including diseases and cancers, even mental health. The recent development of high-throughput sequencing based metagenomics technologies such as 16S ribosomal RNA gene amplicon-based and genome-centric approaches have burst the profiling of the landscape for gut microbiome and the identification of human health related microbes. Here, we presented the &lt;a href=&#34;http://gutmega.omicsbio.info/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;gutMEGA&lt;/a&gt; database, which hosted the results of metagenomics studies. In total, 59,132 quantification events for 6,457 taxa at 7 different levels (kingdom, phylum, class, order, family, genus and species) under 776 conditions were collected and integrated in the database, and the details about the samples and experiments were also curated. Various browse and search options were provided in the database, and the detailed information was organized and visualized for queries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://bio-annotation.cn/gutmgene/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;gutMGene&lt;/a&gt; is a comprehensive database for target genes of gut microbes and microbial metabolites. Metagenomic sequencing of fecal samples has identified 3.3×10&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt; non-redundant microbial genes from up to 1,500 different species. One of the contributions of gut microbiota to host biology is the circulating pool of bacterially derived small-molecule metabolites. It has been estimated that 10% of metabolites found in mammalian blood are derived from the gut microbiota, where they can produce systemic effects on the host through activating or inhibiting gene expression. Currently, detailed information on target genes of gut microbes and microbial metabolites is scattered in literatures and no online repository is available for collecting these data. Here, we manually extracted microbe-metabolite, microbe-target, and metabolite-target relationships in Human and Mouse from almost 400 publications. All of these relationships were experimentally validated in vivo or in vitro and measured by RT-qPCR, high performance liquid chromatography, 16S rRNA sequence, and so on. Currently, users can:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://bio-annotation.cn/gutmgene/resource.dhtml&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Download&lt;/a&gt; all manually curated relationships.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Achieve relationships by &lt;em&gt;browsing&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;searching&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Submit&lt;/em&gt; novel relationships to the &lt;a href=&#34;http://bio-annotation.cn/gutmgene/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;gutMGene&lt;/a&gt; database.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Taxonomic and functional research of microorganisms has increasingly relied upon genome-based data and methods. As the depository of the Global Catalogue of Microorganisms (GCM) 10K prokaryotic type strain sequencing project, &lt;a href=&#34;http://gctype.wdcm.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Global Catalogue of Type Strain (gcType)&lt;/a&gt; has published 1049 type strain genomes sequenced by the GCM 10K project which are preserved in global culture collections with a valid published status. Additionally, the information provided through &lt;a href=&#34;http://gctype.wdcm.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;gcType&lt;/a&gt; includes &amp;gt;12 000 publicly available type strain genome sequences from GenBank incorporated using quality control criteria and standard data annotation pipelines to form a high-quality reference database. This database integrates type strain sequences with their phenotypic information to facilitate phenotypic and genotypic analyses. Multiple formats of cross-genome searches and interactive interfaces have allowed extensive exploration of the database&amp;rsquo;s resources. In this study, we describe web-based data analysis pipelines for genomic analyses and genome-based taxonomy, which could serve as a one-stop platform for the identification of prokaryotic species. The number of type strain genomes that are published will continue to increase as the GCM 10K project increases its collaboration with culture collections worldwide. Data of this project is shared with the International Nucleotide Sequence Database Collaboration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://disbiome.ugent.be/home&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Disbiome&lt;/a&gt; is a database covering microbial composition changes in different kinds of diseases, managed by Ghent University. Disease names, detection methods or organism names can be used as search queries giving you all information related to the experiment (related disease/bacteria, abundancy subject/control, control type, detection method and related literature).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.vmh.life/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Virtual Metabolic Human (VMH)&lt;/a&gt; database captures information on human and gut microbial metabolism and links this information to hundreds of diseases and nutritional data. At its core, there are hundreds of manually curated genome-scale metabolic reconstructions, which have been assembled based on genomic, biochemical, and physiological data. The &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.vmh.life/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;VMH&lt;/a&gt; facilitates rapid analyses and interpretations of complex data arising from large-scale biomedical studies by enabling complex queries of its content, by providing a detailed graphical representation of human metabolism, and by distributing computational models for simulating human and microbial metabolism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dianalab.e-ce.uth.gr/peryton/#/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Peryton&lt;/a&gt; constitutes a novel resource of experimentally supported microbe-disease associations, currently hosting more than 7,900 entries linking 43 diseases and 1,396 microorganisms. &lt;a href=&#34;https://dianalab.e-ce.uth.gr/peryton/#/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Peryton&lt;/a&gt;’s content is exclusively sustained by manual curation of biomedical articles. Importantly, diseases and microorganisms are provided in a systematic, standardized manner using reference resources to create database dictionaries. Information about the experimental design, study cohorts and the applied high- or low-throughput techniques are meticulously annotated and catered to users. Extensive details regarding bacterial abundance, the groups under study (including their sex ratio and their size) and article metadata are available for each entry. A number of functionalities are provided to enhance user experience and enable ingenious use of &lt;a href=&#34;https://dianalab.e-ce.uth.gr/peryton/#/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Peryton&lt;/a&gt;. One or more microorganisms and/or diseases can be queried at the same time. Advanced filtering options and direct text-based filtering of results enable refinement of returned information and the conducting of tailored queries suitable to different research questions. Results can be directly downloaded as tab-separated files for local storage and downstream analyses. &lt;a href=&#34;https://dianalab.e-ce.uth.gr/peryton/#/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Peryton&lt;/a&gt; also provides to users’ interactive visualizations to effectively capture different aspects of its content. Via Network graphs, Chord diagrams and Hierarchy Diagrams users can browse into the available content and perform observations about microbe-disease relationships using information from the latest relevant literature. &lt;a href=&#34;https://dianalab.e-ce.uth.gr/peryton/#/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Peryton&lt;/a&gt;’s content in numbers:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2,918 gastrointestinal disease associations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4,065 cancer-related associations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;869 neurodegenerative disorder associations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;125 cardiovascular disease associations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1,718 entries providing information at species level or below&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3,777 entries comparing a disease group against healthy individuals and 4,200 comparing disease states&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Accumulating evidence about the interaction between human microbiota and therapeutic-related substances, especially for clinical used drugs, deepens and broadens our understanding in the role of &amp;ldquo;our second genome&amp;rdquo; in human health and diseases, and opens a new window for managing/treating human healthy problems/diseases by manipulating microbiota-human interactions. A centralized and standardized database to catalog Microbiota-Active Substances Interactions (MASIs) will be very useful for related research fields, including microbiota-related pharmaceutical research, food and nutrition research, clinical pharmacy, health management studies. Here, the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.aiddlab.com/MASI/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;MASI&lt;/a&gt; database is developed to cater this urgent need by providing manually curated MASIs data from scientific literature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://leb.snu.ac.kr/amdb&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Animal Microbiome Database (AMDB)&lt;/a&gt; is a database covering bacterial 16S rRNA gene profiles from various animal species to assess the relationship between the gut microbiota and animal hosts. We collected 2,530 samples from 34 public projects with manually curated metadata. Currently, &lt;a href=&#34;http://leb.snu.ac.kr/amdb&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;AMDB&lt;/a&gt; contains 10,478 bacterial taxa from 467 animal species. Please refer to our paper for detailed analysis methods. &lt;a href=&#34;http://leb.snu.ac.kr/amdb&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;AMDB&lt;/a&gt; provides four main functions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Taxa: It shows samples enriched with the bacterial taxon of interest.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Samples: It provides the gut microbiota composition of the sample of interest.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Projects/Hosts: It gives you summary information for the project or the host.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Visualization: It visually presents valuable information about the relationships between the samples and the gut microbiota.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/tag/databases/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Databases&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/tool/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Tools &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apoptotic Caspases Suppress Type I Interferon Production via the Cleavage of cGAS, MAVS, and IRF3</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/30878284/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/30878284/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Viral infection triggers host defenses through pattern-recognition receptor-mediated cytokine production, inflammasome activation, and apoptosis of the infected cells. Inflammasome-activated caspases are known to cleave cyclic GMP-AMP synthase (cGAS). Here, we found that apoptotic caspases are critically involved in regulating both DNA and RNA virus-triggered host defenses, in which activated caspase-3 cleaved cGAS, MAVS, and IRF3 to prevent cytokine overproduction. Caspase-3 was exclusively required in human cells, whereas caspase-7 was involved only in murine cells to inactivate cGAS, reflecting distinct regulatory mechanisms in different species. Caspase-mediated cGAS cleavage was enhanced in the presence of dsDNA. Alternative MAVS cleavage sites were used to ensure the inactivation of this critical protein. Elevated type I IFNs were detected in caspase-3-deficient cells without any infection. Casp3-/- mice consistently showed increased resistance to viral infection and experimental autoimmune encephalomyelitis. Our results demonstrate that apoptotic caspases control innate immunity and maintain immune homeostasis against viral infection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploration of extracellular vesicles from Ascaris suum provides evidence of parasite-host cross talk</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/30815237/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/30815237/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The prevalent porcine helminth, &lt;em&gt;Ascaris suum&lt;/em&gt;, compromises pig health and reduces farm productivity worldwide. The closely related human parasite, &lt;em&gt;A. lumbricoides&lt;/em&gt;, infects more than 800 million people representing a disease burden of 1.31 million disability-adjusted life years. The infections are often chronic in nature, and the parasites have a profound ability to modulate their hosts&amp;rsquo; immune responses. This study provides the first in-depth characterisation of extracellular vesicles (EVs) from different developmental stages and body parts of &lt;em&gt;A. suum&lt;/em&gt; and proposes the role of these vesicles in the host-parasite interplay. The release of EVs from the third- (L3) and fourth-stage (L4) larvae and adults was demonstrated by transmission electron microscopy (TEM), and sequencing of EV-derived RNA identified a number of microRNAs (miRNAs) and transcripts of potential host immune targets, such as IL-13, IL-25 and IL-33, were identified. Furthermore, proteomics of EVs identified several proteins with immunomodulatory properties and other proteins previously shown to be associated with parasite EVs. Taken together, these results suggest that A. suum EVs and their cargo may play a role in host-parasite interactions. This knowledge may pave the way to novel strategies for helminth infection control and knowledge of their immune modulatory potential.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Statistical Analysis of Microbiome Data with R</title>
      <link>https://example.com/books/2019-02-02-stat-analy-microbiome-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/books/2019-02-02-stat-analy-microbiome-r/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This unique book addresses the statistical modelling and analysis of microbiome data using cutting-edge R software. It includes real-world data from the authors’ research and from the public domain, and discusses the implementation of R for data analysis step by step. The data and R computer programs are publicly available, allowing readers to replicate the model development and data analysis presented in each chapter, so that these new methods can be readily applied in their own research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The book also discusses recent developments in statistical modelling and data analysis in microbiome research, as well as the latest advances in next-generation sequencing and big data in methodological development and applications. This timely book will greatly benefit all readers involved in microbiome, ecology and microarray data analyses, as well as other fields of research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/books/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Books &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Virtual Metabolic Human database: integrating human and gut microbiome metabolism with nutrition and disease</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/30371894/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/30371894/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A multitude of factors contribute to complex diseases and can be measured with &amp;lsquo;omics&amp;rsquo; methods. Databases facilitate data interpretation for underlying mechanisms. Here, we describe the &lt;a href=&#34;www.vmh.life&#34;&gt;Virtual Metabolic Human (VMH)&lt;/a&gt; database encapsulating current knowledge of human metabolism within five interlinked resources &amp;lsquo;Human metabolism&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;Gut microbiome&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;Disease&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;Nutrition&amp;rsquo;, and &amp;lsquo;ReconMaps&amp;rsquo;. The &lt;a href=&#34;www.vmh.life&#34;&gt;VMH&lt;/a&gt; captures 5180 unique metabolites, 17 730 unique reactions, 3695 human genes, 255 Mendelian diseases, 818 microbes, 632 685 microbial genes and 8790 food items. The &lt;a href=&#34;www.vmh.life&#34;&gt;VMH&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s unique features are (i) the hosting of the metabolic reconstructions of human and gut microbes amenable for metabolic modeling; (ii) seven human metabolic maps for data visualization; (iii) a nutrition designer; (iv) a user-friendly webpage and application-programming interface to access its content; (v) user feedback option for community engagement and (vi) the connection of its entities to 57 other web resources. The &lt;a href=&#34;www.vmh.life&#34;&gt;VMH&lt;/a&gt; represents a novel, interdisciplinary database for data interpretation and hypothesis generation to the biomedical community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comparative Flavivirus-Host Protein Interaction Mapping Reveals Mechanisms of Dengue and Zika Virus Pathogenesis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/30550790/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/30550790/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mosquito-borne flaviviruses, including dengue virus (DENV) and Zika virus (ZIKV), are a growing public health concern. Systems-level analysis of how flaviviruses hijack cellular processes through virus-host protein-protein interactions (PPIs) provides information about their replication and pathogenic mechanisms. We used affinity purification-mass spectrometry (AP-MS) to compare flavivirus-host interactions for two viruses (DENV and ZIKV) in two hosts (human and mosquito). Conserved virus-host PPIs revealed that the flavivirus NS5 protein suppresses interferon stimulated genes by inhibiting recruitment of the transcription complex PAF1C and that chemical modulation of SEC61 inhibits DENV and ZIKV replication in human and mosquito cells. Finally, we identified a ZIKV-specific interaction between NS4A and ANKLE2, a gene linked to hereditary microcephaly, and showed that ZIKV NS4A causes microcephaly in Drosophila in an ANKLE2-dependent manner. Thus, comparative flavivirus-host PPI mapping provides biological insights and, when coupled with in vivo models, can be used to unravel pathogenic mechanisms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An oncolytic herpesvirus expressing E-cadherin improves survival in mouse models of glioblastoma</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/30475349/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/30475349/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The efficacy of oncolytic herpes simplex virus (oHSV) is limited by rapid viral clearance by innate immune effector cells and poor intratumoral viral spread. We combine two approaches to overcome these barriers: inhibition of natural killer (NK) cells and enhancement of intratumoral viral spread. We engineered an oHSV to express CDH1, encoding E-cadherin, an adherent molecule and a ligand for KLRG1, an inhibitory receptor expressed on NK cells. In vitro, infection with this engineered virus, named OV-CDH1, induced high surface E-cadherin expression on infected glioblastoma (GBM) cells, which typically lack endogenous E-cadherin. Ectopically expressed E-cadherin enhanced the spread of OV-CDH1 by facilitating cell-to-cell infection and viral entry and reduced viral clearance by selectively protecting OV-CDH1-infected cells from KLRG1+ NK cell killing. In vivo, OV-CDH1 treatment substantially prolonged the survival in GBM-bearing mouse models, primarily because of improved viral spread rather than inhibition of NK cell activity. Thus, virus-induced overexpression of E-cadherin may be a generalizable strategy for improving cancer virotherapy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Low-Fidelity Assembly of Influenza A Virus Promotes Escape from Host Cells</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/30503209/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/30503209/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Erratum in:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Correction 1: Low-Fidelity Assembly of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674%2819%2930042-X&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Influenza A Virus Promotes Escape from Host Cells&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Correction 2: Low-Fidelity Assembly of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674%2819%2931390-X&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Influenza A Virus Promotes Escape from Host Cells&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Influenza viruses inhabit a wide range of host environments using a limited repertoire of protein components. Unlike viruses with stereotyped shapes, influenza produces virions with significant morphological variability even within clonal populations. Whether this tendency to form pleiomorphic virions is coupled to compositional heterogeneity and whether it affects replicative fitness remains unclear. Here, we address these questions by developing a strain of influenza A virus amenable to rapid compositional characterization through quantitative, site-specific labeling of viral proteins. Using this strain, we find that influenza A produces virions with broad variations in size and composition from even single infected cells. This phenotypic variability contributes to virus survival during environmental challenges, including exposure to antivirals. Complementing genetic adaptations that act over larger populations and longer times, this “low-fidelity” assembly of influenza A virus allows small populations to survive environments that fluctuate over individual replication cycles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Universal protection against influenza infection by a multidomain antibody to influenza hemagglutinin</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/30385580/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/30385580/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Broadly neutralizing antibodies against highly variable pathogens have stimulated the design of vaccines and therapeutics. We report the use of diverse camelid single-domain antibodies to influenza virus hemagglutinin to generate multidomain antibodies with impressive breadth and potency. Multidomain antibody MD3606 protects mice against influenza A and B infection when administered intravenously or expressed locally from a recombinant adeno-associated virus vector. Crystal and single-particle electron microscopy structures of these antibodies with hemagglutinins from influenza A and B viruses reveal binding to highly conserved epitopes. Collectively, our findings demonstrate that multidomain antibodies targeting multiple epitopes exhibit enhanced virus cross-reactivity and potency. In combination with adeno-associated virus-mediated gene delivery, they may provide an effective strategy to prevent infection with influenza virus and other highly variable pathogens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Endotoxin Delivery Protein HMGB1 Mediates Caspase-11-Dependent Lethality in Sepsis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/30314759/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/30314759/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hepatocyte-released HMGB1 mediates caspase-11-dependent lethality in sepsis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;HMGB1-LPS complexes are taken up by macrophages and endothelial cells via RAGE&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;HMGB1 destabilizes phagolysosomes for the transfer of LPS to cytosolic caspase-11&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Neutralizing extracellular HMGB1 inhibits caspase-11 activation in sepsis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Summary&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Caspase-11, a cytosolic endotoxin (lipopolysaccharide: LPS) receptor, mediates pyroptosis, a lytic form of cell death. Caspase-11-dependent pyroptosis mediates lethality in endotoxemia, but it is unclear how LPS is delivered into the cytosol for the activation of caspase-11. Here we discovered that hepatocyte-released high mobility group box 1 (HMGB1) was required for caspase-11-dependent pyroptosis and lethality in endotoxemia and bacterial sepsis. Mechanistically, hepatocyte-released HMGB1 bound LPS and targeted its internalization into the lysosomes of macrophages and endothelial cells via the receptor for advanced glycation end-products (RAGE). Subsequently, HMGB1 permeabilized the phospholipid bilayer in the acidic environment of lysosomes. This resulted in LPS leakage into the cytosol and caspase-11 activation. Depletion of hepatocyte HMGB1, inhibition of hepatocyte HMGB1 release, neutralizing extracellular HMGB1, or RAGE deficiency prevented caspase-11-dependent pyroptosis and death in endotoxemia and bacterial sepsis. These findings indicate that HMGB1 interacts with LPS to mediate caspase-11-dependent pyroptosis in lethal sepsis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Infection-Induced Peroxisome Biogenesis Is a Metabolic Strategy for Herpesvirus Replication</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/30269970/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/30269970/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Viral proteins have evolved to target cellular organelles and usurp their functions for virus replication. Despite the knowledge of these critical functions for several organelles, little is known about peroxisomes during infection. Peroxisomes are primarily metabolic organelles with important functions in lipid metabolism. Here, we discovered that the enveloped viruses human cytomegalovirus (HCMV) and herpes simplex virus type 1 (HSV-1) induce the biogenesis of and unique morphological changes to peroxisomes to support their replication. Targeted proteomic quantification revealed a global virus-induced upregulation of peroxisomal proteins. Mathematical modeling and microscopy structural analysis show that infection triggers peroxisome growth and fission, leading to increased peroxisome numbers and irregular disc-like structures. HCMV-induced peroxisome biogenesis increased the phospholipid plasmalogen, thereby enhancing virus production. Peroxisome regulation and dependence were not observed for the non-enveloped adenovirus. Our findings uncover a role of peroxisomes in viral pathogenesis, with likely implications for multiple enveloped viruses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An orthogonal proteomic survey uncovers novel Zika virus host factors</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/30177828/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/30177828/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zika virus (ZIKV) has recently emerged as a global health concern owing to its widespread diffusion and its association with severe neurological symptoms and microcephaly in newborns. However, the molecular mechanisms that are responsible for the pathogenicity of ZIKV remain largely unknown. Here we use human neural progenitor cells and the neuronal cell line SK-N-BE2 in an integrated proteomics approach to characterize the cellular responses to viral infection at the proteome and phosphoproteome level, and use affinity proteomics to identify cellular targets of ZIKV proteins. Using this approach, we identify 386 ZIKV-interacting proteins, ZIKV-specific and pan-flaviviral activities as well as host factors with known functions in neuronal development, retinal defects and infertility. Moreover, our analysis identified 1,216 phosphorylation sites that are specifically up- or downregulated after ZIKV infection, indicating profound modulation of fundamental signalling pathways such as AKT, MAPK-ERK and ATM-ATR and thereby providing mechanistic insights into the proliferation arrest elicited by ZIKV infection. Functionally, our integrative study identifies ZIKV host-dependency factors and provides a comprehensive framework for a system-level understanding of ZIKV-induced perturbations at the levels of proteins and cellular pathways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>High-Definition Analysis of Host Protein Stability during Human Cytomegalovirus Infection Reveals Antiviral Factors and Viral Evasion Mechanisms</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/30122656/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/30122656/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Human cytomegalovirus (HCMV) is an important pathogen with multiple immune evasion strategies, including virally facilitated degradation of host antiviral restriction factors. Here, we describe a multiplexed approach to discover proteins with innate immune function on the basis of active degradation by the proteasome or lysosome during early-phase HCMV infection. Using three orthogonal proteomic/transcriptomic screens to quantify protein degradation, with high confidence we identified 35 proteins enriched in antiviral restriction factors. A final screen employed a comprehensive panel of viral mutants to predict viral genes that target &amp;gt;250 human proteins. This approach revealed that helicase-like transcription factor (HLTF), a DNA helicase important in DNA repair, potently inhibits early viral gene expression but is rapidly degraded during infection. The functionally unknown HCMV protein UL145 facilitates HLTF degradation by recruiting the Cullin4 E3 ligase complex. Our approach and data will enable further identifications of innate pathways targeted by HCMV and other viruses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Disbiome database: linking the microbiome to disease</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/29866037/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/29866037/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Recent research has provided fascinating indications and evidence that the host health is linked to its microbial inhabitants. Due to the development of high-throughput sequencing technologies, more and more data covering microbial composition changes in different disease types are emerging. However, this information is dispersed over a wide variety of medical and biomedical disciplines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Description:&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://disbiome.ugent.be/home&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Disbiome&lt;/a&gt; is a database which collects and presents published microbiota-disease information in a standardized way. The diseases are classified using the MedDRA classification system and the micro-organisms are linked to their NCBI and SILVA taxonomy. Finally, each study included in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://disbiome.ugent.be/home&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Disbiome&lt;/a&gt; database is assessed for its reporting quality using a standardized questionnaire.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://disbiome.ugent.be/home&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Disbiome&lt;/a&gt; is the first database giving a clear, concise and up-to-date overview of microbial composition differences in diseases, together with the relevant information of the studies published. The strength of this database lies within the combination of the presence of references to other databases, which enables both specific and diverse search strategies within the &lt;a href=&#34;https://disbiome.ugent.be/home&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Disbiome&lt;/a&gt; database, and the human annotation which ensures a simple and structured presentation of the available data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Recognition of an Inducible Host lncRNA by RIG-I Feedback Restricts Innate Immune Response</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/29706547/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/29706547/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The innate RNA sensor RIG-I is critical in the initiation of antiviral type I interferons (IFNs) production upon recognition of &amp;ldquo;non-self&amp;rdquo; viral RNAs. Here, we identify a host-derived, IFN-inducible long noncoding RNA, lnc-Lsm3b, that can compete with viral RNAs in the binding of RIG-I monomers and feedback inactivate the RIG-I innate function at late stage of innate response. Mechanistically, binding of lnc-Lsm3b restricts RIG-I protein&amp;rsquo;s conformational shift and prevents downstream signaling, thereby terminating type I IFNs production. Multivalent structural motifs and long-stem structure are critical features of lnc-Lsm3b for RIG-I binding and inhibition. These data reveal a non-canonical self-recognition mode in the regulation of immune response and demonstrate an important role of an inducible &amp;ldquo;self&amp;rdquo; lncRNA acting as a potent molecular decoy actively saturating RIG-I binding sites to restrict the duration of &amp;ldquo;non-self&amp;rdquo; RNA-induced innate immune response and maintaining immune homeostasis, with potential utility in inflammatory disease management.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Databases for virological research</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tool/2018-02-27-db-virol/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/tool/2018-02-27-db-virol/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bv-brc.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bacterial and Viral Bioinformatics Resource Center (BV-BRC)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is an information system designed to support the biomedical research community’s work on bacterial and viral infectious diseases via integration of vital pathogen information with rich data and analysis tools. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bv-brc.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BV-BRC&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; combines the data, technology, and extensive user communities from two long-running centers: PATRIC, the bacterial system , and IRD/ViPR, the viral systems. In addition to hundreds of thousands of bacterial genomes in PATRIC and over a million viral genomes in IRD/ViPR, the two resources host data on protein structure and function, clinical studies, drug targets and resistance, epidemiology, and other features, and provide open source tools for data analysis and genomic annotation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NCBI &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/genomes/FLU/Database/nph-select.cgi&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Influenza Virus Resource&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://gisaid.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GISAID&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Initiative promotes the rapid sharing of data from all influenza viruses and the coronavirus causing COVID-19. This includes genetic sequence and related clinical and epidemiological data associated with human viruses, and geographical as well as species-specific data associated with avian and other animal viruses, to help researchers understand how viruses evolve and spread during epidemics and pandemics. &lt;a href=&#34;https://gisaid.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GISAID&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; does so by overcoming disincentive hurdles and restrictions, which discourage or prevented sharing of virological data prior to formal publication. The Initiative ensures that open access to data in &lt;a href=&#34;https://gisaid.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GISAID&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is provided free-of-charge to all individuals that agreed to identify themselves and agreed to uphold the &lt;a href=&#34;https://gisaid.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GISAID&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; sharing mechanism governed through its Database Access Agreement. All bonafide users with &lt;a href=&#34;https://gisaid.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GISAID&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; access credentials agreed to the basic premise of upholding a scientific etiquette, by acknowledging the Originating laboratories providing the specimens, and the Submitting laboratories generating sequence and other metadata, ensuring fair exploitation of results derived from the data, and that all users agree that no restrictions shall be attached to data submitted to &lt;a href=&#34;https://gisaid.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GISAID&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, to promote collaboration among researchers on the basis of open sharing of data and respect for all rights and interests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.computationalbiology.cn:18888/IVEW&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FluPhenotype&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is an one-stop platform for early warnings of influenza A viruses. Complete or partial genome sequences, or protein sequences of influenza A viruses could be inputted. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.computationalbiology.cn:18888/IVEW&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FluPhenotype&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; would automatically scan the genomic or protein sequences and output four kinds of information about the virus: the predicted antigenic and genetic relationship between the virus and the vaccine or reference strains,the predicted host of the virus, the mammalian virulence-related amino acids, and the drug-resistance related amino acids.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/tag/databases/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Databases&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/tool/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Tools &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tet2 promotes pathogen infection-induced myelopoiesis through mRNA oxidation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/29364877/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/29364877/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Varieties of RNA modification form the epitranscriptome for post-transcriptional regulation. 5-Methylcytosine (5-mC) is a sparse RNA modification in messenger RNA (mRNA) under physiological conditions. The function of RNA 5-hydroxymethylcytosine (5-hmC) oxidized by ten-eleven translocation (Tet) proteins in Drosophila has been revealed more recently. However, the turnover and function of 5-mC in mammalian mRNA have been largely unknown. Tet2 suppresses myeloid malignancies mostly in an enzymatic activity-dependent manner, and is important in resolving inflammatory response in an enzymatic activity-independent way. Myelopoiesis is a common host immune response in acute and chronic infections; however, its epigenetic mechanism needs to be identified. Here we demonstrate that Tet2 promotes infection-induced myelopoiesis in an mRNA oxidation-dependent manner through Adar1-mediated repression of Socs3 expression at the post-transcription level. Tet2 promotes both abdominal sepsis-induced emergency myelopoiesis and parasite-induced mast cell expansion through decreasing mRNA levels of Socs3, a key negative regulator of the JAK-STAT pathway that is critical for cytokine-induced myelopoiesis. Tet2 represses Socs3 expression through Adar1, which binds and destabilizes Socs3 mRNA in a RNA editing-independent manner. For the underlying mechanism of Tet2 regulation at the mRNA level, Tet2 mediates oxidation of 5-mC in mRNA. Tet2 deficiency leads to the transcriptome-wide appearance of methylated cytosines, including ones in the 3&amp;rsquo; untranslated region of Socs3, which influences double-stranded RNA formation for Adar1 binding, probably through cytosine methylation-specific readers, such as RNA helicases. Our study reveals a previously unknown regulatory role of Tet2 at the epitranscriptomic level, promoting myelopoiesis during infection in the mammalian system by decreasing 5-mCs in mRNAs. Moreover, the inhibitory function of cytosine methylation on double-stranded RNA formation and Adar1 binding in mRNA reveals its new physiological role in the mammalian system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GP73 represses host innate immune response to promote virus replication by facilitating MAVS and TRAF6 degradation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/28394926/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/28394926/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Erratum in:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Correction: &lt;a href=&#34;https://journals.plos.org/plospathogens/article?id=10.1371/journal.ppat.1006938&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;GP73 represses host innate immune response to promote virus replication by facilitating MAVS and TRAF6 degradation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hepatitis C virus (HCV) infection is a leading cause of chronic liver diseases and hepatocellular carcinoma (HCC) and Golgi protein 73 (GP73) is a serum biomarker for liver diseases and HCC. However, the mechanism underlying GP73 regulates HCV infection is largely unknown. Here, we revealed that GP73 acts as a novel negative regulator of host innate immunity to facilitate HCV infection. GP73 expression is activated and correlated with interferon-beta (IFN-β) production during HCV infection in patients&amp;rsquo; serum, primary human hepatocytes (PHHs) and human hepatoma cells through mitochondrial antiviral signaling protein (MAVS), TNF receptor-associated factor 6 (TRAF6) and mitogen-activated protein kinase kinase/extracellular regulated protein kinase (MEK/ERK) pathway. Detailed studies revealed that HCV infection activates MAVS that in turn recruits TRAF6 via TRAF-interacting-motifs (TIMs), and TRAF6 subsequently directly recruits GP73 to MAVS via coiled-coil domain. After binding with MAVS and TRAF6, GP73 promotes MAVS and TRAF6 degradation through proteasome-dependent pathway. Moreover, GP73 attenuates IFN-β promoter, IFN-stimulated response element (ISRE) and nuclear factor κB (NF-κB) promoter and down-regulates IFN-β, IFN-λ1, interleukin-6 (IL-6) and IFN-stimulated gene 56 (ISG56), leading to the repression of host innate immunity. Finally, knock-down of GP73 down-regulates HCV infection and replication in Huh7-MAVSR cells and primary human hepatocytes (PHHs), but such repression is rescued by GP73m4 (a mutant GP73 resists to GP73-shRNA#4) in Huh7-MAVSR cells, suggesting that GP73 facilitates HCV infection. Taken together, we demonstrated that GP73 acts as a negative regulator of innate immunity to facilitate HCV infection by interacting with MAVS/TRAF6 and promoting MAVS/TRAF6 degradation. This study provides new insights into the mechanism of HCV infection and pathogenesis, and suggests that GP73 is a new potential antiviral target in the prevention and treatment of HCV associated diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rethinking Diet to Aid Human-Microbe Symbiosis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/27916707/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/27916707/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The spread of the Western lifestyle has been accompanied by microbial changes thought to underlie the emergence of chronic, nontransmissible, immune-related diseases. The past decade has seen the unprecedented development of therapies for &amp;lsquo;replenishing&amp;rsquo; the microbiota of sick individuals. However, functional and ecological solutions helping the host and the gut microbiota to cope with the ecological stressors of modern life are still lacking. In this review, we discuss how recent advances in gut microbiome science are leading to the identification of microbe-derived and health-relevant metabolites. These molecules will guide the selection of the next-generation of probiotics and dietary recommendations, which should also take the resident gut microbiota into account, to optimise efficacy. These solutions for maintaining a well-functioning gut ecosystem and promoting good health should be customised, palatable, and as widely accessible as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cell autonomous regulation of herpes and influenza virus infection by the circadian clock</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/27528682/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/27528682/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Viruses are intracellular pathogens that hijack host cell machinery and resources to replicate. Rather than being constant, host physiology is rhythmic, undergoing circadian (∼24 h) oscillations in many virus-relevant pathways, but whether daily rhythms impact on viral replication is unknown. We find that the time of day of host infection regulates virus progression in live mice and individual cells. Furthermore, we demonstrate that herpes and influenza A virus infections are enhanced when host circadian rhythms are abolished by disrupting the key clock gene transcription factor Bmal1. Intracellular trafficking, biosynthetic processes, protein synthesis, and chromatin assembly all contribute to circadian regulation of virus infection. Moreover, herpesviruses differentially target components of the molecular circadian clockwork. Our work demonstrates that viruses exploit the clockwork for their own gain and that the clock represents a novel target for modulating viral replication that extends beyond any single family of these ubiquitous pathogens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Mouse Intestinal Bacterial Collection (miBC) provides host-specific insight into cultured diversity and functional potential of the gut microbiota</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/27670113/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/27670113/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Erratum in:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Corrigendum: &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nature.com/articles/nmicrobiol2016219&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;The Mouse Intestinal Bacterial Collection (miBC) provides host-specific insight into cultured diversity and functional potential of the gut microbiota&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Intestinal bacteria influence mammalian physiology, but many types of bacteria are still uncharacterized. Moreover, reference strains of mouse gut bacteria are not easily available, although mouse models are extensively used in medical research. These are major limitations for the investigation of intestinal microbiomes and their interactions with diet and host. It is thus important to study in detail the diversity and functions of gut microbiota members, including those colonizing the mouse intestine. To address these issues, we aimed at establishing the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.dsmz.de/collection/catalogue/microorganisms/special-groups-of-organisms/dzif-sammlung/maus-mikrobiomliste&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Mouse Intestinal Bacterial Collection (miBC)&lt;/a&gt;, a public repository of bacterial strains and associated genomes from the mouse gut, and studied host-specificity of colonization and sequence-based relevance of the resource. The collection includes several strains representing novel species, genera and even one family. Genomic analyses showed that certain species are specific to the mouse intestine and that a minimal consortium of 18 strains covered 50-75% of the known functional potential of metagenomes. The present work will sustain future research on microbiota-host interactions in health and disease, as it will facilitate targeted colonization and molecular studies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Cytomegalovirus Peptide-Specific Antibody Alters Natural Killer Cell Homeostasis and Is Shared in Several Autoimmune Diseases</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/26962948/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/26962948/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Human cytomegalovirus (hCMV), a ubiquitous beta-herpesvirus, has been associated with several autoimmune diseases. However, the direct role of hCMV in inducing autoimmune disorders remains unclear. Here we report the identification of an autoantibody that recognizes a group of peptides with a conserved motif matching the Pp150 protein of hCMV (anti-Pp150) and is shared among patients with various autoimmune diseases. Anti-Pp150 also recognizes the single-pass membrane protein CIP2A and induces the death of CD56(bright) NK cells, a natural killer cell subset whose expansion is correlated with autoimmune disease. Consistent with this finding, the percentage of circulating CD56(bright) NK cells is reduced in patients with several autoimmune diseases and negatively correlates with anti-Pp150 concentration. CD56(bright) NK cell death occurs via both antibody- and complement-dependent cytotoxicity. Our findings reveal that a shared hCMV-induced autoantibody is involved in the decrease of CD56(bright) NK cells and may thus contribute to the onset of autoimmune disorders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inflammatory caspases are innate immune receptors for intracellular LPS</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/25119034/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/25119034/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The murine caspase-11 non-canonical inflammasome responds to various bacterial infections. Caspase-11 activation-induced pyroptosis, in response to cytoplasmic lipopolysaccharide (LPS), is critical for endotoxic shock in mice. The mechanism underlying cytosolic LPS sensing and the responsible pattern recognition receptor are unknown. Here we show that human monocytes, epithelial cells and keratinocytes undergo necrosis upon cytoplasmic delivery of LPS. LPS-induced cytotoxicity was mediated by human caspase-4 that could functionally complement murine caspase-11. Human caspase-4 and the mouse homologue caspase-11 (hereafter referred to as caspase-4/11) and also human caspase-5, directly bound to LPS and lipid A with high specificity and affinity. LPS associated with endogenous caspase-11 in pyroptotic cells. Insect-cell purified caspase-4/11 underwent oligomerization upon LPS binding, resulting in activation of the caspases. Underacylated lipid IVa and lipopolysaccharide from Rhodobacter sphaeroides (LPS-RS) could bind to caspase-4/11 but failed to induce their oligomerization and activation. LPS binding was mediated by the CARD domain of the caspase. Binding-deficient CARD-domain point mutants did not respond to LPS with oligomerization or activation and failed to induce pyroptosis upon LPS electroporation or bacterial infections. The function of caspase-4/5/11 represents a new mode of pattern recognition in immunity and also an unprecedented means of caspase activation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
