<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Multi-Omics | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/multi-omics/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/multi-omics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Multi-Omics</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Multi-Omics</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/multi-omics/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advancing CAR T cell therapy through the use of multidimensional omics data</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/36721024/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/36721024/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Key points&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Multidimensional omics data, encompassing genomics, epigenomics, transcriptomics, T cell receptor-repertoire profiling, proteomics, metabolomics and microbiomics, have been exploited to advance our mechanistic understanding of chimeric antigen receptor (CAR) T cell therapy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Utilization of multi-omics data derived from both tumour and non-malignant tissues at the bulk and/or single-cell levels is a powerful approach to identifying optimal targets for highly efficacious and safe CAR T cell therapy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Integration of bulk and/or single-cell multidimensional omics data has been applied to investigate key determinants of CAR T cell persistence and antitumour efficacy, including T cell states and phenotypes, tumour cell characteristics, the tumour microenvironment and the microbiome.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Leveraging multi-omics data promises to elucidate the mechanisms underlying CAR T cell-related toxicities, including cytokine-release syndrome, immune effector cell-associated neurotoxicity syndrome and on-target, off-tumour toxicities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite the notable success of chimeric antigen receptor (CAR) T cell therapies in the treatment of certain haematological malignancies, challenges remain in optimizing CAR designs and cell products, improving response rates, extending the durability of remissions, reducing toxicity and broadening the utility of this therapeutic modality to other cancer types. Data from multidimensional omics analyses, including genomics, epigenomics, transcriptomics, T cell receptor-repertoire profiling, proteomics, metabolomics and/or microbiomics, provide unique opportunities to dissect the complex and dynamic multifactorial phenotypes, processes and responses of CAR T cells as well as to discover novel tumour targets and pathways of resistance. In this Review, we summarize the multidimensional cellular and molecular profiling technologies that have been used to advance our mechanistic understanding of CAR T cell therapies. In addition, we discuss current applications and potential strategies leveraging multi-omics data to identify optimal target antigens and other molecular features that could be exploited to enhance the antitumour activity and minimize the toxicity of CAR T cell therapy. Indeed, fully utilizing multi-omics data will provide new insights into the biology of CAR T cell therapy, further accelerate the development of products with improved efficacy and safety profiles, and enable clinicians to better predict and monitor patient responses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multi-omics microsampling for the profiling of lifestyle-associated changes in health</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36658343/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36658343/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Current healthcare practices are reactive and use limited physiological and clinical information, often collected months or years apart. Moreover, the discovery and profiling of blood biomarkers in clinical and research settings are constrained by geographical barriers, the cost and inconvenience of in-clinic venepuncture, low sampling frequency and the low depth of molecular measurements. Here we describe a strategy for the frequent capture and analysis of thousands of metabolites, lipids, cytokines and proteins in 10 μl of blood alongside physiological information from wearable sensors. We show the advantages of such frequent and dense multi-omics microsampling in two applications: the assessment of the reactions to a complex mixture of dietary interventions, to discover individualized inflammatory and metabolic responses; and deep individualized profiling, to reveal large-scale molecular fluctuations as well as thousands of molecular relationships associated with intra-day physiological variations (in heart rate, for example) and with the levels of clinical biomarkers (specifically, glucose and cortisol) and of physical activity. Combining wearables and multi-omics microsampling for frequent and scalable omics may facilitate dynamic health profiling and biomarker discovery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lineage Tracing and Single-Nucleus Multiomics Reveal Novel Features of Adaptive and Maladaptive Repair after Acute Kidney Injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36735940/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36735940/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; AKI triggers a proliferative response as part of an intrinsic cellular repair program, which can lead to adaptive renal repair, restoring kidney structure and function, or maladaptive repair with the persistence of injured proximal tubule cells (PTCs) and an altered kidney structure. However, the cellular and molecular understanding of these repair programs is limited.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; To examine chromatin and transcriptional responses in the same cell upon ischemia-reperfusion injury (IRI), we combined genetic fate mapping of cycling (Ki67+) cells labeled early after IRI with single-nucleus multiomics-profiling transcriptome and chromatin accessibility in the same nucleus-and generated a dataset of 83,315 nuclei.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; AKI triggered a broad cell cycle response preceded by cell type-specific and global transcriptional changes in the nephron, the collecting and vascular systems, and stromal and immune cell types. We observed a heterogeneous population of maladaptive PTCs throughout proximal tubule segments 6 months post-AKI, with a marked loss of maladaptive cells from 4 weeks to 6 months. Gene expression and chromatin accessibility profiling in the same nuclei highlighted differences between adaptive and maladaptive PTCs in the activity of &lt;em&gt;cis&lt;/em&gt;-regulatory elements and transcription factors, accompanied by corresponding changes in target gene expression. Adaptive repair was associated with reduced expression of genes encoding transmembrane transport proteins essential to kidney function.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; Analysis of genome organization and gene activity with single-cell resolution using lineage tracing and single-nucleus multiomics offers new insight into the regulation of renal injury repair. Weeks to months after mild-to-moderate IRI, maladaptive PTCs persist with an aberrant epigenetic landscape, and PTCs exhibit an altered transcriptional profile even following adaptive repair.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Applying multi-omics towards tumor microbiome research</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/imt2.73/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/imt2.73/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The tumor microbiome plays a significant role in carcinogenesis, cancer development, metastasis, and cancer therapies.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The tumor microbiome has great potential to become a target for early diagnosis and treatment of cancer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Genomics, transcriptomics, proteomics, and metabolomics are powerful approaches for tumor microbiome studies, by facilitating an understanding of different levels of the central dogma.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Multi-omics will make enormous impacts on future research of the tumor microbiome.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The development of single-cell multi-omics technologies will motivate the progression of the tumor microbiome field.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rather than a “short-term tenant,” the tumor microbiome has been shown to play a vital role as a “permanent resident,” affecting carcinogenesis, cancer development, metastasis, and cancer therapies. As the tumor microbiome has great potential to become a target for the early diagnosis and treatment of cancer, recent research on the relevance of the tumor microbiota has attracted a wide range of attention from various scientific fields, resulting in remarkable progress that benefits from the development of interdisciplinary technologies. However, there are still a great variety of challenges in this emerging area, such as the low biomass of intratumoral bacteria and unculturable character of some microbial species. Due to the complexity of tumor microbiome research (&lt;em&gt;e.g.&lt;/em&gt;, the heterogeneity of tumor microenvironment), new methods with high spatial and temporal resolution are urgently needed. Among these developing methods, multi-omics technologies (combinations of genomics, transcriptomics, proteomics, and metabolomics) are powerful approaches that can facilitate the understanding of the tumor microbiome on different levels of the central dogma. Therefore, multi-omics (especially single-cell omics) will make enormous impacts on the future studies of the interplay between microbes and tumor microenvironment. In this review, we have systematically summarized the advances in multi-omics and their existing and potential applications in tumor microbiome research, thus providing an omics toolbox for investigators to reference in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A spatially resolved atlas of the human lung characterizes a gland-associated immune niche</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36543915/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36543915/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Single-cell transcriptomics has allowed unprecedented resolution of cell types/states in the human lung, but their spatial context is less well defined. To (re)define tissue architecture of lung and airways, we profiled five proximal-to-distal locations of healthy human lungs in depth using multi-omic single cell/nuclei and spatial transcriptomics at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.lungcellatlas.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lung Cell Atlas&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Using computational data integration and analysis, we extend beyond the suspension cell paradigm and discover macro and micro-anatomical tissue compartments including previously unannotated cell types in the epithelial, vascular, stromal and nerve bundle micro-environments. We identify and implicate peribronchial fibroblasts in lung disease. Importantly, we discover and validate a survival niche for IgA plasma cells in the airway submucosal glands (SMG). We show that gland epithelial cells recruit B cells and IgA plasma cells, and promote longevity and antibody secretion locally through expression of CCL28, APRIL and IL-6. This new ‘gland-associated immune niche’ has implications for respiratory health.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deciphering colorectal cancer genetics through multi-omic analysis of 100,204 cases and 154,587 controls of European and east Asian ancestries</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36539618/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36539618/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Colorectal cancer (CRC) is a leading cause of mortality worldwide. We conducted a genome-wide association study meta-analysis of 100,204 CRC cases and 154,587 controls of European and east Asian ancestry, identifying 205 independent risk associations, of which 50 were unreported. We performed integrative genomic, transcriptomic and methylomic analyses across large bowel mucosa and other tissues. Transcriptome- and methylome-wide association studies revealed an additional 53 risk associations. We identified 155 high-confidence effector genes functionally linked to CRC risk, many of which had no previously established role in CRC. These have multiple different functions and specifically indicate that variation in normal colorectal homeostasis, proliferation, cell adhesion, migration, immunity and microbial interactions determines CRC risk. Crosstissue analyses indicated that over a third of effector genes most probably act outside the colonic mucosa. Our findings provide insights into colorectal oncogenesis and highlight potential targets across tissues for new CRC treatment and chemoprevention strategies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Engineered cell entry links receptor biology with single-cell genomics</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36516854/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36516854/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ENTER displays ligands, delivers payloads, and records receptor specificity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ENTER enables antigen-specific expansion or depletion of T or B cells&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ENTER-seq maps TCR specificity, clonality, and cell state in single cells&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ENTER-seq of patient sample decodes antiviral T cell memory&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cells communicate with each other via receptor-ligand interactions. Here, we describe lentiviral-mediated cell entry by engineered receptor-ligand interaction (ENTER) to display ligand proteins, deliver payloads, and record receptor specificity. We optimize ENTER to decode interactions between T cell receptor (TCR)-MHC peptides, antibody-antigen, and other receptor-ligand pairs. A viral presentation strategy allows ENTER to capture interactions between B cell receptor and any antigen. We engineer ENTER to deliver genetic payloads to antigen-specific T or B cells to selectively modulate cellular behavior in mixed populations. Single-cell readout of ENTER by RNA sequencing (ENTER-seq) enables multiplexed enumeration of antigen specificities, TCR clonality, cell type, and states of individual T cells. ENTER-seq of CMV-seropositive patient blood samples reveals the viral epitopes that drive effector memory T cell differentiation and inter-clonal vs. intra-clonal phenotypic diversity targeting the same epitope. ENTER technology enables systematic discovery of receptor specificity, linkage to cell fates, and antigen-specific cargo delivery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integrated multi-omics Landscape of liver metastases</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36574521/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36574521/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;BACKGROUND &amp;amp; AIMS&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lack of thorough knowledge for complicated immune-microenvironment (IM) within a variety of liver metastases (LMs) leads to inappropriate treatment and unsatisfactory prognosis. We aimed to characterize IM subtypes and investigate potential mechanisms in LMs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;METHODS&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mass cytometry was applied to characterize immune landscape of primary liver cancers and liver metastases cohort. Transcriptomic and whole exome sequencing were used to explore potential mechanisms across distinct IM subtypes. Single cell transcriptomic sequencing, multiplex fluorescent immunohistochemistry, cell culture, mouse model, western blot, quantitative polymerase chain reaction and immunohistochemistry were used for validation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;RESULTS&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Five IM subtypes were revealed in 100 LMs and 50 primary liver cancers. Patients featured terminally exhausted (IM1) or rare-T-cell-inflamed (IM2 and IM3) immune characteristics showed worse outcome. Increased intra-tumor heterogeneity, enriched somatic TP53, KRAS, APC, PIK3CA mutations and hyper-activated hypoxia signaling accounted for the formation of vicious subtypes. SLC2A1 promoted immune suppression and desert via increasing proportion of Spp1&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; macrophages and their inhibitory interactions with T cells in liver metastatic lesions. Furthermore, SLC2A1 promoted immune escape and liver metastasis through inducing regulatory T cells including Tregs and LAG3&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt;CD4&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T cells in primary colorectal cancer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;CONCLUSION&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The study provided integrated multi-omics landscape of liver metastasis, uncovering potential mechanisms for vicious IM subtypes and confirming the roles of SLC2A1 in regulating tumor microenvironment remodeling in both primary tumor and liver metastatic lesions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spatial multi-omic map of human myocardial infarction</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35948637/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35948637/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Myocardial infarction is a leading cause of death worldwide1. Although advances have been made in acute treatment, an incomplete understanding of remodelling processes has limited the effectiveness of therapies to reduce late-stage mortality2. Here we generate an integrative high-resolution map of human cardiac remodelling after myocardial infarction using single-cell gene expression, chromatin accessibility and spatial transcriptomic profiling of multiple physiological zones at distinct time points in myocardium from patients with myocardial infarction and controls. Multi-modal data integration enabled us to evaluate cardiac cell-type compositions at increased resolution, yielding insights into changes of the cardiac transcriptome and epigenome through the identification of distinct tissue structures of injury, repair and remodelling. We identified and validated disease-specific cardiac cell states of major cell types and analysed them in their spatial context, evaluating their dependency on other cell types. Our data elucidate the molecular principles of human myocardial tissue organization, recapitulating a gradual cardiomyocyte and myeloid continuum following ischaemic injury. In sum, our study provides an integrative molecular map of human myocardial infarction, represents an essential reference for the field and paves the way for advanced mechanistic and therapeutic studies of cardiac disease.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Metabolic balance in colorectal cancer is maintained by optimal Wnt signaling levels</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35904277/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35904277/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wnt pathways are important for the modulation of tissue homeostasis, and their deregulation is linked to cancer development. Canonical Wnt signaling is hyperactivated in many human colorectal cancers due to genetic alterations of the negative Wnt regulator APC. However, the expression levels of Wnt-dependent targets vary between tumors, and the mechanisms of carcinogenesis concomitant with this Wnt signaling dosage have not been understood. In this study, we integrate whole-genome CRISPR/Cas9 screens with large-scale multi-omic data to delineate functional subtypes of cancer. We engineer APC loss-of-function mutations and thereby hyperactivate Wnt signaling in cells with low endogenous Wnt activity and find that the resulting engineered cells have an unfavorable metabolic equilibrium compared with cells which naturally acquired Wnt hyperactivation. We show that the dosage level of oncogenic Wnt hyperactivation impacts the metabolic equilibrium and the mitochondrial phenotype of a given cell type in a context-dependent manner. These findings illustrate the impact of context-dependent genetic interactions on cellular phenotypes of a central cancer driver mutation and expand our understanding of quantitative modulation of oncogenic signaling in tumorigenesis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Immune- and Stemness-Related Genes Revealed by Comprehensive Analysis and Validation for Cancer Immunity and Prognosis and Its Nomogram in Lung Adenocarcinoma</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35833114/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35833114/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Objective:&lt;/em&gt; Lung adenocarcinoma (LUAD) is a familiar lung cancer with a very poor prognosis. This study investigated the immune- and stemness-related genes to develop model related with cancer immunity and prognosis in LUAD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Method:&lt;/em&gt; The Cancer Genome Atlas (TCGA) was utilized for obtaining original transcriptome data and clinical information. Differential expression, prognostic value, and correlation with clinic parameter of mRNA stemness index (mRNAsi) were conducted in LUAD. Significant mRNAsi-related module and hub genes were screened using weighted gene coexpression network analysis (WGCNA). Meanwhile, immune-related differential genes (IRGs) were screened in LUAD. Stem cell index and immune-related differential genes (SC-IRGs) were screened and further developed to construct prognosis-related model and nomogram. Comprehensive analysis of hub genes and subgroups, involving enrichment in the subgroup [gene set enrichment analysis (GSEA)], gene mutation, genetic correlation, gene expression, immune, tumor mutation burden (TMB), and drug sensitivity, used bioinformatics and reverse transcription polymerase chain reaction (RT-PCR) for verification.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; Through difference analysis, mRNAsi of LUAD group was markedly higher than that of normal group. Clinical parameters (age, gender, and T staging) were ascertained to be highly relevant to mRNAsi. MEturquoise and MEblue were found to be the most significant modules (including positive and negative correlations) related to mRNAsi via WGCNA. The functions and pathways of the two mRNAsi-related modules were mainly enriched in tumorigenesis, development, and metastasis. Combining stem cell index-related differential genes and immune-related differential genes, 30 prognosis-related SC-IRGs were screened via Cox regression analysis. Then, 16 prognosis-related SC-IRGs were screened to construct a LASSO regression model at last. In addition, the model was successfully validated by using TCGA-LUAD and GSE68465, whereas c-index and the calibration curves were utilized to demonstrate the clinical value of our nomogram. Following the validation of the model, GSEA, immune cell correlation, TMB, clinical relevance, etc., have found significant difference in high- and low-risk groups, and 16-gene expression of the SC-IRG model also was tested by RT-PCR. &lt;em&gt;ADRB2&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;ANGPTL4&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;BDNF&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;CBLC&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;CX3CR1&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;IL3RA&lt;/em&gt; were found markedly different expression between the tumor and normal group.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/em&gt; The SC-IRG model and the prognostic nomogram could accurately predict LUAD survival. Our study used mRNAsi combined with immunity that may lay a foundation for the future research studies in LUAD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multi-omics analysis unravels dysregulated lysosomal function and lipid metabolism involved in sub-chronic particulate matter-induced pulmonary injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35525343/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35525343/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A multi-omics approach was used to identify molecular changes in mouse lung tissues.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PM exposure impairs lung structure and inflammatory reactions in the mouse lungs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sub-chronic exposure to PM causes lung injury by disturbing lysosomal function and lipid metabolism homeostasis.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Different pathways are triggered in mouse lung tissues in response to PM exposure.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Particulate matter (PM) is a huge environmental threat and is of major public concern. Oxidative stress and systemic inflammation are known factors that contribute to PM- related damage; however, a systematic understanding of the deleterious pulmonary effects of PM using multi-omics analysis is lacking. In this study, we performed transcriptomic, proteomic, and metabolomic analyses in a mouse model exposed to PM for three months to identify molecular changes in lung tissues. We identified 1690 genes, 326 proteins, and 67 metabolites exhibiting significant differences between PM-challenged and control mice (p &amp;lt; 0.05). Differentially expressed genes and proteins regulated in PM-challenged mice were involved in lipid metabolism and in the immune and inflammatory response processes. Moreover, a comprehensive analysis of transcript, protein, and metabolite datasets revealed that the genes, proteins, and metabolites in the PM-treated group were involved in lysosomal function and lipid metabolism. Specifically, Cathepsin D (Ctsd), Ferritin light chain (Ftl), Lactotransferrin (Ltf), Lipocalin 2 (Lcn2), and Prosaposin (Psap) were major proteins/genes associated with PM-induced pulmonary damage, while two lipid molecules PC (18:1(11Z)/16:0) and PA (16:0/18:1(11Z)) were major metabolites related to PM-induced pulmonary injury. In summary, lipid metabolism might be used as successful precautions and therapeutic targets in PM-induced pulmonary injury to maintain the stability of cellular lysosomal function.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Combined protein and nucleic acid imaging reveals virus-dependent B cell and macrophage immunosuppression of tissue microenvironments</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35447093/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35447093/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Development of a method (PANINI) for multiplexed nucleic acid and protein imaging&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Identification of orchestrated immune events in response to SIV infection&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IL-10 levels in B cells and macrophages correlate with immunosuppression&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tissue microenvironmental cues can influence SIV viral transcription state&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Understanding the mechanisms of HIV tissue persistence necessitates the ability to visualize tissue microenvironments where infected cells reside; however, technological barriers limit our ability to dissect the cellular components of these HIV reservoirs. Here, we developed protein and nucleic acid in situ imaging (PANINI) to simultaneously quantify DNA, RNA, and protein levels within these tissue compartments. By coupling PANINI with multiplexed ion beam imaging (MIBI), we measured over 30 parameters simultaneously across archival lymphoid tissues from healthy or simian immunodeficiency virus (SIV)-infected nonhuman primates. PANINI enabled the spatial dissection of cellular phenotypes, functional markers, and viral events resulting from infection. SIV infection induced IL-10 expression in lymphoid B cells, which correlated with local macrophage M2 polarization. This highlights a potential viral mechanism for conditioning an immunosuppressive tissue environment for virion production. The spatial multimodal framework here can be extended to decipher tissue responses in other infectious diseases and tumor biology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Combined Transcriptomic and Proteomic Approach to Reveal the Effect of Mogroside V on OVA-Induced Pulmonary Inflammation in Mice</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35371026/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35371026/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mogroside V is a bioactive ingredient extracted from the natural food Siraitia grosvenorii which possesses functions that stimulate lung humidification and cough relief activities, but its underlying mechanisms were rarely studied. To estimate its potential protective effect on ovalbumin (OVA)-induced pulmonary inflammation and understand its system-wide mechanism, integrated omics was applied in this study. Mogroside V effectively reduced the levels of IgE, TNF-α, and IL-5 in OVA-induced mice. The results of RNA-seq and data-independent acquisition proteomics approach revealed that 944 genes and 341 proteins were differentially expressed in the normal control group (NC) and ovalbumin-induced control group (OC) and 449 genes and 259 proteins were differentially expressed between the OC and the group treated with 50 mg/kg mogroside V (MV). After a combined analysis of the transcriptome and the proteome, 93 major pathways were screened, and we discovered that mogroside V exerts an anti-inflammation effect in the lung via NF-κB and JAK-STAT, both of which are among the signaling pathways mentioned above. In addition, we found that the key regulatory molecules (Igha, Ighg1, NF-κB, Jak1, and Stat1) in the two pathways were activated in inflammation and inhibited by mogroside V. Thus, mogroside V may be the main bioactivity component in S. grosvenorii that exerts lung humidification and cough relief effects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multi-omic analysis reveals divergent molecular events in scarring and regenerative wound healing</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35077667/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35077667/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Verteporfin (YAP inhibitor) treatment yields wound regeneration in mice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Divergent molecular pathways of scarring versus regeneration are defined by differential mechanical versus Wnt signaling&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Trps1 drives wound regeneration in the context of blocked mechanical signaling&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Summary&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regeneration is the holy grail of tissue repair, but skin injury typically yields fibrotic, non-functional scars. Developing pro-regenerative therapies requires rigorous understanding of the molecular progression from injury to fibrosis or regeneration. Here, we report the divergent molecular events driving skin wound cells toward scarring or regenerative fates. We profile scarring versus YAP-inhibition-induced wound regeneration at the transcriptional (single-cell RNA sequencing), protein (timsTOF proteomics), and tissue (extracellular matrix ultrastructural analysis) levels. Using cell-surface barcoding, we integrate these data to reveal fibrotic and regenerative “molecular trajectories” of healing. We show that disrupting YAP mechanotransduction yields regenerative repair by fibroblasts with activated Trps1 and Wnt signaling. Finally, via in vivo gene knockdown and overexpression in wounds, we identify Trps1 as a key regulatory gene that is necessary and partially sufficient for wound regeneration. Our findings serve as a multi-omic map of wound regeneration and could have therapeutic implications for pathologic fibroses.
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multi-omic characterization of genome-wide abnormal DNA methylation reveals diagnostic and prognostic markers for esophageal squamous-cell carcinoma</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35210398/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35210398/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Viruses are intracellular pathogens that hijack host cell machinery and resources to replicate. Rather than being constant, host physiology is rhythmic, undergoing circadian (∼24 h) oscillations in many virus-relevant pathways, but whether daily rhythms impact on viral replication is unknown. We find that the time of day of host infection regulates virus progression in live mice and individual cells. Furthermore, we demonstrate that herpes and influenza A virus infections are enhanced when host circadian rhythms are abolished by disrupting the key clock gene transcription factor Bmal1. Intracellular trafficking, biosynthetic processes, protein synthesis, and chromatin assembly all contribute to circadian regulation of virus infection. Moreover, herpesviruses differentially target components of the molecular circadian clockwork. Our work demonstrates that viruses exploit the clockwork for their own gain and that the clock represents a novel target for modulating viral replication that extends beyond any single family of these ubiquitous pathogens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DeepMNE: Deep Multi-Network Embedding for lncRNA-Disease Association Prediction</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35180094/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35180094/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Long non-coding RNA (lncRNA) participates in various biological processes, hence its mutations and disorders play an important role in the pathogenesis of multiple human diseases. Identifying disease-related lncRNAs is crucial for the diagnosis, prevention, and treatment of diseases. Although a large number of computational approaches have been developed, effectively integrating multi-omics data and accurately predicting potential lncRNA-disease associations remains a challenge, especially regarding new lncRNAs and new diseases. In this work, we propose a new method with deep multi-network embedding, called &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Mayingjun20179/DeepMNE&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;DeepMNE&lt;/a&gt;, to discover potential lncRNA-disease associations, especially for novel diseases and lncRNAs. &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Mayingjun20179/DeepMNE&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;DeepMNE&lt;/a&gt; extracts multi-omics data to describe diseases and lncRNAs, and proposes a network fusion method based on deep learning to integrate multi-source information. Moreover, &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Mayingjun20179/DeepMNE&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;DeepMNE&lt;/a&gt; complements the sparse association network and uses kernel neighborhood similarity to construct disease similarity and lncRNA similarity networks. Furthermore, a graph embedding method is adopted to predict potential associations. Experimental results demonstrate that compared to other state-of-the-art methods, &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Mayingjun20179/DeepMNE&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;DeepMNE&lt;/a&gt; has a higher predictive performance on new associations, new lncRNAs and new diseases. Besides, &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Mayingjun20179/DeepMNE&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;DeepMNE&lt;/a&gt; also elicits a considerable predictive performance on perturbed datasets. Additionally, the results of two different types of case studies indicate that &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Mayingjun20179/DeepMNE&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;DeepMNE&lt;/a&gt; can be used as an effective tool for disease-related lncRNA prediction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integrative omics analysis identifies biomarkers of idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35015148/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35015148/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis (IPF) is an interstitial lung disease characterized by chronic progressive pulmonary fibrosis and a poor prognosis. Genetic studies, including transcriptomic and proteomics, have provided new insight into revealing mechanisms of IPF. Herein we provided a novel strategy to identify biomarkers by integrative analysis of transcriptomic and proteomic profiles of IPF patients. We examined the landscape of IPF patients&amp;rsquo; gene expression in the transcription and translation phases and investigated the expression and functions of two new potential biomarkers. Differentially expressed (DE) mRNAs were mainly enriched in pathways associated with immune system activities and inflammatory responses, while DE proteins are related to extracellular matrix production and wound repair. The upregulated genes in both phases are associated with wound repair and cell differentiation, while the downregulated genes in both phases are associated with reduced immune activities and the damage of the alveolar tissues. On this basis, we identified thirteen potential marker genes. Among them, we validated the expression changes of butyrophilin-like 9 (BTNL9) and plasmolipin (PLLP) and investigated their functional pathways in the IPF mechanism. Both genes are downregulated in the tissues of IPF patients and Bleomycin-induced mice, and co-expression analysis indicates that they have a protective effect by inhibiting extracellular matrix production and promoting wound repair in alveolar epithelial cells.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SARS-CoV-2 infection triggers profibrotic macrophage responses and lung fibrosis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34914922/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34914922/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;COVID-19-induced &amp;ldquo;acute respiratory distress syndrome&amp;rdquo; (ARDS) is associated with prolonged respiratory failure and high mortality, but the mechanistic basis of lung injury remains incompletely understood. Here, we analyze pulmonary immune responses and lung pathology in two cohorts of patients with COVID-19 ARDS using functional single-cell genomics, immunohistology, and electron microscopy. We describe an accumulation of CD163-expressing monocyte-derived macrophages that acquired a profibrotic transcriptional phenotype during COVID-19 ARDS. Gene set enrichment and computational data integration revealed a significant similarity between COVID-19-associated macrophages and profibrotic macrophage populations identified in idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis. COVID-19 ARDS was associated with clinical, radiographic, histopathological, and ultrastructural hallmarks of pulmonary fibrosis. Exposure of human monocytes to SARS-CoV-2, but not influenza A virus or viral RNA analogs, was sufficient to induce a similar profibrotic phenotype in vitro. In conclusion, we demonstrate that SARS-CoV-2 triggers profibrotic macrophage responses and pronounced fibroproliferative ARDS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integrative multi-omics approach for mechanism of humidifier disinfectant-associated lung injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34841713/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34841713/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;No abstract available&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Longitudinal Multi-omics Reveals Subset-Specific Mechanisms Underlying Irritable Bowel Syndrome</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32916129/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32916129/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Erratum in:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674%2820%2931447-1&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Longitudinal Multi-omics Reveals Subset-Specific Mechanisms Underlying Irritable Bowel Syndrome&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The gut microbiome has been implicated in multiple human chronic gastrointestinal (GI) disorders. Determining its mechanistic role in disease has been difficult due to apparent disconnects between animal and human studies and lack of an integrated multi-omics view of disease-specific physiological changes. We integrated longitudinal multi-omics data from the gut microbiome, metabolome, host epigenome, and transcriptome in the context of irritable bowel syndrome (IBS) host physiology. We identified IBS subtype-specific and symptom-related variation in microbial composition and function. A subset of identified changes in microbial metabolites correspond to host physiological mechanisms that are relevant to IBS. By integrating multiple data layers, we identified purine metabolism as a novel host-microbial metabolic pathway in IBS with translational potential. Our study highlights the importance of longitudinal sampling and integrating complementary multi-omics data to identify functional mechanisms that can serve as therapeutic targets in a comprehensive treatment strategy for chronic GI diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
