<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cell Death | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/cell-death/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/cell-death/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Cell Death</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Cell Death</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/cell-death/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>PANoptosis-like cell death in ischemia/reperfusion injury of retinal neurons</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35900430/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35900430/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We screened small molecules to identify two compounds, which we named RSL3 and RSL5, that have increased lethality in the presence of oncogenic RAS. Counter screening with biologically active compounds defined aspects of the mechanism of action for RSL3 and RSL5, such as a nonapoptotic, MEK-dependent, and iron-dependent oxidative cell death. Erastin, a previously reported compound with RAS-selective lethality, showed similar properties. RNA interference experiments targeting voltage-dependent anion channel 3 (VDAC3), a target of erastin, demonstrated that RSL5 is a scaffold that acts through VDACs to activate the observed pathway. RSL3 activated a similar death mechanism but in a VDAC-independent manner. We found that cells transformed with oncogenic RAS have increased iron content relative to their normal cell counterparts through upregulation of transferrin receptor 1 and downregulation of ferritin heavy chain 1 and ferritin light chain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cannabinoid Receptor 2-Centric Molecular Feedback Loop Drives Necroptosis in Diabetic Heart Injuries</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36448459/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36448459/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Diabetic heart dysfunction is a common complication of diabetes. Cell death is a core event that leads to diabetic heart dysfunction. However, the time sequence of cell death pathways and the precise time to intervene of particular cell death type remain largely unknown in the diabetic heart. This study aims to identify the particular cell death type that is responsible for diabetic heart dysfunction and to propose a promising therapeutic strategy by intervening in the cell death pathway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; Type 2 diabetes models were established using db/db leptin receptor-deficient mice and high-fat diet/streptozotocin-induced mice. The type 1 diabetes model was established in streptozotocin-induced mice. Apoptosis and programmed cell necrosis (necroptosis) were detected in diabetic mouse hearts at different ages. G protein-coupled receptor-targeted drug library was searched to identify potential receptors regulating the key cell death pathway. Pharmacological and genetic approaches that modulate the expression of targets were used. Stable cell lines and a homemade phosphorylation antibody were prepared to conduct mechanistic studies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; Necroptosis was activated after apoptosis at later stages of diabetes and was functionally responsible for cardiac dysfunction. Cannabinoid receptor 2 (CB2R) was a key regulator of necroptosis. Mechanically, during normal glucose levels, CB2R inhibited S6 kinase-mediated phosphorylation of BACH2 at serine 520, thereby leading to BACH2 translocation to the nucleus, where BACH2 transcriptionally repressed the necroptosis genes Rip1, Rip3, and Mlkl. Under hyperglycemic conditions, high glucose induced CB2R internalization in a β-arrestin 2-dependent manner; thereafter, MLKL (mixed lineage kinase domain-like), but not receptor-interacting protein kinase 1 or 3, phosphorylated CB2R at serine 352 and promoted CB2R degradation by ubiquitin modification. Cardiac re-expression of CB2R rescued diabetes-induced cardiomyocyte necroptosis and heart dysfunction, whereas cardiac knockout of Bach2 diminished CB2R-mediated beneficial effects. In human diabetic hearts, both CB2R and BACH2 were negatively associated with diabetes-induced myocardial injuries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; CB2R transcriptionally repressed necroptosis through interaction with BACH2; in turn, MLKL formed a negative feedback to phosphorylate CB2R. Our study provides the integrative view of a novel molecular mechanism loop for regulation of necroptosis centered by CB2R, which represents a promising alternative strategy for controlling diabetic heart dysfunction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Molecular basis for DNA recognition by the maternal pioneer transcription factor FoxH1</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36435807/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36435807/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Forkhead box H1 (FoxH1) is an essential maternal pioneer factor during embryonic development that binds to specific GG/GT-containing DNA target sequences. Here we have determined high-resolution structures of three FoxH1 proteins (from human, frog and fish species) and four DNAs to clarify the way in which FoxH1 binds to these sites. We found that the protein-DNA interactions extend to both the minor and major DNA grooves and are thus almost twice as extensive as those of other FOX family members. Moreover, we identified two specific amino acid changes in FoxH1 that allowed the recognition of GG/GT motifs. Consistent with the pioneer factor activity of FoxH1, we found that its affinity for nucleosomal DNA is even higher than for linear DNA fragments. The structures reported herein illustrate how FoxH1 binding to distinct DNA sites provides specificity and avoids cross-regulation by other FOX proteins that also operate during the maternal-zygotic transition and select canonical forkhead sites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SENP1 prevents steatohepatitis by suppressing RIPK1-driven apoptosis and inflammation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36414671/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36414671/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Activation of RIPK1-driven cell death and inflammation play important roles in the progression of nonalcoholic steatohepatitis (NASH). However, the mechanism underlying RIPK1 activation in NASH remains unclear. Here we identified SENP1, a SUMO-specific protease, as a key endogenous inhibitor of RIPK1. SENP1 is progressively reduced in proportion to NASH severity in patients. Hepatocyte-specific SENP1-knockout mice develop spontaneous NASH-related phenotypes in a RIPK1 kinase-dependent manner. We demonstrate that SENP1 deficiency sensitizes cells to RIPK1 kinase-dependent apoptosis by promoting RIPK1 activation following TNFα stimulation. Mechanistically, SENP1 deSUMOylates RIPK1 in TNF-R1 signaling complex (TNF-RSC), keeping RIPK1 in check. Loss of SENP1 leads to SUMOylation of RIPK1, which re-orchestrates TNF-RSC and modulates the ubiquitination patterns and activity of RIPK1. Notably, genetic inhibition of RIPK1 effectively reverses disease progression in hepatocyte-specific SENP1-knockout male mice with high-fat-diet-induced nonalcoholic fatty liver. We propose that deSUMOylation of RIPK1 by SENP1 provides a pathophysiologically relevant cell death-restricting checkpoint that modulates RIPK1 activation in the pathogenesis of nonalcoholic steatohepatitis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ferroptosis of tumour neutrophils causes immune suppression in cancer</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36385526/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36385526/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ferroptosis is a non-apoptotic form of regulated cell death that is triggered by the discoordination of regulatory redox mechanisms culminating in massive peroxidation of polyunsaturated phospholipids. Ferroptosis inducers have shown considerable effectiveness in killing tumour cells in vitro, yet there has been no obvious success in experimental animal models, with the notable exception of immunodeficient mice. This suggests that the effect of ferroptosis on immune cells remains poorly understood. Pathologically activated neutrophils (PMNs), termed myeloid-derived suppressor cells (PMN-MDSCs), are major negative regulators of anti-tumour immunity. Here we found that PMN-MDSCs in the tumour microenvironment spontaneously die by ferroptosis. Although decreasing the presence of PMN-MDSCs, ferroptosis induces the release of oxygenated lipids and limits the activity of human and mouse T cells. In immunocompetent mice, genetic and pharmacological inhibition of ferroptosis abrogates suppressive activity of PMN-MDSCs, reduces tumour progression and synergizes with immune checkpoint blockade to suppress the tumour growth. By contrast, induction of ferroptosis in immunocompetent mice promotes tumour growth. Thus, ferroptosis is a unique and targetable immunosuppressive mechanism of PMN-MDSCs in the tumour microenvironment that can be pharmacologically modulated to limit tumour progression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exosome modification to better alleviates endoplasmic reticulum stress induced chondrocyte apoptosis and osteoarthritis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36370754/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36370754/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Osteoarthritis (OA) is characterized by cartilage matrix degeneration and chondrocyte apoptosis. Prolonged endoplasmic reticulum (ER) stress participates in chondrocyte apoptosis and cartilage degeneration in OA progression. miR-486-5p could suppress the apoptosis of nucleus pulposus cells and cardiomyocyte, yet whether miR-486-5p modified exosomes could modulate ER stress and apoptosis of chondrocytes remain unknown. We validated the increased inflammation and ER stress in OA synovium and cartilage, and the inhibition of ER stress could attenuate the IL-1β induced chondrocyte apoptosis. Administration of exogenous miR-486-5p could inhibit the ER stress, alleviate chondrocytes apoptosis and promote matrix regeneration. In comparison with direct administration of miR-486-5p and miR-486-5p overexpressing ADSCs, miR-486-5p modified exosomes indicated a better effect in modulating chondrocyte homeostasis. MiR-486-5p containing exosomes could also regulate macrophage polarization. Our IVIS imaging data validated that intraarticular injection of miR-486-5p containing exosomes could sustain for at least 7 days. MiR-486-5p containing exosomes showed a better effect on alleviating rats OA compared with direct administration of miR-486-5p and miR-486-5p overexpressing ADSCs. Our data demonstrated that miR-486-5p modified exosomes have a better effect on alleviating chondrocyte apoptosis and osteoarthritis. This study provides evidence of this efficient strategy of exosomal miRNA delivery and the miRNA-based therapy for OA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ATG9A and ATG2A form a heteromeric complex essential for autophagosome formation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36347259/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36347259/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ATG9A and ATG2A form a heterotetrameric complex&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;HDX and CXL-MS reveal intricate interaction interface between ATG9A and ATG2A&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Disrupting the ATG9A-ATG2A complex disrupts autophagic flux&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lipid transfer tunnel of ATG2A binds proximal to the perpendicular branch of ATG9A&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ATG9A and ATG2A are essential core members of the autophagy machinery. ATG9A is a lipid scramblase that allows equilibration of lipids across a membrane bilayer, whereas ATG2A facilitates lipid flow between tethered membranes. Although both have been functionally linked during the formation of autophagosomes, the molecular details and consequences of their interaction remain unclear. By combining data from peptide arrays, crosslinking, and hydrogen-deuterium exchange mass spectrometry together with cryoelectron microscopy, we propose a molecular model of the ATG9A-2A complex. Using this integrative structure modeling approach, we identify several interfaces mediating ATG9A-2A interaction that would allow a direct transfer of lipids from ATG2A into the lipid-binding perpendicular branch of ATG9A. Mutational analyses combined with functional activity assays demonstrate their importance for autophagy, thereby shedding light on this protein complex at the heart of autophagy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Activation of Pancreatic Acinar FXR Protects against Pancreatitis via Osgin1-Mediated Restoration of Efficient Autophagy</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36405253/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36405253/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pancreatitis is the leading cause of hospitalization in gastroenterology, and no medications are available for treating this disease in current clinical practice. FXR plays an anti-inflammatory role in diverse inflammatory diseases, while its function in pancreatitis remains unknown. In this study, we initially observed a marked increase of nuclear FXR in pancreatic tissues of human patients with pancreatitis. Deleting the FXR in pancreatic acinar cells (FXR&lt;sup&gt;acinarΔ/Δ &lt;/sup&gt;) led to more severe pancreatitis in mouse models of caerulein-induced acute and chronic pancreatitis, while the FXR agonist GW4064 significantly attenuated pancreatitis in caerulein or arginine-induced acute pancreatitis and caerulein-induced chronic pancreatitis. FXR deletion impaired the viability and stress responses of pancreatic exocrine organoids (PEOs) in vitro. Utilizing RNA-seq and ChIP-seq of PEOs, we identified &lt;em&gt;Osgin1&lt;/em&gt; as a direct target of FXR in the exocrine pancreas, which was also increasingly expressed in human pancreatitis tissues compared to normal pancreatic tissues. Pancreatic knockdown of &lt;em&gt;Osgin1&lt;/em&gt; by AAV-pan abolished the therapeutic effects of FXR activation on pancreatitis, whereas pancreatic overexpression of &lt;em&gt;Osgin1&lt;/em&gt; effectively alleviated caerulein-induced pancreatitis. Mechanistically, we found that the FXR-OSGIN1 axis stimulated autophagic flux in the pancreatic tissues and cell lines, which was considered as the intrinsic mechanisms through which FXR-OSGIN1 protecting against pancreatitis. Our results highlight the protective role of the FXR-OSGIN1 axis in pancreatitis and provided a new target for the treatment of this disease.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FerrDb V2: update of the manually curated database of ferroptosis regulators and ferroptosis-disease associations</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36305834/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36305834/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.zhounan.org/ferrdb/current/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;FerrDb&lt;/a&gt; is the world&amp;rsquo;s first database that dedicates to ferroptosis regulators and ferroptosis-disease associations. There are two secondary categories of ferroptosis regulators: (1) genes and (2) substances. Gene regulators include driver, suppressor, marker, and unclassified regulator. Substances cover a wide range of chemical entities, including pure substances (e.g., iron, erastin) and mixtures (e.g., herbal extracts). Substance regulators include inducers and inhibitors. On the basis of this philosophy, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.zhounan.org/ferrdb/current/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;FerrDb&lt;/a&gt; consists of seven independent curated data sets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!---more---&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ferroptosis is a mode of regulated cell death characterized by iron-dependent accumulation of lipid peroxidation. It is closely linked to the pathophysiological processes in many diseases. Since our publication of the first ferroptosis database in 2020 (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.zhounan.org/ferrdb/current/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;FerrDb&lt;/a&gt; V1), many new findings have been published. To keep up with the rapid progress in ferroptosis research and to provide timely and high-quality data, here we present the successor, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.zhounan.org/ferrdb/current/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;FerrDb&lt;/a&gt; V2. It contains 1001 ferroptosis regulators and 143 ferroptosis-disease associations manually curated from 3288 articles. Specifically, there are 621 gene regulators, of which 264 are drivers, 238 are suppressors, 9 are markers, and 110 are unclassified genes; and there are 380 substance regulators, with 201 inducers and 179 inhibitors. Compared to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.zhounan.org/ferrdb/current/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;FerrDb&lt;/a&gt; V1, curated articles increase by &amp;gt;300%, ferroptosis regulators increase by 175%, and ferroptosis-disease associations increase by 50.5%. Circular RNA and pseudogene are novel regulators in &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.zhounan.org/ferrdb/current/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;FerrDb&lt;/a&gt; V2, and the percentage of non-coding RNA increases from 7.3% to 13.6%. External gene-related data were integrated, enabling thought-provoking and gene-oriented analysis in FerrDb V2. In conclusion, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.zhounan.org/ferrdb/current/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;FerrDb&lt;/a&gt; V2 will help to acquire deeper insights into ferroptosis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Novel Protein Encoded by Exosomal CircATG4B Induces Oxaliplatin Resistance in Colorectal Cancer by Promoting Autophagy</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36285810/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36285810/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oxaliplatin is commonly used in chemotherapeutic regimens for colorectal cancer (CRC) after surgical resection. However, acquired chemoresistance seriously affects the curative effect in CRC patients, and the mechanism is still unclear. Here, a circular RNA, circATG4B is identified, which plays an important role in oxaliplatin resistance in CRC. circATG4B expression is found to be increased in exosomes secreted by oxaliplatin-resistant CRC cells. In addition, the results suggest that circATG4B induces oxaliplatin resistance by promoting autophagy. Further in vivo and in vitro studies indicate that the effect of circATG4B is attributed to its potential to encode a novel protein, circATG4B-222aa. Next, circATG4B-222aa is found to function as a decoy to competitively interact with TMED10 and prevent TMED10 from binding to ATG4B, which leads to increased autophagy followed by induction of chemoresistance. Therefore, this study reveals that exosomal circATG4B participates in the decreased chemosensitivity of CRC cells, providing a new rationale for a potential therapeutic target for oxaliplatin resistance in CRC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bclaf1 regulates c-FLIP expression and protects cells from TNF-induced apoptosis and tissue injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34693625/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34693625/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TNF stimulation generates pro-survival signals through activation of NF-κB that restrict the build-in death signaling triggered by TNF. The competition between TNF-induced survival and death signals ultimately determines the fate of a cell. Here, we report the identification of Bclaf1 as a novel component of the anti-apoptotic program of TNF. Bclaf1 depletion in multiple cells sensitizes cells to TNF-induced apoptosis but not to necroptosis. Bclaf1 exerts its anti-apoptotic function by promoting the transcription of CFLAR, a caspase 8 antagonist, downstream of NF-κB activation. Bclaf1 binds to the p50 subunit of NF-κB, which is required for Bclaf1 to stimulate CFLAR transcription. Finally, in Bclaf1 siRNA administered mice, TNF-induced small intestine injury is much more severe than in control mice with aggravated signs of apoptosis and pyroptosis. These results suggest Bclaf1 is a key regulator in TNF-induced apoptosis, both in vitro and in vivo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Protein phosphatase 1 regulates phosphorylation of gasdermin D and pyroptosis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36205355/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36205355/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We report that phosphorylation of gasdermin D (GSDMD)-NT, cleaved by inflammatory caspases, could inhibit pyroptosis. Phosphatase 1 (PP1) is responsible for the regulation of GSDMD phosphorylation and the capacity of GSDMD to induce cell death. Our findings reveal a critical regulatory mechanism as it provides insight into pyroptosis processes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intercellular transfer of activated STING triggered by RAB22A-mediated non-canonical autophagy promotes antitumor immunity</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36280710/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36280710/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;STING, an endoplasmic reticulum (ER) transmembrane protein, mediates innate immune activation upon cGAMP stimulation and is degraded through autophagy. Here, we report that activated STING could be transferred between cells to promote antitumor immunity, a process triggered by RAB22A-mediated non-canonical autophagy. Mechanistically, RAB22A engages PI4K2A to generate PI4P that recruits the Atg12-Atg5-Atg16L1 complex, inducing the formation of ER-derived RAB22A-mediated non-canonical autophagosome, in which STING activated by agonists or chemoradiotherapy is packaged. This RAB22A-induced autophagosome fuses with RAB22A-positive early endosome, generating a new organelle that we name Rafeesome (RAB22A-mediated non-canonical autophagosome fused with early endosome). Meanwhile, RAB22A inactivates RAB7 to suppress the fusion of Rafeesome with lysosome, thereby enabling the secretion of the inner vesicle of the autophagosome bearing activated STING as a new type of extracellular vesicle that we define as R-EV (RAB22A-induced extracellular vesicle). Activated STING-containing R-EVs induce IFNβ release from recipient cells to the tumor microenvironment, promoting antitumor immunity. Consistently, RAB22A enhances the antitumor effect of the STING agonist diABZI in mice, and a high RAB22A level predicts good survival in nasopharyngeal cancer patients treated with chemoradiotherapy. Our findings reveal that Rafeesome regulates the intercellular transfer of activated STING to trigger and spread antitumor immunity, and that the inner vesicle of non-canonical autophagosome originated from ER is secreted as R-EV, providing a new perspective for understanding the intercellular communication of organelle membrane proteins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A bacterial phospholipid phosphatase inhibits host pyroptosis by hijacking ubiquitin</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36227980/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36227980/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Pyroptosis is a proinflammatory form of programmed cell death adopted by mammalian hosts to control infections, but how pathogens evade this immune response remains largely unexplored. Chai et al. found that PtpB, a known protein phosphatase secreted by &lt;em&gt;Mycobacterium tuberculosis&lt;/em&gt;, acts as a phospholipid phosphatase that dephosphorylates host plasma membrane phosphoinositides upon activation by ubiquitin to inhibit pyroptosis. These findings reveal a delicate strategy by which pathogens suppress pyroptosis by altering host membrane composition, and provide a potential tuberculosis treatment by targeting the PtpB-ubiquitin interacting interface.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The inflammasome-mediated cleavage of gasdermin D (GSDMD) causes pyroptosis and inflammatory cytokine release to control pathogen infection, but how pathogens evade this immune response remains largely unexplored. Here we identify the known protein phosphatase PtpB from Mycobacterium tuberculosis as a phospholipid phosphatase inhibiting the host inflammasome-pyroptosis pathway. Mechanistically, PtpB dephosphorylated phosphatidylinositol-4-monophosphate and phosphatidylinositol-(4,5)-bisphosphate in host cell membrane, thus disrupting the membrane localization of the cleaved GSDMD to inhibit cytokine release and pyroptosis of macrophages. Notably, this phosphatase activity requires PtpB binding to ubiquitin. Disrupting phospholipid phosphatase activity or the ubiquitin-interacting motif of PtpB enhanced host GSDMD-dependent immune responses and reduced intracellular pathogen survival. Thus, pathogens inhibit pyroptosis and counteract host immunity by altering host membrane composition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Introduction&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pyroptosis is a proinflammatory form of programmed cell death characterized by membrane pore formation that allows the release of intracellular inflammatory mediators, a process that is elicited by the inflammasome-mediated cleavage and activation of gasdermin D (GSDMD). Growing evidence supports a critical role for pyroptosis in the control of infections by mammalian hosts, but how pathogens evade this immune response remains largely unexplored.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rationale&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Mycobacterium tuberculosis&lt;/em&gt; (Mtb), an ancient pathogen that causes tuberculosis (TB), has developed numerous intracellular survival strategies to evade host immunity and to drive the occurrence and development of TB. One notable feature evolved by Mtb is a set of eukaryotic-like effectors, but their host targets and regulatory roles in pathogen–host interactions remain largely unclear. In this study, we sought to identify the key pathogenic regulators of inflammasome-pyroptosis pathways from Mtb eukaryotic-like effectors, information that could improve our understanding of TB pathogenesis and provide potential targets for novel anti-TB treatment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We examined the whole genome of Mtb to predict its secreted eukaryotic-like proteins possessing eukaryotic-like motifs or domains that might target host factors directly. These Mtb effector proteins were then subjected to further experimental analyses using an inflammasome reconstitution system for screening inhibitors of inflammasome-pyroptosis pathways. Out of 201 predicted Mtb-secreted eukaryotic proteins, six Mtb proteins (Rv0153c, Rv0561c, Rv0824c, Rv0861c, Rv1515c, and Rv1679) exhibited strong inhibitory effects on both NOD-like receptor protein 3 (NLRP3) and absent in melanoma 2 (AIM2) inflammasome pathways. Among these proteins, PtpB (i.e., Rv0153c) was most abundantly secreted by Mtb during infection. We thus focused on PtpB and further confirmed its inhibitory effect on AIM2 or NLRP3 inflammasome-mediated interleukin-1β (IL-1β) secretion. Subsequent experiments demonstrated that PtpB inhibited gasdermin D (GSDMD)–dependent cytokine release and pyroptosis to promote Mtb intracellular survival in macrophages. Mechanistically, Mtb-secreted PtpB could target and dephosphorylate host plasma membrane phosphatidylinositol-4-monophosphate (PI4P) and phosphatidylinositol-(4,5)-bisphosphate [PI(4,5)P2] to inhibit the membrane localization of the N-terminal cleavage fragment of GSDMD (GSDMD-N), thus preventing GSDMD-mediated immune responses. This phosphoinositide phosphatase activity requires binding of PtpB to ubiquitin. Accordingly, disrupting phospholipid phosphatase activity or the unusual ubiquitin-interacting motif (UIM)–like domain of PtpB markedly enhanced host innate immune responses and reduced intracellular pathogen survival in mice in a GSDMD-dependent manner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We demonstrate that GSDMD-mediated pyroptosis and inflammatory cytokine release play a critical role in host anti-infection immunity, which is counteracted by Mtb effector protein PtpB. Our data reveal a role of the pathogen-derived phospholipid phosphatase in the regulation of GSDMD-dependent pyroptosis and cytokine releases, extending our understanding of the elaborate regulatory mechanism of cellular inflammasome-pyroptosis signaling pathways during pathogen infection. The present study also presents a strategy by which pathogens hijack ubiquitin to inhibit host pyroptosis by altering the phospholipid composition of the host membrane. Our discovery of the PtpB UIM-like domain, which is not homologous to any human protein, may provide potential selectivity for the development of anti-TB therapies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Calcium transients on the ER surface trigger liquid-liquid phase separation of FIP200 to specify autophagosome initiation sites</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36198318/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36198318/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The mechanism that initiates autophagosome formation on the ER in multicellular organisms is elusive. Here, we showed that autophagy stimuli trigger Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt; transients on the outer surface of the ER membrane, whose amplitude, frequency, and duration are controlled by the metazoan-specific ER transmembrane autophagy protein EPG-4/EI24. Persistent Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt; transients/oscillations on the cytosolic ER surface in EI24-depleted cells cause accumulation of FIP200 autophagosome initiation complexes on the ER. This defect is suppressed by attenuating ER Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt; transients. Multi-modal SIM analysis revealed that Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt; transients on the ER trigger the formation of dynamic and fusion-prone liquid-like FIP200 puncta. Starvation-induced Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt; transients on lysosomes also induce FIP200 puncta that further move to the ER. Multiple FIP200 puncta on the ER, whose association depends on the ER proteins VAPA/B and ATL2/3, assemble into autophagosome formation sites. Thus, Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt; transients are crucial for triggering phase separation of FIP200 to specify autophagosome initiation sites in metazoans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Identification and validation of an anoikis-associated gene signature to predict clinical character, stemness, IDH mutation, and immune filtration in glioblastoma</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36091049/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36091049/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Glioblastoma (GBM) is the most prominent and aggressive primary brain tumor in adults. Anoikis is a specific form of programmed cell death that plays a key role in tumor invasion and metastasis. The presence of anti-anoikis factors is associated with tumor aggressiveness and drug resistance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; The non-negative matrix factorization algorithm was used for effective dimension reduction for integrated datasets. Differences in the tumor microenvironment (TME), stemness indices, and clinical characteristics between the two clusters were analyzed. Difference analysis, weighted gene coexpression network analysis (WGCNA), univariate Cox regression, and least absolute shrinkage and selection operator regression were leveraged to screen prognosis-related genes and construct a risk score model. Immunohistochemistry was performed to evaluate the expression of representative genes in clinical specimens. The relationship between the risk score and the TME, stemness, clinical traits, and immunotherapy response was assessed in GBM and pancancer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; Two definite clusters were identified on the basis of anoikis-related gene expression. Patients with GBM assigned to C1 were characterized by shortened overall survival, higher suppressive immune infiltration levels, and lower stemness indices. We further constructed a risk scoring model to quantify the regulatory patterns of anoikis-related genes. The higher risk score group was characterized by a poor prognosis, the infiltration of suppressive immune cells and a differentiated phenotype, whereas the lower risk score group exhibited the opposite effects. In addition, patients in the lower risk score group exhibited a higher frequency of isocitrate dehydrogenase (IDH) mutations and a more sensitive response to immunotherapy. Drug sensitivity analysis was performed, revealing that the higher risk group may benefit more from drugs targeting the PI3K/mTOR signaling pathway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/em&gt; We revealed potential relationships between anoikis-related genes and clinical features, TME, stemness, IDH mutation, and immunotherapy and elucidated their therapeutic value.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UBXD8 mediates mitochondria-associated degradation to restrain apoptosis and mitophagy</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35979733/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35979733/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The hexameric AAA-ATPase valosin-containing protein (VCP) is essential for mitochondrial protein quality control. How VCP is recruited to mammalian mitochondria remains obscure. Here we report that UBXD8, an ER- and lipid droplet-localized VCP adaptor, also localizes to mitochondria and locally recruits VCP. UBXD8 associates with mitochondrial and ER ubiquitin E3 ligases and targets their substrates for degradation. Remarkably, both mitochondria- and ER-localized UBXD8 can degrade mitochondrial and ER substrates in cis and in trans. UBXD8 also associates with the TOM complex but is dispensable for translocation-associated degradation. UBXD8 knockout impairs the degradation of the pro-survival protein Mcl1 but surprisingly sensitizes cells to apoptosis and mitochondrial stresses. UBXD8 knockout also hyperactivates mitophagy. We identify pro-apoptotic BH3-only proteins Noxa, Bik, and Bnip3 as novel UBXD8 substrates and determine that UBXD8 inhibits apoptosis via degrading Noxa and restrains mitophagy via degrading Bnip3. Collectively, our characterizations reveal UBXD8 as the major mitochondrial adaptor of VCP and unveil its role in apoptosis and mitophagy regulation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>KDM6B promotes PARthanatos via suppression of O6-methylguanine DNA methyltransferase repair and sustained checkpoint response</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35648484/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35648484/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Poly(ADP-ribose) polymerase-1 (PARP-1) is a DNA damage sensor and contributes to both DNA repair and cell death processes. However, how PARP-1 signaling is regulated to switch its function from DNA repair to cell death remains largely unknown. Here, we found that PARP-1 plays a central role in alkylating agent-induced PARthanatic cancer cell death. Lysine demethylase 6B (KDM6B) was identified as a key regulator of PARthanatos. Loss of KDM6B protein or its demethylase activity conferred cancer cell resistance to PARthanatic cell death in response to alkylating agents. Mechanistically, KDM6B knockout suppressed methylation at the promoter of O&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;-methylguanine-DNA methyltransferase (MGMT) to enhance MGMT expression and its direct DNA repair function, thereby inhibiting DNA damage-evoked PARP-1 hyperactivation and subsequent cell death. Moreover, KDM6B knockout triggered sustained Chk1 phosphorylation and activated a second XRCC1-dependent repair machinery to fix DNA damage evading from MGMT repair. Inhibition of MGMT or checkpoint response re-sensitized KDM6B deficient cells to PARthanatos induced by alkylating agents. These findings provide new molecular insights into epigenetic regulation of PARP-1 signaling mediating DNA repair or cell death and identify KDM6B as a biomarker for prediction of cancer cell vulnerability to alkylating agent treatment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CircCEMIP promotes anoikis-resistance by enhancing protective autophagy in prostate cancer cells</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35655258/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35655258/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Circular RNAs (circRNAs) are essential participants in the development and progression of various malignant tumors. Previous studies have shown that cell migration-inducing protein (CEMIP) accelerates prostate cancer (PCa) anoikis resistance (AR) by activating autophagy. This study focused on the effect of circCEMIP on PCa metastasis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; This study gradually revealed the role of circ_0004585 in PCa anoikis resistance via quantitative real-time PCR (qRT-PCR) analysis, western blotting, pull-down assays, and dual fluorescence reporter assays.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; Functionally, circ_0004585 promoted PCa cells invasion and metastasis both in vitro and in vivo. Mechanistically, circ_0004585 directly interacted with miR-1248 to upregulate target gene expression. Furthermore, target prediction and dual-luciferase reporter assays identified transmembrane 9 superfamily member 4 (TM9SF4) as a potential miR-1248 target. Pathway analysis revealed that TM9SF4 activated autophagy to promote PCa cells anoikis resistance via mTOR phosphorylation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; These results demonstrated that circ_0004585 played an oncogenic role during PCa invasion and metastasis by targeting the miR-1248/TM9SF4 axis while providing new insight into therapeutic strategy development for metastatic PCa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Activated Drp1 regulates p62-mediated autophagic flux and aggravates inflammation in cerebral ischemia-reperfusion via the ROS-RIP1/RIP3-exosome axis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35624495/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35624495/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Cerebral ischemia-reperfusion injury (CIRI) refers to a secondary brain injury that can occur when the blood supply to the ischemic brain tissue is restored. However, the mechanism underlying such injury remains elusive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; The 150 male C57 mice underwent middle cerebral artery occlusion (MCAO) for 1 h and reperfusion for 24 h, Among them, 50 MCAO mice were further treated with Mitochondrial division inhibitor 1 (Mdivi-1) and 50 MCAO mice were further treated with N-acetylcysteine (NAC). SH-SY5Y cells were cultured in a low-glucose culture medium for 4 h under hypoxic conditions and then transferred to normal conditions for 12 h. Then, cerebral blood flow, mitochondrial structure, mitochondrial DNA (mtDNA) copy number, intracellular and mitochondrial reactive oxygen species (ROS), autophagic flux, aggresome and exosome expression profiles, cardiac tissue structure, mitochondrial length and cristae density, mtDNA and ROS content, as well as the expression of Drp1-Ser616/Drp1, RIP1/RIP3, LC3 II/LC3 I, TNF-α, IL-1β, etc., were detected under normal or Drp1 interference conditions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; The mtDNA content, ROS levels, and Drp1-Ser616/Drp1 were elevated by 2.2, 1.7 and 2.7 times after CIRI (&lt;em&gt;P&lt;/em&gt; &amp;lt; 0.05). However, the high cytoplasmic LC3 II/I ratio and increased aggregation of p62 could be reversed by 44% and 88% by Drp1 short hairpin RNA (shRNA) (&lt;em&gt;P&lt;/em&gt; &amp;lt; 0.05). The low fluorescence intensity of autophagic flux and the increased phosphorylation of RIP3 induced by CIRI could be attenuated by ROS scavenger, NAC (&lt;em&gt;P&lt;/em&gt; &amp;lt; 0.05). RIP1/RIP3 inhibitor Necrostatin-1 (Nec-1) restored 75% to a low LC3 II/LC3 I ratio and enhanced 2 times to a high RFP-LC3 after Drp1 activation (&lt;em&gt;P&lt;/em&gt; &amp;lt; 0.05). In addition, although CIRI-induced ROS production caused no considerable accumulation of autophagosomes (&lt;em&gt;P&lt;/em&gt; &amp;gt; 0.05), it increased the packaging and extracellular secretion of exosomes containing p62 by 4 - 5 times, which could be decreased by Mdivi-1, Drp1 shRNA, and Nec-1 (&lt;em&gt;P&lt;/em&gt; &amp;lt; 0.05). Furthermore, TNF-α and IL-1β increased in CIRI-derived exosomes could increase RIP3 phosphorylation in normal or oxygen-glucose deprivation/reoxygenation (OGD/R) conditions (&lt;em&gt;P&lt;/em&gt; &amp;lt; 0.05).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; CIRI activated Drp1 and accelerated the p62-mediated formation of autophagosomes while inhibiting the transition of autophagosomes to autolysosomes via the RIP1/RIP3 pathway activation. Undegraded autophagosomes were secreted extracellularly in the form of exosomes, leading to inflammatory cascades that further damaged mitochondria, resulting in excessive ROS generation and the blockage of autophagosome degradation, triggering a vicious cycle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Osmotic stress activates RIPK3/MLKL-mediated necroptosis by increasing cytosolic pH through a plasma membrane Na&#43;/H&#43; exchanger</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35580168/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35580168/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Necroptosis is a form of cell death triggered by stimuli such as the tumor necrosis factor family of cytokines, which induce necrotic cell death through the RIPK1-RIPK3-MLKL pathway. We report here that necroptosis is also activated by extracellular osmotic stresses. Unlike the previously identified inducers of necroptosis, osmotic stress stimulated necroptosis through the direct activation of the kinase activity of RIPK3 by an increase in cytosolic pH mediated by the Na&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt;/H&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; exchanger SLC9A1. Knockout, knockdown, or chemical inhibition of SLC9A1 blocked necroptosis induced by osmotic stresses. Moreover, setting intracellular pH at above-physiological values directly activated RIPK3 and necroptosis. The activation of RIPK3 by osmotic stresses did not require its RHIM domain, the protein-interacting domain required for the activation of RIPK3 when cells respond to other previously identified necroptotic stimuli. These results thus delineate a pathway that activates necroptosis in response to osmotic stresses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PAAN/MIF nuclease inhibition prevents neurodegeneration in Parkinson&#39;s disease</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35545089/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35545089/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Parthanatos-associated apoptosis-inducing factor (AIF) nuclease (PAAN), also known as macrophage migration inhibitor factor (MIF), is a member of the PD-D/E(X)K nucleases that acts as a final executioner in parthanatos. PAAN&amp;rsquo;s role in Parkinson&amp;rsquo;s disease (PD) and whether it is amenable to chemical inhibition is not known. Here, we show that neurodegeneration induced by pathologic α-synuclein (α-syn) occurs via PAAN/MIF nuclease activity. Genetic depletion of PAAN/MIF and a mutant lacking nuclease activity prevent the loss of dopaminergic neurons and behavioral deficits in the α-syn preformed fibril (PFF) mouse model of sporadic PD. Compound screening led to the identification of PAANIB-1, a brain-penetrant PAAN/MIF nuclease inhibitor that prevents neurodegeneration induced by α-syn PFF, AAV-α-syn overexpression, or MPTP intoxication in vivo. Our findings could have broad relevance in human pathologies where parthanatos plays a role in the development of cell death inhibitors targeting the druggable PAAN/MIF nuclease.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Z-DNA binding protein 1 promotes heatstroke-induced cell death</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35511979/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35511979/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Heatstroke is a heat stress-induced, life-threatening condition associated with circulatory failure and multiple organ dysfunctions. If global warming continues, heatstroke might become a more prominent cause of mortality worldwide, but its pathogenic mechanism is not well understood. We found that Z-DNA binding protein 1 (ZBP1), a Z-nucleic acid receptor, mediated heatstroke by triggering receptor-interacting protein kinase 3 (RIPK3)-dependent cell death. Heat stress increased the expression of ZBP1 through heat shock transcription factor 1 (HSF1) and activated ZBP1 through a mechanism independent of the nucleic acid sensing action. Deletion of ZBP1, RIPK3, or both mixed lineage kinase domain-like (MLKL) and caspase-8 decreased heat stress-induced circulatory failure, organ injury, and lethality. Thus, ZBP1 appears to have a second function that orchestrates host responses to heat stress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dynamic O-GlcNAcylation coordinates ferritinophagy and mitophagy to activate ferroptosis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35504898/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35504898/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ferroptosis is a regulated iron-dependent cell death characterized by the accumulation of lipid peroxidation. A myriad of facets linking amino acid, lipid, redox, and iron metabolisms were found to drive or to suppress the execution of ferroptosis. However, how the cells decipher the diverse pro-ferroptotic stress to activate ferroptosis remains elusive. Here, we report that protein O-GlcNAcylation, the primary nutrient sensor of glucose flux, orchestrates both ferritinophagy and mitophagy for ferroptosis. Following the treatment of ferroptosis stimuli such as RSL3, a commonly used ferroptosis inducer, there exists a biphasic change of protein O-GlcNAcylation to modulate ferroptosis. Pharmacological or genetic inhibition of O-GlcNAcylation promoted ferritinophagy, resulting in the accumulation of labile iron towards mitochondria. Inhibition of O-GlcNAcylation resulted in mitochondria fragmentation and enhanced mitophagy, providing an additional source of labile iron and rendering the cell more sensitive to ferroptosis. Mechanistically, we found that de-O-GlcNAcylation of the ferritin heavy chain at S179 promoted its interaction with NCOA4, the ferritinophagy receptor, thereby accumulating labile iron for ferroptosis. Our findings reveal a previously uncharacterized link of dynamic O-GlcNAcylation with iron metabolism and decision-making for ferroptosis, thus offering potential therapeutic intervention for fighting disease.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Long noncoding RNA LINC01606 protects colon cancer cells from ferroptotic cell death and promotes stemness by SCD1-Wnt/β-catenin-TFE3 feedback loop signalling</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35485210/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35485210/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Ferroptosis is principally caused by iron catalytic activity and intracellular lipid peroxidation. Long noncoding RNAs (lncRNAs) play crucial roles in tumorigenesis. However, the potential interplay between lncRNA LINC01606 and ferroptosis in colon cancer remains elusive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; The expression level of LNC01606 in colon cancer tissue was detected by quantitative real-time polymerase chain reaction. The functional role of LNC01606 was investigated by gain- and loss-of-function assays both in vitro and in vivo. The LINC01606-SCD1-Wnt/β-catenin-TFE3 axis were screened and validated by DNA/RNA pull down, gas chromatography-mass spectrometry, RNA immunoprecipitation and dual-luciferase reporter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; The expression of lncRNA LINC01606 was frequently upregulated in human colon cancer and strongly associated with a poor prognosis. LINC01606 functioned as an oncogene and promotes colon cancer cell growth, invasion and stemness both in vitro and in vivo. Moreover, LINC01606 protected colon cancer cells from ferroptosis by decreasing the concentration of iron, lipid reactive oxygen species, mitochondrial superoxide and increasing mitochondrial membrane potential. Mechanistically, LINC01606 enhanced the expression of stearoyl-CoA desaturase 1 (SCD1), serving as a competing endogenous RNA to modulate miR-423-5p expression, subsequently activating the canonical Wnt/β-catenin signaling, and transcription factor binding to IGHM enhancer 3 (TFE3) increased LINC01606 transcription after recruitment to the promoter regions of LINC01606. Furthermore, we confirmed that upregulated LINC01606 and Wnt/β-catenin formed a positive feedback regulatory loop, further inhibiting ferroptosis and enhancing stemness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; LINC01606 functions as an oncogene to facilitate tumor cell stemness, proliferation and inhibit ferroptosis and is a promising therapeutic target for colon cancer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Filamentous GLS1 promotes ROS-induced apoptosis upon glutamine deprivation via insufficient asparagine synthesis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35381197/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35381197/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GLS1 orchestrates glutaminolysis and promotes cell proliferation when glutamine is abundant by regenerating TCA cycle intermediates and supporting redox homeostasis. CB-839, an inhibitor of GLS1, is currently under clinical investigation for a variety of cancer types. Here, we show that GLS1 facilitates apoptosis when glutamine is deprived. Mechanistically, the absence of exogenous glutamine sufficiently reduces glutamate levels to convert dimeric GLS1 to a self-assembled, extremely low-Km filamentous polymer. GLS1 filaments possess an enhanced catalytic activity, which further depletes intracellular glutamine. Functionally, filamentous GLS1-dependent glutamine scarcity leads to inadequate synthesis of asparagine and mitogenome-encoded proteins, resulting in ROS-induced apoptosis that can be rescued by asparagine supplementation. Physiologically, we observed GLS1 filaments in solid tumors and validated the tumor-suppressive role of constitutively active, filamentous GLS1 mutants K320A and S482C in xenograft models. Our results change our understanding of GLS1 in cancer metabolism and suggest the therapeutic potential of promoting GLS1 filament formation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CCT2 is an aggrephagy receptor for clearance of solid protein aggregates</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35366418/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35366418/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Protein aggregation is a hallmark of multiple human pathologies. Autophagy selectively degrades protein aggregates via aggrephagy. How selectivity is achieved has been elusive. Here, we identify the chaperonin subunit CCT2 as an autophagy receptor regulating the clearance of aggregation-prone proteins in the cell and the mouse brain. CCT2 associates with aggregation-prone proteins independent of cargo ubiquitination and interacts with autophagosome marker ATG8s through a non-classical VLIR motif. In addition, CCT2 regulates aggrephagy independently of the ubiquitin-binding receptors (P62, NBR1, and TAX1BP1) or chaperone-mediated autophagy. Unlike P62, NBR1, and TAX1BP1, which facilitate the clearance of protein condensates with liquidity, CCT2 specifically promotes the autophagic degradation of protein aggregates with little liquidity (solid aggregates). Furthermore, aggregation-prone protein accumulation induces the functional switch of CCT2 from a chaperone subunit to an autophagy receptor by promoting CCT2 monomer formation, which exposes the VLIR to ATG8s interaction and, therefore, enables the autophagic function.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>m6A mRNA modification maintains colonic epithelial cell homeostasis via NF-κB-mediated antiapoptotic pathway</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35333576/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35333576/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Colonic mucosal barrier dysfunction is one of the major causes of inflammatory bowel disease (IBD). However, the mechanisms underlying mucosal barrier dysfunction are poorly understood. N6-methyladenosine (m6A) mRNA modification is an important modulator of epitranscriptional regulation of gene expression, participating in multiple physiological and pathological processes. However, the function of m6A modification in colonic epithelial cells and stem cells is unknown. Here, we show that m6A modification is essential for maintaining the homeostatic self-renewal in colonic stem cells. Specific deletion of the methyltransferase 14 (Mettl14) gene in mouse colon resulted in colonic stem cell apoptosis, causing mucosal barrier dysfunction and severe colitis. Mechanistically, we revealed that Mettl14 restricted colonic epithelial cell death by regulating the stability of Nfkbia mRNA and modulating the NF-κB pathway. Our results identified a previously unidentified role for m6A modification in colonic epithelial cells and stem cells, suggesting that m6A modification may be a potential therapeutic target for IBD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Copper induces cell death by targeting lipoylated TCA cycle proteins</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35298263/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35298263/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Erratum in:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.abq4855&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Copper induces cell death by targeting lipoylated TCA cycle proteins&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Copper is an essential cofactor for all organisms, and yet it becomes toxic if concentrations exceed a threshold maintained by evolutionarily conserved homeostatic mechanisms. How excess copper induces cell death, however, is unknown. Here, we show in human cells that copper-dependent, regulated cell death is distinct from known death mechanisms and is dependent on mitochondrial respiration. We show that copper-dependent death occurs by means of direct binding of copper to lipoylated components of the tricarboxylic acid (TCA) cycle. This results in lipoylated protein aggregation and subsequent iron-sulfur cluster protein loss, which leads to proteotoxic stress and ultimately cell death. These findings may explain the need for ancient copper homeostatic mechanisms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Copper induces cell death&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cell death is an essential, finely tuned process that is critical for the removal of damaged and superfluous cells. Multiple forms of programmed and nonprogrammed cell death have been identified, including apoptosis, ferroptosis, and necroptosis. Tsvetkov et al. investigated whether abnormal copper ion elevations may sensitize cells toward a previously unidentified death pathway (see the Perspective by Kahlson and Dixon). By performing CRISPR/Cas9 screens, several genes were identified that could protect against copper-induced cell killing. Using genetically modified cells and a mouse model of a copper overload disorder, the researchers report that excess copper promotes the aggregation of lipoylated proteins and links mitochondrial metabolism to copper-dependent death.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ubiquitin ligase E3 HUWE1/MULE targets transferrin receptor for degradation and suppresses ferroptosis in acute liver injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35260822/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35260822/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hepatic ischemia followed by reperfusion (I/R), a major clinical problem during liver surgical procedures, can induce liver injury with severe cell death including ferroptosis which is characterized by iron-dependent accumulation of lipid peroxidation. The HECT domain-containing ubiquitin E3 ligase HUWE1 (also known as MULE) was initially shown to promote apoptosis. However, our preliminary study demonstrates that high expression of HUWE1 in the liver donors corelates with less injury and better hepatic function after liver transplantation in patients. Thus, we investigate the role of HUWE1 in acute liver injury, and identify HUWE1 as a negative ferroptosis modulator through transferrin receptor 1(TfR1). Deficiency of Huwe1 in mice hepatocytes (HKO) exacerbated I/R and CCl4-induced liver injury with more ferroptosis occurrence. Moreover, Suppression of Huwe1 remarkably enhances cellular sensitivity to ferroptosis in primary hepatocytes and mouse embryonic fibroblasts. Mechanistically, HUWE1 specifically targets TfR1 for ubiquitination and proteasomal degradation, thereby regulates iron metabolism. Importantly, chemical and genetic inhibition of TfR1 dramatically diminishes the ferroptotic cell death in Huwe1 KO cells and Huwe1 HKO mice. Therefore, HUWE1 is a potential protective factor to antagonize both aberrant iron accumulation and ferroptosis thereby mitigating acute liver injury. These findings may provide clinical implications for patients with the high-expression Huwe1 alleles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ferroptotic stress promotes macrophages against intracellular bacteria</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35265210/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35265210/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rational:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Intracellular bacterial survival is a major factor causing chronic or recurrent infection, leading to the failure of both host defense and/or antibiotic treatment. However, the elimination of intracellular bacteria is challenging as they are protected from antibiotics and host immune attack. Recent studies have indicated that iron helps macrophages against intracellular bacteria, contradictory to traditional &amp;ldquo;nutritional immunity&amp;rdquo;, in which iron is considered a key nutrient for bacterial survival in host cells. However, how iron facilitates intracellular bacterial death has not been fully clarified. In this study, we found that ferroptotic stress can help macrophages suppress intracellular bacteria by reversing the importation of ferrous iron into bacterial vacuoles via ferroportin and thereby inducing in situ ferroptosis-like bacterial death.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A macrophage model of bacterial invasion was established to monitor dynamic changes in ferroptotic hallmarks, including ferrous iron and lipid peroxidation. Ferroptosis inducers and inhibitors were added to the model to evaluate the relationship between ferroptotic stress and intracellular bacterial survival. We then determined the spatiotemporal distributions of ferroportin, ferrous iron, and lipid peroxidation in macrophages and intracellular bacteria. A bacterial infection mouse model was established to evaluate the therapeutic effects of drugs that regulate ferroptotic stress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ferrous iron and lipid peroxidation increased sharply in the early stage of bacterial infection in the macrophages, then decreased to normal levels in the late stage of infection. The addition of ferroptosis inducers (ras-selective lethal small molecule 3, sulfasalazine, and acetaminophen) in macrophages promoted intracellular bacterial suppression. Further studies revealed that ferrous iron could be delivered to the intracellular bacterial compartment via inward ferroportin transportation, where ferrous iron induced ferroptosis-like death of bacteria. In addition, ferroptotic stress declined to normal levels in the late stage of infection by regulating iron-related pathways in the macrophages. Importantly, we found that enhancing ferroptotic stress with a ferroptosis inducer (sulfasalazine) successfully suppressed bacteria in the mouse infection models.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our study suggests that the spatiotemporal response to ferroptosis stress is an efficient pathway for macrophage defense against bacterial invasion, and targeting ferroptosis may achieve therapeutic targets for infectious diseases challenged by intracellular pathogens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Streptococcal pyrogenic exotoxin B cleaves GSDMA and triggers pyroptosis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35110732/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35110732/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Erratum in:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author Correction: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-022-05109-x&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Streptococcal pyrogenic exotoxin B cleaves GSDMA and triggers pyroptosis&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gasdermins, a family of five pore-forming proteins (GSDMA-GSDME) in humans expressed predominantly in the skin, mucosa and immune sentinel cells, are key executioners of inflammatory cell death (pyroptosis), which recruits immune cells to infection sites and promotes protective immunity. Pore formation is triggered by gasdermin cleavage. Although the proteases that activate GSDMB, C, D and E have been identified, how GSDMA-the dominant gasdermin in the skin-is activated, remains unknown. Streptococcus pyogenes, also known as group A Streptococcus (GAS), is a major skin pathogen that causes substantial morbidity and mortality worldwide. Here we show that the GAS cysteine protease SpeB virulence factor triggers keratinocyte pyroptosis by cleaving GSDMA after Gln246, unleashing an active N-terminal fragment that triggers pyroptosis. Gsdma1 genetic deficiency blunts mouse immune responses to GAS, resulting in uncontrolled bacterial dissemination and death. GSDMA acts as both a sensor and substrate of GAS SpeB and as an effector to trigger pyroptosis, adding a simple one-molecule mechanism for host recognition and control of virulence of a dangerous microbial pathogen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Lysosomal Rag-Ragulator Complex Licenses RIPK1 and Caspase-8-mediated Pyroptosis by Yersinia</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35058659/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35058659/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Host cells initiate cell death programs to limit pathogen infection. Inhibition of transforming growth factor-β-activated kinase 1 (TAK1) by pathogenic &lt;em&gt;Yersinia&lt;/em&gt; in macrophages triggers receptor-interacting serine/threonine-protein kinase 1 (RIPK1)-dependent caspase-8 cleavage of gasdermin D (GSDMD) and inflammatory cell death (pyroptosis). A genome-wide clustered regularly interspaced short palindromic repeats (CRISPR) screen to uncover mediators of caspase-8-dependent pyroptosis identified an unexpected role of the lysosomal FLCN-FNIP2-Rag-Ragulator supercomplex, which regulates metabolic signalling and the mechanistic target of rapamycin complex 1 (mTORC1). In response to &lt;em&gt;Yersinia&lt;/em&gt; infection, FADD, RIPK1 and caspase-8 were recruited to Rag-Ragulator, causing RIPK1 phosphorylation and caspase-8 activation. Pyroptosis activation depended on Rag GTPase activity and lysosomal tethering of Rag-Ragulator, but not mTORC1. Thus, the lysosomal metabolic regulator Rag-Ragulator instructs the inflammatory response to &lt;em&gt;Yersinia&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A targetable LIFR-NF-κB-LCN2 axis controls liver tumorigenesis and vulnerability to ferroptosis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34921145/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34921145/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The growing knowledge of ferroptosis has suggested the role and therapeutic potential of ferroptosis in cancer, but has not been translated into effective therapy. Liver cancer, primarily hepatocellular carcinoma (HCC), is highly lethal with limited treatment options. LIFR is frequently downregulated in HCC. Here, by studying hepatocyte-specific and inducible Lifr-knockout mice, we show that loss of Lifr promotes liver tumorigenesis and confers resistance to drug-induced ferroptosis. Mechanistically, loss of LIFR activates NF-κB signaling through SHP1, leading to upregulation of the iron-sequestering cytokine LCN2, which depletes iron and renders insensitivity to ferroptosis inducers. Notably, an LCN2-neutralizing antibody enhances the ferroptosis-inducing and anticancer effects of sorafenib on HCC patient-derived xenograft tumors with low LIFR expression and high LCN2 expression. Thus, anti-LCN2 therapy is a promising way to improve liver cancer treatment by targeting ferroptosis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>XDeathDB: a visualization platform for cell death molecular interactions</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34907160/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34907160/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lots of cell death initiator and effector molecules, signalling pathways and subcellular sites have been identified as key mediators in both cell death processes in cancer. The &lt;a href=&#34;https://pcm2019.shinyapps.io/XDeathDB/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;XDeathDB&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; visualization platform provides a comprehensive cell death and their crosstalk resource for deciphering the signaling network organization of interactions among different cell death modes associated with 1461 cancer types and COVID-19, with an aim to understand the molecular mechanisms of physiological cell death in disease and facilitate systems-oriented novel drug discovery in inducing cell deaths properly. Apoptosis, autosis, efferocytosis, ferroptosis, immunogenic cell death, intrinsic apoptosis, lysosomal cell death, mitotic cell death, mitochondrial permeability transition, necroptosis, parthanatos, and pyroptosis related to 12 cell deaths and their crosstalk can be observed systematically by the platform. Big data for cell death gene-disease associations, gene-cell death pathway associations, pathway-cell death mode associations, and cell death-cell death associations is collected by literature review articles and public database from iRefIndex, STRING, BioGRID, Reactom, Pathway&amp;rsquo;s commons, DisGeNET, DrugBank, and Therapeutic Target Database (TTD). An interactive webtool, &lt;a href=&#34;https://pcm2019.shinyapps.io/XDeathDB/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;XDeathDB&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, is built by web applications with R-Shiny, JavaScript (JS) and Shiny Server Iso. With this platform, users can search specific interactions from vast interdependent networks that occur in the realm of cell death. A multilayer spectral graph clustering method that performs convex layer aggregation to identify crosstalk function among cell death modes for a specific cancer. 147 hallmark genes of cell death could be observed in detail in these networks. These potential druggable targets are displayed systematically and tailoring networks to visualize specified relations is available to fulfil user-specific needs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oxidized Phospholipids Promote NETosis and Arterial Thrombosis in LNK(SH2B3) Deficiency</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34846914/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34846914/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; LNK/SH2B3 inhibits Janus kinase/signal transducer and activator of transcription (JAK/STAT) signaling by hematopoietic cytokine receptors. Genome-wide association studies have shown association of a common single nucleotide polymorphism in &lt;em&gt;LNK&lt;/em&gt; (R262W, T allele) with neutrophilia, thrombocytosis, and coronary artery disease. We have shown that &lt;em&gt;LNK(TT)&lt;/em&gt; reduces LNK function and that LNK-deficient mice display prominent platelet-neutrophil aggregates, accelerated atherosclerosis, and thrombosis. Platelet-neutrophil interactions can promote neutrophil extracellular trap (NET) formation. The goals of this study were to assess the role of NETs in atherosclerosis and thrombosis in mice with hematopoietic &lt;em&gt;Lnk&lt;/em&gt; deficiency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; We bred mice with combined deficiency of &lt;em&gt;Lnk&lt;/em&gt; and the NETosis-essential enzyme PAD4 (peptidyl arginine deiminase 4) and transplanted their bone marrow into &lt;em&gt;Ldlr&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; mice. We evaluated the role of LNK in atherothrombosis in humans and mice bearing a gain of function variant in JAK2 (JAK2&lt;sup&gt;V617F&lt;/sup&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; Lnk-deficient mice displayed accelerated carotid artery thrombosis with prominent NETosis that was completely reversed by PAD4 deficiency. Thrombin-activated &lt;em&gt;Lnk&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; platelets promoted increased NETosis when incubated with &lt;em&gt;Lnk&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; neutrophils compared with wild-type platelets or wild-type neutrophils. This involved increased surface exposure and release of oxidized phospholipids (OxPL) from &lt;em&gt;Lnk&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; platelets, as well as increased priming and response of &lt;em&gt;Lnk&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; neutrophils to OxPL. To counteract the effects of OxPL, we introduced a transgene expressing the single-chain variable fragment of E06 (E06-scFv). E06-scFv reversed accelerated NETosis, atherosclerosis, and thrombosis in Lnk-/- mice. We also showed increased NETosis when human induced pluripotent stem cell-derived &lt;em&gt;LNK(TT)&lt;/em&gt; neutrophils were incubated with &lt;em&gt;LNK(TT)&lt;/em&gt; platelet/megakaryocytes, but not in isogenic &lt;em&gt;LNK(CC)&lt;/em&gt; controls, confirming human relevance. Using data from the UK Biobank, we found that individuals with the JAK2&lt;sup&gt;VF&lt;/sup&gt; mutation only showed increased risk of coronary artery disease when also carrying the LNK R262W allele. Mice with hematopoietic &lt;em&gt;Lnk&lt;sup&gt;+/-&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Jak2&lt;sup&gt;VF&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; clonal hematopoiesis showed accelerated arterial thrombosis but not atherosclerosis compared with &lt;em&gt;Jak2&lt;sup&gt;VF&lt;/sup&gt;Lnk&lt;sup&gt;+/+&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; controls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; Hematopoietic &lt;em&gt;Lnk&lt;/em&gt; deficiency promotes NETosis and arterial thrombosis in an OxPL-dependent fashion. LNK(R262W) reduces LNK function in human platelets and neutrophils, promoting NETosis, and increases coronary artery disease risk in humans carrying &lt;em&gt;Jak2&lt;sup&gt;VF&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; mutations. Therapies targeting OxPL may be beneficial for coronary artery disease in genetically defined human populations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RBMS1 regulates lung cancer ferroptosis through translational control of SLC7A11</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34609966/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34609966/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ferroptosis, an iron-dependent nonapoptotic cell death, is a highly regulated tumor suppressing process. However, functions and mechanisms of RNA-binding proteins in regulation of evasion of ferroptosis during lung cancer progression are still largely unknown. Here, we report that the RNA-binding protein RBMS1 participates in lung cancer development via mediating ferroptosis evasion. Through an shRNA-mediated systematic screen, we discovered that RBMS1 is a key ferroptosis regulator. Clinically, RBMS1 was elevated in lung cancer and its high expression was associated with reduced patient survival. Conversely, depletion of RBMS1 inhibited lung cancer progression both in vivo and in vitro. Mechanistically, RBMS1 interacted with the translation initiation factor eIF3d directly to bridge the 3&amp;rsquo;- and 5&amp;rsquo;-UTR of SLC7A11. RBMS1 ablation inhibited the translation of SLC7A11, reduced SLC7A11-mediated cystine uptake, and promoted ferroptosis. In a drug screen that targeted RBMS1, we further uncovered that nortriptyline hydrochloride decreased the level of RBMS1, thereby promoting ferroptosis. Importantly, RBMS1 depletion or inhibition by nortriptyline hydrochloride sensitized radioresistant lung cancer cells to radiotherapy. Our findings established RBMS1 as a translational regulator of ferroptosis and a prognostic factor with therapeutic potential and clinical value.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NAMPT-derived NAD&#43; fuels PARP1 to promote skin inflammation through parthanatos cell death</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34748530/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34748530/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Several studies have revealed a correlation between chronic inflammation and nicotinamide adenine dinucleotide (NAD+) metabolism, but the precise mechanism involved is unknown. Here, we report that the genetic and pharmacological inhibition of nicotinamide phosphoribosyltransferase (Nampt), the rate-limiting enzyme in the salvage pathway of NAD+ biosynthesis, reduced oxidative stress, inflammation, and keratinocyte DNA damage, hyperproliferation, and cell death in zebrafish models of chronic skin inflammation, while all these effects were reversed by NAD+ supplementation. Similarly, genetic and pharmacological inhibition of poly(ADP-ribose) (PAR) polymerase 1 (Parp1), overexpression of PAR glycohydrolase, inhibition of apoptosis-inducing factor 1, inhibition of NADPH oxidases, and reactive oxygen species (ROS) scavenging all phenocopied the effects of Nampt inhibition. Pharmacological inhibition of NADPH oxidases/NAMPT/PARP/AIFM1 axis decreased the expression of pathology-associated genes in human organotypic 3D skin models of psoriasis. Consistently, an aberrant induction of NAMPT and PARP activity, together with AIFM1 nuclear translocation, was observed in lesional skin from psoriasis patients. In conclusion, hyperactivation of PARP1 in response to ROS-induced DNA damage, fueled by NAMPT-derived NAD+, mediates skin inflammation through parthanatos cell death.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NLRC4 inflammasome-dependent cell death occurs by a complementary series of three death pathways and determines lethality in mice</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34678072/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34678072/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inflammasome is an innate immune defense mechanism, but its overactivation can lead to host death. Here, we show that cell death dictates mouse death caused by NLRC4 inflammasome overactivation. To execute NLRC4-dependent cell death, three death paways complement each other in a specific order: Pyroptosis pathway requiring caspase-1 and GSDMD is the default path; impairment of it initiates ASC-mediated caspase-8–dependent apoptosis; when these two pathways are blocked, caspase-1 triggers intrinsthic apoptotic pathway. Blocking one or two of these death pathways inhibits induction of various cytokines and lipid mediators, but mice still succumb, and only genetic deletions that block all death paths prevent NLRC4-mediated cell death, tissue damage, and mice death. In addition, infection of nonpropagative &lt;em&gt;Salmonella&lt;/em&gt;-caused mice death is attenuated by blocking these death pathways. Thus, to reduce the lethality of infection-related diseases, preventing cell death might be necessary when propagation of infected pathogen was controlled by other means.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shigella evades pyroptosis by arginine ADP-riboxanation of caspase-11</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34671164/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34671164/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mouse caspase-11 and human caspase-4 and caspase-5 recognize cytosolic lipopolysaccharide (LPS) to induce pyroptosis by cleaving the pore-forming protein GSDMD. This non-canonical inflammasome defends against Gram-negative bacteria. Shigella flexneri, which causes bacillary dysentery, lives freely within the host cytosol where these caspases reside. However, the role of caspase-11-mediated pyroptosis in S. flexneri infection is unknown. Here we show that caspase-11 did not protect mice from S. flexneri infection, in contrast to infection with another cytosolic bacterium, Burkholderia thailandensis. S. flexneri evaded pyroptosis mediated by caspase-11 or caspase 4 (hereafter referred to as caspase-11/4) using a type III secretion system (T3SS) effector, OspC3. OspC3, but not its paralogues OspC1 and 2, covalently modified caspase-11/4; although it used the NAD&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; donor, this modification was not ADP-ribosylation. Biochemical dissections uncovered an ADP-riboxanation modification on Arg314 and Arg310 in caspase-4 and caspase-11, respectively. The enzymatic activity was shared by OspC1 and 2, whose ankyrin-repeat domains, unlike that of OspC3, could not recognize caspase-11/4. ADP-riboxanation of the arginine blocked autoprocessing of caspase-4/11 as well as their recognition and cleavage of GSDMD. ADP-riboxanation of caspase-11 paralysed pyroptosis-mediated defence in Shigella-infected mice and mutation of ospC3 stimulated caspase-11- and GSDMD-dependent anti-Shigella humoral immunity, generating a vaccine-like protective effect. Our study establishes ADP-riboxanation of arginine as a bacterial virulence mechanism that prevents LPS-induced pyroptosis.Up to 40% of patients with inflammatory bowel disease present with psychosocial disturbances. We previously identified a gut vascular barrier that controls the dissemination of bacteria from the intestine to the liver. Here, we describe a vascular barrier in the brain choroid plexus (PVB) that is modulated in response to intestinal inflammation through bacteria-derived lipopolysaccharide. The inflammatory response induces PVB closure after gut vascular barrier opening by the up-regulation of the wingless-type, catenin-beta 1 (Wnt/β-catenin) signaling pathway, rendering it inaccessible to large molecules. In a model of genetically driven closure of choroid plexus endothelial cells, we observed a deficit in short-term memory and anxiety-like behavior, suggesting that PVB closure may correlate with mental deficits. Inflammatory bowel disease–related mental symptoms may thus be the consequence of a deregulated gut–brain vascular axis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Control of gasdermin D oligomerization and pyroptosis by the Ragulator-Rag-mTORC1 pathway</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34289345/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34289345/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The process of pyroptosis is mediated by inflammasomes and a downstream effector known as gasdermin D (GSDMD). Upon cleavage by inflammasome-associated caspases, the N-terminal domain of GSDMD forms membrane pores that promote cytolysis. Numerous proteins promote GSDMD cleavage, but none are known to be required for pore formation after GSDMD cleavage. Herein, we report a forward genetic screen that identified the Ragulator-Rag complex as being necessary for GSDMD pore formation and pyroptosis in macrophages. Mechanistic analysis revealed that Ragulator-Rag is not required for GSDMD cleavage upon inflammasome activation but rather promotes GSDMD oligomerization in the plasma membrane. Defects in GSDMD oligomerization and pore formation can be rescued by mitochondrial poisons that stimulate reactive oxygen species (ROS) production, and ROS modulation impacts the ability of inflammasome pathways to promote pore formation downstream of GSDMD cleavage. These findings reveal an unexpected link between key regulators of immunity (inflammasome-GSDMD) and metabolism (Ragulator-Rag).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Metformin induces Ferroptosis by inhibiting UFMylation of SLC7A11 in breast cancer</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34162423/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34162423/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ferroptosis is a newly defined form of regulated cell death characterized by the iron-dependent accumulation of lipid peroxidation and is involved in various pathophysiological conditions, including cancer. Targeting ferroptosis is considered to be a novel anti-cancer strategy. The identification of FDA-approved drugs as ferroptosis inducers is proposed to be a new promising approach for cancer treatment. Despite a growing body of evidence indicating the potential efficacy of the anti-diabetic metformin as an anti-cancer agent, the exact mechanism underlying this efficacy has not yet been fully elucidated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The UFMylation of SLC7A11 is detected by immunoprecipitation and the expression of UFM1 and SLC7A11 in tumor tissues was detected by immunohistochemical staining. The level of ferroptosis is determined by the level of free iron, total/lipid Ros and GSH in the cells and the morphological changes of mitochondria are observed by transmission electron microscope. The mechanism in vivo was verified by in situ implantation tumor model in nude mice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Metformin induces ferroptosis in an AMPK-independent manner to suppress tumor growth. Mechanistically, we demonstrate that metformin increases the intracellular Fe2+ and lipid ROS levels. Specifically, metformin reduces the protein stability of SLC7A11, which is a critical ferroptosis regulator, by inhibiting its UFMylation process. Furthermore, metformin combined with sulfasalazine, the system xc− inhibitor, can work in a synergistic manner to induce ferroptosis and inhibit the proliferation of breast cancer cells.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This study is the first to demonstrate that the ability of metformin to induce ferroptosis may be a novel mechanism underlying its anti-cancer effect. In addition, we identified SLC7A11 as a new UFMylation substrate and found that targeting the UFM1/SLC7A11 pathway could be a promising cancer treatment strategy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IL-6 regulates autophagy and chemotherapy resistance by promoting BECN1 phosphorylation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34131122/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34131122/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Extracellular cytokines are enriched in the tumor microenvironment and regulate various important properties of cancers, including autophagy. However, the precise molecular mechanisms underlying the link between autophagy and extracellular cytokines remain to be elucidated. In the present study, we demonstrate that IL-6 activates autophagy through the IL-6/JAK2/BECN1 pathway and promotes chemotherapy resistance in colorectal cancer (CRC). Mechanistically, IL-6 triggers the interaction between JAK2 and BECN1, where JAK2 phosphorylates BECN1 at Y333. We demonstrate that BECN1 Y333 phosphorylation is crucial for BECN1 activation and IL-6-induced autophagy by regulating PI3KC3 complex formation. Furthermore, we investigate BECN1 Y333 phosphorylation as a predictive marker for poor CRC prognosis and chemotherapy resistance. Combination treatment with autophagy inhibitors or pharmacological agents targeting the IL-6/JAK2/BECN1 signaling pathway may represent a potential strategy for CRC cancer therapy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GPR34-mediated sensing of lysophosphatidylserine released by apoptotic neutrophils activates type 3 innate lymphoid cells to mediate tissue repair</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34107271/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34107271/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Neutrophils migrate rapidly to damaged tissue and play critical roles in host defense and tissue homeostasis. Here we investigated the mechanisms whereby neutrophils participate in tissue repair. In an intestinal epithelia injury model, neutrophil depletion exacerbated colitis and associated with reduced interleukin (IL)-22 and limited activation of type 3 innate lymphoid cells (ILC3s). Co-culture with neutrophils activated ILC3s in a manner dependent on neutrophil apoptosis. Metabolomic analyses revealed that lysophosphatidylserine (LysoPS) from apoptotic neutrophils directly stimulated ILC3 activation. ILC3-specific deletion of Gpr34, encoding the LysoPS receptor GPR34, or inhibition of downstream PI3K-AKT or ERK suppressed IL-22 production in response to apoptotic neutrophils. Gpr34&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt; mice exhibited compromised ILC3 activation and tissue repair during colon injury, and neutrophil depletion abrogated these defects. GPR34 deficiency in ILC3s limited IL-22 production and tissue repair in vivo in settings of colon and skin injury. Thus, GPR34 is an ILC3-expressed damage-sensing receptor that triggers tissue repair upon recognition of dying neutrophils.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Genome-wide CRISPRi/a screens in human neurons link lysosomal failure to ferroptosis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34031600/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34031600/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Single-cell transcriptomics provide a systematic map of gene expression in different human cell types. The next challenge is to systematically understand cell-type-specific gene function. The integration of CRISPR-based functional genomics and stem cell technology enables the scalable interrogation of gene function in differentiated human cells. Here we present the first genome-wide CRISPR interference and CRISPR activation screens in human neurons. We uncover pathways controlling neuronal response to chronic oxidative stress, which is implicated in neurodegenerative diseases. Unexpectedly, knockdown of the lysosomal protein prosaposin strongly sensitizes neurons, but not other cell types, to oxidative stress by triggering the formation of lipofuscin, a hallmark of aging, which traps iron, generating reactive oxygen species and triggering ferroptosis. We also determine transcriptomic changes in neurons after perturbation of genes linked to neurodegenerative diseases. To enable the systematic comparison of gene function across different human cell types, we establish a data commons named &lt;a href=&#34;https://crisprbrain.org&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CRISPRbrain&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://crisprbrain.org&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CRISPRbrain&lt;/a&gt; is a data commons organizing results from genetic screens for different phenotypes in different human cell types, by different research groups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The metabolite α-KG induces GSDMC-dependent pyroptosis through death receptor 6-activated caspase-8</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34012073/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34012073/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pyroptosis is a form of regulated cell death mediated by gasdermin family members, among which the function of GSDMC has not been clearly described. Herein, we demonstrate that the metabolite α-ketoglutarate (α-KG) induces pyroptosis through caspase-8-mediated cleavage of GSDMC. Treatment with DM-αKG, a cell-permeable derivative of α-KG, elevates ROS levels, which leads to oxidation of the plasma membrane-localized death receptor DR6. Oxidation of DR6 triggers its endocytosis, and then recruits both pro-caspase-8 and GSDMC to a DR6 receptosome through protein-protein interactions. The DR6 receptosome herein provides a platform for the cleavage of GSDMC by active caspase-8, thereby leading to pyroptosis. Moreover, this α-KG-induced pyroptosis could inhibit tumor growth and metastasis in mouse models. Interestingly, the efficiency of α-KG in inducing pyroptosis relies on an acidic environment in which α-KG is reduced by MDH1 and converted to L-2HG that further boosts ROS levels. Treatment with lactic acid, the end product of glycolysis, builds an improved acidic environment to facilitate more production of L-2HG, which makes the originally pyroptosis-resistant cancer cells more susceptible to α-KG-induced pyroptosis. This study not only illustrates a pyroptotic pathway linked with metabolites but also identifies an unreported principal axis extending from ROS-initiated DR6 endocytosis to caspase-8-mediated cleavage of GSDMC for potential clinical application in tumor therapy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Atlastin 2/3 regulate ER targeting of the ULK1 complex to initiate autophagy</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33988678/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33988678/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dynamic targeting of the ULK1 complex to the ER is crucial for initiating autophagosome formation and for subsequent formation of ER-isolation membrane (IM; autophagosomal precursor) contact during IM expansion. Little is known about how the ULK1 complex, which comprises FIP200, ULK1, ATG13, and ATG101 and does not exist as a constitutively coassembled complex, is recruited and stabilized on the ER. Here, we demonstrate that the ER-localized transmembrane proteins Atlastin 2 and 3 (ATL2/3) contribute to recruitment and stabilization of ULK1 and ATG101 at the FIP200-ATG13-specified autophagosome formation sites on the ER. In ATL2/3 KO cells, formation of FIP200 and ATG13 puncta is unaffected, while targeting of ULK1 and ATG101 is severely impaired. Consequently, IM initiation is compromised and slowed. ATL2/3 directly interact with ULK1 and ATG13 and facilitate the ATG13-mediated recruitment/stabilization of ULK1 and ATG101. ATL2/3 also participate in forming ER-IM tethering complexes. Our study provides insights into the dynamic assembly of the ULK1 complex on the ER for autophagosome formation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DHODH-mediated ferroptosis defence is a targetable vulnerability in cancer</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33981038/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33981038/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ferroptosis, a form of regulated cell death that is induced by excessive lipid peroxidation, is a key tumour suppression mechanism. Glutathione peroxidase 4 (GPX4) and ferroptosis suppressor protein 1 (FSP1) constitute two major ferroptosis defence systems. Here we show that treatment of cancer cells with GPX4 inhibitors results in acute depletion of N-carbamoyl-L-aspartate, a pyrimidine biosynthesis intermediate, with concomitant accumulation of uridine. Supplementation with dihydroorotate or orotate-the substrate and product of dihydroorotate dehydrogenase (DHODH)-attenuates or potentiates ferroptosis induced by inhibition of GPX4, respectively, and these effects are particularly pronounced in cancer cells with low expression of GPX4 (GPX4&lt;sup&gt;low&lt;/sup&gt;). Inactivation of DHODH induces extensive mitochondrial lipid peroxidation and ferroptosis in GPX4&lt;sup&gt;low&lt;/sup&gt; cancer cells, and synergizes with ferroptosis inducers to induce these effects in GPX4&lt;sup&gt;high&lt;/sup&gt; cancer cells. Mechanistically, DHODH operates in parallel to mitochondrial GPX4 (but independently of cytosolic GPX4 or FSP1) to inhibit ferroptosis in the mitochondrial inner membrane by reducing ubiquinone to ubiquinol (a radical-trapping antioxidant with anti-ferroptosis activity). The DHODH inhibitor brequinar selectively suppresses GPX4&lt;sup&gt;low&lt;/sup&gt; tumour growth by inducing ferroptosis, whereas combined treatment with brequinar and sulfasalazine, an FDA-approved drug with ferroptosis-inducing activity, synergistically induces ferroptosis and suppresses GPX4&lt;sup&gt;high&lt;/sup&gt; tumour growth. Our results identify a DHODH-mediated ferroptosis defence mechanism in mitochondria and suggest a therapeutic strategy of targeting ferroptosis in cancer treatment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>E3 ligase TRIM25 ubiquitinates RIP3 to inhibit TNF induced cell necrosis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33953350/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33953350/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Receptor interacting protein kinase 3 (RIP3 or RIPK3), the critical executor of cell programmed necrosis, plays essential roles in maintaining immune responses and appropriate tissue homeostasis. Although the E3 ligases CHIP and PELI1 are reported to promote RIP3 degradation, however, how post-translational modification regulates RIP3 activity and stability is poorly understood. Here, we identify the tripartite motif protein TRIM25 as a negative regulator of RIP3-dependent necrosis. TRIM25 directly interacts with RIP3 through its SPRY domain and mediates the K48-linked polyubiquitination of RIP3 on residue K501. The RING domain of TRIM25 facilitates the polyubiquitination chain on RIP3, thereby promoting proteasomal degradation of RIP3. Also, TRIM25 deficiency inhibited the ubiquitination of RIP3, thus promoting TNF-induced cell necrosis. Our current finding reveals the regulating mechanism of polyubiquitination on RIP3, which might be a potential therapeutic target for the intervention of RIP3-dependent necrosis-related diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DDRGK1, a crucial player of ufmylation system, is indispensable for autophagic degradation by regulating lysosomal function</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33879777/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33879777/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DDRGK domain-containing protein 1 (DDRGK1) is an important component of the newly discovered ufmylation system and its absence has been reported to induce extensive endoplasmic reticulum (ER) stress. Recently, emerging evidence indicates that the ufmylation system is correlated with autophagy, although the exact mechanism remains largely unknown. To explore the regulation mechanism of DDRGK1 on autophagy, in this study, we established an immortalized mouse embryonic fibroblast (MEF) cell lines harvested from the DDRGK1F/F:ROSA26-CreERT2 mice, in which DDRGK1 depletion can be induced by 4-hydroxytamoxifen (4-OHT) treatment. Here, we show that DDRGK1 deficiency in MEFs has a dual effect on autophagy, which leads to a significant accumulation of autophagosomes. On one hand, it promotes autophagy induction by impairing mTOR signaling; on the other hand, it blocks autophagy degradation by inhibiting autophagosome-lysosome fusion. This dual effect of DDRGK1 depletion on autophagy ultimately aggravates apoptosis in MEFs. Further studies reveal that DDRGK1 loss is correlated with suppressed lysosomal function, including impaired Cathepsin D (CTSD) expression, aberrant lysosomal pH, and v-ATPase accumulation, which might be a potential trigger for impairment in autophagy process. Hence, this study confirms a crucial role of DDRGK1 as an autophagy regulator by controlling lysosomal function. It may provide a theoretical basis for the treatment strategies of various physiological diseases caused by DDRGK1 deficiency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Structural insight into the molecular mechanism of p53-mediated mitochondrial apoptosis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33863900/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33863900/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tumor suppressor p53 is mutated in approximately half of all human cancers. p53 can induce apoptosis through mitochondrial membrane permeabilization by interacting with and antagonizing the anti-apoptotic proteins BCL-xL and BCL-2. However, the mechanisms by which p53 induces mitochondrial apoptosis remain elusive. Here, we report a 2.5 Å crystal structure of human p53/BCL-xL complex. In this structure, two p53 molecules interact as a homodimer, and bind one BCL-xL molecule to form a ternary complex with a 2:1 stoichiometry. Mutations at the p53 dimer interface or p53/BCL-xL interface disrupt p53/BCL-xL interaction and p53-mediated apoptosis. Overall, our current findings of the bona fide structure of p53/BCL-xL complex reveal the molecular basis of the interaction between p53 and BCL-xL, and provide insight into p53-mediated mitochondrial apoptosis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Proteomics reveals distinct mechanisms regulating the release of cytokines and alarmins during pyroptosis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33691121/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33691121/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A major pathway for proinflammatory protein release by macrophages is inflammasome-mediated pyroptotic cell death. As conventional secretion, unconventional secretion, and cell death are executed simultaneously, however, the cellular mechanisms regulating this complex paracrine program remain incompletely understood. Here, we devise a quantitative proteomics strategy to define the cellular exit route for each protein by pharmacological and genetic dissection of cellular checkpoints regulating protein release. We report the release of hundreds of proteins during pyroptosis, predominantly due to cell lysis. They comprise constitutively expressed and transcriptionally induced proteins derived from the cytoplasm and specific intracellular organelles. Many low-molecular-weight proteins including the cytokine interleukin-1β, alarmins, and lysosomal-cargo proteins exit cells in the absence of cell lysis. Cytokines and alarmins are released in an endoplasmic reticulum (ER)-Golgi-dependent manner as free proteins rather than by extracellular vesicles. Our work provides an experimental framework for the dissection of cellular exit pathways and a resource for pyroptotic protein release.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SRSF1 inhibits autophagy through regulating Bcl-x splicing and interacting with PIK3C3 in lung cancer</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33664238/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33664238/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alternative splicing is a critical process to generate protein diversity. However, whether and how alternative splicing regulates autophagy remains largely elusive. Here we systematically identify the splicing factor SRSF1 as an autophagy suppressor. Specifically, SRSF1 inhibits autophagosome formation by reducing the accumulation of LC3-II and numbers of autophagosomes in different cell lines. Mechanistically, SRSF1 promotes the splicing of the long isoform of Bcl-x that interacts with Beclin1, thereby dissociating the Beclin1-PIK3C3 complex. In addition, SRSF1 also directly interacts with PIK3C3 to disrupt the interaction between Beclin1 and PIK3C3. Consequently, the decrease of SRSF1 stabilizes the Beclin1 and PIK3C3 complex and activates autophagy. Interestingly, SRSF1 can be degraded by starvation- and oxidative stresses-induced autophagy through interacting with LC3-II, whereas reduced SRSF1 further promotes autophagy. This positive feedback is critical to inhibiting Gefitinib-resistant cancer cell progression both in vitro and in vivo. Consistently, the expression level of SRSF1 is inversely correlated to LC3 level in clinical cancer samples. Our study not only provides mechanistic insights of alternative splicing in autophagy regulation but also discovers a new regulatory role of SRSF1 in tumorigenesis, thereby offering a novel avenue for potential cancer therapeutics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NINJ1 mediates plasma membrane rupture during lytic cell death</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33472215/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33472215/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Plasma membrane rupture (PMR) is the final cataclysmic event in lytic cell death. PMR releases intracellular molecules known as damage-associated molecular patterns (DAMPs) that propagate the inflammatory response. The underlying mechanism of PMR, however, is unknown. Here we show that the cell-surface NINJ1 protein, which contains two transmembrane regions, has an essential role in the induction of PMR. A forward-genetic screen of randomly mutagenized mice linked NINJ1 to PMR. Ninj1&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt; macrophages exhibited impaired PMR in response to diverse inducers of pyroptotic, necrotic and apoptotic cell death, and were unable to release numerous intracellular proteins including HMGB1 (a known DAMP) and LDH (a standard measure of PMR). Ninj1&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt; macrophages died, but with a distinctive and persistent ballooned morphology, attributable to defective disintegration of bubble-like herniations. Ninj1&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt; mice were more susceptible than wild-type mice to infection with Citrobacter rodentium, which suggests a role for PMR in anti-bacterial host defence. Mechanistically, NINJ1 used an evolutionarily conserved extracellular domain for oligomerization and subsequent PMR. The discovery of NINJ1 as a mediator of PMR overturns the long-held idea that cell death-related PMR is a passive event.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Identification and Validation of Autophagy-Related Genes in Chronic Obstructive Pulmonary Disease</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33469280/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33469280/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Purpose:&lt;/em&gt; Autophagy plays essential roles in the development of COPD. We aim to identify and validate the potential autophagy-related genes of COPD through bioinformatics analysis and experiment validation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; The mRNA expression profile dataset GSE38974 was obtained from GEO database. The potential differentially expressed autophagy-related genes of COPD were screened by R software. Then, protein–protein interactions (PPI), correlation analysis, gene-ontology (GO) enrichment analysis and Kyoto Encyclopedia of Genes and Genomes (KEGG) pathway enrichment analysis were applied for the differentially expressed autophagy-related genes. Finally, RNA expression of top five differentially expressed autophagy-related genes was validated in blood samples from COPD patients and healthy controls by qRT-PCR.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; A total of 40 differentially expressed autophagy-related genes (14 up-regulated genes and 26 down-regulated genes) were identified between 23 COPD patients and 9 healthy controls. The PPI results demonstrated that these autophagy-related genes interacted with each other. The GO and KEGG enrichment analysis of differentially expressed autophagy-related genes indicated several enriched terms related to autophagy and mitophagy. The results of qRT-PCR showed that the expression levels of &lt;em&gt;HIF1A&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;CDKN1A&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;BAG3&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;ERBB2&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;ATG16L1&lt;/em&gt; in COPD patients and healthy controls were consistent with the bioinformatics analysis results from mRNA microarray.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/em&gt; We identified 40 potential autophagy-related genes of COPD through bioinformatics analysis. &lt;em&gt;HIF1A&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;CDKN1A&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;BAG3&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;ERBB2&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;ATG16L1&lt;/em&gt; may affect the development of COPD by regulating autophagy. These results may expand our understanding of COPD and might be useful in the treatment of COPD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apaf-1 Pyroptosome Senses Mitochondrial Permeability Transition</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33308446/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33308446/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Caspase-4 is an intracellular sensor for cytosolic bacterial lipopolysaccharide (LPS) and underlies infection-elicited pyroptosis. It is unclear whether and how caspase-4 detects host-derived factors to trigger pyroptosis. Here we show that mitochondrial permeability transition (MPT) activates caspase-4 by promoting the assembly of a protein complex, which we term the Apaf-1 pyroptosome, for the execution of facilitated pyroptosis. MPT, when induced by bile acids, calcium overload, or an adenine nucleotide translocator 1 (ANT1) activator, triggers assembly of the pyroptosome comprised of Apaf-1 and caspase-4 with a stoichiometry ratio of 7:2. Unlike the direct cleavage of gasdermin D (GSDMD) by caspase-4 upon LPS ligation, caspase-4 activated in the Apaf-1 pyroptosome proceeds to cleave caspase-3 and thereby GSDME to induce pyroptosis. Caspase-4-initiated and GSDME-executed pyroptosis underlies cholestatic liver failure. These findings identify Apaf-1 pyroptosome as a pivotal machinery for cells sensing MPT signals and may shed light on understanding how cells execute intrinsic pyroptosis under sterile conditions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Complement and tissue factor-enriched neutrophil extracellular traps are key drivers in COVID-19 immunothrombosis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32759504/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32759504/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Emerging data indicate that complement and neutrophils contribute to the maladaptive immune response that fuels hyperinflammation and thrombotic microangiopathy, thereby increasing coronavirus 2019 (COVID-19) mortality. Here, we investigated how complement interacts with the platelet/neutrophil extracellular traps (NETs)/thrombin axis, using COVID-19 specimens, cell-based inhibition studies, and NET/human aortic endothelial cell (HAEC) cocultures. Increased plasma levels of NETs, tissue factor (TF) activity, and sC5b-9 were detected in patients. Neutrophils of patients yielded high TF expression and released NETs carrying active TF. Treatment of control neutrophils with COVID-19 platelet-rich plasma generated TF-bearing NETs that induced thrombotic activity of HAECs. Thrombin or NETosis inhibition or C5aR1 blockade attenuated platelet-mediated NET-driven thrombogenicity. COVID-19 serum induced complement activation in vitro, consistent with high complement activity in clinical samples. Complement C3 inhibition with compstatin Cp40 disrupted TF expression in neutrophils. In conclusion, we provide a mechanistic basis for a pivotal role of complement and NETs in COVID-19 immunothrombosis. This study supports strategies against severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 that exploit complement or NETosis inhibition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paradoxical Mitophagy Regulation by PINK1 and TUFm</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33113344/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33113344/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sepsis is the major cause of acute kidney injury (AKI) associated with high mortality rates. Mitochondrial dysfunction contributes to the pathophysiology of septic AKI. Mitophagy is an important mitochondrial quality control mechanism that selectively eliminates damaged mitochondria, but its role and regulation in septic AKI remain largely unknown. Here, we demonstrate the induction of mitophagy in mouse models of septic AKI induced by lipopolysaccharide (LPS) treatment or by cecal ligation and puncture. Mitophagy was also induced in cultured proximal tubular epithelial cells exposed to LPS. Induction of mitophagy under these experimental setting was suppressed by pink1 or park2 knockout, indicating the role of the PINK1/PARK2 pathway of mitophagy in septic AKI. In addition, sepsis induced more severe kidney injury and cell apoptosis in pink1 or park2 knockout mice than in wild-type mice, suggesting a beneficial role of mitophagy in septic AKI. Furthermore, in cultured renal tubular cells treated with LPS, knockdown of pink1 or park2 inhibited mitochondrial accumulation of the autophagy adaptor optineurin (OPTN) and silencing Optn inhibited LPS-induced mitophagy. Taken together, these findings suggest that the PINK1/PARK2 pathway of mitophagy plays an important role in mitochondrial quality control, tubular cell survival, and renal function in septic AKI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>microRNA-199a-3p inhibits hepatic apoptosis and hepatocarcinogenesis by targeting PDCD4</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33099584/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33099584/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hepatic apoptosis and the initiated liver inflammation play the initial roles in inflammation-induced hepatocarcinogenesis. Molecular mechanisms underlying the regulation of hepatocyte apoptosis and their roles in hepatocarcinogenesis have attracted much attention. A set of microRNAs (miRNAs) have been determined to be dysregulated in hepatocellular carcinoma (HCC) and participated in cancer progression, however, the roles of these dysregulated miRNAs in carcinogenesis are still poorly understood. We previously analyzed the dysregulated miRNAs in HCC using high-throughput sequencing, and found that miR-199a/b-3p was abundantly expressed in human normal liver while markedly decreased in HCC, which promotes HCC progression. Whether miR-199a/b-3p participates in HCC carcinogenesis is still unknown up to now. Hence, we focused on the role and mechanism of miR-199a/b-3p in hepatocarcinogenesis in this study. Hepatic miR-199a/b-3p was determined to be expressed by miR-199a-2 gene in mice, and we constructed miR-199a-2 knockout and hepatocyte-specific miR-199a-2 knockout mice. Diethylnitrosamine (DEN)-induced hepatocarcinogenesis were markedly increased by hepatocyte-specific miR-199a-3p knockout, which is mediated by the enhanced hepatocyte apoptosis and hepatic injury by DEN administration. In acetaminophen (APAP)-induced acute hepatic injury model, hepatocyte-specific miR-199a-3p knockout also aggravated hepatic apoptosis. By proteomic screening and reporter gene validation, we identified and verified that hepatic programed cell death 4 (PDCD4), which promotes apoptosis, was directly targeted by miR-199a-3p. Furthermore, we confirmed that miR-199a-3p-suppressed hepatocyte apoptosis and hepatic injury by targeting and suppressing PDCD4. Thus, hepatic miR-199a-3p inhibits hepatocyte apoptosis and hepatocarcinogenesis, and decreased miR-199a-3p in hepatocytes may aggravate hepatic injury and HCC development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The PINK1/PARK2/optineurin pathway of mitophagy is activated for protection in septic acute kidney injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33137712/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33137712/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sepsis is the major cause of acute kidney injury (AKI) associated with high mortality rates. Mitochondrial dysfunction contributes to the pathophysiology of septic AKI. Mitophagy is an important mitochondrial quality control mechanism that selectively eliminates damaged mitochondria, but its role and regulation in septic AKI remain largely unknown. Here, we demonstrate the induction of mitophagy in mouse models of septic AKI induced by lipopolysaccharide (LPS) treatment or by cecal ligation and puncture. Mitophagy was also induced in cultured proximal tubular epithelial cells exposed to LPS. Induction of mitophagy under these experimental setting was suppressed by pink1 or park2 knockout, indicating the role of the PINK1/PARK2 pathway of mitophagy in septic AKI. In addition, sepsis induced more severe kidney injury and cell apoptosis in pink1 or park2 knockout mice than in wild-type mice, suggesting a beneficial role of mitophagy in septic AKI. Furthermore, in cultured renal tubular cells treated with LPS, knockdown of pink1 or park2 inhibited mitochondrial accumulation of the autophagy adaptor optineurin (OPTN) and silencing Optn inhibited LPS-induced mitophagy. Taken together, these findings suggest that the PINK1/PARK2 pathway of mitophagy plays an important role in mitochondrial quality control, tubular cell survival, and renal function in septic AKI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>USP19 suppresses inflammation and promotes M2-like macrophage polarization by manipulating NLRP3 function via autophagy</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33097834/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33097834/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Macrophage polarization to proinflammatory M1-like or anti-inflammatory M2-like cells is critical to mount a host defense or repair tissue. The exact molecular mechanisms controlling this process are still elusive. Here, we report that ubiquitin-specific protease 19 (USP19) acts as an anti-inflammatory switch that inhibits inflammatory responses and promotes M2-like macrophage polarization. USP19 inhibited NLRP3 inflammasome activation by increasing autophagy flux and decreasing the generation of mitochondrial reactive oxygen species. In addition, USP19 inhibited the proteasomal degradation of inflammasome-independent NLRP3 by cleaving its polyubiquitin chains. USP19-stabilized NLRP3 promoted M2-like macrophage polarization by direct association with interferon regulatory factor 4, thereby preventing its p62-mediated selective autophagic degradation. Consistent with these observations, compared to wild-type mice, Usp19-/- mice had decreased M2-like macrophage polarization and increased interleukin-1β secretion, in response to alum and chitin injections. Thus, we have uncovered an unexpected mechanism by which USP19 switches the proinflammatory function of NLRP3 into an anti-inflammatory function, and suggest that USP19 is a potential therapeutic target for inflammatory interventions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TSPAN1 promotes autophagy flux and mediates cooperation between WNT-CTNNB1 signaling and autophagy via the MIR454-FAM83A-TSPAN1 axis in pancreatic cancer</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32972302/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32972302/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pancreatic cancer is one of the most aggressive tumors associated with a poor clinical prognosis, weakly effective therapeutic options. Therefore, there is a strong impetus to discover new therapeutic targets in pancreatic cancer. In the present study, we first demonstrated that TSPAN1 is upregulated in pancreatic cancer and that TSPAN1 depletion decreases pancreatic cancer cell proliferation in vitro and in vivo. TSPAN1 expression was correlated with poor overall survival of pancreatic cancer patients. Moreover, we demonstrated that TSPAN1 is a novel positive regulator of macroautophagy/autophagy characterized by decreased LC3-II and SQSTM1/p62 expressions, inhibited puncta formation of GFP-LC3 and autophagic vacuoles. We also demonstrated that tspan1 mutation impaired autophagy in the zebrafish model. Furthermore, we showed that TSPAN1 promoted autophagy maturation via direct binding to LC3 by two conserved LIR motifs. Mutations in the LIR motifs of TSPAN1 resulted in a loss of the ability to induce autophagy and promote pancreatic cancer proliferation. Second, we discovered two conservative TCF/LEF binding elements present in the promoter region of the TSPAN1 gene, which was further verified through luciferase activity and ChIP assays. Furthermore, TSPAN1 was upregulated by FAM83A through the canonical WNT-CTNNB1 signaling pathway. We further demonstrated that both TSPAN1 and FAM83A are both direct targets of MIR454 (microRNA 454). Additionally, we revealed the role of MIR454-FAM83A-TSPAN1 in the proliferation of pancreatic cancer cells in vitro and in vivo. Our findings suggest that components of the MIR454-FAM83A-TSPAN1 axis may be valuable prognosis markers or therapeutic targets for pancreatic cancer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A gene expression signature of TREM2hi macrophages and γδ T cells predicts immunotherapy response</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33033253/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33033253/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Identifying factors underlying resistance to immune checkpoint therapy (ICT) is still challenging. Most cancer patients do not respond to ICT and the availability of the predictive biomarkers is limited. Here, we re-analyze a publicly available single-cell RNA sequencing (scRNA-seq) dataset of melanoma samples of patients subjected to ICT and identify a subset of macrophages overexpressing TREM2 and a subset of gammadelta T cells that are both overrepresented in the non-responding tumors. In addition, the percentage of a B cell subset is significantly lower in the non-responders. The presence of these immune cell subtypes is corroborated in other publicly available scRNA-seq datasets. The analyses of bulk RNA-seq datasets of the melanoma samples identify and validate a signature - ImmuneCells.Sig - enriched with the genes characteristic of the above immune cell subsets to predict response to immunotherapy. ImmuneCells.Sig could represent a valuable tool for clinical decision making in patients receiving immunotherapy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bacterial nanotubes as a manifestation of cell death</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33009406/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33009406/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bacterial nanotubes are membranous structures that have been reported to function as conduits between cells to exchange DNA, proteins, and nutrients. Here, we investigate the morphology and formation of bacterial nanotubes using Bacillus subtilis. We show that nanotube formation is associated with stress conditions, and is highly sensitive to the cells&amp;rsquo; genetic background, growth phase, and sample preparation methods. Remarkably, nanotubes appear to be extruded exclusively from dying cells, likely as a result of biophysical forces. Their emergence is extremely fast, occurring within seconds by cannibalizing the cell membrane. Subsequent experiments reveal that cell-to-cell transfer of non-conjugative plasmids depends strictly on the competence system of the cell, and not on nanotube formation. Our study thus supports the notion that bacterial nanotubes are a post mortem phenomenon involved in cell disintegration, and are unlikely to be involved in cytoplasmic content exchange between live cells.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Decoding three distinct states of the Syntaxin17 SNARE motif in mediating autophagosome-lysosome fusion</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32817423/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32817423/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Syntaxin17, a key autophagosomal N-ethylmaleimide-sensitive factor attachment protein receptor (SNARE) protein, can associate with ATG8 family proteins SNAP29 and VAMP8 to facilitate the membrane fusion process between the double-membraned autophagosome and single-membraned lysosome in mammalian macroautophagy. However, the inherent properties of Syntaxin17 and the mechanistic basis underlying the interactions of Syntaxin17 with its binding proteins remain largely unknown. Here, using biochemical, NMR, and structural approaches, we systemically characterized Syntaxin17 as well as its interactions with ATG8 family proteins, SNAP29 and VAMP8. We discovered that Syntaxin17 alone adopts an autoinhibited conformation mediated by a direct interaction between its Habc domain and the Qa-SNARE motif. In addition, we revealed that the Qa-SNARE region of Syntaxin17 contains one LC3-interacting region (LIR) motif, which preferentially binds to GABARAP subfamily members. Importantly, the GABARAP binding of Syntaxin17 can release its autoinhibited state. The determined crystal structure of the Syntaxin17 LIR-GABARAP complex not only provides mechanistic insights into the interaction between Syntaxin17 and GABARAP but also reveals an unconventional LIR motif with a C-terminally extended 310 helix for selectively binding to ATG8 family proteins. Finally, we also elucidated structural arrangements of the autophagic Syntaxin17-SNAP29-VAMP8 SNARE core complex, and uncovered its conserved biochemical and structural characteristics common to all other SNAREs. In all, our findings reveal three distinct states of Syntaxin17, and provide mechanistic insights into the Syntaxin17-mediated autophagosome-lysosome fusion process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Autophagy regulates fatty acid availability for oxidative phosphorylation through mitochondria-endoplasmic reticulum contact sites</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32792483/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32792483/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Autophagy has been associated with oncogenesis with one of its emerging key functions being its contribution to the metabolism of tumors. Therefore, deciphering the mechanisms of how autophagy supports tumor cell metabolism is essential. Here, we demonstrate that the inhibition of autophagy induces an accumulation of lipid droplets (LD) due to a decrease in fatty acid β-oxidation, that leads to a reduction of oxidative phosphorylation (OxPHOS) in acute myeloid leukemia (AML), but not in normal cells. Thus, the autophagic process participates in lipid catabolism that supports OxPHOS in AML cells. Interestingly, the inhibition of OxPHOS leads to LD accumulation with the concomitant inhibition of autophagy. Mechanistically, we show that the disruption of mitochondria-endoplasmic reticulum (ER) contact sites (MERCs) phenocopies OxPHOS inhibition. Altogether, our data establish that mitochondria, through the regulation of MERCs, controls autophagy that, in turn finely tunes lipid degradation to fuel OxPHOS supporting proliferation and growth in leukemia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hepatic transferrin plays a role in systemic iron homeostasis and liver ferroptosis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32374849/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32374849/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although the serum-abundant metal-binding protein transferrin (encoded by the &lt;em&gt;Trf&lt;/em&gt; gene) is synthesized primarily in the liver, its function in the liver is largely unknown. Here, we generated hepatocyte-specific &lt;em&gt;Trf&lt;/em&gt; knockout mice (&lt;em&gt;Trf&lt;/em&gt;-LKO), which are viable and fertile but have impaired erythropoiesis and altered iron metabolism. Moreover, feeding &lt;em&gt;Trf&lt;/em&gt;-LKO mice a high-iron diet increased their susceptibility to developing ferroptosis-induced liver fibrosis. Importantly, we found that treating &lt;em&gt;Trf&lt;/em&gt;-LKO mice with the ferroptosis inhibitor ferrostatin-1 potently rescued liver fibrosis induced by either high dietary iron or carbon tetrachloride (CCl&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;) injections. In addition, deleting hepatic Slc39a14 expression in &lt;em&gt;Trf&lt;/em&gt;-LKO mice significantly reduced hepatic iron accumulation, thereby reducing ferroptosis-mediated liver fibrosis induced by either a high-iron diet or CCl&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; injections. Finally, we found that patients with liver cirrhosis have significantly lower levels of serum transferrin and hepatic transferrin, as well as higher levels of hepatic iron and lipid peroxidation, compared with healthy control subjects. Taken together, these data indicate that hepatic transferrin plays a protective role in maintaining liver function, providing a possible therapeutic target for preventing ferroptosis-induced liver fibrosis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A novel selective autophagy receptor, CCDC50, delivers K63 polyubiquitination-activated RIG-I/MDA5 for degradation during viral infection</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32612200/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32612200/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Autophagy is a conserved process that delivers cytosolic substances to the lysosome for degradation, but its direct role in the regulation of antiviral innate immunity remains poorly understood. Here, through high-throughput screening, we discovered that CCDC50 functions as a previously unknown autophagy receptor that negatively regulates the type I interferon (IFN) signaling pathway initiated by RIG-I-like receptors (RLRs), the sensors for RNA viruses. The expression of CCDC50 is enhanced by viral infection, and CCDC50 specifically recognizes K63-polyubiquitinated RLRs, thus delivering the activated RIG-I/MDA5 for autophagic degradation. The association of CCDC50 with phagophore membrane protein LC3 is confirmed by crystal structure analysis. In contrast to other known autophagic cargo receptors that associate with either the LIR-docking site (LDS) or the UIM-docking site (UDS) of LC3, CCDC50 can bind to both LDS and UDS, representing a new type of cargo receptor. In mouse models with RNA virus infection, CCDC50 deficiency reduces the autophagic degradation of RIG-I/MDA5 and promotes type I IFN responses, resulting in enhanced viral resistance and improved survival rates. These results reveal a new link between autophagy and antiviral innate immune responses and provide additional insights into the regulatory mechanisms of RLR-mediated antiviral signaling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Decreased Hepatocyte Autophagy Leads to Synergistic IL-1β and TNF Mouse Liver Injury and Inflammation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32108953/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32108953/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background and aims:&lt;/em&gt; The proinflammatory cytokine IL-1β has been implicated in the pathophysiology of nonalcoholic and alcoholic steatohepatitis. How IL-1β promotes liver injury in these diseases is unclear, as no IL-1β receptor-linked death pathway has been identified. Autophagy functions in hepatocyte resistance to injury and death, and findings of decreased hepatic autophagy in many liver diseases suggest a role for impaired autophagy in disease pathogenesis. Recent findings that autophagy blocks mouse liver injury from lipopolysaccharide led to an examination of autophagy&amp;rsquo;s function in hepatotoxicity from proinflammatory cytokines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Approach and results:&lt;/em&gt; AML12 cells with decreased autophagy from a lentiviral autophagy-related 5 (Atg5) knockdown were resistant to toxicity from TNF, but sensitized to death from IL-1β, which was markedly amplified by TNF co-treatment. IL-1β/TNF death was necrosis by trypan blue and propidium iodide positivity, absence of mitochondrial death pathway and caspase activation, and failure of a caspase inhibitor or necrostatin-1s to prevent death. IL-1β/TNF depleted autophagy-deficient cells of ATP, and ATP depletion and cell death were prevented by supplementation with the energy substrate pyruvate or oleate. Pharmacological inhibitors and genetic knockdown studies demonstrated that IL-1β/TNF-induced necrosis resulted from lysosomal permeabilization and release of cathepsins B and L in autophagy-deficient cells. Mice with a tamoxifen-inducible, hepatocyte-specific Atg5 knockout were similarly sensitized to cathepsin-dependent hepatocellular injury and death from IL-1β/TNF in combination, but neither IL-1β nor TNF alone. Knockout mice had increased hepatic inflammation, and IL-1β/TNF-treated, autophagy-deficient AML12 cells secreted exosomes with proinflammatory damage-associated molecular patterns.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; The findings delineate mechanisms by which decreased hepatocyte autophagy promotes IL-1β/TNF-induced necrosis from impaired energy homeostasis and lysosomal permeabilization and inflammation through the secretion of exosomal damage-associated molecular patterns.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interferon regulatory factor 1 regulates PANoptosis to prevent colorectal cancer</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32554929/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32554929/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interferon regulatory factor 1 (IRF1) regulates diverse biological functions, including modulation of cellular responses involved in tumorigenesis. Genetic mutations and altered IRF1 function are associated with several cancers. Although the function of IRF1 in the immunobiology of cancer is emerging, IRF1-specific mechanisms regulating tumorigenesis and tissue homeostasis in vivo are not clear. Here, we found that mice lacking IRF1 were hypersusceptible to colorectal tumorigenesis. IRF1 functions in both the myeloid and epithelial compartments to confer protection against AOM/DSS-induced colorectal tumorigenesis. We further found that IRF1 also prevents tumorigenesis in a spontaneous mouse model of colorectal cancer. The attenuated cell death in the colons of Irf1-/- mice was due to defective pyroptosis, apoptosis, and necroptosis (PANoptosis). IRF1 does not regulate inflammation and the inflammasome in the colon. Overall, our study identified IRF1 as an upstream regulator of PANoptosis to induce cell death during colitis-associated tumorigenesis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Identification of the PANoptosome: A Molecular Platform Triggering Pyroptosis, Apoptosis, and Necroptosis (PANoptosis)</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32547960/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32547960/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Programmed cell death plays crucial roles in organismal development and host defense. Recent studies have highlighted mechanistic overlaps and extensive, multifaceted crosstalk between pyroptosis, apoptosis, and necroptosis, three programmed cell death pathways traditionally considered autonomous. The growing body of evidence, in conjunction with the identification of molecules controlling the concomitant activation of all three pathways by pathological triggers, has led to the development of the concept of PANoptosis. During PANoptosis, inflammatory cell death occurs through the collective activation of pyroptosis, apoptosis, and necroptosis, which can circumvent pathogen-mediated inhibition of individual death pathways. Many of the molecular details of this emerging pathway are unclear. Here, we describe the activation of PANoptosis by bacterial and viral triggers and report protein interactions that reveal the formation of a PANoptosome complex. Infection of macrophages with influenza A virus, vesicular stomatitis virus, Listeria monocytogenes, or Salmonella enterica serovar Typhimurium resulted in robust cell death and the hallmarks of PANoptosis activation. Combined deletion of the PANoptotic components caspase-1 (CASP1), CASP11, receptor-interacting serine/threonine-protein kinase 3 (RIPK3), and CASP8 largely protected macrophages from cell death induced by these pathogens, while deletion of individual components provided reduced or no protection. Further, molecules from the pyroptotic, apoptotic, and necroptotic cell death pathways interacted to form a single molecular complex that we have termed the PANoptosome. Overall, our study identifies pathogens capable of activating PANoptosis and the formation of a PANoptosome complex.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visualizing and Modulating Mitophagy for Therapeutic Studies of Neurodegeneration</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32437660/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32437660/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dysfunctional mitochondria accumulate in many human diseases. Accordingly, mitophagy, which removes these mitochondria through lysosomal degradation, is attracting broad attention. Due to uncertainties in the operational principles of conventional mitophagy probes, however, the specificity and quantitativeness of their readouts are disputable. Thorough investigation of the behaviors and fates of fluorescent proteins inside and outside lysosomes enabled us to develop an indicator for mitophagy, mito-SRAI. Through strict control of its mitochondrial targeting, we were able to monitor mitophagy in fixed biological samples more reproducibly than before. Large-scale image-based high-throughput screening led to the discovery of a hit compound that induces selective mitophagy of damaged mitochondria. In a mouse model of Parkinsons disease, we found that dopaminergic neurons selectively failed to execute mitophagy that promoted their survival within lesions. These results show that mito-SRAI is an essential tool for quantitative studies of mitochondrial quality control.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crucial Roles of the RIP Homotypic Interaction Motifs of RIPK3 in RIPK1-Dependent Cell Death and Lymphoproliferative Disease</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32433959/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32433959/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Receptor-interacting protein kinase 3 (RIPK3) has been identified as an essential regulator of necroptosis, apoptosis, and inflammatory signaling. RIPK3 contains an N-terminal kinase domain and a C-terminal RIP homotypic interaction motif (RHIM). However, the physiological roles of RIPK3 RHIM remain unclear. Here we generate knockin mice endogenously expressing the RIPK3 RHIM mutant, RIPK3&lt;sup&gt;V448P&lt;/sup&gt;. Cells expressing RIPK3&lt;sup&gt;V448P&lt;/sup&gt; are resistant to RIPK1 kinase-dependent apoptosis and necroptosis, and Ripk3&lt;sup&gt;V448P/V448P&lt;/sup&gt; mice rescue embryonic lethality of Fadd-deficient mice by intercrossing. Strikingly, &lt;em&gt;Ripk3&lt;sup&gt;V448P/V448P&lt;/sup&gt;Fadd&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; mice display more severe lymphoproliferative disease with a marked increase in abnormal CD3&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt;B220&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; lymphocytes compared with &lt;em&gt;Ripk3&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt;Fadd&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; mice. More importantly, these inflammatory morbidities in &lt;em&gt;Ripk3&lt;sup&gt;V448P/V448P&lt;/sup&gt;Fadd&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; mice are profoundly inhibited by additional deletion of &lt;em&gt;Ripk1&lt;/em&gt;. Taken together, these results reveal a previously unidentified physiological function of RHIM of RIPK3 in regulating RIPK1-dependent cell death and lymphoproliferative disease.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Autophagy promotes immune evasion of pancreatic cancer by degrading MHC-I</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32376951/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32376951/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Immune evasion is a major obstacle for cancer treatment. Common mechanisms of evasion include impaired antigen presentation caused by mutations or loss of heterozygosity of the major histocompatibility complex class I (MHC-I), which has been implicated in resistance to immune checkpoint blockade (ICB) therapy. However, in pancreatic ductal adenocarcinoma (PDAC), which is resistant to most therapies including ICB, mutations that cause loss of MHC-I are rarely found despite the frequent downregulation of MHC-I expression. Here we show that, in PDAC, MHC-I molecules are selectively targeted for lysosomal degradation by an autophagy-dependent mechanism that involves the autophagy cargo receptor NBR1. PDAC cells display reduced expression of MHC-I at the cell surface and instead demonstrate predominant localization within autophagosomes and lysosomes. Notably, inhibition of autophagy restores surface levels of MHC-I and leads to improved antigen presentation, enhanced anti-tumour T cell responses and reduced tumour growth in syngeneic host mice. Accordingly, the anti-tumour effects of autophagy inhibition are reversed by depleting CD8&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T cells or reducing surface expression of MHC-I. Inhibition of autophagy, either genetically or pharmacologically with chloroquine, synergizes with dual ICB therapy (anti-PD1 and anti-CTLA4 antibodies), and leads to an enhanced anti-tumour immune response. Our findings demonstrate a role for enhanced autophagy or lysosome function in immune evasion by selective targeting of MHC-I molecules for degradation, and provide a rationale for the combination of autophagy inhibition and dual ICB therapy as a therapeutic strategy against PDAC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Granzyme A from cytotoxic lymphocytes cleaves GSDMB to trigger pyroptosis in target cells</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32299851/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32299851/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Introduction&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In cellular immunity, cytotoxic T lymphocytes (CTLs) and natural killer (NK) cells use perforin to deliver serine protease granzymes into target cells to kill them. Gasdermins are pore-forming proteins that execute pyroptosis, a form of proinflammatory cell death. Gasdermin D (GSDMD) is cleaved by caspase-1/4/5/11 upon inflammasome activation, releasing the pore-forming domain for plasma membrane disruption. Gasdermin E (GSDME) is similarly cleaved by caspase-3, converting apoptosis to pyroptosis. The functional mechanism for other gasdermins is unknown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rationale&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The view that granzymes induce target-cell apoptosis was proposed two decades ago, when apoptosis was thought to be the dominant form of programmed cell death and assays to ascertain apoptosis were insufficiently accurate. Furthermore, granzyme cytotoxicity was only assessed in a few cell types. Discovery of the gasdermin family, which are true cell death executors, has altered our understanding of programmed cell death. In this work, we explored whether members of the gasdermin family might respond to granzymes and induce pyroptosis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Results&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The expression of gasdermin B (GSDMB) but no other gasdermins in human embryonic kidney (HEK) 293T cells induced pyroptotic killing by NK cells, accompanied by an interdomain cleavage of GSDMB. These processes were blocked by inhibiting the perforin–granzyme pathway. In vitro profiling of all five human granzymes identified granzyme A (GZMA), which readily cleaved GSDMB, predominantly at Lys&lt;sup&gt;244&lt;/sup&gt; within the interdomain linker. This cleavage unmasked the pore-forming activity of GSDMB. GZMA, delivered into GSDMB-reconstituted cells by electroporation or perforin, induced extensive pyroptosis with interdomain cleavage of GSDMB. These effects were diminished by a K229A/K244A (KK/A) mutation of GSDMB. In cells normally undergoing apoptosis upon GZMA delivery, the additional expression of GZMA-cleavable GSDMB converted apoptosis into pyroptosis. Pyroptotic killing by NK cells was blocked by both the KK/AA mutation and a knockdown of &lt;em&gt;GZMA&lt;/em&gt; expression. Among 39 cell lines, three, including the esophageal carcinoma (OE19 cells), expressed GSDMB and underwent pyroptosis upon GZMA delivery. Knockout experiments revealed that pyroptosis in OE19 cells required the interdomain cleavage of GSDMB. Furthermore, GSDMB expression was up-regulated by interferon-γ (IFN-γ). Approximately one-third of GSDMB-negative cell lines showed IFN-γ–induced GSDMB expression. IFN-γ promoted GZMA- or NK cell–induced pyroptosis in several target cells. Primary T cells, including anti-CD19 chimeric-antigen receptor (CAR) T cells and NY-ESO-1–specific T cell receptor (TCR)–engineered T cells (TCR T cells), also induced pyroptosis in GSDMB-reconstituted cells through cleavage of GSDMB by GZMA. Introducing GZMA-cleavable GSDMB into mouse cancer cells promoted tumor clearance in mice. &lt;em&gt;GSDMB&lt;/em&gt; was highly expressed in certain tissues, particularly digestive tract epithelia, including the derived tumors. GSDMB appeared to be silenced in gastric and esophageal cancers. The Cancer Genome Atlas database recorded a strong positive correlation between &lt;em&gt;GSDMB&lt;/em&gt; expression and patient survival for bladder carcinoma and skin cutaneous melanoma.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conclusion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GZMA from cytotoxic lymphocytes cleaves and activates GSDMB to induce target cell pyroptosis. This immune effector mechanism promotes CTL-mediated tumor clearance in mice. High GSDMB expression in the digestive system suggests the importance of GSDMB-mediated immunity in these tissues and will guide immunotherapy for related cancers. Our findings suggest that substrates such as gasdermins, rather than their upstream proteases, determine the nature of cell death.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Z-nucleic-acid sensing triggers ZBP1-dependent necroptosis and inflammation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32296175/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32296175/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Erratum in:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Publisher Correction: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-020-2207-y&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Z-nucleic-acid sensing triggers ZBP1-dependent necroptosis and inflammation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The biological function of Z-DNA and Z-RNA, nucleic acid structures with a left-handed double helix, is poorly understood. Z-DNA-binding protein 1 (ZBP1; also known as DAI or DLM-1) is a nucleic acid sensor that contains two Zα domains that bind Z-DNA and Z-RNA. ZBP1 mediates host defence against some viruses by sensing viral nucleic acids. RIPK1 deficiency, or mutation of its RIP homotypic interaction motif (RHIM), triggers ZBP1-dependent necroptosis and inflammation in mice. However, the mechanisms that induce ZBP1 activation in the absence of viral infection remain unknown. Here we show that Zα-dependent sensing of endogenous ligands induces ZBP1-mediated perinatal lethality in mice expressing RIPK1 with mutated RHIM (&lt;em&gt;Ripk1&lt;sup&gt;mR/mR&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt;), skin inflammation in mice with epidermis-specific RIPK1 deficiency (RIPK1&lt;sup&gt;E-KO&lt;/sup&gt;) and colitis in mice with intestinal epithelial-specific FADD deficiency (FADD&lt;sup&gt;IEC-KO&lt;/sup&gt;). Consistently, functional Zα domains were required for ZBP1-induced necroptosis in fibroblasts that were treated with caspase inhibitors or express RIPK1 with mutated RHIM. Inhibition of nuclear export triggered the Zα-dependent activation of RIPK3 in the nucleus resulting in cell death, which suggests that ZBP1 may recognize nuclear Z-form nucleic acids. We found that ZBP1 constitutively bound cellular double-stranded RNA in a Zα-dependent manner. Complementary reads derived from endogenous retroelements were detected in epidermal RNA, which suggests that double-stranded RNA derived from these retroelements may act as a Zα-domain ligand that triggers the activation of ZBP1. Collectively, our results provide evidence that the sensing of endogenous Z-form nucleic acids by ZBP1 triggers RIPK3-dependent necroptosis and inflammation, which could underlie the development of chronic inflammatory conditions-particularly in individuals with mutations in &lt;em&gt;RIPK1&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;CASP8&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mitochondrial DNA stress triggers autophagy-dependent ferroptotic death</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32186434/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32186434/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pancreatic cancer tends to be highly resistant to current therapy and remains one of the great challenges in biomedicine with very low 5-year survival rates. Here, we report that zalcitabine, an antiviral drug for human immunodeficiency virus infection, can suppress the growth of primary and immortalized human pancreatic cancer cells through the induction of ferroptosis, an iron-dependent form of regulated cell death. Mechanically, this effect relies on zalcitabine-induced mitochondrial DNA stress, which activates the STING1/TMEM173-mediated DNA sensing pathway, leading to macroautophagy/autophagy-dependent ferroptotic cell death via lipid peroxidation, but not a type I interferon response. Consequently, the genetic and pharmacological inactivation of the autophagy-dependent ferroptosis pathway diminishes the anticancer effects of zalcitabine in cell culture and animal models. Together, these findings not only provide a new approach for pancreatic cancer therapy but also increase our understanding of the interplay between autophagy and DNA damage response in shaping cell death.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A bioorthogonal system reveals antitumour immune function of pyroptosis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32188939/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32188939/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bioorthogonal chemistry capable of operating in live animals is needed to investigate biological processes such as cell death and immunity. Recent studies have identified a gasdermin family of pore-forming proteins that executes inflammasome-dependent and -independent pyroptosis. Pyroptosis is proinflammatory, but its effect on antitumour immunity is unknown. Here we establish a bioorthogonal chemical system, in which a cancer-imaging probe phenylalanine trifluoroborate (Phe-BF&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;) that can enter cells desilylates and &amp;lsquo;cleaves&amp;rsquo; a designed linker that contains a silyl ether. This system enabled the controlled release of a drug from an antibody-drug conjugate in mice. When combined with nanoparticle-mediated delivery, desilylation catalysed by Phe-BF&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; could release a client protein-including an active gasdermin-from a nanoparticle conjugate, selectively into tumour cells in mice. We applied this bioorthogonal system to gasdermin, which revealed that pyroptosis of less than 15% of tumour cells was sufficient to clear the entire 4T1 mammary tumour graft. The tumour regression was absent in immune-deficient mice or upon T cell depletion, and was correlated with augmented antitumour immune responses. The injection of a reduced, ineffective dose of nanoparticle-conjugated gasdermin along with Phe-BF&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; sensitized 4T1 tumours to anti-PD1 therapy. Our bioorthogonal system based on Phe-BF&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; desilylation is therefore a powerful tool for chemical biology; our application of this system suggests that pyroptosis-induced inflammation triggers robust antitumour immunity and can synergize with checkpoint blockade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Genome-wide ER-phagy Screen Highlights Key Roles of Mitochondrial Metabolism and ER-Resident UFMylation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32160526/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32160526/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Selective autophagy of organelles is critical for cellular differentiation, homeostasis, and organismal health. Autophagy of the ER (ER-phagy) is implicated in human neuropathy but is poorly understood beyond a few autophagosomal receptors and remodelers. By using an ER-phagy reporter and genome-wide CRISPRi screening, we identified 200 high-confidence human ER-phagy factors. Two pathways were unexpectedly required for ER-phagy. First, reduced mitochondrial metabolism represses ER-phagy, which is opposite of general autophagy and is independent of AMPK. Second, ER-localized UFMylation is required for ER-phagy to repress the unfolded protein response via IRE1α. The UFL1 ligase is brought to the ER surface by DDRGK1 to UFMylate RPN1 and RPL26 and preferentially targets ER sheets for degradation, analogous to PINK1-Parkin regulation during mitophagy. Our data provide insight into the cellular logic of ER-phagy, reveal parallels between organelle autophagies, and provide an entry point to the relatively unexplored process of degrading the ER network.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Structural Mechanism for GSDMD Targeting by Autoprocessed Caspases in Pyroptosis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32109412/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32109412/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The pyroptosis execution protein GSDMD is cleaved by inflammasome-activated caspase-1 and LPS-activated caspase-11/4/5. The cleavage unmasks the pore-forming domain from GSDMD-C-terminal domain. How the caspases recognize GSDMD and its connection with caspase activation are unknown. Here, we show site-specific caspase-4/11 autoprocessing, generating a p10 product, is required and sufficient for cleaving GSDMD and inducing pyroptosis. The p10-form autoprocessed caspase-4/11 binds the GSDMD-C domain with a high affinity. Structural comparison of autoprocessed and unprocessed capase-11 identifies a β sheet induced by the autoprocessing. In caspase-4/11-GSDMD-C complex crystal structures, the β sheet organizes a hydrophobic GSDMD-binding interface that is only possible for p10-form caspase-4/11. The binding promotes dimerization-mediated caspase activation, rendering a cleavage independently of the cleavage-site tetrapeptide sequence. Crystal structure of caspase-1-GSDMD-C complex shows a similar GSDMD-recognition mode. Our study reveals an unprecedented substrate-targeting mechanism for caspases. The hydrophobic interface suggests an additional space for developing inhibitors specific for pyroptotic caspases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Local Fatty Acid Channeling into Phospholipid Synthesis Drives Phagophore Expansion during Autophagy</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/31883797/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/31883797/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Autophagy is a conserved catabolic homeostasis process central for cellular and organismal health. During autophagy, small single-membrane phagophores rapidly expand into large double-membrane autophagosomes to encapsulate diverse cargoes for degradation. It is thought that autophagic membranes are mainly derived from preformed organelle membranes. Instead, here we delineate a pathway that expands the phagophore membrane by localized phospholipid synthesis. Specifically, we find that the conserved acyl-CoA synthetase Faa1 accumulates on nucleated phagophores and locally activates fatty acids (FAs) required for phagophore elongation and autophagy. Strikingly, using isotopic FA tracing, we directly show that Faa1 channels activated FAs into the synthesis of phospholipids and promotes their assembly into autophagic membranes. Indeed, the first committed steps of de novo phospholipid synthesis at the ER, which forms stable contacts with nascent autophagosomes, are essential for autophagy. Together, our work illuminates how cells spatially tune synthesis and flux of phospholipids for autophagosome biogenesis during autophagy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LATS1 but not LATS2 represses autophagy by a kinase-independent scaffold function</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/31848340/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/31848340/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Autophagy perturbation represents an emerging therapeutic strategy in cancer. Although LATS1 and LATS2 kinases, core components of the mammalian Hippo pathway, have been shown to exert tumor suppressive activities, here we report a pro-survival role of LATS1 but not LATS2 in hepatocellular carcinoma (HCC) cells. Specifically, LATS1 restricts lethal autophagy in HCC cells induced by sorafenib, the standard of care for advanced HCC patients. Notably, autophagy regulation by LATS1 is independent of its kinase activity. Instead, LATS1 stabilizes the autophagy core-machinery component Beclin-1 by promoting K27-linked ubiquitination at lysine residues K32 and K263 on Beclin-1. Consequently, ubiquitination of Beclin-1 negatively regulates autophagy by promoting inactive dimer formation of Beclin-1. Our study highlights a functional diversity between LATS1 and LATS2, and uncovers a scaffolding role of LATS1 in mediating a cross-talk between the Hippo signaling pathway and autophagy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The ER-Localized Transmembrane Protein TMEM39A/SUSR2 Regulates Autophagy by Controlling the Trafficking of the PtdIns(4)P Phosphatase SAC1</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/31806350/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/31806350/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TMEM39A, encoding an ER-localized transmembrane protein, is a susceptibility locus for multiple autoimmune diseases. The molecular function of TMEM39A remains completely unknown. Here we demonstrated that TMEM39A, also called SUSR2, modulates autophagy activity by regulating the spatial distribution and levels of PtdIns(4)P. Depletion of SUSR2 elevates late endosomal/lysosomal PtdIns(4)P levels, facilitating recruitment of the HOPS complex to promote assembly of the SNARE complex for autophagosome maturation. SUSR2 knockdown also increases the degradative capability of lysosomes. Mechanistically, SUSR2 interacts with the ER-localized PtdIns(4)P phosphatase SAC1 and also the COPII SEC23/SEC24 subunits to promote the ER-to-Golgi transport of SAC1. Retention of SAC1 on the ER in SUSR2 knockdown cells increases the level of PtdIns(3)P produced by the VPS34 complex, promoting autophagosome formation. Our study reveals that TMEM39A/SUSR2 acts as an adaptor protein for efficient export of SAC1 from the ER and provides insights into the pathogenesis of diseases associated with TMEM39A mutations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Caspase-8 is the molecular switch for apoptosis, necroptosis and pyroptosis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/31748744/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/31748744/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Caspase-8 is the initiator caspase of extrinsic apoptosis and inhibits necroptosis mediated by RIPK3 and MLKL. Accordingly, caspase-8 deficiency in mice causes embryonic lethality, which can be rescued by deletion of either &lt;em&gt;Ripk3&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;Mlkl&lt;/em&gt;. Here we show that the expression of enzymatically inactive CASP8(C362S) causes embryonic lethality in mice by inducing necroptosis and pyroptosis. Similar to &lt;em&gt;Casp8&lt;sup&gt;−/−&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; mice, &lt;em&gt;Casp8&lt;sup&gt;C362S/C362S&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; mouse embryos died after endothelial cell necroptosis leading to cardiovascular defects. MLKL deficiency rescued the cardiovascular phenotype but unexpectedly caused perinatal lethality in &lt;em&gt;Casp8&lt;sup&gt;C362S/C362S&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; mice, indicating that CASP8(C362S) causes necroptosis-independent death at later stages of embryonic development. Specific loss of the catalytic activity of caspase-8 in intestinal epithelial cells induced intestinal inflammation similar to intestinal epithelial cell-specific &lt;em&gt;Casp8&lt;/em&gt; knockout mice. Inhibition of necroptosis by additional deletion of &lt;em&gt;Mlkl&lt;/em&gt; severely aggravated intestinal inflammation and caused premature lethality in &lt;em&gt;Mlkl&lt;/em&gt; knockout mice with specific loss of caspase-8 catalytic activity in intestinal epithelial cells. Expression of CASP8(C362S) triggered the formation of ASC specks, activation of caspase-1 and secretion of IL-1β. Both embryonic lethality and premature death were completely rescued in &lt;em&gt;Casp8&lt;sup&gt;C362S/C362S&lt;/sup&gt;Mlkl&lt;sup&gt;−/−&lt;/sup&gt;Asc&lt;sup&gt;−/−&lt;/sup&gt;sup&amp;gt;&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;Casp8&lt;sup&gt;C362S/C362S&lt;/sup&gt;Mlkl&lt;sup&gt;−/−&lt;/sup&gt;Casp1&lt;sup&gt;−/−&lt;/sup&gt;sup&amp;gt;&lt;/em&gt; mice, indicating that the activation of the inflammasome promotes CASP8(C362S)-mediated tissue pathology when necroptosis is blocked. Therefore, caspase-8 represents the molecular switch that controls apoptosis, necroptosis and pyroptosis, and prevents tissue damage during embryonic development and adulthood.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>STYK1 promotes autophagy through enhancing the assembly of autophagy-specific class III phosphatidylinositol 3-kinase complex I</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/31696776/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/31696776/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Macroautophagy/autophagy plays key roles in development, oncogenesis, and cardiovascular and metabolic diseases. Autophagy-specific class III phosphatidylinositol 3-kinase complex I (PtdIns3K-C1) is essential for autophagosome formation. However, the regulation of this complex formation requires further investigation. Here, we discovered that STYK1 (serine/threonine/tyrosine kinase 1), a member of the receptor tyrosine kinases (RTKs) family, is a new upstream regulator of autophagy. We discovered that STYK1 facilitated autophagosome formation in human cells and zebrafish, which was characterized by elevated LC3-II and lowered SQSTM1/p62 levels and increased puncta formation by several marker proteins, such as ATG14, WIPI1, and ZFYVE1. Moreover, we observed that STYK1 directly binds to the PtdIns3K-C1 complex as a homodimer. The binding with this complex was promoted by Tyr191 phosphorylation, by means of which the kinase activity of STYK1 was elevated. We also demonstrated that STYK1 elevated the serine phosphorylation of BECN1, thereby decreasing the interaction between BECN1 and BCL2. Furthermore, we found that STYK1 preferentially facilitated the assembly of the PtdIns3K-C1 complex and was required for PtdIns3K-C1 complex kinase activity. Taken together, our findings provide new insights into autophagy induction and reveal evidence of novel crosstalk between the components of RTK signaling and autophagy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FSP1 is a glutathione-independent ferroptosis suppressor</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/31634899/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/31634899/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ferroptosis is an iron-dependent form of necrotic cell death marked by oxidative damage to phospholipids. To date, ferroptosis has been thought to be controlled only by the phospholipid hydroperoxide-reducing enzyme glutathione peroxidase 4 (GPX4) and radical-trapping antioxidants. However, elucidation of the factors that underlie the sensitivity of a given cell type to ferroptosis is crucial to understand the pathophysiological role of ferroptosis and how it may be exploited for the treatment of cancer. Although metabolic constraints and phospholipid composition contribute to ferroptosis sensitivity, no cell-autonomous mechanisms have been identified that account for the resistance of cells to ferroptosis. Here we used an expression cloning approach to identify genes in human cancer cells that are able to complement the loss of GPX4. We found that the flavoprotein apoptosis-inducing factor mitochondria-associated 2 (AIFM2) is a previously unrecognized anti-ferroptotic gene. AIFM2, which we renamed ferroptosis suppressor protein 1 (FSP1) and which was initially described as a pro-apoptotic gene, confers protection against ferroptosis elicited by GPX4 deletion. We further demonstrate that the suppression of ferroptosis by FSP1 is mediated by ubiquinone (also known as coenzyme Q&lt;sub&gt;10&lt;/sub&gt;, CoQ&lt;sub&gt;10&lt;/sub&gt;): the reduced form, ubiquinol, traps lipid peroxyl radicals that mediate lipid peroxidation, whereas FSP1 catalyses the regeneration of CoQ&lt;sub&gt;10&lt;/sub&gt; using NAD(P)H. Pharmacological targeting of FSP1 strongly synergizes with GPX4 inhibitors to trigger ferroptosis in a number of cancer entities. In conclusion, the FSP1-CoQ&lt;sub&gt;10&lt;/sub&gt;-NAD(P)H pathway exists as a stand-alone parallel system, which co-operates with GPX4 and glutathione to suppress phospholipid peroxidation and ferroptosis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The CoQ oxidoreductase FSP1 acts parallel to GPX4 to inhibit ferroptosis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/31634900/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/31634900/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ferroptosis is a form of regulated cell death that is caused by the iron-dependent peroxidation of lipids. The glutathione-dependent lipid hydroperoxidase glutathione peroxidase 4 (GPX4) prevents ferroptosis by converting lipid hydroperoxides into non-toxic lipid alcohols. Ferroptosis has previously been implicated in the cell death that underlies several degenerative conditions, and induction of ferroptosis by the inhibition of GPX4 has emerged as a therapeutic strategy to trigger cancer cell death. However, sensitivity to GPX4 inhibitors varies greatly across cancer cell lines, which suggests that additional factors govern resistance to ferroptosis. Here, using a synthetic lethal CRISPR-Cas9 screen, we identify ferroptosis suppressor protein 1 (FSP1) (previously known as apoptosis-inducing factor mitochondrial 2 (AIFM2)) as a potent ferroptosis-resistance factor. Our data indicate that myristoylation recruits FSP1 to the plasma membrane where it functions as an oxidoreductase that reduces coenzyme Q&lt;sub&gt;10&lt;/sub&gt; (CoQ) (also known as ubiquinone-10), which acts as a lipophilic radical-trapping antioxidant that halts the propagation of lipid peroxides. We further find that FSP1 expression positively correlates with ferroptosis resistance across hundreds of cancer cell lines, and that FSP1 mediates resistance to ferroptosis in lung cancer cells in culture and in mouse tumour xenografts. Thus, our data identify FSP1 as a key component of a non-mitochondrial CoQ antioxidant system that acts in parallel to the canonical glutathione-based GPX4 pathway. These findings define a ferroptosis suppression pathway and indicate that pharmacological inhibition of FSP1 may provide an effective strategy to sensitize cancer cells to ferroptosis-inducing chemotherapeutic agents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ubiquitination of RIPK1 suppresses programmed cell death by regulating RIPK1 kinase activation during embryogenesis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/31519886/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/31519886/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ubiquitination status of RIPK1 is considered to be critical for cell fate determination. However, the in vivo role for RIPK1 ubiquitination remains undefined. Here we show that mice expressing RIPK1&lt;sup&gt;K376R&lt;/sup&gt; which is defective in RIPK1 ubiquitination die during embryogenesis. This lethality is fully rescued by concomitant deletion of &lt;em&gt;Fadd&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Ripk3&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;Mlkl&lt;/em&gt;. Mechanistically, cells expressing RIPK1K376R are more susceptible to TNF-α induced apoptosis and necroptosis with more complex II formation and increased RIPK1 activation, which is consistent with the observation that &lt;em&gt;Ripk1&lt;sup&gt;K376R/K376R&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; lethality is effectively prevented by treatment of RIPK1 kinase inhibitor and is rescued by deletion of Tnfr1. However, &lt;em&gt;Tnfr1&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt; Ripk1&lt;sup&gt;K376R/K376R&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; mice display systemic inflammation and die within 2 weeks. Significantly, this lethal inflammation is rescued by deletion of &lt;em&gt;Ripk3&lt;/em&gt;. Taken together, these findings reveal a critical role of Lys376-mediated ubiquitination of RIPK1 in suppressing RIPK1 kinase activity-dependent lethal pathways during embryogenesis and RIPK3-dependent inflammation postnatally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A high-throughput screen identifies the long non-coding RNA DRAIC as a regulator of autophagy</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/30872794/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/30872794/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Autophagy is a conserved degradation process that occurs in all eukaryotic cells and its dysfunction has been associated with various diseases including cancer. While a number of large-scale attempts have recently identified new molecular players in autophagy regulation, including proteins and microRNAs, little is known regarding the function of long non-coding RNAs (lncRNAs) in the regulation of this process. To identify new long non-coding RNAs with functional implications in autophagy, we performed a high-throughput RNAi screen targeting more than 600 lncRNA transcripts and monitored their effects on autophagy in MCF-7 cells. We identified 63 lncRNAs that affected GFP-LC3B puncta numbers significantly. We validated the strongest hit, the lncRNA DRAIC previously shown to impact cell proliferation, and revealed a novel role for this lncRNA in the regulation of autophagic flux. Interestingly, we find DRAIC&amp;rsquo;s pro-proliferative effects to be autophagy-independent. This study serves as a valuable resource for researchers from both the lncRNA and autophagy fields as it advances the current understanding of autophagy regulation by non-coding RNAs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The role of STAT3 in autophagy</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/25951043/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/25951043/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Autophagy is an evolutionarily conserved process in eukaryotes that eliminates harmful components and maintains cellular homeostasis in response to a series of extracellular insults. However, these insults may trigger the downstream signaling of another prominent stress responsive pathway, the STAT3 signaling pathway, which has been implicated in multiple aspects of the autophagic process. Recent reports further indicate that different subcellular localization patterns of STAT3 affect autophagy in various ways. For example, nuclear STAT3 fine-tunes autophagy via the transcriptional regulation of several autophagy-related genes such as BCL2 family members, BECN1, PIK3C3, CTSB, CTSL, PIK3R1, HIF1A, BNIP3, and microRNAs with targets of autophagy modulators. Cytoplasmic STAT3 constitutively inhibits autophagy by sequestering EIF2AK2 as well as by interacting with other autophagy-related signaling molecules such as FOXO1 and FOXO3. Additionally, the mitochondrial translocation of STAT3 suppresses autophagy induced by oxidative stress and may effectively preserve mitochondria from being degraded by mitophagy. Understanding the role of STAT3 signaling in the regulation of autophagy may provide insight into the classic autophagy model and also into cancer therapy, especially for the emerging targeted therapy, because a series of targeted agents execute antitumor activities via blocking STAT3 signaling, which inevitably affects the autophagy pathway. Here, we review several of the representative studies and the current understanding in this particular field.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Molecular pathways: autophagy in cancer--a matter of timing and context</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/25165101/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/25165101/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Autophagy is an intracellular self-digestion mechanism, by which cellular components are sorted into double-membrane autophagosomes and delivered to lysosomes for degradation. Cells use autophagy to dispose of wastes and eliminate hazards, while recycling nutrients and tuning metabolism in the process. Through these functions, autophagy promotes cell fitness, genome integrity, tissue homeostasis, and cell survival and growth under stress. Both autophagy upregulation and downregulation have been found in human cancers, suggesting a complex role in tumor development. Accumulating results from autophagy-deficient mice and mouse models of human cancers have demonstrated that autophagy generally suppresses tumor initiation, but promotes tumor progression, in a manner that is dependent on timing and context and modified by specific tumorigenic events. Given the role of autophagy in facilitating tumor growth, autophagy inhibition has gained wide attention as a potential anticancer therapy. Here, we summarize relevant genetic, preclinical, and clinical studies and discuss the multifaceted role of autophagy in cancer, as well as the prospects of autophagy inhibition for cancer therapy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ferroptosis: an iron-dependent form of nonapoptotic cell death</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/22632970/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/22632970/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nonapoptotic forms of cell death may facilitate the selective elimination of some tumor cells or be activated in specific pathological states. The oncogenic RAS-selective lethal small molecule erastin triggers a unique iron-dependent form of nonapoptotic cell death that we term ferroptosis. Ferroptosis is dependent upon intracellular iron, but not other metals, and is morphologically, biochemically, and genetically distinct from apoptosis, necrosis, and autophagy. We identify the small molecule ferrostatin-1 as a potent inhibitor of ferroptosis in cancer cells and glutamate-induced cell death in organotypic rat brain slices, suggesting similarities between these two processes. Indeed, erastin, like glutamate, inhibits cystine uptake by the cystine/glutamate antiporter (system x(c)(-)), creating a void in the antioxidant defenses of the cell and ultimately leading to iron-dependent, oxidative death. Thus, activation of ferroptosis results in the nonapoptotic destruction of certain cancer cells, whereas inhibition of this process may protect organisms from neurodegeneration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anoikis: an emerging hallmark in health and diseases</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/21953325/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/21953325/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anoikis is a programmed cell death occurring upon cell detachment from the correct extracellular matrix, thus disrupting integrin ligation. It is a critical mechanism in preventing dysplastic cell growth or attachment to an inappropriate matrix. Anoikis prevents detached epithelial cells from colonizing elsewhere and is thus essential for tissue homeostasis and development. As anchorage-independent growth and epithelial-mesenchymal transition, two features associated with anoikis resistance, are crucial steps during tumour progression and metastatic spreading of cancer cells, anoikis deregulation has now evoked particular attention from the scientific community. The aim of this review is to analyse the molecular mechanisms governing both anoikis and anoikis resistance, focusing on their regulation in physiological processes, as well as in several diseases, including metastatic cancers, cardiovascular diseases and diabetes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Synthetic lethal screening identifies compounds activating iron-dependent, nonapoptotic cell death in oncogenic-RAS-harboring cancer cells</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/18355723/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/18355723/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We screened small molecules to identify two compounds, which we named RSL3 and RSL5, that have increased lethality in the presence of oncogenic RAS. Counter screening with biologically active compounds defined aspects of the mechanism of action for RSL3 and RSL5, such as a nonapoptotic, MEK-dependent, and iron-dependent oxidative cell death. Erastin, a previously reported compound with RAS-selective lethality, showed similar properties. RNA interference experiments targeting voltage-dependent anion channel 3 (VDAC3), a target of erastin, demonstrated that RSL5 is a scaffold that acts through VDACs to activate the observed pathway. RSL3 activated a similar death mechanism but in a VDAC-independent manner. We found that cells transformed with oncogenic RAS have increased iron content relative to their normal cell counterparts through upregulation of transferrin receptor 1 and downregulation of ferritin heavy chain 1 and ferritin light chain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RAS-RAF-MEK-dependent oxidative cell death involving voltage-dependent anion channels</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/17568748/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jun 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/17568748/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therapeutics that discriminate between the genetic makeup of normal cells and tumour cells are valuable for treating and understanding cancer. Small molecules with oncogene-selective lethality may reveal novel functions of oncoproteins and enable the creation of more selective drugs. Here we describe the mechanism of action of the selective anti-tumour agent erastin, involving the RAS-RAF-MEK signalling pathway functioning in cell proliferation, differentiation and survival. Erastin exhibits greater lethality in human tumour cells harbouring mutations in the oncogenes HRAS, KRAS or BRAF. Using affinity purification and mass spectrometry, we discovered that erastin acts through mitochondrial voltage-dependent anion channels (VDACs)&amp;ndash;a novel target for anti-cancer drugs. We show that erastin treatment of cells harbouring oncogenic RAS causes the appearance of oxidative species and subsequent death through an oxidative, non-apoptotic mechanism. RNA-interference-mediated knockdown of VDAC2 or VDAC3 caused resistance to erastin, implicating these two VDAC isoforms in the mechanism of action of erastin. Moreover, using purified mitochondria expressing a single VDAC isoform, we found that erastin alters the permeability of the outer mitochondrial membrane. Finally, using a radiolabelled analogue and a filter-binding assay, we show that erastin binds directly to VDAC2. These results demonstrate that ligands to VDAC proteins can induce non-apoptotic cell death selectively in some tumour cells harbouring activating mutations in the RAS-RAF-MEK pathway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
