<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cell Death | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/cell-death/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/cell-death/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Cell Death</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Cell Death</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/cell-death/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>E3 ligase TRIM25 ubiquitinates RIP3 to inhibit TNF induced cell necrosis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33953350/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33953350/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Receptor interacting protein kinase 3 (RIP3 or RIPK3), the critical executor of cell programmed necrosis, plays essential roles in maintaining immune responses and appropriate tissue homeostasis. Although the E3 ligases CHIP and PELI1 are reported to promote RIP3 degradation, however, how post-translational modification regulates RIP3 activity and stability is poorly understood. Here, we identify the tripartite motif protein TRIM25 as a negative regulator of RIP3-dependent necrosis. TRIM25 directly interacts with RIP3 through its SPRY domain and mediates the K48-linked polyubiquitination of RIP3 on residue K501. The RING domain of TRIM25 facilitates the polyubiquitination chain on RIP3, thereby promoting proteasomal degradation of RIP3. Also, TRIM25 deficiency inhibited the ubiquitination of RIP3, thus promoting TNF-induced cell necrosis. Our current finding reveals the regulating mechanism of polyubiquitination on RIP3, which might be a potential therapeutic target for the intervention of RIP3-dependent necrosis-related diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DDRGK1, a crucial player of ufmylation system, is indispensable for autophagic degradation by regulating lysosomal function</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33879777/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33879777/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DDRGK domain-containing protein 1 (DDRGK1) is an important component of the newly discovered ufmylation system and its absence has been reported to induce extensive endoplasmic reticulum (ER) stress. Recently, emerging evidence indicates that the ufmylation system is correlated with autophagy, although the exact mechanism remains largely unknown. To explore the regulation mechanism of DDRGK1 on autophagy, in this study, we established an immortalized mouse embryonic fibroblast (MEF) cell lines harvested from the DDRGK1F/F:ROSA26-CreERT2 mice, in which DDRGK1 depletion can be induced by 4-hydroxytamoxifen (4-OHT) treatment. Here, we show that DDRGK1 deficiency in MEFs has a dual effect on autophagy, which leads to a significant accumulation of autophagosomes. On one hand, it promotes autophagy induction by impairing mTOR signaling; on the other hand, it blocks autophagy degradation by inhibiting autophagosome-lysosome fusion. This dual effect of DDRGK1 depletion on autophagy ultimately aggravates apoptosis in MEFs. Further studies reveal that DDRGK1 loss is correlated with suppressed lysosomal function, including impaired Cathepsin D (CTSD) expression, aberrant lysosomal pH, and v-ATPase accumulation, which might be a potential trigger for impairment in autophagy process. Hence, this study confirms a crucial role of DDRGK1 as an autophagy regulator by controlling lysosomal function. It may provide a theoretical basis for the treatment strategies of various physiological diseases caused by DDRGK1 deficiency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Structural insight into the molecular mechanism of p53-mediated mitochondrial apoptosis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33863900/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33863900/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tumor suppressor p53 is mutated in approximately half of all human cancers. p53 can induce apoptosis through mitochondrial membrane permeabilization by interacting with and antagonizing the anti-apoptotic proteins BCL-xL and BCL-2. However, the mechanisms by which p53 induces mitochondrial apoptosis remain elusive. Here, we report a 2.5 Å crystal structure of human p53/BCL-xL complex. In this structure, two p53 molecules interact as a homodimer, and bind one BCL-xL molecule to form a ternary complex with a 2:1 stoichiometry. Mutations at the p53 dimer interface or p53/BCL-xL interface disrupt p53/BCL-xL interaction and p53-mediated apoptosis. Overall, our current findings of the bona fide structure of p53/BCL-xL complex reveal the molecular basis of the interaction between p53 and BCL-xL, and provide insight into p53-mediated mitochondrial apoptosis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Proteomics reveals distinct mechanisms regulating the release of cytokines and alarmins during pyroptosis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33691121/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33691121/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A major pathway for proinflammatory protein release by macrophages is inflammasome-mediated pyroptotic cell death. As conventional secretion, unconventional secretion, and cell death are executed simultaneously, however, the cellular mechanisms regulating this complex paracrine program remain incompletely understood. Here, we devise a quantitative proteomics strategy to define the cellular exit route for each protein by pharmacological and genetic dissection of cellular checkpoints regulating protein release. We report the release of hundreds of proteins during pyroptosis, predominantly due to cell lysis. They comprise constitutively expressed and transcriptionally induced proteins derived from the cytoplasm and specific intracellular organelles. Many low-molecular-weight proteins including the cytokine interleukin-1β, alarmins, and lysosomal-cargo proteins exit cells in the absence of cell lysis. Cytokines and alarmins are released in an endoplasmic reticulum (ER)-Golgi-dependent manner as free proteins rather than by extracellular vesicles. Our work provides an experimental framework for the dissection of cellular exit pathways and a resource for pyroptotic protein release.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SRSF1 inhibits autophagy through regulating Bcl-x splicing and interacting with PIK3C3 in lung cancer</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33664238/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33664238/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alternative splicing is a critical process to generate protein diversity. However, whether and how alternative splicing regulates autophagy remains largely elusive. Here we systematically identify the splicing factor SRSF1 as an autophagy suppressor. Specifically, SRSF1 inhibits autophagosome formation by reducing the accumulation of LC3-II and numbers of autophagosomes in different cell lines. Mechanistically, SRSF1 promotes the splicing of the long isoform of Bcl-x that interacts with Beclin1, thereby dissociating the Beclin1-PIK3C3 complex. In addition, SRSF1 also directly interacts with PIK3C3 to disrupt the interaction between Beclin1 and PIK3C3. Consequently, the decrease of SRSF1 stabilizes the Beclin1 and PIK3C3 complex and activates autophagy. Interestingly, SRSF1 can be degraded by starvation- and oxidative stresses-induced autophagy through interacting with LC3-II, whereas reduced SRSF1 further promotes autophagy. This positive feedback is critical to inhibiting Gefitinib-resistant cancer cell progression both in vitro and in vivo. Consistently, the expression level of SRSF1 is inversely correlated to LC3 level in clinical cancer samples. Our study not only provides mechanistic insights of alternative splicing in autophagy regulation but also discovers a new regulatory role of SRSF1 in tumorigenesis, thereby offering a novel avenue for potential cancer therapeutics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NINJ1 mediates plasma membrane rupture during lytic cell death</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33472215/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33472215/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Plasma membrane rupture (PMR) is the final cataclysmic event in lytic cell death. PMR releases intracellular molecules known as damage-associated molecular patterns (DAMPs) that propagate the inflammatory response. The underlying mechanism of PMR, however, is unknown. Here we show that the cell-surface NINJ1 protein, which contains two transmembrane regions, has an essential role in the induction of PMR. A forward-genetic screen of randomly mutagenized mice linked NINJ1 to PMR. Ninj1&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt; macrophages exhibited impaired PMR in response to diverse inducers of pyroptotic, necrotic and apoptotic cell death, and were unable to release numerous intracellular proteins including HMGB1 (a known DAMP) and LDH (a standard measure of PMR). Ninj1&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt; macrophages died, but with a distinctive and persistent ballooned morphology, attributable to defective disintegration of bubble-like herniations. Ninj1&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt; mice were more susceptible than wild-type mice to infection with Citrobacter rodentium, which suggests a role for PMR in anti-bacterial host defence. Mechanistically, NINJ1 used an evolutionarily conserved extracellular domain for oligomerization and subsequent PMR. The discovery of NINJ1 as a mediator of PMR overturns the long-held idea that cell death-related PMR is a passive event.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Identification and Validation of Autophagy-Related Genes in Chronic Obstructive Pulmonary Disease</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33469280/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33469280/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Purpose:&lt;/em&gt; Autophagy plays essential roles in the development of COPD. We aim to identify and validate the potential autophagy-related genes of COPD through bioinformatics analysis and experiment validation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; The mRNA expression profile dataset GSE38974 was obtained from GEO database. The potential differentially expressed autophagy-related genes of COPD were screened by R software. Then, protein–protein interactions (PPI), correlation analysis, gene-ontology (GO) enrichment analysis and Kyoto Encyclopedia of Genes and Genomes (KEGG) pathway enrichment analysis were applied for the differentially expressed autophagy-related genes. Finally, RNA expression of top five differentially expressed autophagy-related genes was validated in blood samples from COPD patients and healthy controls by qRT-PCR.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; A total of 40 differentially expressed autophagy-related genes (14 up-regulated genes and 26 down-regulated genes) were identified between 23 COPD patients and 9 healthy controls. The PPI results demonstrated that these autophagy-related genes interacted with each other. The GO and KEGG enrichment analysis of differentially expressed autophagy-related genes indicated several enriched terms related to autophagy and mitophagy. The results of qRT-PCR showed that the expression levels of &lt;em&gt;HIF1A&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;CDKN1A&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;BAG3&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;ERBB2&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;ATG16L1&lt;/em&gt; in COPD patients and healthy controls were consistent with the bioinformatics analysis results from mRNA microarray.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/em&gt; We identified 40 potential autophagy-related genes of COPD through bioinformatics analysis. &lt;em&gt;HIF1A&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;CDKN1A&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;BAG3&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;ERBB2&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;ATG16L1&lt;/em&gt; may affect the development of COPD by regulating autophagy. These results may expand our understanding of COPD and might be useful in the treatment of COPD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apaf-1 Pyroptosome Senses Mitochondrial Permeability Transition</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33308446/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33308446/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Caspase-4 is an intracellular sensor for cytosolic bacterial lipopolysaccharide (LPS) and underlies infection-elicited pyroptosis. It is unclear whether and how caspase-4 detects host-derived factors to trigger pyroptosis. Here we show that mitochondrial permeability transition (MPT) activates caspase-4 by promoting the assembly of a protein complex, which we term the Apaf-1 pyroptosome, for the execution of facilitated pyroptosis. MPT, when induced by bile acids, calcium overload, or an adenine nucleotide translocator 1 (ANT1) activator, triggers assembly of the pyroptosome comprised of Apaf-1 and caspase-4 with a stoichiometry ratio of 7:2. Unlike the direct cleavage of gasdermin D (GSDMD) by caspase-4 upon LPS ligation, caspase-4 activated in the Apaf-1 pyroptosome proceeds to cleave caspase-3 and thereby GSDME to induce pyroptosis. Caspase-4-initiated and GSDME-executed pyroptosis underlies cholestatic liver failure. These findings identify Apaf-1 pyroptosome as a pivotal machinery for cells sensing MPT signals and may shed light on understanding how cells execute intrinsic pyroptosis under sterile conditions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Complement and tissue factor-enriched neutrophil extracellular traps are key drivers in COVID-19 immunothrombosis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32759504/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32759504/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Emerging data indicate that complement and neutrophils contribute to the maladaptive immune response that fuels hyperinflammation and thrombotic microangiopathy, thereby increasing coronavirus 2019 (COVID-19) mortality. Here, we investigated how complement interacts with the platelet/neutrophil extracellular traps (NETs)/thrombin axis, using COVID-19 specimens, cell-based inhibition studies, and NET/human aortic endothelial cell (HAEC) cocultures. Increased plasma levels of NETs, tissue factor (TF) activity, and sC5b-9 were detected in patients. Neutrophils of patients yielded high TF expression and released NETs carrying active TF. Treatment of control neutrophils with COVID-19 platelet-rich plasma generated TF-bearing NETs that induced thrombotic activity of HAECs. Thrombin or NETosis inhibition or C5aR1 blockade attenuated platelet-mediated NET-driven thrombogenicity. COVID-19 serum induced complement activation in vitro, consistent with high complement activity in clinical samples. Complement C3 inhibition with compstatin Cp40 disrupted TF expression in neutrophils. In conclusion, we provide a mechanistic basis for a pivotal role of complement and NETs in COVID-19 immunothrombosis. This study supports strategies against severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 that exploit complement or NETosis inhibition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paradoxical Mitophagy Regulation by PINK1 and TUFm</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33113344/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33113344/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sepsis is the major cause of acute kidney injury (AKI) associated with high mortality rates. Mitochondrial dysfunction contributes to the pathophysiology of septic AKI. Mitophagy is an important mitochondrial quality control mechanism that selectively eliminates damaged mitochondria, but its role and regulation in septic AKI remain largely unknown. Here, we demonstrate the induction of mitophagy in mouse models of septic AKI induced by lipopolysaccharide (LPS) treatment or by cecal ligation and puncture. Mitophagy was also induced in cultured proximal tubular epithelial cells exposed to LPS. Induction of mitophagy under these experimental setting was suppressed by pink1 or park2 knockout, indicating the role of the PINK1/PARK2 pathway of mitophagy in septic AKI. In addition, sepsis induced more severe kidney injury and cell apoptosis in pink1 or park2 knockout mice than in wild-type mice, suggesting a beneficial role of mitophagy in septic AKI. Furthermore, in cultured renal tubular cells treated with LPS, knockdown of pink1 or park2 inhibited mitochondrial accumulation of the autophagy adaptor optineurin (OPTN) and silencing Optn inhibited LPS-induced mitophagy. Taken together, these findings suggest that the PINK1/PARK2 pathway of mitophagy plays an important role in mitochondrial quality control, tubular cell survival, and renal function in septic AKI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>microRNA-199a-3p inhibits hepatic apoptosis and hepatocarcinogenesis by targeting PDCD4</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33099584/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33099584/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hepatic apoptosis and the initiated liver inflammation play the initial roles in inflammation-induced hepatocarcinogenesis. Molecular mechanisms underlying the regulation of hepatocyte apoptosis and their roles in hepatocarcinogenesis have attracted much attention. A set of microRNAs (miRNAs) have been determined to be dysregulated in hepatocellular carcinoma (HCC) and participated in cancer progression, however, the roles of these dysregulated miRNAs in carcinogenesis are still poorly understood. We previously analyzed the dysregulated miRNAs in HCC using high-throughput sequencing, and found that miR-199a/b-3p was abundantly expressed in human normal liver while markedly decreased in HCC, which promotes HCC progression. Whether miR-199a/b-3p participates in HCC carcinogenesis is still unknown up to now. Hence, we focused on the role and mechanism of miR-199a/b-3p in hepatocarcinogenesis in this study. Hepatic miR-199a/b-3p was determined to be expressed by miR-199a-2 gene in mice, and we constructed miR-199a-2 knockout and hepatocyte-specific miR-199a-2 knockout mice. Diethylnitrosamine (DEN)-induced hepatocarcinogenesis were markedly increased by hepatocyte-specific miR-199a-3p knockout, which is mediated by the enhanced hepatocyte apoptosis and hepatic injury by DEN administration. In acetaminophen (APAP)-induced acute hepatic injury model, hepatocyte-specific miR-199a-3p knockout also aggravated hepatic apoptosis. By proteomic screening and reporter gene validation, we identified and verified that hepatic programed cell death 4 (PDCD4), which promotes apoptosis, was directly targeted by miR-199a-3p. Furthermore, we confirmed that miR-199a-3p-suppressed hepatocyte apoptosis and hepatic injury by targeting and suppressing PDCD4. Thus, hepatic miR-199a-3p inhibits hepatocyte apoptosis and hepatocarcinogenesis, and decreased miR-199a-3p in hepatocytes may aggravate hepatic injury and HCC development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The PINK1/PARK2/optineurin pathway of mitophagy is activated for protection in septic acute kidney injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33137712/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33137712/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sepsis is the major cause of acute kidney injury (AKI) associated with high mortality rates. Mitochondrial dysfunction contributes to the pathophysiology of septic AKI. Mitophagy is an important mitochondrial quality control mechanism that selectively eliminates damaged mitochondria, but its role and regulation in septic AKI remain largely unknown. Here, we demonstrate the induction of mitophagy in mouse models of septic AKI induced by lipopolysaccharide (LPS) treatment or by cecal ligation and puncture. Mitophagy was also induced in cultured proximal tubular epithelial cells exposed to LPS. Induction of mitophagy under these experimental setting was suppressed by pink1 or park2 knockout, indicating the role of the PINK1/PARK2 pathway of mitophagy in septic AKI. In addition, sepsis induced more severe kidney injury and cell apoptosis in pink1 or park2 knockout mice than in wild-type mice, suggesting a beneficial role of mitophagy in septic AKI. Furthermore, in cultured renal tubular cells treated with LPS, knockdown of pink1 or park2 inhibited mitochondrial accumulation of the autophagy adaptor optineurin (OPTN) and silencing Optn inhibited LPS-induced mitophagy. Taken together, these findings suggest that the PINK1/PARK2 pathway of mitophagy plays an important role in mitochondrial quality control, tubular cell survival, and renal function in septic AKI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>USP19 suppresses inflammation and promotes M2-like macrophage polarization by manipulating NLRP3 function via autophagy</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33097834/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33097834/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Macrophage polarization to proinflammatory M1-like or anti-inflammatory M2-like cells is critical to mount a host defense or repair tissue. The exact molecular mechanisms controlling this process are still elusive. Here, we report that ubiquitin-specific protease 19 (USP19) acts as an anti-inflammatory switch that inhibits inflammatory responses and promotes M2-like macrophage polarization. USP19 inhibited NLRP3 inflammasome activation by increasing autophagy flux and decreasing the generation of mitochondrial reactive oxygen species. In addition, USP19 inhibited the proteasomal degradation of inflammasome-independent NLRP3 by cleaving its polyubiquitin chains. USP19-stabilized NLRP3 promoted M2-like macrophage polarization by direct association with interferon regulatory factor 4, thereby preventing its p62-mediated selective autophagic degradation. Consistent with these observations, compared to wild-type mice, Usp19-/- mice had decreased M2-like macrophage polarization and increased interleukin-1β secretion, in response to alum and chitin injections. Thus, we have uncovered an unexpected mechanism by which USP19 switches the proinflammatory function of NLRP3 into an anti-inflammatory function, and suggest that USP19 is a potential therapeutic target for inflammatory interventions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TSPAN1 promotes autophagy flux and mediates cooperation between WNT-CTNNB1 signaling and autophagy via the MIR454-FAM83A-TSPAN1 axis in pancreatic cancer</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32972302/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32972302/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pancreatic cancer is one of the most aggressive tumors associated with a poor clinical prognosis, weakly effective therapeutic options. Therefore, there is a strong impetus to discover new therapeutic targets in pancreatic cancer. In the present study, we first demonstrated that TSPAN1 is upregulated in pancreatic cancer and that TSPAN1 depletion decreases pancreatic cancer cell proliferation in vitro and in vivo. TSPAN1 expression was correlated with poor overall survival of pancreatic cancer patients. Moreover, we demonstrated that TSPAN1 is a novel positive regulator of macroautophagy/autophagy characterized by decreased LC3-II and SQSTM1/p62 expressions, inhibited puncta formation of GFP-LC3 and autophagic vacuoles. We also demonstrated that tspan1 mutation impaired autophagy in the zebrafish model. Furthermore, we showed that TSPAN1 promoted autophagy maturation via direct binding to LC3 by two conserved LIR motifs. Mutations in the LIR motifs of TSPAN1 resulted in a loss of the ability to induce autophagy and promote pancreatic cancer proliferation. Second, we discovered two conservative TCF/LEF binding elements present in the promoter region of the TSPAN1 gene, which was further verified through luciferase activity and ChIP assays. Furthermore, TSPAN1 was upregulated by FAM83A through the canonical WNT-CTNNB1 signaling pathway. We further demonstrated that both TSPAN1 and FAM83A are both direct targets of MIR454 (microRNA 454). Additionally, we revealed the role of MIR454-FAM83A-TSPAN1 in the proliferation of pancreatic cancer cells in vitro and in vivo. Our findings suggest that components of the MIR454-FAM83A-TSPAN1 axis may be valuable prognosis markers or therapeutic targets for pancreatic cancer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A gene expression signature of TREM2hi macrophages and γδ T cells predicts immunotherapy response</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33033253/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33033253/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Identifying factors underlying resistance to immune checkpoint therapy (ICT) is still challenging. Most cancer patients do not respond to ICT and the availability of the predictive biomarkers is limited. Here, we re-analyze a publicly available single-cell RNA sequencing (scRNA-seq) dataset of melanoma samples of patients subjected to ICT and identify a subset of macrophages overexpressing TREM2 and a subset of gammadelta T cells that are both overrepresented in the non-responding tumors. In addition, the percentage of a B cell subset is significantly lower in the non-responders. The presence of these immune cell subtypes is corroborated in other publicly available scRNA-seq datasets. The analyses of bulk RNA-seq datasets of the melanoma samples identify and validate a signature - ImmuneCells.Sig - enriched with the genes characteristic of the above immune cell subsets to predict response to immunotherapy. ImmuneCells.Sig could represent a valuable tool for clinical decision making in patients receiving immunotherapy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bacterial nanotubes as a manifestation of cell death</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33009406/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33009406/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bacterial nanotubes are membranous structures that have been reported to function as conduits between cells to exchange DNA, proteins, and nutrients. Here, we investigate the morphology and formation of bacterial nanotubes using Bacillus subtilis. We show that nanotube formation is associated with stress conditions, and is highly sensitive to the cells&amp;rsquo; genetic background, growth phase, and sample preparation methods. Remarkably, nanotubes appear to be extruded exclusively from dying cells, likely as a result of biophysical forces. Their emergence is extremely fast, occurring within seconds by cannibalizing the cell membrane. Subsequent experiments reveal that cell-to-cell transfer of non-conjugative plasmids depends strictly on the competence system of the cell, and not on nanotube formation. Our study thus supports the notion that bacterial nanotubes are a post mortem phenomenon involved in cell disintegration, and are unlikely to be involved in cytoplasmic content exchange between live cells.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Decoding three distinct states of the Syntaxin17 SNARE motif in mediating autophagosome-lysosome fusion</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32817423/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32817423/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Syntaxin17, a key autophagosomal N-ethylmaleimide-sensitive factor attachment protein receptor (SNARE) protein, can associate with ATG8 family proteins SNAP29 and VAMP8 to facilitate the membrane fusion process between the double-membraned autophagosome and single-membraned lysosome in mammalian macroautophagy. However, the inherent properties of Syntaxin17 and the mechanistic basis underlying the interactions of Syntaxin17 with its binding proteins remain largely unknown. Here, using biochemical, NMR, and structural approaches, we systemically characterized Syntaxin17 as well as its interactions with ATG8 family proteins, SNAP29 and VAMP8. We discovered that Syntaxin17 alone adopts an autoinhibited conformation mediated by a direct interaction between its Habc domain and the Qa-SNARE motif. In addition, we revealed that the Qa-SNARE region of Syntaxin17 contains one LC3-interacting region (LIR) motif, which preferentially binds to GABARAP subfamily members. Importantly, the GABARAP binding of Syntaxin17 can release its autoinhibited state. The determined crystal structure of the Syntaxin17 LIR-GABARAP complex not only provides mechanistic insights into the interaction between Syntaxin17 and GABARAP but also reveals an unconventional LIR motif with a C-terminally extended 310 helix for selectively binding to ATG8 family proteins. Finally, we also elucidated structural arrangements of the autophagic Syntaxin17-SNAP29-VAMP8 SNARE core complex, and uncovered its conserved biochemical and structural characteristics common to all other SNAREs. In all, our findings reveal three distinct states of Syntaxin17, and provide mechanistic insights into the Syntaxin17-mediated autophagosome-lysosome fusion process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Autophagy regulates fatty acid availability for oxidative phosphorylation through mitochondria-endoplasmic reticulum contact sites</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32792483/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32792483/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Autophagy has been associated with oncogenesis with one of its emerging key functions being its contribution to the metabolism of tumors. Therefore, deciphering the mechanisms of how autophagy supports tumor cell metabolism is essential. Here, we demonstrate that the inhibition of autophagy induces an accumulation of lipid droplets (LD) due to a decrease in fatty acid β-oxidation, that leads to a reduction of oxidative phosphorylation (OxPHOS) in acute myeloid leukemia (AML), but not in normal cells. Thus, the autophagic process participates in lipid catabolism that supports OxPHOS in AML cells. Interestingly, the inhibition of OxPHOS leads to LD accumulation with the concomitant inhibition of autophagy. Mechanistically, we show that the disruption of mitochondria-endoplasmic reticulum (ER) contact sites (MERCs) phenocopies OxPHOS inhibition. Altogether, our data establish that mitochondria, through the regulation of MERCs, controls autophagy that, in turn finely tunes lipid degradation to fuel OxPHOS supporting proliferation and growth in leukemia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hepatic transferrin plays a role in systemic iron homeostasis and liver ferroptosis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32374849/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32374849/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although the serum-abundant metal-binding protein transferrin (encoded by the &lt;em&gt;Trf&lt;/em&gt; gene) is synthesized primarily in the liver, its function in the liver is largely unknown. Here, we generated hepatocyte-specific &lt;em&gt;Trf&lt;/em&gt; knockout mice (&lt;em&gt;Trf&lt;/em&gt;-LKO), which are viable and fertile but have impaired erythropoiesis and altered iron metabolism. Moreover, feeding &lt;em&gt;Trf&lt;/em&gt;-LKO mice a high-iron diet increased their susceptibility to developing ferroptosis-induced liver fibrosis. Importantly, we found that treating &lt;em&gt;Trf&lt;/em&gt;-LKO mice with the ferroptosis inhibitor ferrostatin-1 potently rescued liver fibrosis induced by either high dietary iron or carbon tetrachloride (CCl&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;) injections. In addition, deleting hepatic Slc39a14 expression in &lt;em&gt;Trf&lt;/em&gt;-LKO mice significantly reduced hepatic iron accumulation, thereby reducing ferroptosis-mediated liver fibrosis induced by either a high-iron diet or CCl&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; injections. Finally, we found that patients with liver cirrhosis have significantly lower levels of serum transferrin and hepatic transferrin, as well as higher levels of hepatic iron and lipid peroxidation, compared with healthy control subjects. Taken together, these data indicate that hepatic transferrin plays a protective role in maintaining liver function, providing a possible therapeutic target for preventing ferroptosis-induced liver fibrosis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A novel selective autophagy receptor, CCDC50, delivers K63 polyubiquitination-activated RIG-I/MDA5 for degradation during viral infection</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32612200/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32612200/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Autophagy is a conserved process that delivers cytosolic substances to the lysosome for degradation, but its direct role in the regulation of antiviral innate immunity remains poorly understood. Here, through high-throughput screening, we discovered that CCDC50 functions as a previously unknown autophagy receptor that negatively regulates the type I interferon (IFN) signaling pathway initiated by RIG-I-like receptors (RLRs), the sensors for RNA viruses. The expression of CCDC50 is enhanced by viral infection, and CCDC50 specifically recognizes K63-polyubiquitinated RLRs, thus delivering the activated RIG-I/MDA5 for autophagic degradation. The association of CCDC50 with phagophore membrane protein LC3 is confirmed by crystal structure analysis. In contrast to other known autophagic cargo receptors that associate with either the LIR-docking site (LDS) or the UIM-docking site (UDS) of LC3, CCDC50 can bind to both LDS and UDS, representing a new type of cargo receptor. In mouse models with RNA virus infection, CCDC50 deficiency reduces the autophagic degradation of RIG-I/MDA5 and promotes type I IFN responses, resulting in enhanced viral resistance and improved survival rates. These results reveal a new link between autophagy and antiviral innate immune responses and provide additional insights into the regulatory mechanisms of RLR-mediated antiviral signaling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Decreased Hepatocyte Autophagy Leads to Synergistic IL-1β and TNF Mouse Liver Injury and Inflammation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32108953/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32108953/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background and aims:&lt;/em&gt; The proinflammatory cytokine IL-1β has been implicated in the pathophysiology of nonalcoholic and alcoholic steatohepatitis. How IL-1β promotes liver injury in these diseases is unclear, as no IL-1β receptor-linked death pathway has been identified. Autophagy functions in hepatocyte resistance to injury and death, and findings of decreased hepatic autophagy in many liver diseases suggest a role for impaired autophagy in disease pathogenesis. Recent findings that autophagy blocks mouse liver injury from lipopolysaccharide led to an examination of autophagy&amp;rsquo;s function in hepatotoxicity from proinflammatory cytokines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Approach and results:&lt;/em&gt; AML12 cells with decreased autophagy from a lentiviral autophagy-related 5 (Atg5) knockdown were resistant to toxicity from TNF, but sensitized to death from IL-1β, which was markedly amplified by TNF co-treatment. IL-1β/TNF death was necrosis by trypan blue and propidium iodide positivity, absence of mitochondrial death pathway and caspase activation, and failure of a caspase inhibitor or necrostatin-1s to prevent death. IL-1β/TNF depleted autophagy-deficient cells of ATP, and ATP depletion and cell death were prevented by supplementation with the energy substrate pyruvate or oleate. Pharmacological inhibitors and genetic knockdown studies demonstrated that IL-1β/TNF-induced necrosis resulted from lysosomal permeabilization and release of cathepsins B and L in autophagy-deficient cells. Mice with a tamoxifen-inducible, hepatocyte-specific Atg5 knockout were similarly sensitized to cathepsin-dependent hepatocellular injury and death from IL-1β/TNF in combination, but neither IL-1β nor TNF alone. Knockout mice had increased hepatic inflammation, and IL-1β/TNF-treated, autophagy-deficient AML12 cells secreted exosomes with proinflammatory damage-associated molecular patterns.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; The findings delineate mechanisms by which decreased hepatocyte autophagy promotes IL-1β/TNF-induced necrosis from impaired energy homeostasis and lysosomal permeabilization and inflammation through the secretion of exosomal damage-associated molecular patterns.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interferon regulatory factor 1 regulates PANoptosis to prevent colorectal cancer</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32554929/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32554929/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interferon regulatory factor 1 (IRF1) regulates diverse biological functions, including modulation of cellular responses involved in tumorigenesis. Genetic mutations and altered IRF1 function are associated with several cancers. Although the function of IRF1 in the immunobiology of cancer is emerging, IRF1-specific mechanisms regulating tumorigenesis and tissue homeostasis in vivo are not clear. Here, we found that mice lacking IRF1 were hypersusceptible to colorectal tumorigenesis. IRF1 functions in both the myeloid and epithelial compartments to confer protection against AOM/DSS-induced colorectal tumorigenesis. We further found that IRF1 also prevents tumorigenesis in a spontaneous mouse model of colorectal cancer. The attenuated cell death in the colons of Irf1-/- mice was due to defective pyroptosis, apoptosis, and necroptosis (PANoptosis). IRF1 does not regulate inflammation and the inflammasome in the colon. Overall, our study identified IRF1 as an upstream regulator of PANoptosis to induce cell death during colitis-associated tumorigenesis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Identification of the PANoptosome: A Molecular Platform Triggering Pyroptosis, Apoptosis, and Necroptosis (PANoptosis)</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32547960/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32547960/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Programmed cell death plays crucial roles in organismal development and host defense. Recent studies have highlighted mechanistic overlaps and extensive, multifaceted crosstalk between pyroptosis, apoptosis, and necroptosis, three programmed cell death pathways traditionally considered autonomous. The growing body of evidence, in conjunction with the identification of molecules controlling the concomitant activation of all three pathways by pathological triggers, has led to the development of the concept of PANoptosis. During PANoptosis, inflammatory cell death occurs through the collective activation of pyroptosis, apoptosis, and necroptosis, which can circumvent pathogen-mediated inhibition of individual death pathways. Many of the molecular details of this emerging pathway are unclear. Here, we describe the activation of PANoptosis by bacterial and viral triggers and report protein interactions that reveal the formation of a PANoptosome complex. Infection of macrophages with influenza A virus, vesicular stomatitis virus, Listeria monocytogenes, or Salmonella enterica serovar Typhimurium resulted in robust cell death and the hallmarks of PANoptosis activation. Combined deletion of the PANoptotic components caspase-1 (CASP1), CASP11, receptor-interacting serine/threonine-protein kinase 3 (RIPK3), and CASP8 largely protected macrophages from cell death induced by these pathogens, while deletion of individual components provided reduced or no protection. Further, molecules from the pyroptotic, apoptotic, and necroptotic cell death pathways interacted to form a single molecular complex that we have termed the PANoptosome. Overall, our study identifies pathogens capable of activating PANoptosis and the formation of a PANoptosome complex.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visualizing and Modulating Mitophagy for Therapeutic Studies of Neurodegeneration</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32437660/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32437660/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dysfunctional mitochondria accumulate in many human diseases. Accordingly, mitophagy, which removes these mitochondria through lysosomal degradation, is attracting broad attention. Due to uncertainties in the operational principles of conventional mitophagy probes, however, the specificity and quantitativeness of their readouts are disputable. Thorough investigation of the behaviors and fates of fluorescent proteins inside and outside lysosomes enabled us to develop an indicator for mitophagy, mito-SRAI. Through strict control of its mitochondrial targeting, we were able to monitor mitophagy in fixed biological samples more reproducibly than before. Large-scale image-based high-throughput screening led to the discovery of a hit compound that induces selective mitophagy of damaged mitochondria. In a mouse model of Parkinsons disease, we found that dopaminergic neurons selectively failed to execute mitophagy that promoted their survival within lesions. These results show that mito-SRAI is an essential tool for quantitative studies of mitochondrial quality control.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crucial Roles of the RIP Homotypic Interaction Motifs of RIPK3 in RIPK1-Dependent Cell Death and Lymphoproliferative Disease</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32433959/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32433959/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Receptor-interacting protein kinase 3 (RIPK3) has been identified as an essential regulator of necroptosis, apoptosis, and inflammatory signaling. RIPK3 contains an N-terminal kinase domain and a C-terminal RIP homotypic interaction motif (RHIM). However, the physiological roles of RIPK3 RHIM remain unclear. Here we generate knockin mice endogenously expressing the RIPK3 RHIM mutant, RIPK3&lt;sup&gt;V448P&lt;/sup&gt;. Cells expressing RIPK3&lt;sup&gt;V448P&lt;/sup&gt; are resistant to RIPK1 kinase-dependent apoptosis and necroptosis, and Ripk3&lt;sup&gt;V448P/V448P&lt;/sup&gt; mice rescue embryonic lethality of Fadd-deficient mice by intercrossing. Strikingly, &lt;em&gt;Ripk3&lt;sup&gt;V448P/V448P&lt;/sup&gt;Fadd&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; mice display more severe lymphoproliferative disease with a marked increase in abnormal CD3&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt;B220&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; lymphocytes compared with &lt;em&gt;Ripk3&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt;Fadd&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; mice. More importantly, these inflammatory morbidities in &lt;em&gt;Ripk3&lt;sup&gt;V448P/V448P&lt;/sup&gt;Fadd&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; mice are profoundly inhibited by additional deletion of &lt;em&gt;Ripk1&lt;/em&gt;. Taken together, these results reveal a previously unidentified physiological function of RHIM of RIPK3 in regulating RIPK1-dependent cell death and lymphoproliferative disease.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Autophagy promotes immune evasion of pancreatic cancer by degrading MHC-I</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32376951/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32376951/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Immune evasion is a major obstacle for cancer treatment. Common mechanisms of evasion include impaired antigen presentation caused by mutations or loss of heterozygosity of the major histocompatibility complex class I (MHC-I), which has been implicated in resistance to immune checkpoint blockade (ICB) therapy. However, in pancreatic ductal adenocarcinoma (PDAC), which is resistant to most therapies including ICB, mutations that cause loss of MHC-I are rarely found despite the frequent downregulation of MHC-I expression. Here we show that, in PDAC, MHC-I molecules are selectively targeted for lysosomal degradation by an autophagy-dependent mechanism that involves the autophagy cargo receptor NBR1. PDAC cells display reduced expression of MHC-I at the cell surface and instead demonstrate predominant localization within autophagosomes and lysosomes. Notably, inhibition of autophagy restores surface levels of MHC-I and leads to improved antigen presentation, enhanced anti-tumour T cell responses and reduced tumour growth in syngeneic host mice. Accordingly, the anti-tumour effects of autophagy inhibition are reversed by depleting CD8&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T cells or reducing surface expression of MHC-I. Inhibition of autophagy, either genetically or pharmacologically with chloroquine, synergizes with dual ICB therapy (anti-PD1 and anti-CTLA4 antibodies), and leads to an enhanced anti-tumour immune response. Our findings demonstrate a role for enhanced autophagy or lysosome function in immune evasion by selective targeting of MHC-I molecules for degradation, and provide a rationale for the combination of autophagy inhibition and dual ICB therapy as a therapeutic strategy against PDAC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Granzyme A from cytotoxic lymphocytes cleaves GSDMB to trigger pyroptosis in target cells</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32299851/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32299851/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Introduction&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In cellular immunity, cytotoxic T lymphocytes (CTLs) and natural killer (NK) cells use perforin to deliver serine protease granzymes into target cells to kill them. Gasdermins are pore-forming proteins that execute pyroptosis, a form of proinflammatory cell death. Gasdermin D (GSDMD) is cleaved by caspase-1/4/5/11 upon inflammasome activation, releasing the pore-forming domain for plasma membrane disruption. Gasdermin E (GSDME) is similarly cleaved by caspase-3, converting apoptosis to pyroptosis. The functional mechanism for other gasdermins is unknown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rationale&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The view that granzymes induce target-cell apoptosis was proposed two decades ago, when apoptosis was thought to be the dominant form of programmed cell death and assays to ascertain apoptosis were insufficiently accurate. Furthermore, granzyme cytotoxicity was only assessed in a few cell types. Discovery of the gasdermin family, which are true cell death executors, has altered our understanding of programmed cell death. In this work, we explored whether members of the gasdermin family might respond to granzymes and induce pyroptosis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Results&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The expression of gasdermin B (GSDMB) but no other gasdermins in human embryonic kidney (HEK) 293T cells induced pyroptotic killing by NK cells, accompanied by an interdomain cleavage of GSDMB. These processes were blocked by inhibiting the perforin–granzyme pathway. In vitro profiling of all five human granzymes identified granzyme A (GZMA), which readily cleaved GSDMB, predominantly at Lys&lt;sup&gt;244&lt;/sup&gt; within the interdomain linker. This cleavage unmasked the pore-forming activity of GSDMB. GZMA, delivered into GSDMB-reconstituted cells by electroporation or perforin, induced extensive pyroptosis with interdomain cleavage of GSDMB. These effects were diminished by a K229A/K244A (KK/A) mutation of GSDMB. In cells normally undergoing apoptosis upon GZMA delivery, the additional expression of GZMA-cleavable GSDMB converted apoptosis into pyroptosis. Pyroptotic killing by NK cells was blocked by both the KK/AA mutation and a knockdown of &lt;em&gt;GZMA&lt;/em&gt; expression. Among 39 cell lines, three, including the esophageal carcinoma (OE19 cells), expressed GSDMB and underwent pyroptosis upon GZMA delivery. Knockout experiments revealed that pyroptosis in OE19 cells required the interdomain cleavage of GSDMB. Furthermore, GSDMB expression was up-regulated by interferon-γ (IFN-γ). Approximately one-third of GSDMB-negative cell lines showed IFN-γ–induced GSDMB expression. IFN-γ promoted GZMA- or NK cell–induced pyroptosis in several target cells. Primary T cells, including anti-CD19 chimeric-antigen receptor (CAR) T cells and NY-ESO-1–specific T cell receptor (TCR)–engineered T cells (TCR T cells), also induced pyroptosis in GSDMB-reconstituted cells through cleavage of GSDMB by GZMA. Introducing GZMA-cleavable GSDMB into mouse cancer cells promoted tumor clearance in mice. &lt;em&gt;GSDMB&lt;/em&gt; was highly expressed in certain tissues, particularly digestive tract epithelia, including the derived tumors. GSDMB appeared to be silenced in gastric and esophageal cancers. The Cancer Genome Atlas database recorded a strong positive correlation between &lt;em&gt;GSDMB&lt;/em&gt; expression and patient survival for bladder carcinoma and skin cutaneous melanoma.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conclusion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GZMA from cytotoxic lymphocytes cleaves and activates GSDMB to induce target cell pyroptosis. This immune effector mechanism promotes CTL-mediated tumor clearance in mice. High GSDMB expression in the digestive system suggests the importance of GSDMB-mediated immunity in these tissues and will guide immunotherapy for related cancers. Our findings suggest that substrates such as gasdermins, rather than their upstream proteases, determine the nature of cell death.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Z-nucleic-acid sensing triggers ZBP1-dependent necroptosis and inflammation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32296175/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32296175/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Erratum in:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Publisher Correction: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-020-2207-y&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Z-nucleic-acid sensing triggers ZBP1-dependent necroptosis and inflammation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The biological function of Z-DNA and Z-RNA, nucleic acid structures with a left-handed double helix, is poorly understood. Z-DNA-binding protein 1 (ZBP1; also known as DAI or DLM-1) is a nucleic acid sensor that contains two Zα domains that bind Z-DNA and Z-RNA. ZBP1 mediates host defence against some viruses by sensing viral nucleic acids. RIPK1 deficiency, or mutation of its RIP homotypic interaction motif (RHIM), triggers ZBP1-dependent necroptosis and inflammation in mice. However, the mechanisms that induce ZBP1 activation in the absence of viral infection remain unknown. Here we show that Zα-dependent sensing of endogenous ligands induces ZBP1-mediated perinatal lethality in mice expressing RIPK1 with mutated RHIM (&lt;em&gt;Ripk1&lt;sup&gt;mR/mR&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt;), skin inflammation in mice with epidermis-specific RIPK1 deficiency (RIPK1&lt;sup&gt;E-KO&lt;/sup&gt;) and colitis in mice with intestinal epithelial-specific FADD deficiency (FADD&lt;sup&gt;IEC-KO&lt;/sup&gt;). Consistently, functional Zα domains were required for ZBP1-induced necroptosis in fibroblasts that were treated with caspase inhibitors or express RIPK1 with mutated RHIM. Inhibition of nuclear export triggered the Zα-dependent activation of RIPK3 in the nucleus resulting in cell death, which suggests that ZBP1 may recognize nuclear Z-form nucleic acids. We found that ZBP1 constitutively bound cellular double-stranded RNA in a Zα-dependent manner. Complementary reads derived from endogenous retroelements were detected in epidermal RNA, which suggests that double-stranded RNA derived from these retroelements may act as a Zα-domain ligand that triggers the activation of ZBP1. Collectively, our results provide evidence that the sensing of endogenous Z-form nucleic acids by ZBP1 triggers RIPK3-dependent necroptosis and inflammation, which could underlie the development of chronic inflammatory conditions-particularly in individuals with mutations in &lt;em&gt;RIPK1&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;CASP8&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mitochondrial DNA stress triggers autophagy-dependent ferroptotic death</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32186434/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32186434/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pancreatic cancer tends to be highly resistant to current therapy and remains one of the great challenges in biomedicine with very low 5-year survival rates. Here, we report that zalcitabine, an antiviral drug for human immunodeficiency virus infection, can suppress the growth of primary and immortalized human pancreatic cancer cells through the induction of ferroptosis, an iron-dependent form of regulated cell death. Mechanically, this effect relies on zalcitabine-induced mitochondrial DNA stress, which activates the STING1/TMEM173-mediated DNA sensing pathway, leading to macroautophagy/autophagy-dependent ferroptotic cell death via lipid peroxidation, but not a type I interferon response. Consequently, the genetic and pharmacological inactivation of the autophagy-dependent ferroptosis pathway diminishes the anticancer effects of zalcitabine in cell culture and animal models. Together, these findings not only provide a new approach for pancreatic cancer therapy but also increase our understanding of the interplay between autophagy and DNA damage response in shaping cell death.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A bioorthogonal system reveals antitumour immune function of pyroptosis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32188939/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32188939/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bioorthogonal chemistry capable of operating in live animals is needed to investigate biological processes such as cell death and immunity. Recent studies have identified a gasdermin family of pore-forming proteins that executes inflammasome-dependent and -independent pyroptosis. Pyroptosis is proinflammatory, but its effect on antitumour immunity is unknown. Here we establish a bioorthogonal chemical system, in which a cancer-imaging probe phenylalanine trifluoroborate (Phe-BF&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;) that can enter cells desilylates and &amp;lsquo;cleaves&amp;rsquo; a designed linker that contains a silyl ether. This system enabled the controlled release of a drug from an antibody-drug conjugate in mice. When combined with nanoparticle-mediated delivery, desilylation catalysed by Phe-BF&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; could release a client protein-including an active gasdermin-from a nanoparticle conjugate, selectively into tumour cells in mice. We applied this bioorthogonal system to gasdermin, which revealed that pyroptosis of less than 15% of tumour cells was sufficient to clear the entire 4T1 mammary tumour graft. The tumour regression was absent in immune-deficient mice or upon T cell depletion, and was correlated with augmented antitumour immune responses. The injection of a reduced, ineffective dose of nanoparticle-conjugated gasdermin along with Phe-BF&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; sensitized 4T1 tumours to anti-PD1 therapy. Our bioorthogonal system based on Phe-BF&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; desilylation is therefore a powerful tool for chemical biology; our application of this system suggests that pyroptosis-induced inflammation triggers robust antitumour immunity and can synergize with checkpoint blockade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Genome-wide ER-phagy Screen Highlights Key Roles of Mitochondrial Metabolism and ER-Resident UFMylation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32160526/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32160526/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Selective autophagy of organelles is critical for cellular differentiation, homeostasis, and organismal health. Autophagy of the ER (ER-phagy) is implicated in human neuropathy but is poorly understood beyond a few autophagosomal receptors and remodelers. By using an ER-phagy reporter and genome-wide CRISPRi screening, we identified 200 high-confidence human ER-phagy factors. Two pathways were unexpectedly required for ER-phagy. First, reduced mitochondrial metabolism represses ER-phagy, which is opposite of general autophagy and is independent of AMPK. Second, ER-localized UFMylation is required for ER-phagy to repress the unfolded protein response via IRE1α. The UFL1 ligase is brought to the ER surface by DDRGK1 to UFMylate RPN1 and RPL26 and preferentially targets ER sheets for degradation, analogous to PINK1-Parkin regulation during mitophagy. Our data provide insight into the cellular logic of ER-phagy, reveal parallels between organelle autophagies, and provide an entry point to the relatively unexplored process of degrading the ER network.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Structural Mechanism for GSDMD Targeting by Autoprocessed Caspases in Pyroptosis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32109412/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32109412/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The pyroptosis execution protein GSDMD is cleaved by inflammasome-activated caspase-1 and LPS-activated caspase-11/4/5. The cleavage unmasks the pore-forming domain from GSDMD-C-terminal domain. How the caspases recognize GSDMD and its connection with caspase activation are unknown. Here, we show site-specific caspase-4/11 autoprocessing, generating a p10 product, is required and sufficient for cleaving GSDMD and inducing pyroptosis. The p10-form autoprocessed caspase-4/11 binds the GSDMD-C domain with a high affinity. Structural comparison of autoprocessed and unprocessed capase-11 identifies a β sheet induced by the autoprocessing. In caspase-4/11-GSDMD-C complex crystal structures, the β sheet organizes a hydrophobic GSDMD-binding interface that is only possible for p10-form caspase-4/11. The binding promotes dimerization-mediated caspase activation, rendering a cleavage independently of the cleavage-site tetrapeptide sequence. Crystal structure of caspase-1-GSDMD-C complex shows a similar GSDMD-recognition mode. Our study reveals an unprecedented substrate-targeting mechanism for caspases. The hydrophobic interface suggests an additional space for developing inhibitors specific for pyroptotic caspases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Local Fatty Acid Channeling into Phospholipid Synthesis Drives Phagophore Expansion during Autophagy</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/31883797/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/31883797/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Autophagy is a conserved catabolic homeostasis process central for cellular and organismal health. During autophagy, small single-membrane phagophores rapidly expand into large double-membrane autophagosomes to encapsulate diverse cargoes for degradation. It is thought that autophagic membranes are mainly derived from preformed organelle membranes. Instead, here we delineate a pathway that expands the phagophore membrane by localized phospholipid synthesis. Specifically, we find that the conserved acyl-CoA synthetase Faa1 accumulates on nucleated phagophores and locally activates fatty acids (FAs) required for phagophore elongation and autophagy. Strikingly, using isotopic FA tracing, we directly show that Faa1 channels activated FAs into the synthesis of phospholipids and promotes their assembly into autophagic membranes. Indeed, the first committed steps of de novo phospholipid synthesis at the ER, which forms stable contacts with nascent autophagosomes, are essential for autophagy. Together, our work illuminates how cells spatially tune synthesis and flux of phospholipids for autophagosome biogenesis during autophagy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LATS1 but not LATS2 represses autophagy by a kinase-independent scaffold function</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/31848340/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/31848340/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Autophagy perturbation represents an emerging therapeutic strategy in cancer. Although LATS1 and LATS2 kinases, core components of the mammalian Hippo pathway, have been shown to exert tumor suppressive activities, here we report a pro-survival role of LATS1 but not LATS2 in hepatocellular carcinoma (HCC) cells. Specifically, LATS1 restricts lethal autophagy in HCC cells induced by sorafenib, the standard of care for advanced HCC patients. Notably, autophagy regulation by LATS1 is independent of its kinase activity. Instead, LATS1 stabilizes the autophagy core-machinery component Beclin-1 by promoting K27-linked ubiquitination at lysine residues K32 and K263 on Beclin-1. Consequently, ubiquitination of Beclin-1 negatively regulates autophagy by promoting inactive dimer formation of Beclin-1. Our study highlights a functional diversity between LATS1 and LATS2, and uncovers a scaffolding role of LATS1 in mediating a cross-talk between the Hippo signaling pathway and autophagy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The ER-Localized Transmembrane Protein TMEM39A/SUSR2 Regulates Autophagy by Controlling the Trafficking of the PtdIns(4)P Phosphatase SAC1</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/31806350/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/31806350/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TMEM39A, encoding an ER-localized transmembrane protein, is a susceptibility locus for multiple autoimmune diseases. The molecular function of TMEM39A remains completely unknown. Here we demonstrated that TMEM39A, also called SUSR2, modulates autophagy activity by regulating the spatial distribution and levels of PtdIns(4)P. Depletion of SUSR2 elevates late endosomal/lysosomal PtdIns(4)P levels, facilitating recruitment of the HOPS complex to promote assembly of the SNARE complex for autophagosome maturation. SUSR2 knockdown also increases the degradative capability of lysosomes. Mechanistically, SUSR2 interacts with the ER-localized PtdIns(4)P phosphatase SAC1 and also the COPII SEC23/SEC24 subunits to promote the ER-to-Golgi transport of SAC1. Retention of SAC1 on the ER in SUSR2 knockdown cells increases the level of PtdIns(3)P produced by the VPS34 complex, promoting autophagosome formation. Our study reveals that TMEM39A/SUSR2 acts as an adaptor protein for efficient export of SAC1 from the ER and provides insights into the pathogenesis of diseases associated with TMEM39A mutations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Caspase-8 is the molecular switch for apoptosis, necroptosis and pyroptosis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/31748744/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/31748744/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Caspase-8 is the initiator caspase of extrinsic apoptosis and inhibits necroptosis mediated by RIPK3 and MLKL. Accordingly, caspase-8 deficiency in mice causes embryonic lethality, which can be rescued by deletion of either &lt;em&gt;Ripk3&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;Mlkl&lt;/em&gt;. Here we show that the expression of enzymatically inactive CASP8(C362S) causes embryonic lethality in mice by inducing necroptosis and pyroptosis. Similar to &lt;em&gt;Casp8&lt;sup&gt;−/−&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; mice, &lt;em&gt;Casp8&lt;sup&gt;C362S/C362S&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; mouse embryos died after endothelial cell necroptosis leading to cardiovascular defects. MLKL deficiency rescued the cardiovascular phenotype but unexpectedly caused perinatal lethality in &lt;em&gt;Casp8&lt;sup&gt;C362S/C362S&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; mice, indicating that CASP8(C362S) causes necroptosis-independent death at later stages of embryonic development. Specific loss of the catalytic activity of caspase-8 in intestinal epithelial cells induced intestinal inflammation similar to intestinal epithelial cell-specific &lt;em&gt;Casp8&lt;/em&gt; knockout mice. Inhibition of necroptosis by additional deletion of &lt;em&gt;Mlkl&lt;/em&gt; severely aggravated intestinal inflammation and caused premature lethality in &lt;em&gt;Mlkl&lt;/em&gt; knockout mice with specific loss of caspase-8 catalytic activity in intestinal epithelial cells. Expression of CASP8(C362S) triggered the formation of ASC specks, activation of caspase-1 and secretion of IL-1β. Both embryonic lethality and premature death were completely rescued in &lt;em&gt;Casp8&lt;sup&gt;C362S/C362S&lt;/sup&gt;Mlkl&lt;sup&gt;−/−&lt;/sup&gt;Asc&lt;sup&gt;−/−&lt;/sup&gt;sup&amp;gt;&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;Casp8&lt;sup&gt;C362S/C362S&lt;/sup&gt;Mlkl&lt;sup&gt;−/−&lt;/sup&gt;Casp1&lt;sup&gt;−/−&lt;/sup&gt;sup&amp;gt;&lt;/em&gt; mice, indicating that the activation of the inflammasome promotes CASP8(C362S)-mediated tissue pathology when necroptosis is blocked. Therefore, caspase-8 represents the molecular switch that controls apoptosis, necroptosis and pyroptosis, and prevents tissue damage during embryonic development and adulthood.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>STYK1 promotes autophagy through enhancing the assembly of autophagy-specific class III phosphatidylinositol 3-kinase complex I</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/31696776/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/31696776/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Macroautophagy/autophagy plays key roles in development, oncogenesis, and cardiovascular and metabolic diseases. Autophagy-specific class III phosphatidylinositol 3-kinase complex I (PtdIns3K-C1) is essential for autophagosome formation. However, the regulation of this complex formation requires further investigation. Here, we discovered that STYK1 (serine/threonine/tyrosine kinase 1), a member of the receptor tyrosine kinases (RTKs) family, is a new upstream regulator of autophagy. We discovered that STYK1 facilitated autophagosome formation in human cells and zebrafish, which was characterized by elevated LC3-II and lowered SQSTM1/p62 levels and increased puncta formation by several marker proteins, such as ATG14, WIPI1, and ZFYVE1. Moreover, we observed that STYK1 directly binds to the PtdIns3K-C1 complex as a homodimer. The binding with this complex was promoted by Tyr191 phosphorylation, by means of which the kinase activity of STYK1 was elevated. We also demonstrated that STYK1 elevated the serine phosphorylation of BECN1, thereby decreasing the interaction between BECN1 and BCL2. Furthermore, we found that STYK1 preferentially facilitated the assembly of the PtdIns3K-C1 complex and was required for PtdIns3K-C1 complex kinase activity. Taken together, our findings provide new insights into autophagy induction and reveal evidence of novel crosstalk between the components of RTK signaling and autophagy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FSP1 is a glutathione-independent ferroptosis suppressor</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/31634899/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/31634899/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ferroptosis is an iron-dependent form of necrotic cell death marked by oxidative damage to phospholipids. To date, ferroptosis has been thought to be controlled only by the phospholipid hydroperoxide-reducing enzyme glutathione peroxidase 4 (GPX4) and radical-trapping antioxidants. However, elucidation of the factors that underlie the sensitivity of a given cell type to ferroptosis is crucial to understand the pathophysiological role of ferroptosis and how it may be exploited for the treatment of cancer. Although metabolic constraints and phospholipid composition contribute to ferroptosis sensitivity, no cell-autonomous mechanisms have been identified that account for the resistance of cells to ferroptosis. Here we used an expression cloning approach to identify genes in human cancer cells that are able to complement the loss of GPX4. We found that the flavoprotein apoptosis-inducing factor mitochondria-associated 2 (AIFM2) is a previously unrecognized anti-ferroptotic gene. AIFM2, which we renamed ferroptosis suppressor protein 1 (FSP1) and which was initially described as a pro-apoptotic gene, confers protection against ferroptosis elicited by GPX4 deletion. We further demonstrate that the suppression of ferroptosis by FSP1 is mediated by ubiquinone (also known as coenzyme Q&lt;sub&gt;10&lt;/sub&gt;, CoQ&lt;sub&gt;10&lt;/sub&gt;): the reduced form, ubiquinol, traps lipid peroxyl radicals that mediate lipid peroxidation, whereas FSP1 catalyses the regeneration of CoQ&lt;sub&gt;10&lt;/sub&gt; using NAD(P)H. Pharmacological targeting of FSP1 strongly synergizes with GPX4 inhibitors to trigger ferroptosis in a number of cancer entities. In conclusion, the FSP1-CoQ&lt;sub&gt;10&lt;/sub&gt;-NAD(P)H pathway exists as a stand-alone parallel system, which co-operates with GPX4 and glutathione to suppress phospholipid peroxidation and ferroptosis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The CoQ oxidoreductase FSP1 acts parallel to GPX4 to inhibit ferroptosis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/31634900/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/31634900/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ferroptosis is a form of regulated cell death that is caused by the iron-dependent peroxidation of lipids. The glutathione-dependent lipid hydroperoxidase glutathione peroxidase 4 (GPX4) prevents ferroptosis by converting lipid hydroperoxides into non-toxic lipid alcohols. Ferroptosis has previously been implicated in the cell death that underlies several degenerative conditions, and induction of ferroptosis by the inhibition of GPX4 has emerged as a therapeutic strategy to trigger cancer cell death. However, sensitivity to GPX4 inhibitors varies greatly across cancer cell lines, which suggests that additional factors govern resistance to ferroptosis. Here, using a synthetic lethal CRISPR-Cas9 screen, we identify ferroptosis suppressor protein 1 (FSP1) (previously known as apoptosis-inducing factor mitochondrial 2 (AIFM2)) as a potent ferroptosis-resistance factor. Our data indicate that myristoylation recruits FSP1 to the plasma membrane where it functions as an oxidoreductase that reduces coenzyme Q&lt;sub&gt;10&lt;/sub&gt; (CoQ) (also known as ubiquinone-10), which acts as a lipophilic radical-trapping antioxidant that halts the propagation of lipid peroxides. We further find that FSP1 expression positively correlates with ferroptosis resistance across hundreds of cancer cell lines, and that FSP1 mediates resistance to ferroptosis in lung cancer cells in culture and in mouse tumour xenografts. Thus, our data identify FSP1 as a key component of a non-mitochondrial CoQ antioxidant system that acts in parallel to the canonical glutathione-based GPX4 pathway. These findings define a ferroptosis suppression pathway and indicate that pharmacological inhibition of FSP1 may provide an effective strategy to sensitize cancer cells to ferroptosis-inducing chemotherapeutic agents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ubiquitination of RIPK1 suppresses programmed cell death by regulating RIPK1 kinase activation during embryogenesis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/31519886/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/31519886/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ubiquitination status of RIPK1 is considered to be critical for cell fate determination. However, the in vivo role for RIPK1 ubiquitination remains undefined. Here we show that mice expressing RIPK1&lt;sup&gt;K376R&lt;/sup&gt; which is defective in RIPK1 ubiquitination die during embryogenesis. This lethality is fully rescued by concomitant deletion of &lt;em&gt;Fadd&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Ripk3&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;Mlkl&lt;/em&gt;. Mechanistically, cells expressing RIPK1K376R are more susceptible to TNF-α induced apoptosis and necroptosis with more complex II formation and increased RIPK1 activation, which is consistent with the observation that &lt;em&gt;Ripk1&lt;sup&gt;K376R/K376R&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; lethality is effectively prevented by treatment of RIPK1 kinase inhibitor and is rescued by deletion of Tnfr1. However, &lt;em&gt;Tnfr1&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt; Ripk1&lt;sup&gt;K376R/K376R&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; mice display systemic inflammation and die within 2 weeks. Significantly, this lethal inflammation is rescued by deletion of &lt;em&gt;Ripk3&lt;/em&gt;. Taken together, these findings reveal a critical role of Lys376-mediated ubiquitination of RIPK1 in suppressing RIPK1 kinase activity-dependent lethal pathways during embryogenesis and RIPK3-dependent inflammation postnatally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A high-throughput screen identifies the long non-coding RNA DRAIC as a regulator of autophagy</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/30872794/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/30872794/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Autophagy is a conserved degradation process that occurs in all eukaryotic cells and its dysfunction has been associated with various diseases including cancer. While a number of large-scale attempts have recently identified new molecular players in autophagy regulation, including proteins and microRNAs, little is known regarding the function of long non-coding RNAs (lncRNAs) in the regulation of this process. To identify new long non-coding RNAs with functional implications in autophagy, we performed a high-throughput RNAi screen targeting more than 600 lncRNA transcripts and monitored their effects on autophagy in MCF-7 cells. We identified 63 lncRNAs that affected GFP-LC3B puncta numbers significantly. We validated the strongest hit, the lncRNA DRAIC previously shown to impact cell proliferation, and revealed a novel role for this lncRNA in the regulation of autophagic flux. Interestingly, we find DRAIC&amp;rsquo;s pro-proliferative effects to be autophagy-independent. This study serves as a valuable resource for researchers from both the lncRNA and autophagy fields as it advances the current understanding of autophagy regulation by non-coding RNAs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The role of STAT3 in autophagy</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/25951043/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/25951043/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Autophagy is an evolutionarily conserved process in eukaryotes that eliminates harmful components and maintains cellular homeostasis in response to a series of extracellular insults. However, these insults may trigger the downstream signaling of another prominent stress responsive pathway, the STAT3 signaling pathway, which has been implicated in multiple aspects of the autophagic process. Recent reports further indicate that different subcellular localization patterns of STAT3 affect autophagy in various ways. For example, nuclear STAT3 fine-tunes autophagy via the transcriptional regulation of several autophagy-related genes such as BCL2 family members, BECN1, PIK3C3, CTSB, CTSL, PIK3R1, HIF1A, BNIP3, and microRNAs with targets of autophagy modulators. Cytoplasmic STAT3 constitutively inhibits autophagy by sequestering EIF2AK2 as well as by interacting with other autophagy-related signaling molecules such as FOXO1 and FOXO3. Additionally, the mitochondrial translocation of STAT3 suppresses autophagy induced by oxidative stress and may effectively preserve mitochondria from being degraded by mitophagy. Understanding the role of STAT3 signaling in the regulation of autophagy may provide insight into the classic autophagy model and also into cancer therapy, especially for the emerging targeted therapy, because a series of targeted agents execute antitumor activities via blocking STAT3 signaling, which inevitably affects the autophagy pathway. Here, we review several of the representative studies and the current understanding in this particular field.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Molecular pathways: autophagy in cancer--a matter of timing and context</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/25165101/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/25165101/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Autophagy is an intracellular self-digestion mechanism, by which cellular components are sorted into double-membrane autophagosomes and delivered to lysosomes for degradation. Cells use autophagy to dispose of wastes and eliminate hazards, while recycling nutrients and tuning metabolism in the process. Through these functions, autophagy promotes cell fitness, genome integrity, tissue homeostasis, and cell survival and growth under stress. Both autophagy upregulation and downregulation have been found in human cancers, suggesting a complex role in tumor development. Accumulating results from autophagy-deficient mice and mouse models of human cancers have demonstrated that autophagy generally suppresses tumor initiation, but promotes tumor progression, in a manner that is dependent on timing and context and modified by specific tumorigenic events. Given the role of autophagy in facilitating tumor growth, autophagy inhibition has gained wide attention as a potential anticancer therapy. Here, we summarize relevant genetic, preclinical, and clinical studies and discuss the multifaceted role of autophagy in cancer, as well as the prospects of autophagy inhibition for cancer therapy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ferroptosis: an iron-dependent form of nonapoptotic cell death</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/22632970/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/22632970/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nonapoptotic forms of cell death may facilitate the selective elimination of some tumor cells or be activated in specific pathological states. The oncogenic RAS-selective lethal small molecule erastin triggers a unique iron-dependent form of nonapoptotic cell death that we term ferroptosis. Ferroptosis is dependent upon intracellular iron, but not other metals, and is morphologically, biochemically, and genetically distinct from apoptosis, necrosis, and autophagy. We identify the small molecule ferrostatin-1 as a potent inhibitor of ferroptosis in cancer cells and glutamate-induced cell death in organotypic rat brain slices, suggesting similarities between these two processes. Indeed, erastin, like glutamate, inhibits cystine uptake by the cystine/glutamate antiporter (system x(c)(-)), creating a void in the antioxidant defenses of the cell and ultimately leading to iron-dependent, oxidative death. Thus, activation of ferroptosis results in the nonapoptotic destruction of certain cancer cells, whereas inhibition of this process may protect organisms from neurodegeneration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anoikis: an emerging hallmark in health and diseases</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/21953325/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/21953325/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anoikis is a programmed cell death occurring upon cell detachment from the correct extracellular matrix, thus disrupting integrin ligation. It is a critical mechanism in preventing dysplastic cell growth or attachment to an inappropriate matrix. Anoikis prevents detached epithelial cells from colonizing elsewhere and is thus essential for tissue homeostasis and development. As anchorage-independent growth and epithelial-mesenchymal transition, two features associated with anoikis resistance, are crucial steps during tumour progression and metastatic spreading of cancer cells, anoikis deregulation has now evoked particular attention from the scientific community. The aim of this review is to analyse the molecular mechanisms governing both anoikis and anoikis resistance, focusing on their regulation in physiological processes, as well as in several diseases, including metastatic cancers, cardiovascular diseases and diabetes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Synthetic lethal screening identifies compounds activating iron-dependent, nonapoptotic cell death in oncogenic-RAS-harboring cancer cells</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/18355723/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/18355723/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We screened small molecules to identify two compounds, which we named RSL3 and RSL5, that have increased lethality in the presence of oncogenic RAS. Counter screening with biologically active compounds defined aspects of the mechanism of action for RSL3 and RSL5, such as a nonapoptotic, MEK-dependent, and iron-dependent oxidative cell death. Erastin, a previously reported compound with RAS-selective lethality, showed similar properties. RNA interference experiments targeting voltage-dependent anion channel 3 (VDAC3), a target of erastin, demonstrated that RSL5 is a scaffold that acts through VDACs to activate the observed pathway. RSL3 activated a similar death mechanism but in a VDAC-independent manner. We found that cells transformed with oncogenic RAS have increased iron content relative to their normal cell counterparts through upregulation of transferrin receptor 1 and downregulation of ferritin heavy chain 1 and ferritin light chain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RAS-RAF-MEK-dependent oxidative cell death involving voltage-dependent anion channels</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/17568748/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jun 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/17568748/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therapeutics that discriminate between the genetic makeup of normal cells and tumour cells are valuable for treating and understanding cancer. Small molecules with oncogene-selective lethality may reveal novel functions of oncoproteins and enable the creation of more selective drugs. Here we describe the mechanism of action of the selective anti-tumour agent erastin, involving the RAS-RAF-MEK signalling pathway functioning in cell proliferation, differentiation and survival. Erastin exhibits greater lethality in human tumour cells harbouring mutations in the oncogenes HRAS, KRAS or BRAF. Using affinity purification and mass spectrometry, we discovered that erastin acts through mitochondrial voltage-dependent anion channels (VDACs)&amp;ndash;a novel target for anti-cancer drugs. We show that erastin treatment of cells harbouring oncogenic RAS causes the appearance of oxidative species and subsequent death through an oxidative, non-apoptotic mechanism. RNA-interference-mediated knockdown of VDAC2 or VDAC3 caused resistance to erastin, implicating these two VDAC isoforms in the mechanism of action of erastin. Moreover, using purified mitochondria expressing a single VDAC isoform, we found that erastin alters the permeability of the outer mitochondrial membrane. Finally, using a radiolabelled analogue and a filter-binding assay, we show that erastin binds directly to VDAC2. These results demonstrate that ligands to VDAC proteins can induce non-apoptotic cell death selectively in some tumour cells harbouring activating mutations in the RAS-RAF-MEK pathway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
