<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Lipid | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/lipid/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/lipid/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Lipid</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Lipid</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/lipid/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Epsin Nanotherapy Regulates Cholesterol Transport to Fortify Atheroma Regression</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36444722/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36444722/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Excess cholesterol accumulation in lesional macrophages elicits complex responses in atherosclerosis. Epsins, a family of endocytic adaptors, fuel the progression of atherosclerosis; however, the underlying mechanism and therapeutic potential of targeting Epsins remains unknown. In this study, we determined the role of Epsins in macrophage-mediated metabolic regulation. We then developed an innovative method to therapeutically target macrophage Epsins with specially designed S2P-conjugated lipid nanoparticles, which encapsulate small-interfering RNAs to suppress Epsins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; We used single-cell RNA sequencing with our newly developed algorithm MEBOCOST to study cell-cell communications mediated by metabolites from sender cells and sensor proteins on receiver cells. Biomedical, cellular, and molecular approaches were utilized to investigate the role of macrophage Epsins in regulating lipid metabolism and transport. We performed this study using myeloid-specific Epsin double knockout (LysM-DKO) mice and mice with a genetic reduction of ABCG1 (ATP-binding cassette subfamily G member 1; LysM-DKO-ABCG1&lt;sup&gt;fl/+&lt;/sup&gt;). The nanoparticles targeting lesional macrophages were developed to encapsulate interfering RNAs to treat atherosclerosis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; We revealed that Epsins regulate lipid metabolism and transport in atherosclerotic macrophages. Inhibiting Epsins by nanotherapy halts inflammation and accelerates atheroma resolution. Harnessing lesional macrophage-specific nanoparticle delivery of Epsin small-interfering RNAs, we showed that silencing of macrophage Epsins diminished atherosclerotic plaque size and promoted plaque regression. Mechanistically, we demonstrated that Epsins bound to CD36 to facilitate lipid uptake by enhancing CD36 endocytosis and recycling. Conversely, Epsins promoted ABCG1 degradation via lysosomes and hampered ABCG1-mediated cholesterol efflux and reverse cholesterol transport. In a LysM-DKO-ABCG1&lt;sup&gt;fl/+&lt;/sup&gt; mouse model, enhanced cholesterol efflux and reverse transport due to Epsin deficiency was suppressed by the reduction of ABCG1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; Our findings suggest that targeting Epsins in lesional macrophages may offer therapeutic benefits for advanced atherosclerosis by reducing CD36-mediated lipid uptake and increasing ABCG1-mediated cholesterol efflux.
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A multivalent nucleoside-modified mRNA vaccine against all known influenza virus subtypes</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36423275/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36423275/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seasonal influenza vaccines offer little protection against pandemic influenza virus strains. It is difficult to create effective prepandemic vaccines because it is uncertain which influenza virus subtype will cause the next pandemic. In this work, we developed a nucleoside-modified messenger RNA (mRNA)-lipid nanoparticle vaccine encoding hemagglutinin antigens from all 20 known influenza A virus subtypes and influenza B virus lineages. This multivalent vaccine elicited high levels of cross-reactive and subtype-specific antibodies in mice and ferrets that reacted to all 20 encoded antigens. Vaccination protected mice and ferrets challenged with matched and mismatched viral strains, and this protection was at least partially dependent on antibodies. Our studies indicate that mRNA vaccines can provide protection against antigenically variable viruses by simultaneously inducing antibodies against multiple antigens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TMEM41B acts as an ER scramblase required for lipoprotein biogenesis and lipid homeostasis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34015269/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34015269/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How amphipathic phospholipids are shuttled between the membrane bilayer remains an essential but elusive process, particularly at the endoplasmic reticulum (ER). One prominent phospholipid shuttling process concerns the biogenesis of APOB-containing lipoproteins within the ER lumen, which may require bulk trans-bilayer movement of phospholipids from the cytoplasmic leaflet of the ER bilayer. Here, we show that TMEM41B, present in the lipoprotein export machinery, encodes a previously conceptualized ER lipid scramblase mediating trans-bilayer shuttling of bulk phospholipids. Loss of hepatic TMEM41B eliminates plasma lipids, due to complete absence of mature lipoproteins within the ER, but paradoxically also activates lipid production. Mechanistically, scramblase deficiency triggers unique ER morphological changes and unsuppressed activation of SREBPs, which potently promotes lipid synthesis despite stalled secretion. Together, this response induces full-blown nonalcoholic hepatosteatosis in the TMEM41B-deficient mice within weeks. Collectively, our data uncovered a fundamental mechanism safe-guarding ER function and integrity, dysfunction of which disrupts lipid homeostasis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adipocyte-Derived Anticancer Lipid Droplets</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33987883/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33987883/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Engineering of efficient and safe materials remains a challenge for cancer therapy. Here, the lipid droplet, an organelle in adipocytes, is demonstrated to be a controllable and biocompatible vehicle to deliver anticancer drugs. It is validated that isolated lipid droplets maintain their key physiological functions to interact with other organelles and augment the therapeutic effect of cancer photodynamic therapy by encapsulation with a lipid-conjugated photosensitizer (Pyrolipid) through a variety of pathways, including generation of reactive oxygen species (ROS); lipid peroxidation; and endoplasmic reticulum (ER) stress. As such, the IC&lt;sub&gt;50&lt;/sub&gt; value of Pyrolipid is reduced by 6.0-fold when loaded into the lipid droplet. Of note, in vivo results demonstrate that engineered lipid droplets induce significant inhibition of tumor growth with minimal side effects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
