<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Lipid | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/lipid/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/lipid/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Lipid</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Lipid</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/lipid/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interactions of Inhaled Liposome with Macrophages and Neutrophils Determine Particle Biofate and Anti-Inflammatory Effect in Acute Lung Inflammation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36583377/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36583377/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since most current studies have focused on exploring how phagocyte internalization of drug-loaded nanovesicles by macrophages would affect the function and therapeutic effects of infiltrated neutrophils or monocytes, research has evaluated the specificity of the inhaled nanovesicles for targeting various phagocytes subpopulations. In this study, liposomes with various charges (including neutral (L1), anionic (L2), and cationic at inflammatory sites (L3)) were constructed to investigate how particle charge determined their interactions with key phagocytes (including macrophages and neutrophils) in acute lung injury (ALI) models and to establish correlations with their biofate and overall anti-inflammatory effect. Our results clearly indicated that neutrophils were capable of rapidly sequestering L3 with a 3.2-fold increase in the cellular liposome distribution, compared to that in AMs, while 70.5% of L2 were preferentially uptaken by alveolar macrophages (AMs). Furthermore, both AMs and the infiltrated neutrophils performed as the potential vesicles for the inhaled liposomes to prolong their lung retention in ALI models, whereas AMs function as sweepers to recognize and process liposomes in the healthy lung. Finally, inhaled roflumilast-loaded macrophage or neutrophil preferential liposomes (L2 or L3) exhibited optimal anti-inflammatory effect because of the decreased AMs phagocytic capacity or the prolonged circulation times of neutrophils. Such findings will be beneficial in exploiting a potential pathway to specifically manipulate lung phagocyte functions in lung inflammatory diseases where these cells play crucial roles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The lipid flippase SLC47A1 blocks metabolic vulnerability to ferroptosis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36575162/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36575162/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ferroptosis is a type of regulated necrosis caused by unrestricted lipid peroxidation and subsequent plasma membrane rupture. However, the lipid remodeling mechanism that determines sensitivity to ferroptosis remains poorly understood. Here, we report a previously unrecognized role for the lipid flippase solute carrier family 47 member 1 (SLC47A1) as a regulator of lipid remodeling and survival during ferroptosis. Among 49 phospholipid scramblases, flippases, and floppases we analyzed, only SLC47A1 had mRNA that was selectively upregulated in multiple cancer cells exposed to ferroptotic inducers. Large-scale lipidomics and functional analyses revealed that the silencing of SLC47A1 increased RSL3- or erastin-induced ferroptosis by favoring ACSL4-SOAT1-mediated production of polyunsaturated fatty acid cholesterol esters. We identified peroxisome proliferator activated receptor alpha (PPARA) as a transcription factor that transactivates SLC47A1. The depletion of PPARA and SLC47A1 similarly sensitized cells to ferroptosis induction, whereas transfection-enforced re-expression of SLC47A1 restored resistance to ferroptosis in PPARA-deficient cells. Pharmacological or genetic blockade of the PPARA-SLC47A1 pathway increased the anticancer activity of a ferroptosis inducer in mice. These findings establish a direct molecular link between ferroptosis and lipid transporters, which may provide metabolic targets for overcoming drug resistance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tripterin liposome relieves severe acute respiratory syndrome as a potent COVID-19 treatment</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36566328/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36566328/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19), caused by severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 (SARS-CoV-2), 15-30% of patients are likely to develop COVID-19-related acute respiratory distress syndrome (ARDS). There are still few effective and well-understood therapies available. Novel variants and short-lasting immunity are posing challenges to vaccine efficacy, so finding antiviral and antiinflammatory treatments remains crucial. Here, tripterin (TP), a traditional Chinese medicine, was encapsulated into liposome (TP lipo) to investigate its antiviral and antiinflammatory effects in severe COVID-19. By using two severe COVID-19 models in human ACE2-transgenic (hACE2) mice, an analysis of TP lipo&amp;rsquo;s effects on pulmonary immune responses was conducted. Pulmonary pathological alterations and viral burden were reduced by TP lipo treatment. TP lipo inhibits SARS-CoV-2 replication and hyperinflammation in infected cells and mice, two crucial events in severe COVID-19 pathophysiology, it is a promising drug candidate to treat SARS-CoV-2-induced ARDS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Endosomal lipid signaling reshapes the endoplasmic reticulum to control mitochondrial function</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36520888/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36520888/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;INTRODUCTION&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cells need to react appropriately to nutritional cues. Defects in the rewiring of metabolism in response to alterations in nutrient supply have been linked to human diseases ranging from diabetes to muscle atrophy. Starvation represses anabolic pathways and facilitates catabolic ones, such as the degradation of macromolecules by autophagy and endolysosomes. Starvation also promotes the β-oxidation of fatty acids in mitochondria to produce adenosine triphosphate (ATP). Within cells, organelles including lysosomes and mitochondria undergo changes in shape and dynamics. These processes are often regulated by phosphoinositide lipids. Phosphoinositides are also involved in the formation of membrane contacts between organelles and in the response of cells and tissues to growth and nutrient signals. How the adaptive changes that protect mammalian cells and tissues from starvation-induced damage are coordinated on a cell-wide scale is unknown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;RATIONALE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Endolysosomal membrane dynamics and function are controlled by phosphoinositide signaling lipids, most notably by the synthesis and turnover of phosphatidylinositol 3-phosphate [PI(3)P]. Patients carrying mutations in the gene encoding the lipid phosphatase MTM1, an enzyme that mediates endosomal PI(3)P turnover, suffer from X-linked centronuclear myopathy (XLCNM), a severe neuromuscular disease characterized by muscle atrophy, disorganization of mitochondria, and defects in the organization of the muscle endoplasmic reticulum (ER). Given that PI(3)P is a hallmark of endosomes, we hypothesized that the control of early endosomal PI(3)P by MTM1 might serve to orchestrate adaptive changes in the dynamics of the ER and mitochondria in response to altering nutrient supply.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;RESULTS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Working with XLCNM patient–derived myoblasts and engineered cell lines, we found that nutrient starvation (for example, lack of amino acids) induced the hydrolysis of PI(3)P by endosomal recruitment of MTM1. Concomitantly, tubular ER membranes were observed to be converted into ER sheets by live super-resolution light microscopy. Mechanistically, loss of early endosomal PI(3)P upon starvation was found to reduce membrane contacts between peripheral ER tubules and early endosomes. These contacts function as physical tethers that may transmit pulling forces from highly motile peripheral endosomes to the tubular ER. Using proximity labeling proteomic and functional cell biological experiments we demonstrated that the ER–endosome contacts were mediated by binding of the related ER membrane proteins RRBP1 and kinectin 1 to PI(3)P on endosomes. To study the role of starvation-induced reshaping of tubular ER membranes into sheets on mitochondrial form and function, we combined live imaging with three-dimensional focused ion beam milling scanning electron microscopy (FIB-SEM) and proteomic analysis. We found that starvation-induced ER reshaping by MTM1 reduced the rate of mitochondrial fission and promoted the formation of a hyperfused mitochondrial network. Genetic manipulations that resulted in ER sheet expansion caused the formation of an enlarged mitochondrial network even in fed cells. Conversely, impaired ER reshaping and reduced mitochondrial network formation were observed in starved myoblasts from XLCNM patients. Mitochondrial network formation appeared to be critical for the delivery of fatty acids from lipid droplets to mitochondria and for oxidative ATP production to sustain energy supply in nutrient-deprived cells.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CONCLUSION&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our data unravel a crucial role for early endosomal lipid signaling in controlling ER morphology and, thereby, mitochondrial form and function to orchestrate the adaptive response of cells to alterations in nutrient (e.g., amino acid) supply. This mechanism operates independent of autophagy, a cellular self-eating process typically induced by prolonged starvation. Rather, it resembles an organellar conveyor belt, in which the tubular ER serves as a membrane conduit that transmits nutrient-triggered changes in endosomal PI(3)P levels to metabolic organelles to enable metabolic rewiring. How early endosomal PI(3)P levels and MTM1 function are controlled by cellular nutrient status is currently unknown. Defects in ER shape, mitochondrial morphogenesis, and cellular ATP depletion caused by loss of MTM1 function can explain the observed myofiber hypotrophy and defective ER organization in animal models of XLCNM and in human patients who often appear undernourished. We therefore hypothesize that dysregulated organelle remodeling may underlie XLCNM caused by MTM1 mutations in humans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ORP8 acts as a lipophagy receptor to mediate lipid droplet turnover</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/pwac063/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/pwac063/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lipophagy, the selective engulfment of lipid droplets (LDs) by autophagosomes for lysosomal degradation, is critical to lipid and energy homeostasis. Here we show that the lipid transfer protein ORP8 is located on LDs and mediates the encapsulation of LDs by autophagosomal membranes. This function of ORP8 is independent of its lipid transporter activity and is achieved through direct interaction with phagophore-anchored LC3/GABARAPs. Upon lipophagy induction, ORP8 has increased localization on LDs and is phosphorylated by AMPK, thereby enhancing its affinity for LC3/GABARAPs. Deletion of ORP8 or interruption of ORP8-LC3/GABARAP interaction results in accumulation of LDs and increased intracellular triglyceride. Overexpression of ORP8 alleviates LD and triglyceride deposition in the liver of ob/ob mice, and Osbpl8&lt;sup&gt;−/−&lt;/sup&gt; mice exhibit liver lipid clearance defects. Our results suggest that ORP8 is a lipophagy receptor that plays a key role in cellular lipid metabolism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lipid-laden lung mesenchymal cells foster breast cancer metastasis via metabolic reprogramming of tumor cells and natural killer cells</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36476935/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36476935/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lung mesenchymal cells (MCs) store neutral lipids during breast cancer progression&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IL-1β elicits neutral lipid accumulation in lung MCs to foster metastasis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lipid-laden MCs metabolically reprogram both tumor cells and NK cells&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Targeting lipid-laden MCs improves the efficacy of NK cell-based immunotherapy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Summary&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the distant organ environment is known to support metastasis of primary tumors, its metabolic roles in this process remain underdetermined. Here, in breast cancer models, we found lung-resident mesenchymal cells (MCs) accumulating neutral lipids at the pre-metastatic stage. This was partially mediated by interleukin-1β (IL-1β)-induced hypoxia-inducible lipid droplet-associated (HILPDA) that subsequently represses adipose triglyceride lipase (ATGL) activity in lung MCs. MC-specific ablation of the ATGL or HILPDA genes in mice reinforced and reduced lung metastasis of breast cancer respectively, suggesting a metastasis-promoting effect of lipid-laden MCs. Mechanistically, lipid-laden MCs transported their lipids to tumor cells and natural killer (NK) cells via exosome-like vesicles, leading to heightened tumor cell survival and proliferation and NK cell dysfunction. Blockage of IL-1β, which was effective singly, improved the efficacy of adoptive NK cell immunotherapy in mitigating lung metastasis. Collectively, lung MCs metabolically regulate tumor cells and anti-tumor immunity to facilitate breast cancer lung metastasis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Epsin Nanotherapy Regulates Cholesterol Transport to Fortify Atheroma Regression</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36444722/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36444722/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Excess cholesterol accumulation in lesional macrophages elicits complex responses in atherosclerosis. Epsins, a family of endocytic adaptors, fuel the progression of atherosclerosis; however, the underlying mechanism and therapeutic potential of targeting Epsins remains unknown. In this study, we determined the role of Epsins in macrophage-mediated metabolic regulation. We then developed an innovative method to therapeutically target macrophage Epsins with specially designed S2P-conjugated lipid nanoparticles, which encapsulate small-interfering RNAs to suppress Epsins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; We used single-cell RNA sequencing with our newly developed algorithm MEBOCOST to study cell-cell communications mediated by metabolites from sender cells and sensor proteins on receiver cells. Biomedical, cellular, and molecular approaches were utilized to investigate the role of macrophage Epsins in regulating lipid metabolism and transport. We performed this study using myeloid-specific Epsin double knockout (LysM-DKO) mice and mice with a genetic reduction of ABCG1 (ATP-binding cassette subfamily G member 1; LysM-DKO-ABCG1&lt;sup&gt;fl/+&lt;/sup&gt;). The nanoparticles targeting lesional macrophages were developed to encapsulate interfering RNAs to treat atherosclerosis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; We revealed that Epsins regulate lipid metabolism and transport in atherosclerotic macrophages. Inhibiting Epsins by nanotherapy halts inflammation and accelerates atheroma resolution. Harnessing lesional macrophage-specific nanoparticle delivery of Epsin small-interfering RNAs, we showed that silencing of macrophage Epsins diminished atherosclerotic plaque size and promoted plaque regression. Mechanistically, we demonstrated that Epsins bound to CD36 to facilitate lipid uptake by enhancing CD36 endocytosis and recycling. Conversely, Epsins promoted ABCG1 degradation via lysosomes and hampered ABCG1-mediated cholesterol efflux and reverse cholesterol transport. In a LysM-DKO-ABCG1&lt;sup&gt;fl/+&lt;/sup&gt; mouse model, enhanced cholesterol efflux and reverse transport due to Epsin deficiency was suppressed by the reduction of ABCG1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; Our findings suggest that targeting Epsins in lesional macrophages may offer therapeutic benefits for advanced atherosclerosis by reducing CD36-mediated lipid uptake and increasing ABCG1-mediated cholesterol efflux.
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A multivalent nucleoside-modified mRNA vaccine against all known influenza virus subtypes</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36423275/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36423275/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seasonal influenza vaccines offer little protection against pandemic influenza virus strains. It is difficult to create effective prepandemic vaccines because it is uncertain which influenza virus subtype will cause the next pandemic. In this work, we developed a nucleoside-modified messenger RNA (mRNA)-lipid nanoparticle vaccine encoding hemagglutinin antigens from all 20 known influenza A virus subtypes and influenza B virus lineages. This multivalent vaccine elicited high levels of cross-reactive and subtype-specific antibodies in mice and ferrets that reacted to all 20 encoded antigens. Vaccination protected mice and ferrets challenged with matched and mismatched viral strains, and this protection was at least partially dependent on antibodies. Our studies indicate that mRNA vaccines can provide protection against antigenically variable viruses by simultaneously inducing antibodies against multiple antigens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exosomes─Nature&#39;s Lipid Nanoparticles, a Rising Star in Drug Delivery and Diagnostics</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/36354238/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/36354238/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Exosomes are a subgroup of nanosized extracellular vesicles enclosed by a lipid bilayer membrane and secreted by most eukaryotic cells. They represent a route of intercellular communication and participate in a wide variety of physiological and pathological processes. The biological roles of exosomes rely on their bioactive cargos, including proteins, nucleic acids, and lipids, which are delivered to target cells. Their distinctive properties─innate stability, low immunogenicity, biocompatibility, and good biomembrane penetration capacity─allow them to function as superior natural nanocarriers for efficient drug delivery. Another notably favorable clinical application of exosomes is in diagnostics. They hold various biomolecules from host cells, which are indicative of pathophysiological conditions; therefore, they are considered vital for biomarker discovery in clinical diagnostics. Here, we use data from the CAS Content Collection and provide a landscape overview of the current state and delineate trends in research advancement on exosome applications in therapeutics and diagnostics across time, geography, composition, cargo loading, and development pipelines. We discuss exosome composition and pathway, from their biogenesis and secretion from host cells to recipient cell uptake. We assess methods for exosome isolation and purification, their clinical applications in therapy and diagnostics, their development pipelines, the exploration goals of the companies, the assortment of diseases they aim to treat, development stages of their research, and publication trends. We hope this review will be useful for understanding the current knowledge in the field of medical applications of exosomes, in an effort to further solve the remaining challenges in fulfilling their potential.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interplay between mucus mobility and alveolar macrophage targeting of surface-modified liposomes</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36209941/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36209941/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alveolar macrophages play a crucial role in the initiation and resolution of the immune response in the lungs. Pro-inflammatory M1 alveolar macrophages are an interesting target for treating inflammatory and infectious pulmonary diseases. One commune targeting strategy is to use nanoparticles conjugated with hyaluronic acid, which interact with CD44 overexpressed on the membrane of those cells. Unfortunately, this coating strategy may be countered by the presence on the surface of the nanoparticles of a poly(ethylene glycol) corona employed to improve nanoparticles&amp;rsquo; diffusion in the lung mucus. This study aims to measure this phenomenon by comparing the behavior in a murine lung inflammation model of three liposomal platforms designed to represent different poly(ethylene glycol) and hyaluronic acid densities (Liposome-PEG, Liposome-PEG-HA and Liposome-HA). In this work, the liposomes were obtained by a one-step ethanol injection method. Their interaction with mucin and targeting ability toward pro-inflammatory macrophages were then investigated in vitro and in vivo in a LPS model of lung inflammation. In vitro, poly(ethylene glycol) free HA-liposomes display a superior targeting efficiency toward M1 macrophages, while the addition of poly(ethylene glycol) induces better mucus mobility. Interestingly in vivo studies revealed that the three liposomes showed distinct cell specificity with alveolar macrophages demonstrating an avidity for poly(ethylene glycol) free HA-liposomes, while neutrophils favored PEGylated liposomes exempt of HA. Those results could be explained by the presence of two forces exercising a balance between mucus penetration and receptor targeting. This study corroborates the importance of considering the site of action and the targeted cells when designing nanoparticles to treat lung diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microglial hexokinase 2 deficiency increases ATP generation through lipid metabolism leading to β-amyloid clearance</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36203054/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36203054/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Erratum in:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author Correction: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nature.com/articles/s42255-022-00682-x&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Microglial hexokinase 2 deficiency increases ATP generation through lipid metabolism leading to β-amyloid clearance&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Microglial cells consume adenosine triphosphate (ATP) during phagocytosis to clear neurotoxic β-amyloid in Alzheimer&amp;rsquo;s disease (AD). However, the contribution of energy metabolism to microglial function in AD remains unclear. Here, we demonstrate that hexokinase 2 (HK2) is elevated in microglia from an AD mouse model (5xFAD) and AD patients. Genetic deletion or pharmacological inhibition of HK2 significantly promotes microglial phagocytosis, lowers the amyloid plaque burden and attenuates cognitive impairment in male AD mice. Notably, the ATP level is dramatically increased in HK2-deficient or inactive microglia, which can be attributed to a marked upregulation in lipoprotein lipase (LPL) expression and subsequent increase in lipid metabolism. We further show that two downstream metabolites of HK2, glucose-6-phosphate and fructose-6-phosphate, can reverse HK2-deficiency-induced upregulation of LPL, thus supporting ATP production and microglial phagocytosis. Our findings uncover a crucial role for HK2 in phagocytosis through regulation of microglial energy metabolism, suggesting a potential therapeutic strategy for AD by targeting HK2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Molecular Mechanisms of Ferroptosis and Relevance to Cardiovascular Disease</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/36078133/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/36078133/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ferroptosis has recently been demonstrated to be a novel regulated non-apoptotic cell death characterized by iron-dependence and the accumulation of lipid peroxidation that results in membrane damage. Excessive iron induces ferroptosis by promoting the generation of both soluble and lipid ROS via an iron-dependent Fenton reaction and lipoxygenase (LOX) enzyme activity. Cytosolic glutathione peroxidase 4 (cGPX4) pairing with ferroptosis suppressor protein 1 (FSP1) and mitochondrial glutathione peroxidase 4 (mGPX4) pairing with dihydroorotate dehydrogenase (DHODH) serve as two separate defense systems to detoxify lipid peroxidation in the cytoplasmic as well as the mitochondrial membrane, thereby defending against ferroptosis in cells under normal conditions. However, disruption of these defense systems may cause ferroptosis. Emerging evidence has revealed that ferroptosis plays an essential role in the development of diverse cardiovascular diseases (CVDs), such as hemochromatosis-associated cardiomyopathy, doxorubicin-induced cardiotoxicity, ischemia/reperfusion (I/R) injury, heart failure (HF), atherosclerosis, and COVID-19-related arrhythmias. Iron chelators, antioxidants, ferroptosis inhibitors, and genetic manipulations may alleviate the aforementioned CVDs by blocking ferroptosis pathways. In conclusion, ferroptosis plays a critical role in the pathogenesis of various CVDs and suppression of cardiac ferroptosis is expected to become a potential therapeutic option. Here, we provide a comprehensive review on the molecular mechanisms involved in ferroptosis and its implications in cardiovascular disease.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Obesity reprograms the pulmonary polyunsaturated fatty acid-derived lipidome, transcriptome, and gene-oxylipin networks</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36028048/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36028048/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Obesity exacerbates inflammation upon lung injury; however, the mechanisms by which obesity primes pulmonary dysregulation prior to external injury are not well studied. Herein, we tested the hypothesis that obesity dysregulates pulmonary PUFA metabolism that is central to inflammation initiation and resolution. We first show that a high-fat diet (HFD) administered to C57BL/6J mice increased the relative abundance of pulmonary PUFA-containing triglycerides and the concentration of PUFA-derived oxylipins (particularly prostaglandins and hydroxyeicosatetraenoic acids), independent of an increase in total pulmonary PUFAs, prior to onset of pulmonary inflammation. Experiments with a genetic model of obesity (ob/ob) generally recapitulated the effects of the HFD on the pulmonary oxylipin signature. Subsequent pulmonary next-generation RNA sequencing identified complex and unique transcriptional regulation with the HFD. We found the HFD increased pathways related to glycerophospholipid metabolism and immunity, including a unique elevation in B cell differentiation and signaling. Furthermore, we conducted computational integration of lipidomic with transcriptomic data. These analyses identified novel HFD-driven networks between glycerophospholipid metabolism and B cell receptor signaling with specific PUFA-derived pulmonary oxylipins. Finally, we confirmed the hypothesis by demonstrating that the concentration of pulmonary oxylipins, in addition to inflammatory markers, were generally increased in mice consuming a HFD upon ozone-induced acute lung injury. Collectively, these data show that a HFD dysregulates pulmonary PUFA metabolism prior to external lung injury, which may be a mechanism by which obesity primes the lungs to respond poorly to infectious and/or inflammatory challenges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A multi-layer functional genomic analysis to understand noncoding genetic variation in lipids</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35931049/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35931049/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A major challenge of genome-wide association studies (GWASs) is to translate phenotypic associations into biological insights. Here, we integrate a large GWAS on blood lipids involving 1.6 million individuals from five ancestries with a wide array of functional genomic datasets to discover regulatory mechanisms underlying lipid associations. We first prioritize lipid-associated genes with expression quantitative trait locus (eQTL) colocalizations and then add chromatin interaction data to narrow the search for functional genes. Polygenic enrichment analysis across 697 annotations from a host of tissues and cell types confirms the central role of the liver in lipid levels and highlights the selective enrichment of adipose-specific chromatin marks in high-density lipoprotein cholesterol and triglycerides. Overlapping transcription factor (TF) binding sites with lipid-associated loci identifies TFs relevant in lipid biology. In addition, we present an integrative framework to prioritize causal variants at GWAS loci, producing a comprehensive list of candidate causal genes and variants with multiple layers of functional evidence. We highlight two of the prioritized genes, CREBRF and RRBP1, which show convergent evidence across functional datasets supporting their roles in lipid biology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Total flavonoids of Inula japonica alleviated the inflammatory response and oxidative stress in LPS-induced acute lung injury via inhibiting the sEH activity: Insights from lipid metabolomics</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36150346/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36150346/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Acute lung injury (ALI) is a severe respiratory disease characterized by diffuse lung interstitial and respiratory distress and pulmonary edema with a mortality rate of 35%-40%. Inula japonica Thunb., known as &amp;ldquo;Xuan Fu Hua&amp;rdquo; in Chinese, is a traditional Chinese medicine Inulae Flos to use for relieving cough, eliminating expectorant, and preventing bacterial infections in the clinic, and possesses an anti-pulmonary fibrosis effect. However, the effect and action mechanism of I. japonica on ALI is still unclear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Purpose:&lt;/em&gt; This study aimed to investigate the protective effect and underlying mechanism of total flavonoids of I. japonica (TFIJ) in the treatment of ALI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Study design and methods:&lt;/em&gt; A mouse ALI model was established through administration of LPS by the intratracheal instillation. Protective effects of TFIJ in the inflammation and oxidative stress were studied in LPS-induced ALI mice based on inflammatory and oxidative stress factors, including MDA, MPO, SOD, and TNF-α. Lipid metabolomics, bioinformatics, Western blot, quantitative real-time PCR, and immunohistochemistry were performed to reveal the potential mechanism of TFIJ in the treatment of ALI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; TFIJ significantly alleviated the interstitial infiltration of inflammatory cells and the collapse of the alveoli in LPS-induced ALI mice. Lipid metabolomics demonstrated that TFIJ could significantly affect the CYP2J/sEH-mediated arachidonic acid metabolism, such as 11,12-EET, 14,15-EET, 8,9-DHET, 11,12-DHET, and 14,15-DHET, revealing that sEH was the potential target of TFIJ, which was further supported by the recombinant sEH-mediated the substrate hydrolysis in vitro (IC50 = 1.18 μg/ml). Inhibition of sEH by TFIJ alleviated the inflammatory response and oxidative stress via the MAPK, NF-κB, and Nrf2 signaling pathways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/em&gt; These results demonstrated that TFIJ could suppress the sEH activity to stabilize the level of EETs, allowing the alleviation of the pathological course of lung injury in LPS-treated mice, which suggested that TFIJ could serve as the potential agents in the treatment of ALI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interferon-β regulates proresolving lipids to promote the resolution of acute airway inflammation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35878041/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35878041/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aberrant immune responses, including hyperresponsiveness to Toll-like receptor (TLR) ligands, underlie acute respiratory distress syndrome (ARDS). Type I interferons confer antiviral activities and could also regulate the inflammatory response, whereas little is known about their actions to resolve aberrant inflammation. Here we report that interferon-β (IFN-β) exerts partially overlapping, but also cooperative actions with aspirin-triggered 15-epi-lipoxin A4 (15-epi-LXA4) and 17-epi-resolvin D1 to counter TLR9-generated cues to regulate neutrophil apoptosis and phagocytosis in human neutrophils. In mice, TLR9 activation impairs bacterial clearance, prolongs Escherichia coli-evoked lung injury, and suppresses production of IFN-β and the proresolving lipid mediators 15-epi-LXA4 and resolvin D1 (RvD1) in the lung. Neutralization of endogenous IFN-β delays pulmonary clearance of E. coli and aggravates mucosal injury. Conversely, treatment of mice with IFN-β accelerates clearance of bacteria, restores neutrophil phagocytosis, promotes neutrophil apoptosis and efferocytosis, and accelerates resolution of airway inflammation with concomitant increases in 15-epi-LXA4 and RvD1 production in the lungs. Pharmacological blockade of the lipoxin receptor ALX/FPR2 partially prevents IFN-β-mediated resolution. These findings point to a pivotal role of IFN-β in orchestrating timely resolution of neutrophil and TLR9 activation-driven airway inflammation and uncover an IFN-β-initiated resolution program, activation of an ALX/FPR2-centered, proresolving lipids-mediated circuit, for ARDS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A novel lncRNA RP11-386G11.10 reprograms lipid metabolism to promote hepatocellular carcinoma progression</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35798238/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35798238/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;LncRNA &lt;em&gt;RP11-386G11.10&lt;/em&gt; was up-regulated in HCC.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Overexpression of lncRNA &lt;em&gt;RP11-386G11.10&lt;/em&gt; promoted the proliferation, metastasis of HCC cells in vivo and in vitro.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We confirmed that regulation of HNRNPU expression by RP11-286H15.1 resulted in lipid accumulation in HCC cells.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;HNRNPU forms a ZBTB7A-&lt;em&gt;RP11-386G11.10&lt;/em&gt;-HNRNPU positive feedback loop by promoting mRNA stability of ZBTB7A.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Objective:&lt;/em&gt; Emerging studies suggest that long non-coding RNAs (lncRNAs) play crucial roles in hepatocellular carcinoma (HCC). A rapidly increasing number of studies have shown that metabolic changes including lipid metabolic reprogramming play a significant role in the progression of HCC. But it remains to be elucidated how lncRNAs affect tumor cell metabolism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; Through analysis and screening of The Cancer Genome Atlas-Liver Hepatocellular Carcinoma (TCGA-LIHC) dataset, we found a novel lncRNA RP11-386G11.10 was overexpressed, related to prognosis, conserved and non-protein-coding in HCC and related to poor prognosis. Then, CCK-8, colony formation, Transwell invasion, wound healing assays were performed and nude mouse subcutaneous tumour formation and lung metastasis models were established to explore the effect of RP11-386G11.10 on HCC tumour growth and metastasis. Chromatography-mass spectrometry (GC-MS) and Nile red staining detected the effect of RP11-386G11.10 on lipid metabolism in HCC. Mechanistically, we clarified the RP11-386G11.10/miR-345-3p/HNRNPU signalling pathway through dual luciferase reporter, RNA immunoprecipitation (RIP) and chromatin immunoprecipitation (ChIP) assays and identified ZBTB7A as a transcription factor of RP11-386G11.10.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; RP11-386G11.10 was overexpressed in HCC and positively correlated with tumour size, TNM stage, and poor prognosis in HCC patients. RP11-386G11.10 promoted the proliferation and metastasis of HCC cells in vitro and in vivo. Mechanistically, RP11-386G11.10 acted as a competing endogenous RNA (ceRNA) for miR-345-3p to regulate the expression of HNRNPU and its downstream lipogenic enzymes, leading to lipid accumulation in HCC cells and promoting their growth and metastasis. In addition, we identified ZBTB7A as a transcription factor of RP11-386G11.10. Moreover, HNRNPU promoted the expression of ZBTB7A in HCC cells, thereby increasing the transcriptional activity of RP11-386G11.10, and forming a positive feedback loop, ultimately leading continuous lipid accumulation, growth and metastasis in HCC cells.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; Our results indicated that the lncRNA RP11-386G11.10 was a novel oncogenic lncRNA that was strongly correlated with the poor prognosis of HCC. The ZBTB7A-RP11-386G11.10-HNRNPU positive feedback loop promoted the progression of HCC by regulating lipid anabolism. RP11-386G11.10 may become a new diagnostic and prognostic biomarker and therapy target for HCC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Therapeutic potential of traditional Chinese medicine for the treatment of NAFLD: A promising drug Potentilla discolor Bunge</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/36176915/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/36176915/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nonalcoholic fatty liver disease (NAFLD) is characterized by excessive accumulation of hepatic lipids and metabolic stress-induced liver injury. There are currently no approved effective pharmacological treatments for NAFLD. Traditional Chinese medicine (TCM) has been used for centuries to treat patients with chronic liver diseases without clear disease types and mechanisms. More recently, TCM has been shown to have unique advantages in the treatment of NAFLD. We performed a systematic review of the medical literature published over the last two decades and found that many TCM formulas have been reported to be beneficial for the treatment of metabolic dysfunctions, including &lt;em&gt;Potentilla discolor&lt;/em&gt; Bunge (PDB). PDB has a variety of active compounds, including flavonoids, terpenoids, organic acids, steroids and tannins. Many compounds have been shown to exhibit a series of beneficial effects for the treatment of NAFLD, including anti-oxidative and anti-inflammatory functions, improvement of lipid metabolism and reversal of insulin resistance. In this review, we summarize potential therapeutic effects of TCM formulas for the treatment of NAFLD, focusing on the medicinal properties of natural active compounds from PDB and their underlying mechanisms. We point out that PDB can be classified as a novel candidate for the treatment and prevention of NAFLD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multi-omics analysis unravels dysregulated lysosomal function and lipid metabolism involved in sub-chronic particulate matter-induced pulmonary injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35525343/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35525343/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A multi-omics approach was used to identify molecular changes in mouse lung tissues.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PM exposure impairs lung structure and inflammatory reactions in the mouse lungs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sub-chronic exposure to PM causes lung injury by disturbing lysosomal function and lipid metabolism homeostasis.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Different pathways are triggered in mouse lung tissues in response to PM exposure.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Particulate matter (PM) is a huge environmental threat and is of major public concern. Oxidative stress and systemic inflammation are known factors that contribute to PM- related damage; however, a systematic understanding of the deleterious pulmonary effects of PM using multi-omics analysis is lacking. In this study, we performed transcriptomic, proteomic, and metabolomic analyses in a mouse model exposed to PM for three months to identify molecular changes in lung tissues. We identified 1690 genes, 326 proteins, and 67 metabolites exhibiting significant differences between PM-challenged and control mice (p &amp;lt; 0.05). Differentially expressed genes and proteins regulated in PM-challenged mice were involved in lipid metabolism and in the immune and inflammatory response processes. Moreover, a comprehensive analysis of transcript, protein, and metabolite datasets revealed that the genes, proteins, and metabolites in the PM-treated group were involved in lysosomal function and lipid metabolism. Specifically, Cathepsin D (Ctsd), Ferritin light chain (Ftl), Lactotransferrin (Ltf), Lipocalin 2 (Lcn2), and Prosaposin (Psap) were major proteins/genes associated with PM-induced pulmonary damage, while two lipid molecules PC (18:1(11Z)/16:0) and PA (16:0/18:1(11Z)) were major metabolites related to PM-induced pulmonary injury. In summary, lipid metabolism might be used as successful precautions and therapeutic targets in PM-induced pulmonary injury to maintain the stability of cellular lysosomal function.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Poly(rC)-binding protein 1 represses ferritinophagy-mediated ferroptosis in head and neck cancer</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35290903/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35290903/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PCBP1 expression is related to head and neck cancer survival and response to ferroptosis inducers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Knockdown of PCBP1 increased ferroptosis sensitivity by inducing an increased labile iron pool.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PCBP1 negatively regulated ferritinophagy by the 3′-UTR binding of BECN1 mRNA.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Knockdown of PCBP1 increased lipid peroxidation by ALOX15 expression.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PCBP1 depletion promoted ferroptosis susceptibility in vitro and in vivo.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A cytosolic iron chaperone poly(rC)-binding protein 1 (PCBP1) is a multifunctional RNA-binding protein involving gene transcription, RNA regulation, and iron loading to ferritins. PCBP1 is also known to repress autophagy, but the role of PCBP1 in ferritinophagy and ferroptosis remains unrevealed. Therefore, we examined the role of PCBP1 in ferritinophagy-mediated ferroptosis in head and neck cancer (HNC) cells. The effects of system xc&lt;sup&gt;-&lt;/sup&gt; cystine/glutamate antiporter (xCT) inhibitors and PCBP1 gene silencing/overexpression were tested on HNC cell lines and mouse tumor xenograft models. These effects were analyzed by assessing cell viability and death, lipid reactive oxygen species and iron production, lipid, malondialdehyde, mRNA/protein expression, and autophagy flux assays. Interaction between PCBP1 and BECN1 mRNA was also examined by luciferase and RNA-protein pull-down assays. PCBP1 gene silencing increased autophagosome generation and autophagic flux. Conversely, PCBP1 upregulation inhibited autophagy activation via direct binding to the CU-rich elements on the 3&amp;rsquo;-untranslated region (3&amp;rsquo;-UTR) of BECN1 mRNA. The internal deletion or mutation of the 3&amp;rsquo;-UTR F2 region recovered BECN1 mRNA stability repressed by PCBP1, resulting in enhanced ferritinophagy-mediated ferroptosis. Besides, PCBP1 knockdown promoted polyunsaturated fatty acid peroxidation by increasing ALOX15 expression. Further, excess iron accumulation caused mitochondrial dysfunction in PCBP1-suppressed cells. A ferroptosis inducer sulfasalazine significantly suppressed tumor growth in mice with the transplantation of PCBP1-silenced HNC. Our data suggest that the dual functions of PCBP1 repressing BECN1 and ALOX15 mRNAs contribute to attenuating cancer susceptibility to ferroptosis inducers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Affimer Tagged Cubosomes: Targeting of Carcinoembryonic Antigen Expressing Colorectal Cancer Cells Using In Vitro and In Vivo Models</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35196008/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35196008/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nanomedicines, while having been approved for cancer therapy, present many challenges such as low stability, rapid clearance, and nonspecificity leading to off-target toxicity. Cubosomes are porous lyotropic liquid crystalline nanoparticles that have shown great premise as drug delivery vehicles; however, their behavior &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt; is largely underexplored, hindering clinical translation. Here, we have engineered cubosomes based on the space group &lt;em&gt;Im3m&lt;/em&gt; that are loaded with copper acetylacetonate as a model drug, and their surfaces are functionalized for the first time with Affimer proteins via copper-free click chemistry to actively target overexpressed carcinoembryonic antigens on LS174T colorectal cancer cells. Unlike nontargeted cubosomes, Affimer tagged cubosomes showed preferential accumulation in cancer cells compared to normal cells not only &lt;em&gt;in vitro&lt;/em&gt; (2D monolayer cell culture and 3D spheroid models) but also &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt; in colorectal cancer mouse xenografts, while exhibiting low nonspecific absorption and toxicity in other vital organs. Cancerous spheroids had maximum cell death compared to noncancerous cells upon targeted delivery. Xenografts subjected to targeted drug-loaded cubosomes showed a 5-7-fold higher drug accumulation in the tumor tissue compared to the liver, kidneys, and other vital organs, a significant decrease in tumor growth, and an increased survival rate compared to the nontargeted group. This work encompasses the first thorough preclinical investigation of Affimer targeted cubosomes as a cancer therapeutic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emulating Membrane Protein Environments─How Much Lipid Is Required for a Native Structure: Influenza S31N M2</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35089701/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35089701/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This report investigates the homotetrameric membrane protein structure of the S31N M2 protein from Influenza A virus in the presence of a high molar ratio of lipid. The structured regions of this protein include a single transmembrane helix and an amphipathic helix. Two structures of the S31N M2 conductance domain from Influenza A virus have been deposited in the Protein Data Bank (PDB). These structures present different symmetries about the channel main axis. We present new magic angle spinning and oriented sample solid-state NMR spectroscopic data for S31N M2 in liquid crystalline lipid bilayers using protein tetramer:lipid molar ratios ranging from 1:120 to 1:240. The data is consistent with an essentially 4-fold-symmetric structure very similar to the M2 WT structure that also has a single conformation for the four monomers, except at the His37 and Trp41 functional sites when characterized in samples with a high molar ratio of lipid. While detergent solubilization is well recognized today as a nonideal environment for small membrane proteins, here we discuss the influence of a high lipid to protein ratio for samples of the S31N M2 protein to stabilize an essentially 4-fold-symmetric conformation of the M2 membrane protein. While it is generally accepted that the chemical and physical properties of the native environment of membrane proteins needs to be reproduced judiciously to achieve the native protein structure, here we show that not only the character of the emulated membrane environment is important but also the abundance of the environment is important for achieving the native structure. This is a critical finding as a membrane protein spectroscopist&amp;rsquo;s goal is always to generate a sample with the highest possible protein sensitivity while obtaining spectra of the native-like structure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>USP19 exacerbates lipogenesis and colorectal carcinogenesis by stabilizing ME1</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34965422/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34965422/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ERK2 phosphorylates ME1 T103 to promote USP19 deubiquitinating and stabilizing ME1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;USP19 deficiency attenuates lipogenesis and colorectal tumorigenesis in mice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ERK2 inhibition increases NRF2 trans-activating PD-L1 via ME1-mediated ROS reduction&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;USP19/ME1 is dysregulated, and combined targeting of ERK2/PD-L1 is effective in CRCs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lipogenesis plays a critical role in colorectal carcinogenesis, but precisely how remains unclear. Here, we show that ERK2 phosphorylates ME1 at T103, thereby inhibiting its polyubiquitination and proteasomal degradation and enhancing its interaction with USP19. USP19 antagonizes RNF1-mediated ME1 degradation by deubiquitination, which in turn promotes lipid metabolism and NADPH production and suppresses ROS. Meanwhile, ROS dramatically increases PD-L1 mRNA levels through accelerating expression of the transcription factor NRF2. Increased lipid metabolism is correlated with ERK2 activity and colorectal carcinogenesis in human patients. Therefore, the combination of ERK2 inhibitor and anti-PD-L1 antibody significantly inhibits spontaneous and chemically induced colorectal carcinogenesis. Collectively, the USP19-ME1 axis plays a vital role in colorectal carcinogenesis and may also provide a potential therapeutic target.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TMEM41B acts as an ER scramblase required for lipoprotein biogenesis and lipid homeostasis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34015269/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34015269/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How amphipathic phospholipids are shuttled between the membrane bilayer remains an essential but elusive process, particularly at the endoplasmic reticulum (ER). One prominent phospholipid shuttling process concerns the biogenesis of APOB-containing lipoproteins within the ER lumen, which may require bulk trans-bilayer movement of phospholipids from the cytoplasmic leaflet of the ER bilayer. Here, we show that TMEM41B, present in the lipoprotein export machinery, encodes a previously conceptualized ER lipid scramblase mediating trans-bilayer shuttling of bulk phospholipids. Loss of hepatic TMEM41B eliminates plasma lipids, due to complete absence of mature lipoproteins within the ER, but paradoxically also activates lipid production. Mechanistically, scramblase deficiency triggers unique ER morphological changes and unsuppressed activation of SREBPs, which potently promotes lipid synthesis despite stalled secretion. Together, this response induces full-blown nonalcoholic hepatosteatosis in the TMEM41B-deficient mice within weeks. Collectively, our data uncovered a fundamental mechanism safe-guarding ER function and integrity, dysfunction of which disrupts lipid homeostasis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adipocyte-Derived Anticancer Lipid Droplets</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33987883/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33987883/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Engineering of efficient and safe materials remains a challenge for cancer therapy. Here, the lipid droplet, an organelle in adipocytes, is demonstrated to be a controllable and biocompatible vehicle to deliver anticancer drugs. It is validated that isolated lipid droplets maintain their key physiological functions to interact with other organelles and augment the therapeutic effect of cancer photodynamic therapy by encapsulation with a lipid-conjugated photosensitizer (Pyrolipid) through a variety of pathways, including generation of reactive oxygen species (ROS); lipid peroxidation; and endoplasmic reticulum (ER) stress. As such, the IC&lt;sub&gt;50&lt;/sub&gt; value of Pyrolipid is reduced by 6.0-fold when loaded into the lipid droplet. Of note, in vivo results demonstrate that engineered lipid droplets induce significant inhibition of tumor growth with minimal side effects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lipid Metabolism in Regulation of Macrophage Functions</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/33036870/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/33036870/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Macrophages are cells of the innate immune system that regulate the maintenance of tissue homeostasis, host defense during pathogen infection, and tissue repair in response to tissue injury. Recent studies indicate that macrophage functions are influenced by cellular metabolism, including lipid metabolism. Here, we review how macrophage lipid metabolism can be dynamically altered in different physiological and pathophysiological contexts and the key regulators involved. We also describe how alterations in lipid metabolism are integrated with the signaling pathways that specify macrophage functions, allowing for coordinated control of macrophage biology. Finally, we discuss how dysregulated lipid metabolism contributes to perturbed macrophage functions in settings such as atherosclerosis and pathogen infections.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Circadian rhythms and obesity: Timekeeping governs lipid metabolism</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/32656907/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/32656907/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Almost all living organisms have evolved autoregulatory transcriptional-translational feedback loops that produce oscillations with a period of approximately 24-h. These endogenous time keeping mechanisms are called circadian clocks. The main function of these circadian clocks is to drive overt circadian rhythms in the physiology of the organisms to ensure that main physiological functions are in synchrony with the external environment. Disruption of circadian rhythms caused by genetic or environmental factors has long-term consequences for metabolic health. Of relevance, host circadian rhythmicity and lipid metabolism are increasingly recognized to cross-regulate and the circadian clock-lipid metabolism interplay may involve in the development of obesity. Multiple systemic and molecular mechanisms, such as hormones (ie, melatonin, leptin, and glucocorticoid), the gut microbiome, and energy metabolism, link the circadian clock and lipid metabolism, and predictably, the deregulation of circadian clock-lipid metabolism interplay can increase the risk of obesity, which in turn may exacerbate circadian disorganization. Feeding time and dietary nutrients are two of key environmental Zeitgebers affecting the circadian rhythm-lipid metabolism interplay, and the influencing mechanisms in obesity development are highlighted in this review. Together, the characterization of the clock machinery in lipid metabolism aimed at producing a healthy circadian lifestyle may improve obesity care.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emerging Roles for the Lysosome in Lipid Metabolism</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/28838620/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/28838620/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Precise regulation of lipid biosynthesis, transport, and storage is key to the homeostasis of cells and organisms. Cells rely on a sophisticated but poorly understood network of vesicular and nonvesicular transport mechanisms to ensure efficient delivery of lipids to target organelles. The lysosome stands at the crossroads of this network due to its ability to process and sort exogenous and endogenous lipids. The lipid-sorting function of the lysosome is intimately connected to its recently discovered role as a metabolic command-and-control center, which relays multiple nutrient cues to the master growth regulator, mechanistic target of rapamycin complex (mTORC)1 kinase. In turn, mTORC1 potently drives anabolic processes, including de novo lipid synthesis, while inhibiting lipid catabolism. Here, we describe the dual role of the lysosome in lipid transport and biogenesis, and we discuss how integration of these two processes may play important roles both in normal physiology and in disease.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
