<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>piRNA | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/pirna/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/pirna/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>piRNA</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>piRNA</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/pirna/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>piRNAs Interact with Cold-Shock Domain-Containing RNA Binding Proteins and Regulate Neuronal Gene Expression During Differentiation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34982407/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34982407/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;piRNAs (PIWI-interacting RNAs) are a class of small non-coding RNAs (ncRNAs) abundantly expressed in germline cells and involved in suppressing the transposon activity. Interestingly, recent studies have found piRNA expression in the central nervous system (CNS), yet the underlying biological significance remains largely unknown. In this study, we investigated the expression and function of piRNAs during the retinoic acid (RA)-mediated neuronal differentiation in NT2 cells, a human embryonal carcinoma cell line. We identified a cohort of differentially expressed piRNAs by microarray. Two piRNAs, DQ582359 and DQ596268, were increasingly upregulated during the RA-induced differentiation and involved in regulating the expression of neuronal markers, MAP2 and TUBB3. Furthermore, these piRNAs were found to associate with cold-shock domain (CSD)-containing RNA binding proteins, DIS3, DIS3L2, and YB-1. Markedly, overexpression of these piRNAs further enhanced the protein levels of MAP2 and TUBB3, potentially by downregulating DIS3, DIS3L2, and YB-1. Hence, our study has identified a novel somatic function of piRNAs in regulating neuronal gene expression. The interaction of piRNA with some CSD-containing proteins can be further explored to enhance neuronal differentiation to treat neurodegenerative diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Terminal modification, sequence, length, and PIWI-protein identity determine piRNA stability</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34626567/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34626567/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2′-O-methylation protects mouse and fly piRNAs from complementarity-dependent decay&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Distinct pathways decay mouse piRNAs with triggers complementary to a piRNA 5′ or 3′ end&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mouse pre-piRNAs with U- or G-rich tracts decay faster in testis lysate and in vivo&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MIWI-bound pre-piRNAs decay faster than MILI-bound pre-piRNAs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Summary&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In animals, PIWI-interacting RNAs (piRNAs) silence transposons, fight viral infections, and regulate gene expression. piRNA biogenesis concludes with 3′ terminal trimming and 2′-O-methylation. Both trimming and methylation influence piRNA stability. Our biochemical data show that multiple mechanisms destabilize unmethylated mouse piRNAs, depending on whether the piRNA 5′ or 3′ sequence is complementary to a trigger RNA. Unlike target-directed degradation of microRNAs, complementarity-dependent destabilization of piRNAs in mice and flies is blocked by 3′ terminal 2′-O-methylation and does not require base pairing to both the piRNA seed and the 3′ sequence. In flies, 2′-O-methylation also protects small interfering RNAs (siRNAs) from complementarity-dependent destruction. By contrast, pre-piRNA trimming protects mouse piRNAs from a degradation pathway unaffected by trigger complementarity. In testis lysate and &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt;, internal or 3′ terminal uridine- or guanine-rich tracts accelerate pre-piRNA decay. Loss of both trimming and 2′-O-methylation causes the mouse piRNA pathway to collapse, demonstrating that these modifications collaborate to stabilize piRNAs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PIWIL1 promotes gastric cancer via a piRNA-independent mechanism</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32848063/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32848063/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Erratum in:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Correction for Shi &lt;em&gt;et al.&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.pnas.org/doi/full/10.1073/pnas.2019929117&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;PIWIL1 promotes gastric cancer via a piRNA-independent mechanism&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Targeted cancer therapy aims to achieve specific elimination of cancerous but not normal cells. Recently, PIWI proteins, a subfamily of the PAZ-PIWI domain (PPD) protein family, have emerged as promising candidates for targeted cancer therapy. PPD proteins are essential for small noncoding RNA pathways. The Argonaute subfamily partners with microRNA and small interfering RNA, whereas the PIWI subfamily partners with PIWI-interacting RNA (piRNA). Both PIWI proteins and piRNA are mostly expressed in the germline and best known for their function in transposon silencing, with no detectable function in mammalian somatic tissues. However, PIWI proteins become aberrantly expressed in multiple types of somatic cancers, thus gaining interest in targeted therapy. Despite this, little is known about the regulatory mechanism of PIWI proteins in cancer. Here we report that one of the four PIWI proteins in humans, PIWIL1, is highly expressed in gastric cancer tissues and cell lines. Knocking out the PIWIL1 gene (&lt;em&gt;PIWIL1-KO&lt;/em&gt;) drastically reduces gastric cancer cell proliferation, migration, metastasis, and tumorigenesis. RNA deep sequencing of gastric cancer cell line SNU-1 reveals that KO significantly changes the transcriptome, causing the up-regulation of most of its associated transcripts. Surprisingly, few bona fide piRNAs exist in gastric cancer cells. Furthermore, abolishing the piRNA-binding activity of PIWIL1 does not affect its oncogenic function. Thus, PIWIL1 function in gastric cancer cells is independent of piRNA. This piRNA-independent regulation involves interaction with the UPF1-mediated nonsense-mediated mRNA decay (NMD) mechanism. Altogether, our findings reveal a piRNA-independent function of PIWIL1 in promoting gastric cancer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rapid evolution and conserved function of the piRNA pathway</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/30958115/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/30958115/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Transposons are major genome constituents that can mobilize and trigger mutations, DNA breaks and chromosome rearrangements. Transposon silencing is particularly important in the germline, which is dedicated to transmission of the inherited genome. Piwi-interacting RNAs (piRNAs) guide a host defence system that transcriptionally and post-transcriptionally silences transposons during germline development. While germline control of transposons by the piRNA pathway is conserved, many piRNA pathway genes are evolving rapidly under positive selection, and the piRNA biogenesis machinery shows remarkable phylogenetic diversity. Conservation of core function combined with rapid gene evolution is characteristic of a host-pathogen arms race, suggesting that transposons and the piRNA pathway are engaged in an evolutionary tug of war that is driving divergence of the biogenesis machinery. Recent studies suggest that this process may produce biochemical incompatibilities that contribute to reproductive isolation and species divergence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PIWI-interacting RNAs: small RNAs with big functions</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/30446728/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/30446728/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In animals, PIWI-interacting RNAs (piRNAs) of 21-35 nucleotides in length silence transposable elements, regulate gene expression and fight viral infection. piRNAs guide PIWI proteins to cleave target RNA, promote heterochromatin assembly and methylate DNA. The architecture of the piRNA pathway allows it both to provide adaptive, sequence-based immunity to rapidly evolving viruses and transposons and to regulate conserved host genes. piRNAs silence transposons in the germ line of most animals, whereas somatic piRNA functions have been lost, gained and lost again across evolution. Moreover, most piRNA pathway proteins are deeply conserved, but different animals employ remarkably divergent strategies to produce piRNA precursor transcripts. Here, we discuss how a common piRNA pathway allows animals to recognize diverse targets, ranging from selfish genetic elements to genes essential for gametogenesis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
