<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Porcine Reproductive and Respiratory Syndrome Virus | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/porcine-reproductive-and-respiratory-syndrome-virus/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/porcine-reproductive-and-respiratory-syndrome-virus/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Porcine Reproductive and Respiratory Syndrome Virus</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Porcine Reproductive and Respiratory Syndrome Virus</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/porcine-reproductive-and-respiratory-syndrome-virus/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>miRNA let-7 family regulated by NEAT1 and ARID3A/NF-κB inhibits PRRSV-2 replication in vitro and in vivo</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36215225/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36215225/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Porcine reproductive and respiratory syndrome (PRRS) is one of the most economically devastating diseases affecting the swine industry worldwide. To investigate the role of miRNAs in the infection and susceptibility of PRRS virus (PRRSV), twenty-four miRNA libraries were constructed and sequenced from PRRSV-infected and mock-infected Porcine alveolar macrophages (PAMs) of Meishan, Landrace, Pietrain and Qingping pigs at 9 hours post infection (hpi), 36 hpi, and 60 hpi. The let-7 family miRNAs were significantly differentially expressed between PRRSV-infected and mock-infected PAMs from 4 pig breeds. The let-7 family miRNAs could significantly inhibit PRRSV-2 replication by directly targeting the 3&amp;rsquo;UTR of the PRRSV-2 genome and porcine IL6, which plays an important role in PRRSV replication and lung injury. NEAT1 acts as a competing endogenous lncRNA (ceRNA) to upregulate IL6 by attaching let-7 in PAMs. EMSA and ChIP results confirmed that ARID3A could bind to the promoter region of pri-let-7a/let-7f/let-7d gene cluster and inhibit the expression of the let-7 family. Moreover, the NF-κB signaling pathway inhibits the expression of the let-7 family by affecting the nuclear import of ARID3A. The pEGFP-N1-let-7 significantly reduced viral infections and pathological changes in PRRSV-infected piglets. Taken together, NEAT1/ARID3A/let-7/IL6 play significant roles in PRRSV-2 infection and may be promising therapeutic targets for PRRS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Construction of a Porcine Reproductive and Respiratory Syndrome Virus with Nanoluc Luciferase Reporter: a Stable and Highly Efficient Tool for Viral Quantification Both In Vitro and In Vivo</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35758677/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35758677/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Porcine reproductive and respiratory syndrome virus (PRRSV) is one of the most economically important pathogens for the global pork industry, characterized for its genetic variation and unsatisfied heterological protection from vaccines. A high-throughput screening platform for developing anti-PRRSV therapies is urgently needed. Here, an 11-amino-acid subunit HiBiT derived from NanoLuc luciferase was inserted into the PRRSV genome at four loci of the Nsp2 coding region or as an additional TRS2 driven open reading frame (ORF) between the ORF7 and 3&amp;rsquo;-untranscribed region (3&amp;rsquo;-UTR), respectively, and five recombinant viruses with luciferase activity were successfully rescued. The virological characteristics of the representative virus RvJX-Nsp2&lt;sub&gt;325&lt;/sub&gt;-HiBiT were investigated. &lt;em&gt;In vitro&lt;/em&gt;, it displayed similar growth kinetics as the parental virus and keeps the luciferase activity and genetic stability after eight rounds of serial passages. The concept-proof test confirmed that RvJX-Nsp2&lt;sub&gt;325&lt;/sub&gt;-HiBiT can be easily used to evaluate the efficacy of antiviral reagents by detecting the reduction of luciferase activity, showing a consistent trend with infectious titers, as well as to set a novel convenient virus neutralization assay based on the intensity of luciferase activity. Last, the viral proliferation, virulence, validity, and HiBiT stability were further investigated in pig inoculation study, showing that the luciferase activity can be directly detected in the tissue samples or indirectly from the MARC-145 cells inoculated with sera from RvJX-Nsp2&lt;sub&gt;325&lt;/sub&gt;-HiBiT-inoculated pigs. Taken together, the results indicate that the HiBiT-tagged virus is a convenient and stable tool for evaluating viral propagation both &lt;em&gt;in vitro&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt;, which can provide a high-efficient platform for screening and evaluating anti-PRRSV therapies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Importance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luciferase reporter tagged virus is crucial to viral quantification in the study of viral replication, pathogenesis and exploring antiviral reagents. It is urgently needed for PRRSV academia to construct a stable, fast, and high-throughput reporting system, which can be used both &lt;em&gt;in vitro&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt;. Here, an 11-amino-acid luciferase subunit was successfully inserted into the PRRSV genome; the feasibility, genetic stability, and efficiency for viral quantification both &lt;em&gt;in vitro&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt; were characterized; and the results demonstrated it has greatly improved the convenience and efficiency for screening the anti-PRRSV reagents. Furthermore, a novel luciferase-based virus neutralization assay was successfully set, which can eliminate the step of sample gradient dilution and greatly improve the convenience and throughput of neutralizing antibody testing. Predictably, it will greatly facilitate the screening and evaluating anti-PRRSV therapies, as well as the mechanistic study of its replication and pathogenesis in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AMG487 inhibits PRRSV replication and ameliorates lung injury in pig lung xenografts by down-regulating the expression of ANXA2</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35405171/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35405171/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Porcine reproductive and respiratory syndrome (PRRS) is a pig disease caused by the PRRS virus (PRRSV) that is characterized with diffuse interstitial pneumonia and lung edema. High expressions of chemokine CXCL10 and its receptor CXCR3 are reported in infected porcine lungs. Since CXCR3 is a key player in host inflammatory response, it might be a therapeutic target to treat lung damage caused by PRRSV infection. The size of pigs has long hampered research into molecular mechanisms of PRRS and validating the potential pharmaceutical targets. In this study, a porcine lung xenograft model with PRRSV infection was generated in immunodeficient mice to evaluate the therapeutic effects of the CXCR3 antagonist AMG487 on PRRSV infection-induced lung injury. The porcine lung tissues developed normally two weeks after xeno-transplantation in the mouse kidney capsule. Infection of PRRSV resulted in its efficient replication in the xenografts and histological damage to the porcine lung tissue structure, with no or little effects on mouse lungs. AMG487 administration dramatically reduced the number of PRRSV genome copies and significantly alleviated the porcine lung injury. Furthermore, treatment of AMG487 in cultured porcine macrophages consistently suppressed PRRSV replication with significant downregulation of Annexin A2 (ANXA2), a cellular protein facilitating viral replication. These findings provide a suitable model for evaluating new antiviral therapies as well as a possible therapeutic option for virus infection-induced lung injury.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Porcine reproductive and respiratory syndrome virus nsp4 positively regulates cellular cholesterol to inhibit type I interferon production</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34911669/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34911669/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cellular cholesterol plays an important role in the life cycles of enveloped viruses. Previous studies by our group and other groups have demonstrated that the depletion of cellular cholesterol by methyl-β-cyclodextrin (MβCD) reduces the proliferation of porcine reproductive and respiratory syndrome virus (PRRSV), a porcine Arterivirus that has been devastating the swine industry worldwide for over two decades. However, how PRRSV infection regulates cholesterol synthesis is not fully understood. In this study, we showed that PRRSV infection upregulated the activity of protein phosphatase 2 (PP2A), which subsequently activated 3-hydroxy-3-methylglutaryl coenzyme A reductase (HMGCR), the rate-limiting enzyme in the cholesterol synthesis pathway, to increase the levels of cellular cholesterol. By screening the PRRSV-encoded proteins, we showed that nsp4 dominated the upregulation of cellular cholesterol, independently of the 3C-like protease activity of nsp4. A mutation analysis showed that domain I (amino acids 1-80) of PRRSV nsp4 interacted with PR65 alpha (PR65α), the structural subunit, and PP2Ac, the catalytic subunit, of PP2A. Importantly, domain I of nsp4 inhibited Sendai virus-induced interferon β production, and this inhibitory effect was eliminated by Lovastatin, an HMGCR inhibitor, indicating that the upregulation of cellular cholesterol by nsp4 is a strategy used by PRRSV to suppress the antiviral innate immunity of its host. Collectively, we here demonstrated the mechanism by which PRRSV regulates cellular cholesterol synthesis and reported a novel strategy by which PRRSV evades its host&amp;rsquo;s antiviral innate immune response.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
