<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Immunotherapy | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/immunotherapy/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/immunotherapy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Immunotherapy</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Immunotherapy</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/immunotherapy/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Soluble and cell-based markers of immune checkpoint inhibitor-associated nephritis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36657813/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36657813/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Non-invasive biomarkers of immune checkpoint inhibitor-associated acute tubulointerstitial nephritis (ICI-nephritis) are urgently needed. Because ICIs block immune checkpoint pathways that include cytotoxic T lymphocyte antigen 4 (CTLA4), we hypothesized that biomarkers of immune dysregulationpreviously defined in patients with congenital CTLA4 deficiency, including elevated soluble interleukin-2 receptor alpha (sIL-2R) and flow cytometric cell-based markers of B and T cell dysregulation in peripheral blood may aid the diagnosis of ICI-nephritis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; A retrospective cohort of patients diagnosed with ICI-nephritis was compared with three prospectively enrolled control cohorts: ICI-treated controls without immune-related adverse events, patients not on ICIs with hemodynamic acute kidney injury (hemodynamic AKI), and patients not on ICIs with biopsy proven acute interstitial nephritis from other causes (non-ICI-nephritis). sIL-2R level and flow cytometric parameters were compared between groups using Wilcoxon rank sum test or Kruskal-Wallis test. Receiver operating characteristic curves were generated to define the accuracy of sIL-2R and flow cytometric biomarkers in diagnosing ICI-nephritis. The downstream impact of T cell activation in the affected kidney was investigated using archived biopsy samples to evaluate the gene expression of &lt;em&gt;IL2RA&lt;/em&gt;, IL-2 signaling, and T cell receptor signaling in patients with ICI-nephritis compared with other causes of drug-induced nephritis, acute tubular injury, and histologically normal controls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; sIL-2R level in peripheral blood was significantly higher in patients with ICI-nephritis (N=24) (median 2.5-fold upper limit of normal (ULN), IQR 1.9-3.3), compared with ICI-treated controls (N=10) (median 0.8-fold ULN, IQR 0.5-0.9, &lt;em&gt;p&lt;/em&gt;&amp;lt;0.001) and hemodynamic AKI controls (N=6) (median 0.9-fold-ULN, IQR 0.7-1.1, &lt;em&gt;p&lt;/em&gt;=0.008). A sIL-2R cut-off point of 1.75-fold ULN was highly diagnostic of ICI-nephritis (area under the curve &amp;gt;96%) when compared with either ICI-treated or hemodynamic AKI controls. By peripheral blood flow cytometry analysis, lower absolute CD8+T cells, CD45RA+CD8+ T cells, memory CD27+B cells, and expansion of plasmablasts were prominent features of ICI-nephritis compared with ICI-treated controls. Gene expressions for &lt;em&gt;IL2RA&lt;/em&gt;, IL-2 signaling, and T cell receptor signaling in the kidney tissue with ICI-nephritis were significantly higher compared with controls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/em&gt; Elevated sIL-2R level and flow cytometric markers of both B and T cell dysregulation may aid the diagnosis of ICI-nephritis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CD200&#43; cytotoxic T lymphocytes in the tumor microenvironment are crucial for efficacious anti-PD-1/PD-L1 therapy</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36652534/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36652534/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anti-PD-1/PD-L1 therapy, either by anti-PD-1 antibody or anti-PD-L1 antibody, has efficacy by reinvigorating tumor-infiltrating CD8+ T cells in a subset of patients with cancer, but it has unequal effects on heterogeneous CD8+ T cell populations. Hence, the subset crucial to efficacious PD-1 blockade therapy remains elusive. Here, we found an increase in tumor-infiltrating CD200&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; cytotoxic T lymphocytes (CTLs) upon PD-1/PD-L1 blockade, with higher proportions of CD200&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T cells positively related to a favorable clinical outcome to anti-PD-1/PD-L1 therapy in three independent cohorts of patients with cancer. Using multiple mouse tumor models, we demonstrated that CD200&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; CTLs are essential for efficacious anti-PD-L1 therapy. Mechanistically, we observed a unique chromatin landscape in CD200&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; CTLs and found that these cells are enriched for tumor antigen-specific CTLs and have antitumor effector functions. Coinoculation of CD200&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; CTLs with tumor cells led to robust tumor regression in two transplanted mouse models. Clinically, we found that infiltration of CD200&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; CTLs into tumors could predict immunotherapy efficacy in six patient cohorts. Together, our findings reveal that CD200&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; CTLs in the tumor microenvironment are crucial for efficacious anti-PD-1/PD-L1 therapy and could serve as a predictor of successful immunotherapy in the clinic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Macrophage Membrane-Coated Nano-Gemcitabine Promotes Lymphocyte Infiltration and Synergizes AntiPD-L1 to Restore the Tumoricidal Function</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36525314/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36525314/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The limited lymphocyte infiltration and exhaustion of tumoricidal functions in solid tumors remain a formidable obstacle to cancer immunotherapy. Herein, we designed a macrophage membrane-coated nano-gemcitabine system (MNGs) to promote lymphocyte infiltration and then synergized anti-programmed death ligand 1 (antiPD-L1) to reinvigorate the exhausted lymphocytes. MNGs exhibited effective intratumor-permeating and responsive drug-releasing capacity, produced notable elimination of versatile immunosuppressive cells, and promoted lymphocyte infiltration into cancer cell regions in tumors, but over 50% of these infiltrated lymphocytes were in the exhausted state. Compared with MNG monotherapy, the MNGs+antiPD-L1 combination produced 31.77% and 30.63% reduction of exhausted CD3&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt;CD8&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T cells and natural killer (NK) cells and 2.83- and 3.17-fold increases of interferon-γ (IFN-γ)-positive subtypes, respectively, thereby resulting in considerable therapeutic benefits in several tumor models. Thus, MNGs provide an encouraging strategy to promote lymphocyte infiltration and synergize antiPD-L1 to restore their tumoricidal function for cancer immunotherapy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microenvironmental ammonia enhances T cell exhaustion in colorectal cancer</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36528023/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36528023/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Autochthonous metastatic mouse model of colon cancer is refractory to immunotherapy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ammonia accumulates in tumors and reduces T cell function &lt;em&gt;in vitro&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ammonia decreases T cell transsulfuration leading to altered redox status&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clearance of ammonia reactivates T cells and decreases colorectal cancer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Effective therapies are lacking for patients with advanced colorectal cancer (CRC). The CRC tumor microenvironment has elevated metabolic waste products due to altered metabolism and proximity to the microbiota. The role of metabolite waste in tumor development, progression, and treatment resistance is unclear. We generated an autochthonous metastatic mouse model of CRC and used unbiased multi-omic analyses to reveal a robust accumulation of tumoral ammonia. The high ammonia levels induce T cell metabolic reprogramming, increase exhaustion, and decrease proliferation. CRC patients have increased serum ammonia, and the ammonia-related gene signature correlates with altered T cell response, adverse patient outcomes, and lack of response to immune checkpoint blockade. We demonstrate that enhancing ammonia clearance reactivates T cells, decreases tumor growth, and extends survival. Moreover, decreasing tumor-associated ammonia enhances anti-PD-L1 efficacy. These findings indicate that enhancing ammonia detoxification can reactivate T cells, highlighting a new approach to enhance the efficacy of immunotherapies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dendritic cell derived exosomes loaded neoantigens for personalized cancer immunotherapies</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36470333/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36470333/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therapeutics that discriminate between the genetic makeup of normal cells and tumour cells are valuable for treating and understanding cancer. Small molecules with oncogene-selective lethality may reveal novel functions of oncoproteins and enable the creation of more selective drugs. Here we describe the mechanism of action of the selective anti-tumour agent erastin, involving the RAS-RAF-MEK signalling pathway functioning in cell proliferation, differentiation and survival. Erastin exhibits greater lethality in human tumour cells harbouring mutations in the oncogenes HRAS, KRAS or BRAF. Using affinity purification and mass spectrometry, we discovered that erastin acts through mitochondrial voltage-dependent anion channels (VDACs)&amp;ndash;a novel target for anti-cancer drugs. We show that erastin treatment of cells harbouring oncogenic RAS causes the appearance of oxidative species and subsequent death through an oxidative, non-apoptotic mechanism. RNA-interference-mediated knockdown of VDAC2 or VDAC3 caused resistance to erastin, implicating these two VDAC isoforms in the mechanism of action of erastin. Moreover, using purified mitochondria expressing a single VDAC isoform, we found that erastin alters the permeability of the outer mitochondrial membrane. Finally, using a radiolabelled analogue and a filter-binding assay, we show that erastin binds directly to VDAC2. These results demonstrate that ligands to VDAC proteins can induce non-apoptotic cell death selectively in some tumour cells harbouring activating mutations in the RAS-RAF-MEK pathway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reprogramming of T cell-derived small extracellular vesicles using IL2 surface engineering induces potent anti-cancer effects through miRNA delivery</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36447429/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36447429/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;T cell-derived small extracellular vesicles (sEVs) exhibit anti-cancer effects. However, their anti-cancer potential should be reinforced to enhance clinical applicability. Herein, we generated interleukin-2-tethered sEVs (IL2-sEVs) from engineered Jurkat T cells expressing IL2 at the plasma membrane via a flexible linker to induce an autocrine effect. IL2-sEVs increased the anti-cancer ability of CD8&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T cells without affecting regulatory T (T&lt;sub&gt;reg&lt;/sub&gt; ) cells and down-regulated cellular and exosomal PD-L1 expression in melanoma cells, causing their increased sensitivity to CD8+ T cell-mediated cytotoxicity. Its effect on CD8&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T and melanoma cells was mediated by several IL2-sEV-resident microRNAs (miRNAs), whose expressions were upregulated by the autocrine effects of IL2. Among the miRNAs, miR-181a-3p and miR-223-3p notably reduced the PD-L1 protein levels in melanoma cells. Interestingly, miR-181a-3p increased the activity of CD8&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T cells while suppressing Treg cell activity. IL2-sEVs inhibited tumour progression in melanoma-bearing immunocompetent mice, but not in immunodeficient mice. The combination of IL2-sEVs and existing anti-cancer drugs significantly improved anti-cancer efficacy by decreasing PD-L1 expression in vivo. Thus, IL2-sEVs are potential cancer immunotherapeutic agents that regulate both immune and cancer cells by reprogramming miRNA levels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IL-6/STAT3 signaling in tumor cells restricts the expression of frameshift-derived neoantigens by SMG1 induction</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36443756/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36443756/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; The quality and quantity of tumor neoantigens derived from tumor mutations determines the fate of the immune response in cancer. Frameshift mutations elicit better tumor neoantigens, especially when they are not targeted by nonsense-mediated mRNA decay (NMD). For tumor progression, malignant cells need to counteract the immune response including the silencing of immunodominant neoantigens (antigen immunoediting) and promoting an immunosuppressive tumor microenvironment. Although NMD inhibition has been reported to induce tumor immunity and increase the expression of cryptic neoantigens, the possibility that NMD activity could be modulated by immune forces operating in the tumor microenvironment as a new immunoediting mechanism has not been addressed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; We study the effect of SMG1 expression (main kinase that initiates NMD) in the survival and the nature of the tumor immune infiltration using TCGA RNAseq and scRNAseq datasets of breast, lung and pancreatic cancer. Different murine tumor models were used to corroborate the antitumor immune dependencies of NMD. We evaluate whether changes of SMG1 expression in malignant cells impact the immune response elicited by cancer immunotherapy. To determine how NMD fluctuates in malignant cells we generated a luciferase reporter system to track NMD activity in vivo under different immune conditions. Cytokine screening, in silico studies and functional assays were conducted to determine the regulation of SMG1 via IL-6/STAT3 signaling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; IL-6/STAT3 signaling induces SMG1, which limits the expression of potent frameshift neoantigens that are under NMD control compromising the outcome of the immune response.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/em&gt; We revealed a new neoantigen immunoediting mechanism regulated by immune forces (IL-6/STAT3 signaling) responsible for silencing otherwise potent frameshift mutation-derived neoantigens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The emerging field of oncolytic virus-based cancer immunotherapy</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/36402738/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/36402738/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Natural or genetically modified oncolytic viruses (OVs) are promising antitumor agents for specifically targeting tumor cells without harming normal cells.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;OV-based oncolysis and OV-induced antiviral immune responses play an important role in remodeling the tumor microenvironment (TME) from immunologically &amp;lsquo;cold&amp;rsquo; to &amp;lsquo;hot&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As single agents or combined with other strategies, OVs can enhance cancer immunotherapy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;OV persistence, replication, spread, systemic delivery, lack of therapeutic biomarkers, and moderate efficacy as single agents are among the main challenges in the field. If these problems can be solved, OV will most likely substantially enhance clinical outcomes for cancer patients.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oncolytic viruses (OVs) provide novel and promising therapeutic options for patients with cancers resistant to traditional therapies. Natural or genetically modified OVs are multifaceted tumor killers. They directly lyse tumor cells while sparing normal cells, and indirectly potentiate antitumor immunity by releasing antigens and activating inflammatory responses in the tumor microenvironment. However, some limitations, such as limited penetration of OVs into tumors, short persistence, and the host antiviral immune response, are impeding the broad translation of oncolytic virotherapy into the clinic. If these challenges can be overcome, combination therapies, such as OVs plus immune checkpoint blockade (ICB), chimeric antigen receptor (CAR) T cells, or CAR natural killer (NK) cells, may provide powerful therapeutic platforms in the clinic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Immunological conversion of solid tumours using a bispecific nanobioconjugate for cancer immunotherapy</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36357792/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36357792/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Solid tumours display a limited response to immunotherapies. By contrast, haematological malignancies exhibit significantly higher response rates to immunotherapies as compared with solid tumours. Among several microenvironmental and biological disparities, the differential expression of unique immune regulatory molecules contributes significantly to the interaction of blood cancer cells with immune cells. The self-ligand receptor of the signalling lymphocytic activation molecule family member 7 (SLAMF7), a molecule that is critical in promoting the body&amp;rsquo;s innate immune cells to detect and engulf cancer cells, is expressed nearly exclusively on the cell surface of haematologic tumours, but not on solid ones. Here we show that a bispecific nanobioconjugate that enables the decoration of SLAMF7 on the surface of solid tumours induces robust phagocytosis and activates the phagocyte cyclic guanosine monophosphate-adenosine monophosphate synthase-stimulator of interferon genes (cGAS-STING) pathway, sensitizing the tumours to immune checkpoint blockade. Our findings support an immunological conversion strategy that uses nano-adjuvants to improve the effectiveness of immunotherapies for solid tumours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Targeting tumour-intrinsic N7-methylguanosine tRNA modification inhibits MDSC recruitment and improves anti-PD-1 efficacy</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36283801/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36283801/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;u&gt;Objective&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/em&gt; Intrahepatic cholangiocarcinoma (ICC) exhibits very low response rate to immune checkpoint inhibitors (ICIs) and the underlying mechanism is largely unknown. We investigate the tumour immune microenvironment (TIME) of ICCs and the underlying regulatory mechanisms with the aim of developing new target to inhibit tumour growth and improve anti-programmed cell death protein-1 (PD-1) efficacy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;u&gt;Design&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/em&gt; Tumour tissues from patients with ICC together with hydrodynamic ICC mouse models were employed to identify the key cell population in TIME of ICCs. Functional analysis and mechanism studies were performed using cell culture, conditional knockout mouse model and hydrodynamic transfection ICC model. The efficacy of single or combined therapy with anti-PD-1 antibody, gene knockout and chemical inhibitor were evaluated in vivo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;u&gt;Results&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/em&gt; Polymorphonuclear myeloid-derived suppressor cells (PMN-MDSCs) are enriched in advanced ICCs and significantly correlated with N&lt;sup&gt;7&lt;/sup&gt;-methylguanosine tRNA methyltransferase METTL1. Using diverse in vivo cancer models, we demonstrate the crucial immunomodulator function of METTL1 in regulation of PMN-MDSC accumulation in TIME and ICC progression. Mechanistically, &lt;em&gt;CXCL8&lt;/em&gt; in human and &lt;em&gt;Cxcl5&lt;/em&gt; in mouse are key translational targets of METTL1 that facilitate its function in promoting PMN-MDSC accumulation in TIME and ICC progression in vivo. Co-blockade of METTL1 and its downstream chemokine pathway enhances the anti-PD-1 efficacy in ICC preclinical mouse models.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;u&gt;Conclusions&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/em&gt; Our data uncover novel mechanisms underlying chemokine regulation and TIME shaping at the layer of messenger RNA translation level and provide new insights for development of efficient cancer immunotherapeutic strategies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hierarchical Microparticles Delivering Oxaliplatin and NLG919 Nanoprodrugs for Local Chemo-immunotherapy</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36263713/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36263713/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chemo-immunotherapy shows promising antitumor therapeutic outcomes for many primary cancers. Research in this area has been focusing on developing an ideal formula that enables the potent efficacy of chemo-immunotherapy in combating various cancers with reduced systemic toxicity. Herein, we present novel hierarchical hydrogel microparticles (MDDP) delivering oxaliplatin and NLG919 nanoprodrugs for local chemo-immunotherapy with desired features. The oxaliplatin prodrug and NLG919 were efficiently loaded in the dual-drug polymeric nanoparticles (DDP NPs), which were further encapsulated into a MDDP by using microfluidic technology. When delivered to the tumor site, the DDP NPs will be sustainedly released from the MDDP and retained locally to reduce systemic toxicity. After being endocytosed by cancer cells, the cytotoxic oxaliplatin and NLG919 could be successfully triggered to release from DDP NPs in a chain-shattering manner, leading to the immunogenic cell death (ICD) of tumor cells and the suppression of intratumoral immunosuppressive Tregs, respectively. With the assistance of an immune modulator, the chemotherapeutics-induced ICD could trigger robust systemic antitumor immune responses, presenting superior synergistic antitumor efficacies. Thus, the hierarchical microparticles could substantially inhibit the growth of mouse subcutaneous colorectal tumors, breast tumors, and colorectal tumors with large initial sizes via synergized chemo-immunotherapy, showing great potential in the practical clinical application of oncotherapy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Facts and Hopes in the Relationship of EBV with Cancer Immunity and Immunotherapy</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/35686929/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/35686929/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Epstein-Barr virus (EBV), the first identified human tumor virus, infects and takes up residency in almost every human. However, EBV genome-positive tumors arise in only a tiny minority of infected people, presumably when the virus-carrying tumor cells are able to evade immune surveillance. Traditional views regard viral antigens as the principal targets of host immune surveillance against virus-infected cells. However, recent findings indicate that EBV-infected/-transformed B cells elicit both cytotoxic CD8&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; and CD4&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T-cell responses against a wide range of overexpressed cellular antigens known to function as tumor-associated antigens (TAA), in addition to various EBV-encoded antigens. This not only broadens the ways by which the immune system controls EBV infection and prevents it from causing cancers, but also potentially extends immune protection toward EBV-unrelated cancers by targeting shared TAAs. The goal of this review is to incorporate these new findings with literature data and discuss future directions for improved understanding of EBV-induced antitumor immunity, as well as the hopes for rational immune strategies for cancer prevention and therapy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integrated T cell cytometry metrics for immune-monitoring applications in immunotherapy clinical trials</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36214223/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36214223/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mass cytometry, or cytometry by TOF (CyTOF), provides a robust means of determining protein-level measurements of more than 40 markers simultaneously. While the functional states of immune cells occur along continuous phenotypic transitions, cytometric studies surveying cell phenotypes often rely on static metrics, such as discrete cell-type abundances, based on canonical markers and/or restrictive gating strategies. To overcome this limitation, we applied single-cell trajectory inference and nonnegative matrix factorization methods to CyTOF data to trace the dynamics of T cell states. In the setting of cancer immunotherapy, we showed that patient-specific summaries of continuous phenotypic shifts in T cells could be inferred from peripheral blood-derived CyTOF mass cytometry data. We further illustrated that transfer learning enabled these T cell continuous metrics to be used to estimate patient-specific cell states in new sample cohorts from a reference patient data set. Our work establishes the utility of continuous metrics for CyTOF analysis as tools for translational discovery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Induction of tumor cell autosis by myxoma virus-infected CAR-T and TCR-T cells to overcome primary and acquired resistance</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36027915/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36027915/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CAR-T&lt;sup&gt;MYXV&lt;/sup&gt; cells systemically deliver MYXV into cognate antigen-expressing tumors&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;T cell-derived IFNγ synergizes with MYXV-derived M-T5 to trigger tumor cell autosis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Autosis is a form of potent bystander killing to eradicate antigen-negative tumor cells&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CAR/TCR-T&lt;sup&gt;10%MYXV&lt;/sup&gt; induces autosis and adaptive immunity to restrain antigen escape&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cytotoxicity of tumor-specific T cells requires tumor cell-to-T cell contact-dependent induction of classic tumor cell apoptosis and pyroptosis. However, this may not trigger sufficient primary responses of solid tumors to adoptive cell therapy or prevent tumor antigen escape-mediated acquired resistance. Here we test myxoma virus (MYXV)-infected tumor-specific T (T&lt;sup&gt;MYXV&lt;/sup&gt;) cells expressing chimeric antigen receptor (CAR) or T cell receptor (TCR), which systemically deliver MYXV into solid tumors to overcome primary resistance. In addition to T cell-induced apoptosis and pyroptosis, tumor eradication by CAR/TCR-T&lt;sup&gt;MYXV&lt;/sup&gt; cells is also attributed to tumor cell autosis induction, a special type of cell death. Mechanistically, T cell-derived interferon γ (IFNγ)-protein kinase B (AKT) signaling synergizes with MYXV-induced M-T5-SKP-1-VPS34 signaling to trigger robust tumor cell autosis. CAR/TCR-T&lt;sup&gt;MYXV&lt;/sup&gt;-elicited autosis functions as a type of potent bystander killing to restrain antigen escape. We uncover an unexpected synergy between T cells and MYXV to bolster solid tumor cell autosis that reinforces tumor clearance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bidirectional anisotropic palladium nanozymes reprogram macrophages to enhance collaborative chemodynamic therapy of colorectal cancer</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35981687/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35981687/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although genomewide RNA expression analysis has become a routine tool in biomedical research, extracting biological insight from such information remains a major challenge. Here, we describe a powerful analytical method called Gene Set Enrichment Analysis (GSEA) for interpreting gene expression data. The method derives its power by focusing on gene sets, that is, groups of genes that share common biological function, chromosomal location, or regulation. We demonstrate how GSEA yields insights into several cancer-related data sets, including leukemia and lung cancer. Notably, where single-gene analysis finds little similarity between two independent studies of patient survival in lung cancer, GSEA reveals many biological pathways in common. The GSEA method is embodied in a freely available software package, together with an initial database of 1,325 biologically defined gene sets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PARP inhibitor plus radiotherapy reshapes an inflamed tumor microenvironment that sensitizes small cell lung cancer to the anti-PD-1 immunotherapy</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35926817/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35926817/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PARPI plus radiation further activated cGAS/STING pathway than single treatment.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PARPI plus radiation upregulated the expression of PD-L1.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PARPI plus radiation sensitizes small cell lung cancer to anti-PD-1 immunotherapy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Small cell lung cancer (SCLC) is a highly malignant tumor with extremely poor prognosis. The treatment strategy is very limited, and patient outcomes remain dismal with the 5-year survival rate being mere 3-6%. Thus, novel therapeutic strategies for SCLC patients are urgently needed. In this study, we found that the triple-therapy of poly (ADP-ribose) polymerase (PARP) inhibitor, radiotherapy (RT) and anti-PD-1 treatment significantly inhibited tumor growth and prolonged survival in the syngeneic SCLC models in immunocompetent C57BL/6 mice. Mechanistically, we demonstrated that the combination of PARP inhibitor niraparib and RT reshaped an inflamed tumor microenvironment, including activation of the cGAS/STING immune response pathway, induction of immunogenic cell death, and upregulation of PD-L1 on tumor cells. Furthermore, this triple-therapy substantially augmented CD8+ T cell infiltration and activation, and enhanced anti-tumor effects as revealed by increased median survival time and reduced tumor volume without additional myelosuppression or hepatic injury. Together, our studies demonstrated that PARP inhibitor combined with RT potentiated anti-tumor immunity and enhanced the efficacy of anti-PD-1 immunotherapy in preclinical study, which provided a promising therapeutic strategy for SCLC patients in clinic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Organ-specific response after low-dose interleukin-2 therapy for steroid-refractory chronic graft-versus-host disease</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35617682/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35617682/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Key Points&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For 105 patients enrolled in 5 trials, the overall response rate after 8 or 12 weeks’ LD IL-2 was 48.6% and 53.3% with continued therapy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Skin involvement was the most frequent (84%); the organ-specific response rate was highest in liver (66.7%) and lowest in lung (19.2%).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite new therapeutic options, treatment of steroid-refractory chronic graft-versus-host disease (SR-cGVHD) remains challenging as organ involvement and clinical manifestations are highly variable. In previous trials of low-dose interleukin-2 (LD IL-2), we established the safety and efficacy of LD IL-2 for the treatment of SR-cGVHD. In the present report, we combined five phase 1 or 2 clinical trials conducted at our center to investigate organ-specific response rate, coinvolvement of organs, predictors of organ-specific response, and its possible association with immune response. For the 105 adult patients included in this report, the overall response rate after 8 or 12 weeks of LD IL-2 was 48.6% and 53.3%, including late responses in patients who continued treatment for extended periods. Skin was the most frequent organ involved (84%). The organ-specific response rate was highest in liver (66.7%) followed by the gastrointestinal tract (62.5%), skin (36.4%), joint/muscle/fascia (34.2%), and lung (19.2%). In multivariable analysis, shorter time from diagnosis of cGVHD to IL-2 initiation, shorter time from transplant to IL-2 initiation, and fewer prior therapies were associated with overall response as well as skin response. For immunologic correlates, the ratio of regulatory T cells:conventional T cells (ie, CD4Treg:CD4Tcon) ratio at 1 week was significantly higher in patients with overall and skin response; skin response was significantly associated with lower number of total CD3 T cells, CD4Tcon cells, and CD8 T cells and a higher number of B cells. For lung responders, terminal effector memory cell counts were lower within all T-cell populations compared with nonresponders. Organ-specific mechanisms of injury should be investigated, and organ-specific targeted therapies need to be developed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Large-scale multiplexed mosaic CRISPR perturbation in the whole organism</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35870449/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35870449/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Inducible mosaic animal for perturbation (iMAP) combines Cre-LoxP and CRISPR-Cas&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;iMAP enables large-scale in situ multiplexed mosaic gene targeting and Perturb-Atlas mapping&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;iMAP enables rapid derivation of single-gene perturbation mouse lines via breeding&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;iMAP lines are permanent resources just as conventional transgenic lines&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here, we report inducible mosaic animal for perturbation (iMAP), a transgenic platform enabling in situ CRISPR targeting of at least 100 genes in parallel throughout the mouse body. iMAP combines Cre-loxP and CRISPR-Cas9 technologies and utilizes a germline-transmitted transgene carrying a large array of individually floxed, tandemly linked gRNA-coding units. Cre-mediated recombination triggers expression of all the gRNAs in the array but only one of them per cell, converting the mice to mosaic organisms suitable for phenotypic characterization and also for high-throughput derivation of conventional single-gene perturbation lines via breeding. Using gRNA representation as a readout, we mapped a miniature Perturb-Atlas cataloging the perturbations of 90 genes across 39 tissues, which yields rich insights into context-dependent gene functions and provides a glimpse of the potential of iMAP in genome decoding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Designing antibodies as therapeutics</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/35868279/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/35868279/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Antibody therapeutics are a large and rapidly expanding drug class providing major health benefits. We provide a snapshot of current antibody therapeutics including their formats, common targets, therapeutic areas, and routes of administration. Our focus is on selected emerging directions in antibody design where progress may provide a broad benefit. These topics include enhancing antibodies for cancer, antibody delivery to organs such as the brain, gastrointestinal tract, and lungs, plus antibody developability challenges including immunogenicity risk assessment and mitigation and subcutaneous delivery. Machine learning has the potential, albeit as yet largely unrealized, for a transformative future impact on antibody discovery and engineering.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docetaxel resistance-derived LINC01085 contributes to the immunotherapy of hormone-independent prostate cancer by activating the STING/MAVS signaling pathway</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35868534/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35868534/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;LINC01085&lt;/em&gt; is deleted in hormone-independent prostate cancer (HIPC) which can predict better outcomes of HIPC patients.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;LINC01085 acts as a tumor suppressor in the tumourigenicity and metastasis of HIPC.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;LINC01085 exerts its functions by both interacting with TBK1 and GSK3β, accelerated TBK1 phosphorylation at the Ser-172 site, in HIPC.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;LINC01085 combined with PARP inhibitor and anti-PD-L1 treatment may be pivotal in the treatment of HIPC patients.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acquired docetaxel (doc) resistance, one of the major reasons for unfavorable prognosis in patients with aggressive hormone-independent prostate cancer (HIPC), is a major obstacle for patient treatment. Dysregulation of long non-coding RNAs promotes or suppresses chemoresistance in multiple cancers; however, the specific molecular mechanisms underlying HIPC remain unknown. In this study, we found that the LINC01085, as a tumor-suppressor, which showed significant clinically relevant in HIPC patients with doc-resistance. Mechanistically, in docetaxel-sensitive cells, LINC01085 could specifically bind to both TANK-binding kinase 1 (TBK1) and glycogen synthase kinase 3β (GSK3β), and higher LINC01085 RNA levels could inhibit TBK1 dimerization. Whereas, in doc-resistant cells, lower LINC01085 RNA level lost the strong binding with both, meanwhile, the interaction between TBK1 and GSK3β enhanced which accelerated TBK1 phosphorylation at the Ser-172 site, resulting in decreased expression levels of PD-L1 and NF-κB as well as the secretion of type I/III interferons. Thus, Overexpression of LINC01085 combined with immune checkpoint blockade is an effective strategy for the treatment of HIPC patients.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HuR as a molecular target for cancer therapeutics and immune-related disorders</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/35817212/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/35817212/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The control of eukaryotic gene expression occurs at multiple levels, from transcription to messenger RNA processing, transport, localization, turnover, and translation. RNA-binding proteins control gene expression and are involved in different stages of mRNA processing, including splicing, maturation, turnover, and translation. A ubiquitously expressed RBP Human antigen R is engaged in the RNA processes mentioned above but, most importantly, controls mRNA stability and turnover. Dysregulation of HuR is linked to many diseases, including cancer and other immune-related disorders. HuR targets mRNAs containing AU-rich elements at their 3&amp;rsquo;untranslated region, which encodes proteins involved in cell growth, proliferation, tumor formation, angiogenesis, immune evasion, inflammation, invasion, and metastasis. HuR overexpression has been reported in many tumor types, which led to a poor prognosis for patients. Hence, HuR is considered an appealing drug target for cancer treatment. Therefore, multiple attempts have been made to identify small molecule inhibitors for blocking HuR functions. This article reviews the current prospects of drugs that target HuR in numerous cancer types, their mode of action, and off-target effects. Furthermore, we will summarize drugs that interfered with HuR-RNA interactions and established themselves as novel therapeutics. We will also highlight the significance of HuR overexpression in multiple cancers and discuss its role in immune functions. This review provides evidence of a new era of HuR-targeted small molecules that can be used for cancer therapeutics either as a monotherapy or in combination with other cancer treatment modalities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Glycoengineered anti-CD39 promotes anticancer responses by depleting suppressive cells and inhibiting angiogenesis in tumor models</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35775486/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35775486/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Immunosuppressive cells accumulating in the tumor microenvironment constitute a formidable barrier that interferes with current immunotherapeutic approaches. A unifying feature of these tumor-associated immune and vascular endothelial cells appears to be the elevated expression of ectonucleotidase CD39, which in tandem with ecto-5&amp;rsquo;-nucleotidase CD73, catalyzes the conversion of extracellular ATP into adenosine. We glycoengineered an afucosylated anti-CD39 IgG2c and tested this reagent in mouse melanoma and colorectal tumor models. We identified major biological effects of this approach on cancer growth, associated with depletion of immunosuppressive cells, mediated through enhanced Fcγ receptor-directed (FcγR-directed), antibody-dependent cellular cytotoxicity (ADCC). Furthermore, regulatory/exhausted T cells lost CD39 expression, as a consequence of antibody-mediated trogocytosis. Most strikingly, tumor-associated macrophages and endothelial cells with high CD39 expression were effectively depleted following antibody treatment, thereby blocking angiogenesis. Tumor site-specific cellular modulation and lack of angiogenesis synergized with chemotherapy and anti-PD-L1 immunotherapy in experimental tumor models. We conclude that depleting suppressive cells and targeting tumor vasculature, through administration of afucosylated anti-CD39 antibody and the activation of ADCC, comprises an improved, purinergic system-modulating strategy for cancer therapy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NY-ESO-1-specific redirected T cells with endogenous TCR knockdown mediate tumor response and cytokine release syndrome</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35768164/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35768164/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Because of the shortage of ideal cell surface antigens, the development of T-cell receptor (TCR)-engineered T cells (TCR-T) that target intracellular antigens such as NY-ESO-1 is a promising approach for treating patients with solid tumors. However, endogenous TCRs in vector-transduced T cells have been suggested to impair cell-surface expression of transduced TCR while generating mispaired TCRs that can become self-reactive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; We conducted a first-in-human phase I clinical trial with the TCR-transduced T-cell product (TBI-1301) in patients with NY-ESO-1-expressing solid tumors. In manufacturing TCR-T cells, we used a novel affinity-enhanced NY-ESO-1-specific TCR that was transduced by a retroviral vector that enables siRNA (small interfering RNA)-mediated silencing of endogenous TCR. The patients were divided into two cohorts. Cohort 1 was given a dose of 5×10&lt;sup&gt;8&lt;/sup&gt; cells (whole cells including TCR-T cells) preconditioned with 1500 mg/m&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; cyclophosphamide. Cohort 2 was given 5× 10&lt;sup&gt;9&lt;/sup&gt; cells preconditioned with 1500 mg/m&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; cyclophosphamide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; In vitro study showed that both the CD8&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; and CD4&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T fractions of TCR-T cells exhibited cytotoxic effects against NY-ESO-1-expressing tumor cells. Three patients and six patients were allocated to cohort 1 and cohort 2, respectively. Three of the six patients who received 5×10&lt;sup&gt;9&lt;/sup&gt; cells showed tumor response, while three patients developed early-onset cytokine release syndrome (CRS). One of the patients developed a grade 3 lung injury associated with the infiltration of the TCR-T cells. No siRNA-related adverse events other than CRS were observed. Cytokines including interleukin 6 I and monocyte chemotactic protein-1/chemokine (C-C motif) ligand (CCL2)increased in the sera of patients with CRS. In vitro analysis showed these cytokines were not secreted from the T cells infused. A significant fraction of the manufactured T cells in patients with CRS was found to express either CD244, CD39, or both at high levels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; The trial showed that endogenous TCR-silenced and affinity-enhanced NY-ESO-1 TCR-T cells were safely administered except for grade 3 lung injury. The TCR-T cell infusion exhibited significant tumor response and early-onset CRS in patients with tumors that express NY-ESO-1 at high levels. The differentiation properties of the manufactured T cells may be prognostic for TCR-T-related CRS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hypoxia-inducible lentiviral gene expression in engineered human macrophages</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35728871/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35728871/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Human immune cells, including monocyte-derived macrophages, can be engineered to deliver proinflammatory cytokines, bispecific antibodies, and chimeric antigen receptors to support immune responses in different disease settings. When gene expression is regulated by constitutively active promoters, lentiviral payload gene expression is unregulated, and can result in potentially toxic quantities of proteins. Regulated delivery of lentivirally encoded proteins may allow localized or conditional therapeutic protein expression to support safe delivery of adoptively transferred, genetically modified cells with reduced capacity for systemic toxicities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; In this study, we engineered human macrophages to express genes regulated by hypoxia responsive elements included in the lentiviral promoter region to drive conditional lentiviral gene expression only under hypoxic conditions. We tested transduced macrophages cultured in hypoxic conditions for the transient induced expression of reporter genes and the secreted cytokine, interleukin-12. Expression of hypoxia-regulated genes was investigated both transcriptionally and translationally, and in the presence of human tumor cells in a slice culture system. Finally, hypoxia-regulated gene expression was evaluated in a subcutaneous humanized-mouse cancer model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; Engineered macrophages were shown to conditionally and tranisently express lentivirally encoded gene protein products, including IL-12 in hypoxic conditions &lt;em&gt;in vitro&lt;/em&gt;. On return to normoxic conditions, lentiviral payload expression returned to basal levels. Reporter genes under the control of hypoxia response elements were upregulated under hypoxic conditions in the presence of human colorectal carcinoma cells and in the hypoxic xenograft model of glioblastoma, suggesting utility for systemic engineered cell delivery capable of localized gene delivery in cancer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; Macrophages engineered to express hypoxia-regulated payloads have the potential to be administered systemically and conditionally express proteins in tissues with hypoxic conditions. In contrast to immune cells that function or survive poorly in hypoxic conditions, macrophages maintain a proinflammatory phenotype that may support continued gene and protein expression when regulated by conditional hypoxia responsive elements and naturally traffic to hypoxic microenvironments, making them ideal vehicles for therapeutic payloads to hypoxic tissues, such as solid tumors. With the ability to fine-tune delivery of potent proteins in response to endogenous microenvironments, macrophage-based cellular therapies may therefore be designed for different disease settings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implications of Hyperoxia over the Tumor Microenvironment: An Overview Highlighting the Importance of the Immune System</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/35681719/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/35681719/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hyperoxia is used in order to counteract hypoxia effects in the TME (tumor microenvironment), which are described to boost the malignant tumor phenotype and poor prognosis. The reduction of tumor hypoxic state through the formation of a non-aberrant vasculature or an increase in the toxicity of the therapeutic agent improves the efficacy of therapies such as chemotherapy. Radiotherapy efficacy has also improved, where apoptotic mechanisms seem to be implicated. Moreover, hyperoxia increases the antitumor immunity through diverse pathways, leading to an immunopermissive TME. Although hyperoxia is an approved treatment for preventing and treating hypoxemia, it has harmful side-effects. Prolonged exposure to high oxygen levels may cause acute lung injury, characterized by an exacerbated immune response, and the destruction of the alveolar-capillary barrier. Furthermore, under this situation, the high concentration of ROS may cause toxicity that will lead not only to cell death but also to an increase in chemoattractant and proinflammatory cytokine secretion. This would end in a lung leukocyte recruitment and, therefore, lung damage. Moreover, unregulated inflammation causes different consequences promoting tumor development and metastasis. This process is known as protumor inflammation, where different cell types and molecules are implicated; for instance, IL-1β has been described as a key cytokine. Although current results show benefits over cancer therapies using hyperoxia, further studies need to be conducted, not only to improve tumor regression, but also to prevent its collateral damage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CD4&#43; T-cell epitope-based heterologous prime-boost vaccination potentiates anti-tumor immunity and PD-1/PD-L1 immunotherapy</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35580929/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35580929/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Antitumor therapeutic vaccines are generally based on antigenic epitopes presented by major histocompatibility complex (MHC-I) molecules to induce tumor-specific CD8&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T cells. Paradoxically, continuous T cell receptor (TCR) stimulation from tumor-derived CD8&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T-cell epitopes can drive the functional exhaustion of tumor-specific CD8&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T cells. Tumor-specific type-I helper CD4&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T (T&lt;sub&gt;H&lt;/sub&gt;1) cells play an important role in the population maintenance and cytotoxic function of exhausted tumor-specific CD8+ T cells in the tumor microenvironment. Nonetheless, whether the vaccination strategy targeting MHC-II-restricted CD4&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T-cell epitopes to induce tumor-specific TH1 responses can confer effective antitumor immunity to restrain tumor growth is not well studied. Here, we developed a heterologous prime-boost vaccination strategy to effectively induce tumor-specific T&lt;sub&gt;H&lt;/sub&gt;1 cells and evaluated its antitumor efficacy and its capacity to potentiate PD-1/PD-L1 immunotherapy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;Listeria monocytogenes&lt;/em&gt; vector and influenza A virus (PR8 strain) vector stably expressing lymphocytic choriomeningitis virus (LCMV) glycoprotein-specific I-A&lt;sup&gt;b&lt;/sup&gt;-restricted CD4&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T cell epitope (GP&lt;sub&gt;61-80&lt;/sub&gt;) or ovalbumin-specific CD4&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T cell epitope (OVA&lt;sub&gt;323-339&lt;/sub&gt;) were constructed and evaluated their efficacy against mouse models of melanoma and colorectal adenocarcinoma expressing lymphocytic choriomeningitis virus glycoprotein and ovalbumin. The impact of CD4&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T cell epitope-based heterologous prime-boost vaccination was detected by flow-cytometer, single-cell RNA sequencing and single-cell TCR sequencing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; CD4&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T cell epitope-based heterologous prime-boost vaccination efficiently suppressed both mouse melanoma and colorectal adenocarcinoma. This vaccination primarily induced tumor-specific TH1 response, which in turn enhanced the expansion, effector function and clonal breadth of tumor-specific CD8&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T cells. Furthermore, this vaccination strategy synergized PD-L1 blockade mediated tumor suppression. Notably, prime-boost vaccination extended the duration of PD-L1 blockade induced antitumor effects by preventing the re-exhaustion of tumor-specific CD8&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T cells.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/em&gt; CD4&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T cell epitope-based heterologous prime-boost vaccination elicited potent both tumor-specific T&lt;sub&gt;H&lt;/sub&gt;1 and CTL response, leading to the efficient tumor control. This strategy can also potentiate PD-1/PD-L1 immune checkpoint blockade (ICB) against cancer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Targeting SNORA38B attenuates tumorigenesis and sensitizes immune checkpoint blockade in non-small cell lung cancer by remodeling the tumor microenvironment via regulation of GAB2/AKT/mTOR signaling pathway</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35577506/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35577506/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Non-coding RNAs (ncRNAs), including small nucleolar RNAs (snoRNAs), are widely involved in the physiological and pathological processes of human beings. While up to date, although considerable progress has been achieved in ncRNA-related pathogenesis of non-small cell lung cancer (NSCLC), the underlying mechanisms and biological significance of snoRNAs in NSCLC still need to be further clarified.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; Quantitative real-time polymerase chain reaction or RNAscope was performed to verify the expression of Small Nucleolar RNA, H/ACA Box 38B (SNORA38B) in NSCLC cell lines or clinical samples. BALB/c nude mice xenograft model or C57BL/6J mice syngeneic tumor model were estimated to detect the effects of SNORA38B in tumor growth or tumor immune microenvironment in vivo. Cytometry by time of flight, enzyme-linked immunosorbent assay and flow cytometry assay were conducted to clarify the effects and mechanisms of SNORA38B-mediated tumor immunosuppressive microenvironment. The binding activity between SNORA38B and E2F transcription factor 1(E2F1) was detected by RNA immunoprecipitation and RNA pull-down assays. Then, bioinformatics analysis and chromatin immunoprecipitation were utilized to demonstrate the regulation of GRB2-associated-binding protein 2 (GAB2) by E2F1. Moreover, the combinatorial treatment of SNORA38B locked nucleic acid (LNA) and immune checkpoint blockade (ICB) was used to treat murine Lewis lung carcinoma-derived tumor burden C57BL/6J mice to clarify the effectiveness of targeting SNORA38B in NSCLC immunotherapy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; SNORA38B was found highly expressed in NSCLC tissues and cell lines, and associated with worse prognosis. Further results showed that SNORA38B functioned as an oncogene via facilitating cell proliferation, migration, invasion, and inhibiting cell apoptosis in vitro and promoting tumorigenesis of NSCLC cells in vivo. SNORA38B could also recruit the CD4+FOXP3+ regulatory T cells by triggering tumor cells to secrete interleukin 10, which in turn reduced the infiltration of CD3+CD8+ T cells in NSCLC tumor microenvironment (TME), favoring tumor progression and poorer immune efficacy. Mechanistically, SNORA38B mainly distributed in the nucleus, and promoted NSCLC progression by regulating GAB2 transcription to activate protein kinase B (AKT)/mammalian target of rapamycin (mTOR) pathway through directly binding with E2F1. Moreover, we found that SNORA38B LNAs were able to ameliorate CD3+CD8+ T cell infiltration in TME, which sensitized NSCLC to the treatment of ICB.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; In conclusion, our data demonstrated that SNORA38B functioned as an oncogene in NSCLC both in vitro and in vivo at least in part by regulating the GAB2/AKT/mTOR pathway via directly binding to E2F1. SNORA38B could also sensitize NSCLC to immunotherapy, which may be a critical therapeutic target for NSCLC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Universal immunotherapeutic strategy for hepatocellular carcinoma with exosome vaccines that engage adaptive and innate immune responses</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35488312/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35488312/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Personalized immunotherapy utilizing cancer vaccines tailored to the tumors of individual patients holds promise for tumors with high genetic heterogeneity, potentially enabling eradication of the tumor in its entirety.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; Here, we demonstrate a general strategy for biological nanovaccines that trigger tailored tumor-specific immune responses for hepatocellular carcinoma (HCC). Dendritic cell (DC)-derived exosomes (DEX) are painted with a HCC-targeting peptide (P47-P), an α-fetoprotein epitope (AFP212-A2) and a functional domain of high mobility group nucleosome-binding protein 1 (N1ND-N), an immunoadjuvant for DC recruitment and activation, via an exosomal anchor peptide to form a &amp;ldquo;trigger&amp;rdquo; DEX vaccine (DEX&lt;sub&gt;P&amp;amp;A2&amp;amp;N&lt;/sub&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; DEX&lt;sub&gt;P&amp;amp;A2&amp;amp;N&lt;/sub&gt; specifically promoted recruitment, accumulation and activation of DCs in mice with orthotopic HCC tumor, resulting in enhanced cross-presentation of tumor neoantigens and de novo T cell response. DEX&lt;sub&gt;P&amp;amp;A2&amp;amp;N&lt;/sub&gt; elicited significant tumor retardation and tumor-specific immune responses in HCC mice with large tumor burdens. Importantly, tumor eradication was achieved in orthotopic HCC mice when antigenic AFP peptide was replaced with the full-length AFP (A) to form DEX&lt;sub&gt;P&amp;amp;A&amp;amp;N&lt;/sub&gt;. Supplementation of Fms-related tyrosine kinase 3 ligand greatly augmented the antitumor immunity of DEX&lt;sub&gt;P&amp;amp;A&amp;amp;N&lt;/sub&gt; by increasing immunological memory against tumor re-challenge in orthotopic HCC mice. Depletion of T cells, cross-presenting DCs and other innate immune cells abrogated the functionality of DEX&lt;sub&gt;P&amp;amp;A&amp;amp;N&lt;/sub&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; These findings demonstrate the capacity of universal DEX vaccines to induce tumor-specific immune responses by triggering an immune response tailored to the tumors of each individual, thus presenting a generalizable approach for personalized immunotherapy of HCC, by extension of other tumors, without the need to identify tumor antigens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Renal Function Outcomes in Metastatic Non-Small-Cell Lung Carcinoma Patients Treated with Chemotherapy or Immune Checkpoint Inhibitors: An Unexpected Scenario</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35632435/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35632435/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Immune checkpoint inhibitors (ICIs) and platinum-based chemotherapy (CT) are effective therapeutic agents for the palliative treatment of metastatic non-small-cell lung cancer (NSCLC); the aim of our study was to investigate the acute and chronic renal toxicities in this setting. We collected data on 292 patients who received cisplatin (35%), carboplatin-based regimens (25%), or ICI monotherapy (40%). The primary and secondary outcomes were compared to the acute kidney injury (AKI) rate and the mean estimated GFR (eGFR) decay between groups, respectively, over a mean follow-up duration of 15 weeks. We observed 26 AKI events (8.9%), mostly stage I AKI (80.7%); 15% were stage II AKI, 3.8% were stage III, and none required renal replacement therapy or ICU admission. The AKI rates were 10.9%, 6.8%, and 8.9% for the cisplatin, carboplatin, and ICI groups, respectively, and no significant differences were observed between the groups (&lt;em&gt;p&lt;/em&gt; = 0.3). A global mean eGFR decay of 2.2 mL/min was observed, while for the cisplatin, carboplatin, and ICI groups, the eGFR decay values were 2.3 mL/min, 1.1 mL/min, and 3.5 mL/min, respectively. No significant differences were observed between the groups. Cisplatin/carboplatin-based CT and ICIs resulted in a similar incidence of AKI and eGFR decay, suggesting the safety of their cautious use, even in CKD patients.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PD-1 and ICOS coexpression identifies tumor-reactive CD4&#43; T cells in human solid tumors</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35439168/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35439168/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CD4+ Th cells play a key role in orchestrating immune responses, but the identity of the CD4+ Th cells involved in the antitumor immune response remains to be defined. We analyzed the immune cell infiltrates of head and neck squamous cell carcinoma and colorectal cancers and identified a subset of CD4+ Th cells distinct from FOXP3+ Tregs that coexpressed programmed cell death 1 (PD-1) and ICOS. These tumor-infiltrating lymphocyte CD4+ Th cells (CD4+ Th TILs) had a tissue-resident memory phenotype, were present in MHC class II-rich areas, and proliferated in the tumor, suggesting local antigen recognition. The T cell receptor repertoire of the PD-1+ICOS+ CD4+ Th TILs was oligoclonal, with T cell clones expanded in the tumor, but present at low frequencies in the periphery. Finally, these PD-1+ICOS+ CD4+ Th TILs were shown to recognize both tumor-associated antigens and tumor-specific neoantigens. Our findings provide an approach for isolating tumor-reactive CD4+ Th TILs directly ex vivo that will help define their role in the antitumor immune response and potentially improve future adoptive T cell therapy approaches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Potent Anti-SARS-CoV-2 Efficacy of COVID-19 Hyperimmune Globulin from Vaccine-Immunized Plasma</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35403837/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35403837/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) remains a global public health threat. Hence, more effective and specific antivirals are urgently needed. Here, COVID-19 hyperimmune globulin (COVID-HIG), a passive immunotherapy, is prepared from the plasma of healthy donors vaccinated with BBIBP-CorV (Sinopharm COVID-19 vaccine). COVID-HIG shows high-affinity binding to severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 (SARS-CoV-2) spike (S) protein, the receptor-binding domain (RBD), the N-terminal domain of the S protein, and the nucleocapsid protein; and blocks RBD binding to human angiotensin-converting enzyme 2 (hACE2). Pseudotyped and authentic virus-based assays show that COVID-HIG displays broad-spectrum neutralization effects on a wide variety of SARS-CoV-2 variants, including D614G, Alpha (B.1.1.7), Beta (B.1.351), Gamma (P.1), Kappa (B.1.617.1), Delta (B.1.617.2), and Omicron (B.1.1.529) in vitro. However, a significant reduction in the neutralization titer is detected against Beta, Delta, and Omicron variants. Additionally, assessments of the prophylactic and treatment efficacy of COVID-HIG in an Adv5-hACE2-transduced IFNAR-/- mouse model of SARS-CoV-2 infection show significantly reduced weight loss, lung viral loads, and lung pathological injury. Moreover, COVID-HIG exhibits neutralization potency similar to that of anti-SARS-CoV-2 hyperimmune globulin from pooled convalescent plasma. Overall, the results demonstrate the potential of COVID-HIG against SARS-CoV-2 infection and provide reference for subsequent clinical trials.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Role of exosomal non-coding RNAs from tumor cells and tumor-associated macrophages in the tumor microenvironment</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/35405312/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/35405312/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Exosomes have a crucial role in intercellular communication and mediate interactions between tumor cells and tumor-associated macrophages (TAMs). Exosome-encapsulated non-coding RNAs (ncRNAs) are involved in various physiological processes. Tumor-derived exosomal ncRNAs induce M2 macrophage polarization through signaling pathway activation, signal transduction, and transcriptional and post-transcriptional regulation. Conversely, TAM-derived exosomal ncRNAs promote tumor proliferation, metastasis, angiogenesis, chemoresistance, and immunosuppression. MicroRNAs induce gene silencing by directly targeting mRNAs, whereas lncRNAs and circRNAs act as miRNA sponges to indirectly regulate protein expressions. The role of ncRNAs in tumor-host interactions is ubiquitous. Current research is increasingly focused on the tumor microenvironment. On the basis of the &amp;ldquo;cancer-immunity cycle&amp;rdquo; hypothesis, we discuss the effects of exosomal ncRNAs on immune cells to induce T cell exhaustion, overexpression of programmed cell death ligands, and create a tumor immunosuppressive microenvironment. Furthermore, we discuss potential applications and prospects of exosomal ncRNAs as clinical biomarkers and drug delivery systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mannan-decorated pathogen-like polymeric nanoparticles as nanovaccine carriers for eliciting superior anticancer immunity</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35364489/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35364489/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using nanotechnology for cancer vaccine design holds great promise because of the intrinsic feature of nanoparticles in being captured by antigen-presenting cells (APCs). However, there are still obstacles in current nanovaccine systems in achieving efficient tumor therapeutic effects, which could partially be attributed to the unsatisfactory vaccine carrier design. Herein, we report a mannan-decorated pathogen-like polymeric nanoparticle as a protein vaccine carrier for eliciting robust anticancer immunity. This nanovaccine was constructed as a core-shell structure with mannan as the shell, polylactic acid-polyethylenimine (PLA-PEI) assembled nanoparticle as the core, and protein antigens and Toll-like receptor 9 (TLR9) agonist CpG absorbed onto the PLA-PEI core via electrostatic interactions. Compared to other hydrophilic materials, mannan decoration could greatly enhance the lymph node draining ability of the nanovaccine and promote the capturing by the CD8&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; dendritic cells (DCs) in the lymph node, while PLA-PEI as the inner core could enhance antigen endosome escape thus promoting the antigen cross-presentation. In addition, mannan itself as a TLR4 agonist could synergize with CpG for maximally activating the DCs. Excitingly, we observed in several murine tumor models that using this nanovaccine alone could elicit robust immune response in vivo and result in superior anti-tumor effects with 50% of mice completely cured. This study strongly evidenced that mannan decoration and a rationally designed nanovaccine system could be quite robust in tumor vaccine therapy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SENP7 senses oxidative stress to sustain metabolic fitness and antitumor functions of CD8&#43; T cells</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35143421/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35143421/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The functional integrity of CD8&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T cells is tightly coupled to metabolic reprogramming, but how oxidative stress directs CD8&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T cell metabolic fitness in the tumor microenvironment (TME) remains elusive. Here, we report that SUMO-specific protease 7 (SENP7) senses oxidative stress to maintain the CD8&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T cell metabolic state and antitumor functions. SENP7-deficient CD8&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T cells exhibited decreased glycolysis and oxidative phosphorylation, resulting in attenuated proliferation in vitro and dampened antitumor functions in vivo. Mechanistically, CD8&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T cell-derived ROS triggered cytosolic SENP7-mediated PTEN deSUMOylation, thereby promoting PTEN degradation and preventing PTEN-dependent metabolic defects. Importantly, lowering T cell-intrinsic ROS restricted SENP7 cytosolic translocation and repressed CD8&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T cell metabolic and functional activity in human colorectal cancer samples. Our findings reveal that SENP7, as an oxidative stress sensor, sustains CD8&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T cell metabolic fitness and effector functions and unveil an oxidative stress-sensing machinery in tumor-infiltrating CD8&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T cells.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Localized Degradation of Neutrophil Extracellular Traps by Photoregulated Enzyme Delivery for Cancer Immunotherapy and Metastasis Suppression</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35080858/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35080858/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Extrusion of neutrophil extracellular traps (NETs), a fundamental host innate immune defense against pathogens, has recently been linked to cancer resistance to immunotherapy and distant metastasis. These findings highlight interesting areas of cancer-elicited inflammation and potential therapeutic strategies. Disrupting existing NETs with DNase I has been proved to enhance the therapeutic efficacy of tumor immunotherapy and attenuate metastatic spread. However, systemic biodistribution of DNase I raises safety issues, potentially impairing host defense against infection. Hence, tumor-specific delivery and metastatic niche-targeted effects are attractive options for localized degradation of NETs. We have engineered a nanoplatform with a plasmonic gold blackbody (AuPB) core with broad-spectrum photo activity and a mesoporous polydopamine (mPDA) shell for efficient loading and photoregulated release of DNase I. The on-demand released DNase I triggered by the second near-infrared (NIR-II) light irradiation breaks the &amp;ldquo;NET-mediated physical barrier&amp;rdquo;, thereby increasing the contact of immune cytotoxic cells with tumor cells in living mice and sensitizing immune checkpoint therapy of primary colorectal cancer (CRC). Moreover, the deposition and light-controlled cargo release from systemically delivered AuPB@mPDA carriers in liver, the most frequent site of CRC metastasis, abolished NET-mediated capture of circulating tumor cells and hence metastatic seeding. Our findings indicate that the localized, light-regulated release of DNase I by photoactive carriers in the NIR-II window represent a translational route for immune-mediated tumor regression and metastasis inhibition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An RNA-RNA crosstalk network involving HMGB1 and RICTOR facilitates hepatocellular carcinoma tumorigenesis by promoting glutamine metabolism and impedes immunotherapy by PD-L1&#43; exosomes activity</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34916485/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34916485/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hepatocellular carcinoma (HCC) is the global leading cause of cancer-related deaths due to the deficiency of targets for precision therapy. A new modality of epigenetic regulation has emerged involving RNA-RNA crosstalk networks where two or more competing endogenous RNAs (ceRNAs) bind to the same microRNAs. However, the contribution of such mechanisms in HCC has not been well studied. Herein, potential HMGB1-driven RNA-RNA crosstalk networks were evaluated at different HCC stages, identifying the mTORC2 component RICTOR as a potential HMGB1 ceRNA in HBV&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; early stage HCC. Indeed, elevated HMGB1 mRNA was found to promote the expression of RICTOR mRNA through competitively binding with the miR-200 family, especially miR-429. Functional assays employing overexpression or interference strategies demonstrated that the HMGB1 and RICTOR 3&amp;rsquo;untranslated regions (UTR) epigenetically promoted the malignant proliferation, self-renewal, and tumorigenesis in HCC cells. Intriguingly, interference against HMGB1 and RICTOR in HCC cells promoted a stronger anti-PD-L1 immunotherapy response, which appeared to associate with the production of PD-L1&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; exosomes. Mechanistically, the HMGB1-driven RNA-RNA crosstalk network facilitated HCC cell glutamine metabolism via dual mechanisms, activating a positive feedback loop involving mTORC2-AKT-C-MYC to upregulate glutamine synthetase (GS) expression, and inducing mTORC1 signaling to derepress SIRT4 on glutamate dehydrogenase (GDH). Meanwhile, this crosstalk network could impede the efficacy of immunotherapy through mTORC1-P70S6K dependent PD-L1 production and PD-L1&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; exosomes activity. In conclusion, our study highlights the non-coding regulatory role of HMGB1 with implications for RNA-based therapeutic targeting together with a prediction of anti-PD-L1 immunotherapy in HCC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advancing to the era of cancer immunotherapy</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/34165252/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/34165252/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cancer greatly affects the quality of life of humans worldwide and the number of patients suffering from it is continuously increasing. Over the last century, numerous treatments have been developed to improve the survival of cancer patients but substantial progress still needs to be made before cancer can be truly cured. In recent years, antitumor immunity has become the most debated topic in cancer research and the booming development of immunotherapy has led to a new epoch in cancer therapy. In this review, we describe the relationships between tumors and the immune system, and the rise of immunotherapy. Then, we summarize the characteristics of tumor-associated immunity and immunotherapeutic strategies with various molecular mechanisms by showing the typical immune molecules whose antibodies are broadly used in the clinic and those that are still under investigation. We also discuss important elements from individual cells to the whole human body, including cellular mutations and modulation, metabolic reprogramming, the microbiome, and the immune contexture. In addition, we also present new observations and technical advancements of both diagnostic and therapeutic methods aimed at cancer immunotherapy. Lastly, we discuss the controversies and challenges that negatively impact patient outcomes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gene-engineered exosomes-thermosensitive liposomes hybrid nanovesicles by the blockade of CD47 signal for combined photothermal therapy and cancer immunotherapy</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34147721/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34147721/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CD47, overexpressed on kinds of tumor cells, activates a &amp;ldquo;don&amp;rsquo;t eat me&amp;rdquo; signal through binding to signal regulatory protein α (SIRPα), leading to immune escape from the mononuclear phagocyte system (MPS). It is also a huge challenge to deliver therapeutic drugs to the tumor sites due to the short retention time in blood, poor targeting of tumor cells and accelerated clearance by MPS. Herein, we designed a hybrid therapeutic nanovesicles, named as hGLV, by fusing gene-engineered exosomes with drug-loaded thermosensitive liposomes. We demonstrated that the CD47-overexpressed hGLV exhibited the long blood circulation and improved the macrophages-mediated the phagocytosis of tumor cells by blocking CD47 signal. Moreover, the resulted hGLV could remarkably target the homologous tumor in mice, achieving the preferential accumulation at the tumor sites. Importantly, hGLV loading the photothermal agent could achieve the excellent photothermal therapy (PTT) under laser irradiation after the intravenous injection, completely eliminating the tumors, leading to immunogenic cell death and generating substantial tumor-associated antigens, which could promote the maturation of immature dendritic cells with the help of the co-encapsulated immune adjuvant to trigger strong immune responses. Generally, the hybrid nanovesicles based on CD47 immune check point blockade can be a promising platform for the drug delivery in cancer treatment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cancer and the Microbiome-Influence of the Commensal Microbiota on Cancer, Immune Responses, and Immunotherapy</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33253684/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33253684/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The commensal microbiota has been implicated in the regulation of a diverse array of physiological processes, both within the gastrointestinal tract and at distant tissue sites. Cancer is no exception, and distinct aspects of the microbiota have been reported to have either pro- or anti-tumor effects. The functional role of the microbiota in regulating not only mucosal but also systemic immune responses has led to investigations into the impact on cancer immunotherapies, particularly with agents targeting the immunologic checkpoints PD-1 and CTLA-4. Microbial sequencing and reconstitution of germ-free mice have indicated both positive and negative regulatory bacteria likely exist, which either promote or interfere with immunotherapy efficacy. These collective findings have led to the development of clinical trials pursuing microbiome-based therapeutic interventions, with the hope of expanding immunotherapy efficacy. This review summarizes recent knowledge about the relationship between the host microbiota and cancer and anti-tumor immune response, with implications for cancer therapy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>c-Rel Is a Myeloid Checkpoint for Cancer Immunotherapy</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33458695/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33458695/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therapy that targets lymphoid cell checkpoints holds great promise for curing cancer. However, a majority of cancer patients do not respond to this form of therapy. In addition to lymphoid cells, myeloid cells play essential roles in controlling immunity to cancer. Whether myeloid checkpoints exist that can be targeted to treat cancer is not well established. Here we show that c-Rel, a member of the nuclear factor (NF)-B family, specified the generation of myeloid-derived suppressor cells (MDSCs) by selectively turning on pro-tumoral genes while switching off anti-tumoral genes through a c-Rel enhanceosome. c-Rel deficiency in myeloid cells markedly inhibited cancer growth in mice, and pharmaceutical inhibition of c-Rel had the same effect. Combination therapy that blocked both c-Rel and the lymphoid checkpoint protein PD1 was more effective in treating cancer than blocking either alone. Thus, c-Rel is a myeloid checkpoint that can be targeted for treating cancer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>High systemic and tumor-associated IL-8 correlates with reduced clinical benefit of PD-L1 blockade</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32405063/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32405063/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Erratum in:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; can also be found.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Author Correction: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nature.com/articles/s41591-021-01246-4&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;High systemic and tumor-associated IL-8 correlates with reduced clinical benefit of PD-L1 blockade&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although elevated plasma interleukin-8 (pIL-8) has been associated with poor outcome to immune checkpoint blockade 1, this has not been comprehensively evaluated in large randomized studies. Here we analyzed circulating pIL-8 and IL8 gene expression in peripheral blood mononuclear cells and tumors of patients treated with atezolizumab (anti-PD-L1 monoclonal antibody) from multiple randomized trials representing 1,445 patients with metastatic urothelial carcinoma (mUC) and metastatic renal cell carcinoma. High levels of IL-8 in plasma, peripheral blood mononuclear cells and tumors were associated with decreased efficacy of atezolizumab in patients with mUC and metastatic renal cell carcinoma, even in tumors that were classically CD8+ T cell inflamed. Low baseline pIL-8 in patients with mUC was associated with increased response to atezolizumab and chemotherapy. Patients with mUC who experienced on-treatment decreases in pIL-8 exhibited improved overall survival when treated with atezolizumab but not with chemotherapy. Single-cell RNA sequencing of the immune compartment showed that IL8 is primarily expressed in circulating and intratumoral myeloid cells and that high IL8 expression is associated with downregulation of the antigen-presentation machinery. Therapies that can reverse the impacts of IL-8-mediated myeloid inflammation will be essential for improving outcomes of patients treated with immune checkpoint inhibitors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Targeting STAT3 in Cancer Immunotherapy</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/32972405/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/32972405/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a point of convergence for numerous oncogenic signaling pathways, signal transducer and activator of transcription 3 (STAT3) is central in regulating the anti-tumor immune response. STAT3 is broadly hyperactivated both in cancer and non-cancerous cells within the tumor ecosystem and plays important roles in inhibiting the expression of crucial immune activation regulators and promoting the production of immunosuppressive factors. Therefore, targeting the STAT3 signaling pathway has emerged as a promising therapeutic strategy for numerous cancers. In this review, we outline the importance of STAT3 signaling pathway in tumorigenesis and its immune regulation, and highlight the current status for the development of STAT3-targeting therapeutic approaches. We also summarize and discuss recent advances in STAT3-based combination immunotherapy in detail. These endeavors provide new insights into the translational application of STAT3 in cancer and may contribute to the promotion of more effective treatments toward malignancies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
