<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Immunotherapy | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/immunotherapy/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/immunotherapy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Immunotherapy</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Immunotherapy</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/immunotherapy/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Macrophage Membrane-Coated Nano-Gemcitabine Promotes Lymphocyte Infiltration and Synergizes AntiPD-L1 to Restore the Tumoricidal Function</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36525314/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36525314/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The limited lymphocyte infiltration and exhaustion of tumoricidal functions in solid tumors remain a formidable obstacle to cancer immunotherapy. Herein, we designed a macrophage membrane-coated nano-gemcitabine system (MNGs) to promote lymphocyte infiltration and then synergized anti-programmed death ligand 1 (antiPD-L1) to reinvigorate the exhausted lymphocytes. MNGs exhibited effective intratumor-permeating and responsive drug-releasing capacity, produced notable elimination of versatile immunosuppressive cells, and promoted lymphocyte infiltration into cancer cell regions in tumors, but over 50% of these infiltrated lymphocytes were in the exhausted state. Compared with MNG monotherapy, the MNGs+antiPD-L1 combination produced 31.77% and 30.63% reduction of exhausted CD3&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt;CD8&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T cells and natural killer (NK) cells and 2.83- and 3.17-fold increases of interferon-γ (IFN-γ)-positive subtypes, respectively, thereby resulting in considerable therapeutic benefits in several tumor models. Thus, MNGs provide an encouraging strategy to promote lymphocyte infiltration and synergize antiPD-L1 to restore their tumoricidal function for cancer immunotherapy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dendritic cell derived exosomes loaded neoantigens for personalized cancer immunotherapies</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36470333/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36470333/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therapeutics that discriminate between the genetic makeup of normal cells and tumour cells are valuable for treating and understanding cancer. Small molecules with oncogene-selective lethality may reveal novel functions of oncoproteins and enable the creation of more selective drugs. Here we describe the mechanism of action of the selective anti-tumour agent erastin, involving the RAS-RAF-MEK signalling pathway functioning in cell proliferation, differentiation and survival. Erastin exhibits greater lethality in human tumour cells harbouring mutations in the oncogenes HRAS, KRAS or BRAF. Using affinity purification and mass spectrometry, we discovered that erastin acts through mitochondrial voltage-dependent anion channels (VDACs)&amp;ndash;a novel target for anti-cancer drugs. We show that erastin treatment of cells harbouring oncogenic RAS causes the appearance of oxidative species and subsequent death through an oxidative, non-apoptotic mechanism. RNA-interference-mediated knockdown of VDAC2 or VDAC3 caused resistance to erastin, implicating these two VDAC isoforms in the mechanism of action of erastin. Moreover, using purified mitochondria expressing a single VDAC isoform, we found that erastin alters the permeability of the outer mitochondrial membrane. Finally, using a radiolabelled analogue and a filter-binding assay, we show that erastin binds directly to VDAC2. These results demonstrate that ligands to VDAC proteins can induce non-apoptotic cell death selectively in some tumour cells harbouring activating mutations in the RAS-RAF-MEK pathway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reprogramming of T cell-derived small extracellular vesicles using IL2 surface engineering induces potent anti-cancer effects through miRNA delivery</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36447429/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36447429/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;T cell-derived small extracellular vesicles (sEVs) exhibit anti-cancer effects. However, their anti-cancer potential should be reinforced to enhance clinical applicability. Herein, we generated interleukin-2-tethered sEVs (IL2-sEVs) from engineered Jurkat T cells expressing IL2 at the plasma membrane via a flexible linker to induce an autocrine effect. IL2-sEVs increased the anti-cancer ability of CD8&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T cells without affecting regulatory T (T&lt;sub&gt;reg&lt;/sub&gt; ) cells and down-regulated cellular and exosomal PD-L1 expression in melanoma cells, causing their increased sensitivity to CD8+ T cell-mediated cytotoxicity. Its effect on CD8&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T and melanoma cells was mediated by several IL2-sEV-resident microRNAs (miRNAs), whose expressions were upregulated by the autocrine effects of IL2. Among the miRNAs, miR-181a-3p and miR-223-3p notably reduced the PD-L1 protein levels in melanoma cells. Interestingly, miR-181a-3p increased the activity of CD8&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T cells while suppressing Treg cell activity. IL2-sEVs inhibited tumour progression in melanoma-bearing immunocompetent mice, but not in immunodeficient mice. The combination of IL2-sEVs and existing anti-cancer drugs significantly improved anti-cancer efficacy by decreasing PD-L1 expression in vivo. Thus, IL2-sEVs are potential cancer immunotherapeutic agents that regulate both immune and cancer cells by reprogramming miRNA levels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IL-6/STAT3 signaling in tumor cells restricts the expression of frameshift-derived neoantigens by SMG1 induction</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36443756/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36443756/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; The quality and quantity of tumor neoantigens derived from tumor mutations determines the fate of the immune response in cancer. Frameshift mutations elicit better tumor neoantigens, especially when they are not targeted by nonsense-mediated mRNA decay (NMD). For tumor progression, malignant cells need to counteract the immune response including the silencing of immunodominant neoantigens (antigen immunoediting) and promoting an immunosuppressive tumor microenvironment. Although NMD inhibition has been reported to induce tumor immunity and increase the expression of cryptic neoantigens, the possibility that NMD activity could be modulated by immune forces operating in the tumor microenvironment as a new immunoediting mechanism has not been addressed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; We study the effect of SMG1 expression (main kinase that initiates NMD) in the survival and the nature of the tumor immune infiltration using TCGA RNAseq and scRNAseq datasets of breast, lung and pancreatic cancer. Different murine tumor models were used to corroborate the antitumor immune dependencies of NMD. We evaluate whether changes of SMG1 expression in malignant cells impact the immune response elicited by cancer immunotherapy. To determine how NMD fluctuates in malignant cells we generated a luciferase reporter system to track NMD activity in vivo under different immune conditions. Cytokine screening, in silico studies and functional assays were conducted to determine the regulation of SMG1 via IL-6/STAT3 signaling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; IL-6/STAT3 signaling induces SMG1, which limits the expression of potent frameshift neoantigens that are under NMD control compromising the outcome of the immune response.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/em&gt; We revealed a new neoantigen immunoediting mechanism regulated by immune forces (IL-6/STAT3 signaling) responsible for silencing otherwise potent frameshift mutation-derived neoantigens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The emerging field of oncolytic virus-based cancer immunotherapy</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/36402738/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/36402738/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Natural or genetically modified oncolytic viruses (OVs) are promising antitumor agents for specifically targeting tumor cells without harming normal cells.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;OV-based oncolysis and OV-induced antiviral immune responses play an important role in remodeling the tumor microenvironment (TME) from immunologically &amp;lsquo;cold&amp;rsquo; to &amp;lsquo;hot&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As single agents or combined with other strategies, OVs can enhance cancer immunotherapy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;OV persistence, replication, spread, systemic delivery, lack of therapeutic biomarkers, and moderate efficacy as single agents are among the main challenges in the field. If these problems can be solved, OV will most likely substantially enhance clinical outcomes for cancer patients.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oncolytic viruses (OVs) provide novel and promising therapeutic options for patients with cancers resistant to traditional therapies. Natural or genetically modified OVs are multifaceted tumor killers. They directly lyse tumor cells while sparing normal cells, and indirectly potentiate antitumor immunity by releasing antigens and activating inflammatory responses in the tumor microenvironment. However, some limitations, such as limited penetration of OVs into tumors, short persistence, and the host antiviral immune response, are impeding the broad translation of oncolytic virotherapy into the clinic. If these challenges can be overcome, combination therapies, such as OVs plus immune checkpoint blockade (ICB), chimeric antigen receptor (CAR) T cells, or CAR natural killer (NK) cells, may provide powerful therapeutic platforms in the clinic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Immunological conversion of solid tumours using a bispecific nanobioconjugate for cancer immunotherapy</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36357792/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36357792/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Solid tumours display a limited response to immunotherapies. By contrast, haematological malignancies exhibit significantly higher response rates to immunotherapies as compared with solid tumours. Among several microenvironmental and biological disparities, the differential expression of unique immune regulatory molecules contributes significantly to the interaction of blood cancer cells with immune cells. The self-ligand receptor of the signalling lymphocytic activation molecule family member 7 (SLAMF7), a molecule that is critical in promoting the body&amp;rsquo;s innate immune cells to detect and engulf cancer cells, is expressed nearly exclusively on the cell surface of haematologic tumours, but not on solid ones. Here we show that a bispecific nanobioconjugate that enables the decoration of SLAMF7 on the surface of solid tumours induces robust phagocytosis and activates the phagocyte cyclic guanosine monophosphate-adenosine monophosphate synthase-stimulator of interferon genes (cGAS-STING) pathway, sensitizing the tumours to immune checkpoint blockade. Our findings support an immunological conversion strategy that uses nano-adjuvants to improve the effectiveness of immunotherapies for solid tumours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Targeting tumour-intrinsic N7-methylguanosine tRNA modification inhibits MDSC recruitment and improves anti-PD-1 efficacy</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36283801/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36283801/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;u&gt;Objective&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/em&gt; Intrahepatic cholangiocarcinoma (ICC) exhibits very low response rate to immune checkpoint inhibitors (ICIs) and the underlying mechanism is largely unknown. We investigate the tumour immune microenvironment (TIME) of ICCs and the underlying regulatory mechanisms with the aim of developing new target to inhibit tumour growth and improve anti-programmed cell death protein-1 (PD-1) efficacy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;u&gt;Design&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/em&gt; Tumour tissues from patients with ICC together with hydrodynamic ICC mouse models were employed to identify the key cell population in TIME of ICCs. Functional analysis and mechanism studies were performed using cell culture, conditional knockout mouse model and hydrodynamic transfection ICC model. The efficacy of single or combined therapy with anti-PD-1 antibody, gene knockout and chemical inhibitor were evaluated in vivo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;u&gt;Results&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/em&gt; Polymorphonuclear myeloid-derived suppressor cells (PMN-MDSCs) are enriched in advanced ICCs and significantly correlated with N&lt;sup&gt;7&lt;/sup&gt;-methylguanosine tRNA methyltransferase METTL1. Using diverse in vivo cancer models, we demonstrate the crucial immunomodulator function of METTL1 in regulation of PMN-MDSC accumulation in TIME and ICC progression. Mechanistically, &lt;em&gt;CXCL8&lt;/em&gt; in human and &lt;em&gt;Cxcl5&lt;/em&gt; in mouse are key translational targets of METTL1 that facilitate its function in promoting PMN-MDSC accumulation in TIME and ICC progression in vivo. Co-blockade of METTL1 and its downstream chemokine pathway enhances the anti-PD-1 efficacy in ICC preclinical mouse models.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;u&gt;Conclusions&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/em&gt; Our data uncover novel mechanisms underlying chemokine regulation and TIME shaping at the layer of messenger RNA translation level and provide new insights for development of efficient cancer immunotherapeutic strategies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hierarchical Microparticles Delivering Oxaliplatin and NLG919 Nanoprodrugs for Local Chemo-immunotherapy</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36263713/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36263713/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chemo-immunotherapy shows promising antitumor therapeutic outcomes for many primary cancers. Research in this area has been focusing on developing an ideal formula that enables the potent efficacy of chemo-immunotherapy in combating various cancers with reduced systemic toxicity. Herein, we present novel hierarchical hydrogel microparticles (MDDP) delivering oxaliplatin and NLG919 nanoprodrugs for local chemo-immunotherapy with desired features. The oxaliplatin prodrug and NLG919 were efficiently loaded in the dual-drug polymeric nanoparticles (DDP NPs), which were further encapsulated into a MDDP by using microfluidic technology. When delivered to the tumor site, the DDP NPs will be sustainedly released from the MDDP and retained locally to reduce systemic toxicity. After being endocytosed by cancer cells, the cytotoxic oxaliplatin and NLG919 could be successfully triggered to release from DDP NPs in a chain-shattering manner, leading to the immunogenic cell death (ICD) of tumor cells and the suppression of intratumoral immunosuppressive Tregs, respectively. With the assistance of an immune modulator, the chemotherapeutics-induced ICD could trigger robust systemic antitumor immune responses, presenting superior synergistic antitumor efficacies. Thus, the hierarchical microparticles could substantially inhibit the growth of mouse subcutaneous colorectal tumors, breast tumors, and colorectal tumors with large initial sizes via synergized chemo-immunotherapy, showing great potential in the practical clinical application of oncotherapy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bidirectional anisotropic palladium nanozymes reprogram macrophages to enhance collaborative chemodynamic therapy of colorectal cancer</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35981687/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35981687/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although genomewide RNA expression analysis has become a routine tool in biomedical research, extracting biological insight from such information remains a major challenge. Here, we describe a powerful analytical method called Gene Set Enrichment Analysis (GSEA) for interpreting gene expression data. The method derives its power by focusing on gene sets, that is, groups of genes that share common biological function, chromosomal location, or regulation. We demonstrate how GSEA yields insights into several cancer-related data sets, including leukemia and lung cancer. Notably, where single-gene analysis finds little similarity between two independent studies of patient survival in lung cancer, GSEA reveals many biological pathways in common. The GSEA method is embodied in a freely available software package, together with an initial database of 1,325 biologically defined gene sets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PARP inhibitor plus radiotherapy reshapes an inflamed tumor microenvironment that sensitizes small cell lung cancer to the anti-PD-1 immunotherapy</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35926817/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35926817/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PARPI plus radiation further activated cGAS/STING pathway than single treatment.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PARPI plus radiation upregulated the expression of PD-L1.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PARPI plus radiation sensitizes small cell lung cancer to anti-PD-1 immunotherapy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Small cell lung cancer (SCLC) is a highly malignant tumor with extremely poor prognosis. The treatment strategy is very limited, and patient outcomes remain dismal with the 5-year survival rate being mere 3-6%. Thus, novel therapeutic strategies for SCLC patients are urgently needed. In this study, we found that the triple-therapy of poly (ADP-ribose) polymerase (PARP) inhibitor, radiotherapy (RT) and anti-PD-1 treatment significantly inhibited tumor growth and prolonged survival in the syngeneic SCLC models in immunocompetent C57BL/6 mice. Mechanistically, we demonstrated that the combination of PARP inhibitor niraparib and RT reshaped an inflamed tumor microenvironment, including activation of the cGAS/STING immune response pathway, induction of immunogenic cell death, and upregulation of PD-L1 on tumor cells. Furthermore, this triple-therapy substantially augmented CD8+ T cell infiltration and activation, and enhanced anti-tumor effects as revealed by increased median survival time and reduced tumor volume without additional myelosuppression or hepatic injury. Together, our studies demonstrated that PARP inhibitor combined with RT potentiated anti-tumor immunity and enhanced the efficacy of anti-PD-1 immunotherapy in preclinical study, which provided a promising therapeutic strategy for SCLC patients in clinic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Designing antibodies as therapeutics</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/35868279/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/35868279/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Antibody therapeutics are a large and rapidly expanding drug class providing major health benefits. We provide a snapshot of current antibody therapeutics including their formats, common targets, therapeutic areas, and routes of administration. Our focus is on selected emerging directions in antibody design where progress may provide a broad benefit. These topics include enhancing antibodies for cancer, antibody delivery to organs such as the brain, gastrointestinal tract, and lungs, plus antibody developability challenges including immunogenicity risk assessment and mitigation and subcutaneous delivery. Machine learning has the potential, albeit as yet largely unrealized, for a transformative future impact on antibody discovery and engineering.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docetaxel resistance-derived LINC01085 contributes to the immunotherapy of hormone-independent prostate cancer by activating the STING/MAVS signaling pathway</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35868534/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35868534/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;LINC01085&lt;/em&gt; is deleted in hormone-independent prostate cancer (HIPC) which can predict better outcomes of HIPC patients.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;LINC01085 acts as a tumor suppressor in the tumourigenicity and metastasis of HIPC.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;LINC01085 exerts its functions by both interacting with TBK1 and GSK3β, accelerated TBK1 phosphorylation at the Ser-172 site, in HIPC.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;LINC01085 combined with PARP inhibitor and anti-PD-L1 treatment may be pivotal in the treatment of HIPC patients.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acquired docetaxel (doc) resistance, one of the major reasons for unfavorable prognosis in patients with aggressive hormone-independent prostate cancer (HIPC), is a major obstacle for patient treatment. Dysregulation of long non-coding RNAs promotes or suppresses chemoresistance in multiple cancers; however, the specific molecular mechanisms underlying HIPC remain unknown. In this study, we found that the LINC01085, as a tumor-suppressor, which showed significant clinically relevant in HIPC patients with doc-resistance. Mechanistically, in docetaxel-sensitive cells, LINC01085 could specifically bind to both TANK-binding kinase 1 (TBK1) and glycogen synthase kinase 3β (GSK3β), and higher LINC01085 RNA levels could inhibit TBK1 dimerization. Whereas, in doc-resistant cells, lower LINC01085 RNA level lost the strong binding with both, meanwhile, the interaction between TBK1 and GSK3β enhanced which accelerated TBK1 phosphorylation at the Ser-172 site, resulting in decreased expression levels of PD-L1 and NF-κB as well as the secretion of type I/III interferons. Thus, Overexpression of LINC01085 combined with immune checkpoint blockade is an effective strategy for the treatment of HIPC patients.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HuR as a molecular target for cancer therapeutics and immune-related disorders</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/35817212/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/35817212/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The control of eukaryotic gene expression occurs at multiple levels, from transcription to messenger RNA processing, transport, localization, turnover, and translation. RNA-binding proteins control gene expression and are involved in different stages of mRNA processing, including splicing, maturation, turnover, and translation. A ubiquitously expressed RBP Human antigen R is engaged in the RNA processes mentioned above but, most importantly, controls mRNA stability and turnover. Dysregulation of HuR is linked to many diseases, including cancer and other immune-related disorders. HuR targets mRNAs containing AU-rich elements at their 3&amp;rsquo;untranslated region, which encodes proteins involved in cell growth, proliferation, tumor formation, angiogenesis, immune evasion, inflammation, invasion, and metastasis. HuR overexpression has been reported in many tumor types, which led to a poor prognosis for patients. Hence, HuR is considered an appealing drug target for cancer treatment. Therefore, multiple attempts have been made to identify small molecule inhibitors for blocking HuR functions. This article reviews the current prospects of drugs that target HuR in numerous cancer types, their mode of action, and off-target effects. Furthermore, we will summarize drugs that interfered with HuR-RNA interactions and established themselves as novel therapeutics. We will also highlight the significance of HuR overexpression in multiple cancers and discuss its role in immune functions. This review provides evidence of a new era of HuR-targeted small molecules that can be used for cancer therapeutics either as a monotherapy or in combination with other cancer treatment modalities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Glycoengineered anti-CD39 promotes anticancer responses by depleting suppressive cells and inhibiting angiogenesis in tumor models</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35775486/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35775486/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Immunosuppressive cells accumulating in the tumor microenvironment constitute a formidable barrier that interferes with current immunotherapeutic approaches. A unifying feature of these tumor-associated immune and vascular endothelial cells appears to be the elevated expression of ectonucleotidase CD39, which in tandem with ecto-5&amp;rsquo;-nucleotidase CD73, catalyzes the conversion of extracellular ATP into adenosine. We glycoengineered an afucosylated anti-CD39 IgG2c and tested this reagent in mouse melanoma and colorectal tumor models. We identified major biological effects of this approach on cancer growth, associated with depletion of immunosuppressive cells, mediated through enhanced Fcγ receptor-directed (FcγR-directed), antibody-dependent cellular cytotoxicity (ADCC). Furthermore, regulatory/exhausted T cells lost CD39 expression, as a consequence of antibody-mediated trogocytosis. Most strikingly, tumor-associated macrophages and endothelial cells with high CD39 expression were effectively depleted following antibody treatment, thereby blocking angiogenesis. Tumor site-specific cellular modulation and lack of angiogenesis synergized with chemotherapy and anti-PD-L1 immunotherapy in experimental tumor models. We conclude that depleting suppressive cells and targeting tumor vasculature, through administration of afucosylated anti-CD39 antibody and the activation of ADCC, comprises an improved, purinergic system-modulating strategy for cancer therapy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NY-ESO-1-specific redirected T cells with endogenous TCR knockdown mediate tumor response and cytokine release syndrome</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35768164/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35768164/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Because of the shortage of ideal cell surface antigens, the development of T-cell receptor (TCR)-engineered T cells (TCR-T) that target intracellular antigens such as NY-ESO-1 is a promising approach for treating patients with solid tumors. However, endogenous TCRs in vector-transduced T cells have been suggested to impair cell-surface expression of transduced TCR while generating mispaired TCRs that can become self-reactive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; We conducted a first-in-human phase I clinical trial with the TCR-transduced T-cell product (TBI-1301) in patients with NY-ESO-1-expressing solid tumors. In manufacturing TCR-T cells, we used a novel affinity-enhanced NY-ESO-1-specific TCR that was transduced by a retroviral vector that enables siRNA (small interfering RNA)-mediated silencing of endogenous TCR. The patients were divided into two cohorts. Cohort 1 was given a dose of 5×10&lt;sup&gt;8&lt;/sup&gt; cells (whole cells including TCR-T cells) preconditioned with 1500 mg/m&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; cyclophosphamide. Cohort 2 was given 5× 10&lt;sup&gt;9&lt;/sup&gt; cells preconditioned with 1500 mg/m&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; cyclophosphamide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; In vitro study showed that both the CD8&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; and CD4&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T fractions of TCR-T cells exhibited cytotoxic effects against NY-ESO-1-expressing tumor cells. Three patients and six patients were allocated to cohort 1 and cohort 2, respectively. Three of the six patients who received 5×10&lt;sup&gt;9&lt;/sup&gt; cells showed tumor response, while three patients developed early-onset cytokine release syndrome (CRS). One of the patients developed a grade 3 lung injury associated with the infiltration of the TCR-T cells. No siRNA-related adverse events other than CRS were observed. Cytokines including interleukin 6 I and monocyte chemotactic protein-1/chemokine (C-C motif) ligand (CCL2)increased in the sera of patients with CRS. In vitro analysis showed these cytokines were not secreted from the T cells infused. A significant fraction of the manufactured T cells in patients with CRS was found to express either CD244, CD39, or both at high levels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; The trial showed that endogenous TCR-silenced and affinity-enhanced NY-ESO-1 TCR-T cells were safely administered except for grade 3 lung injury. The TCR-T cell infusion exhibited significant tumor response and early-onset CRS in patients with tumors that express NY-ESO-1 at high levels. The differentiation properties of the manufactured T cells may be prognostic for TCR-T-related CRS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hypoxia-inducible lentiviral gene expression in engineered human macrophages</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35728871/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35728871/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Human immune cells, including monocyte-derived macrophages, can be engineered to deliver proinflammatory cytokines, bispecific antibodies, and chimeric antigen receptors to support immune responses in different disease settings. When gene expression is regulated by constitutively active promoters, lentiviral payload gene expression is unregulated, and can result in potentially toxic quantities of proteins. Regulated delivery of lentivirally encoded proteins may allow localized or conditional therapeutic protein expression to support safe delivery of adoptively transferred, genetically modified cells with reduced capacity for systemic toxicities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; In this study, we engineered human macrophages to express genes regulated by hypoxia responsive elements included in the lentiviral promoter region to drive conditional lentiviral gene expression only under hypoxic conditions. We tested transduced macrophages cultured in hypoxic conditions for the transient induced expression of reporter genes and the secreted cytokine, interleukin-12. Expression of hypoxia-regulated genes was investigated both transcriptionally and translationally, and in the presence of human tumor cells in a slice culture system. Finally, hypoxia-regulated gene expression was evaluated in a subcutaneous humanized-mouse cancer model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; Engineered macrophages were shown to conditionally and tranisently express lentivirally encoded gene protein products, including IL-12 in hypoxic conditions &lt;em&gt;in vitro&lt;/em&gt;. On return to normoxic conditions, lentiviral payload expression returned to basal levels. Reporter genes under the control of hypoxia response elements were upregulated under hypoxic conditions in the presence of human colorectal carcinoma cells and in the hypoxic xenograft model of glioblastoma, suggesting utility for systemic engineered cell delivery capable of localized gene delivery in cancer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; Macrophages engineered to express hypoxia-regulated payloads have the potential to be administered systemically and conditionally express proteins in tissues with hypoxic conditions. In contrast to immune cells that function or survive poorly in hypoxic conditions, macrophages maintain a proinflammatory phenotype that may support continued gene and protein expression when regulated by conditional hypoxia responsive elements and naturally traffic to hypoxic microenvironments, making them ideal vehicles for therapeutic payloads to hypoxic tissues, such as solid tumors. With the ability to fine-tune delivery of potent proteins in response to endogenous microenvironments, macrophage-based cellular therapies may therefore be designed for different disease settings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advancing to the era of cancer immunotherapy</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/34165252/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/34165252/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cancer greatly affects the quality of life of humans worldwide and the number of patients suffering from it is continuously increasing. Over the last century, numerous treatments have been developed to improve the survival of cancer patients but substantial progress still needs to be made before cancer can be truly cured. In recent years, antitumor immunity has become the most debated topic in cancer research and the booming development of immunotherapy has led to a new epoch in cancer therapy. In this review, we describe the relationships between tumors and the immune system, and the rise of immunotherapy. Then, we summarize the characteristics of tumor-associated immunity and immunotherapeutic strategies with various molecular mechanisms by showing the typical immune molecules whose antibodies are broadly used in the clinic and those that are still under investigation. We also discuss important elements from individual cells to the whole human body, including cellular mutations and modulation, metabolic reprogramming, the microbiome, and the immune contexture. In addition, we also present new observations and technical advancements of both diagnostic and therapeutic methods aimed at cancer immunotherapy. Lastly, we discuss the controversies and challenges that negatively impact patient outcomes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gene-engineered exosomes-thermosensitive liposomes hybrid nanovesicles by the blockade of CD47 signal for combined photothermal therapy and cancer immunotherapy</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34147721/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34147721/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CD47, overexpressed on kinds of tumor cells, activates a &amp;ldquo;don&amp;rsquo;t eat me&amp;rdquo; signal through binding to signal regulatory protein α (SIRPα), leading to immune escape from the mononuclear phagocyte system (MPS). It is also a huge challenge to deliver therapeutic drugs to the tumor sites due to the short retention time in blood, poor targeting of tumor cells and accelerated clearance by MPS. Herein, we designed a hybrid therapeutic nanovesicles, named as hGLV, by fusing gene-engineered exosomes with drug-loaded thermosensitive liposomes. We demonstrated that the CD47-overexpressed hGLV exhibited the long blood circulation and improved the macrophages-mediated the phagocytosis of tumor cells by blocking CD47 signal. Moreover, the resulted hGLV could remarkably target the homologous tumor in mice, achieving the preferential accumulation at the tumor sites. Importantly, hGLV loading the photothermal agent could achieve the excellent photothermal therapy (PTT) under laser irradiation after the intravenous injection, completely eliminating the tumors, leading to immunogenic cell death and generating substantial tumor-associated antigens, which could promote the maturation of immature dendritic cells with the help of the co-encapsulated immune adjuvant to trigger strong immune responses. Generally, the hybrid nanovesicles based on CD47 immune check point blockade can be a promising platform for the drug delivery in cancer treatment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>c-Rel Is a Myeloid Checkpoint for Cancer Immunotherapy</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33458695/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33458695/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therapy that targets lymphoid cell checkpoints holds great promise for curing cancer. However, a majority of cancer patients do not respond to this form of therapy. In addition to lymphoid cells, myeloid cells play essential roles in controlling immunity to cancer. Whether myeloid checkpoints exist that can be targeted to treat cancer is not well established. Here we show that c-Rel, a member of the nuclear factor (NF)-B family, specified the generation of myeloid-derived suppressor cells (MDSCs) by selectively turning on pro-tumoral genes while switching off anti-tumoral genes through a c-Rel enhanceosome. c-Rel deficiency in myeloid cells markedly inhibited cancer growth in mice, and pharmaceutical inhibition of c-Rel had the same effect. Combination therapy that blocked both c-Rel and the lymphoid checkpoint protein PD1 was more effective in treating cancer than blocking either alone. Thus, c-Rel is a myeloid checkpoint that can be targeted for treating cancer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>High systemic and tumor-associated IL-8 correlates with reduced clinical benefit of PD-L1 blockade</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32405063/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32405063/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Erratum in:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; can also be found.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Author Correction: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nature.com/articles/s41591-021-01246-4&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;High systemic and tumor-associated IL-8 correlates with reduced clinical benefit of PD-L1 blockade&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although elevated plasma interleukin-8 (pIL-8) has been associated with poor outcome to immune checkpoint blockade 1, this has not been comprehensively evaluated in large randomized studies. Here we analyzed circulating pIL-8 and IL8 gene expression in peripheral blood mononuclear cells and tumors of patients treated with atezolizumab (anti-PD-L1 monoclonal antibody) from multiple randomized trials representing 1,445 patients with metastatic urothelial carcinoma (mUC) and metastatic renal cell carcinoma. High levels of IL-8 in plasma, peripheral blood mononuclear cells and tumors were associated with decreased efficacy of atezolizumab in patients with mUC and metastatic renal cell carcinoma, even in tumors that were classically CD8+ T cell inflamed. Low baseline pIL-8 in patients with mUC was associated with increased response to atezolizumab and chemotherapy. Patients with mUC who experienced on-treatment decreases in pIL-8 exhibited improved overall survival when treated with atezolizumab but not with chemotherapy. Single-cell RNA sequencing of the immune compartment showed that IL8 is primarily expressed in circulating and intratumoral myeloid cells and that high IL8 expression is associated with downregulation of the antigen-presentation machinery. Therapies that can reverse the impacts of IL-8-mediated myeloid inflammation will be essential for improving outcomes of patients treated with immune checkpoint inhibitors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Targeting STAT3 in Cancer Immunotherapy</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/32972405/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/32972405/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a point of convergence for numerous oncogenic signaling pathways, signal transducer and activator of transcription 3 (STAT3) is central in regulating the anti-tumor immune response. STAT3 is broadly hyperactivated both in cancer and non-cancerous cells within the tumor ecosystem and plays important roles in inhibiting the expression of crucial immune activation regulators and promoting the production of immunosuppressive factors. Therefore, targeting the STAT3 signaling pathway has emerged as a promising therapeutic strategy for numerous cancers. In this review, we outline the importance of STAT3 signaling pathway in tumorigenesis and its immune regulation, and highlight the current status for the development of STAT3-targeting therapeutic approaches. We also summarize and discuss recent advances in STAT3-based combination immunotherapy in detail. These endeavors provide new insights into the translational application of STAT3 in cancer and may contribute to the promotion of more effective treatments toward malignancies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
