<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>JAK/STAT | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/jak/stat/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/jak/stat/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>JAK/STAT</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>JAK/STAT</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/jak/stat/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>STAT3 regulates CD8&#43; T cell differentiation and functions in cancer and acute infection</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36688918/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36688918/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In cancer, persistent antigens drive CD8&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T cell differentiation into exhausted progenitor (T&lt;sub&gt;ex&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;sup&gt;prog&lt;/sup&gt;) and terminally exhausted (T&lt;sub&gt;ex&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;sup&gt;term&lt;/sup&gt;) cells. However, how the extrinsic and intrinsic regulatory mechanisms cooperate during this process still remains not well understood. Here, we found that STAT3 signaling plays essential roles in promoting intratumor T&lt;sub&gt;ex&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;sup&gt;term&lt;/sup&gt; cell development by enhancing their effector functions and survival, which results in better tumor control. In tumor microenvironments, STAT3 is predominantly activated by IL-10 and IL-21, but not IL-6. Besides, STAT3 also plays critical roles in the development and function of terminally differentiated effector CD8&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T cells in acute infection. Mechanistically, STAT3 transcriptionally promotes the expression of effector function-related genes, while it suppresses those expressed by the progenitor T&lt;sub&gt;ex&lt;/sub&gt; subset. Moreover, STAT3 functions in collaboration with BATF and IRF4 to mediate chromatin activation at the effector gene loci. Thus, we have elucidated the roles of STAT3 signaling in terminally differentiated CD8&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T cell development, especially in cancer, which benefits the development of more effective immunotherapies against tumors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dual-Responsive STAT3 Inhibitor Nanoprodrug Combined with Oncolytic Virus Elicits Synergistic Antitumor Immune Responses by Igniting Pyroptosis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36545949/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36545949/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Immune checkpoint blockade (ICB) therapy shows excellent efficacy against malignancies; however, insufficient tumor immunogenicity and immunosuppressive tumor microenvironment are considered as the two major stumbling blocks to a broad ICB response. Here, we report a combinational therapeutic strategy combining tumor microenvironment reactive oxygen species (ROS)/pH dual-responsive signal transducers and activators of transcription 3 (STAT3) inhibitor nanoprodrugs MPNPs with oncolytic herpes simplex virus 1 (HSV-1) virotherapy to synergistically ignite pyroptosis for enhancing immunotherapy. MPNPs exhibited a certain level of tumor accumulation, reduce tumor cell stemness, and enhance antitumor immune responses. Furthermore, the simultaneous application of oncolytic viruses (OVs) confers MPNPs with higher tumor penetration capacity and remarkable gasdermin E-mediated pyroptosis, thereby reshaping the tumor microenvironment and transforming &amp;ldquo;cold&amp;rdquo; tumors into &amp;ldquo;hot&amp;rdquo; ones. This &amp;ldquo;fire of immunity&amp;rdquo; strategy successfully activates robust T cell-dependent antitumor responses, potentiating ICB effects against local recurrence and pulmonary metastasis in preclinical &amp;ldquo;cold&amp;rdquo; murine triple-negative breast cancer and syngeneic oral cancer models. Collectively, this work may pave a new way and offer an unprecedented opportunity for the combination of OVs with nanomedicine for cancer immunotherapy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>STAT3/mitophagy axis coordinates macrophage NLRP3 inflammasome activation and inflammatory bone loss</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36502520/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36502520/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Signal transducer and activator of transcription 3 (STAT3), a cytokine-responsive transcription factor, is known to play a role in immunity and bone remodeling. However, whether and how STAT3 impacts macrophage NLR family pyrin domain containing 3 (NLRP3) inflammasome activation associated with inflammatory bone loss remains unknown. Here, STAT3 signaling is hyperactivated in macrophages in the context of both non-sterile and sterile inflammatory osteolysis, and this was highly correlated with the cleaved interleukin-1β (IL-1β) expression pattern. Strikingly, pharmacological inhibition of STAT3 markedly blocks macrophage NLRP3 inflammasome activation in vitro, thereby relieving inflammatory macrophage-amplified osteoclast formation and bone resorptive activity. Mechanistically, STAT3 inhibition in macrophages triggers PTEN-induced kinase 1 (PINK1)-dependent mitophagy that eliminates dysfunctional mitochondria, reverses mitochondrial membrane potential collapse, and inhibits mitochondrial reactive oxygen species release, thus inactivating the NLRP3 inflammasome. In vivo, STAT3 inhibition effectively protects mice from both infection-induced periapical lesions and aseptic titanium particle-mediated calvarial bone erosion with potent induction of PINK1 and downregulation of inflammasome activation, macrophage infiltration, and osteoclast formation. This study reveals the regulatory role of the STAT3/mitophagy axis at the osteo-immune interface and highlights a potential therapeutic intervention to prevent inflammatory bone loss.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Astaxanthin ameliorates lipopolysaccharide-induced acute lung injury via inhibition of inflammatory reactions and modulation of the SOCS3/JAK2/STAT3 signaling pathways in mice</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36278420/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36278420/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acute lung injury (ALI) is a systemic inflammatory process. A large number of studies have shown that astaxanthin (ASTA) has strong anti-inflammatory effects and almost non-toxic side effects. The purpose of this study was to explore the effect of ASTA on lipopolysaccharide (LPS)-induced ALI in mice and its underlying mechanism. The result showed that compared with the LPS group, the expression levels of the respiratory resistance (Re), inspiratory resistance (Ri), dynamic lung compliance (Cdyn), wet/dry weight (W/D) ratio, albumin (BA/SA) ratio and myeloperoxidase (MPO) activity in the ASTA pretreatment group were significantly reduced, and total cell, neutrophil and macrophage counts were significantly decreased. HE staining results showed that alveolar interstitial edema, bleeding and erythrocyte exudation were reduced. Compared with the LPS group, the percentage of Th17 cells and the content of interleukin (IL)-17 and tumor necrosis factor-α (TNF-α) in the ASTA pretreatment group were significantly decreased, while the content of the transforming growth factor (TGF)-β and the percentage of Treg cells were significantly increased. Western blot analysis showed that ASTA could up-regulate the expression level of the suppressor of cytokine signaling-3 (SOCS3) and down-regulate the expression levels of phosphorylated Janus kinase 2 (p-JAK2), phosphorylated signal transducer and activator of transcription 3 (p-STAT3) in lung tissue. The results showed that ASTA had a protective effect on LPS-induced acute lung injury in mice, and its protective mechanism was through activating the SOCS3/JAK2/STAT3 signaling pathway, promoting Treg cell differentiation and reducing inflammatory reactions and Th17 cell differentiation, which provided a theoretical basis for the clinical treatment of ALI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The influenza virus PB2 protein evades antiviral innate immunity by inhibiting JAK1/STAT signalling</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36271046/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36271046/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Influenza A virus (IAV) polymerase protein PB2 has been shown to partially inhibit the host immune response by blocking the induction of interferons (IFNs). However, the IAV PB2 protein that regulates the downstream signaling pathway of IFNs is not well characterized. Here, we report that IAV PB2 protein reduces cellular sensitivity to IFNs, suppressing the activation of STAT1/STAT2 and ISGs. Furthermore, IAV PB2 protein targets mammalian JAK1 at lysine 859 and 860 for ubiquitination and degradation. Notably, the H5 subtype of highly pathogenic avian influenza virus with I283M/K526R mutations on PB2 increases the ability to degrade mammalian JAK1 and exhibits higher replicate efficiency in mammalian (but not avian) cells and mouse lung tissues, and causes greater mortality in infected mice. Altogether, these data describe a negative regulatory mechanism involving PB2-JAK1 and provide insights into an evasion strategy from host antiviral immunity employed by IAV.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Serine metabolism orchestrates macrophage polarization by regulating the IGF1-p38 axis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36180780/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36180780/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Serine metabolism is reportedly involved in immune cell functions, but whether and how serine metabolism regulates macrophage polarization remain largely unknown. Here, we show that suppressing serine metabolism, either by inhibiting the activity of the key enzyme phosphoglycerate dehydrogenase in the serine biosynthesis pathway or by exogenous serine and glycine restriction, robustly enhances the polarization of interferon-γ-activated macrophages (M(IFN-γ)) but suppresses that of interleukin-4-activated macrophages (M(IL-4)) both in vitro and in vivo. Mechanistically, serine metabolism deficiency increases the expression of IGF1 by reducing the promoter abundance of S-adenosyl methionine-dependent histone H3 lysine 27 trimethylation. IGF1 then activates the p38-dependent JAK-STAT1 axis to promote M(IFN-γ) polarization and suppress STAT6-mediated M(IL-4) activation. This study reveals a new mechanism by which serine metabolism orchestrates macrophage polarization and suggests the manipulation of serine metabolism as a therapeutic strategy for macrophage-mediated immune diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>H1N1 influenza virus dose dependent induction of dysregulated innate immune responses and STAT1/3 activation are associated with pulmonary immunopathological damage</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36082929/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36082929/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Influenza A virus (IAV) infection poses a substantial challenge and causes high morbidity and mortality. Exacerbated pulmonary inflammatory responses are the major causes of extensive diffuse alveolar immunopathological damage. However, the relationship between the extent of cytokine storm, neutrophils/macrophages infiltration, and different IAV infection dose and time still needs to be further elucidated, and it is still unclear whether the signal transduction and transcriptional activator 1/3 (STAT1/3) signalling pathway plays a beneficial or detrimental role. Here, we established a mouse model of high- and low-dose pH1N1 infection. We found that pH1N1 infection induced robust and early pathological damage and cytokine storm in an infection dose- and time-dependent manner. High-dose pH1N1 infection induced massive and sustained recruitment of neutrophils as well as a higher ratio of M1:M2, which may contribute to severe lung immunopathological damage. pH1N1 infection activated dose- and time-dependent STAT1 and STAT3. Inhibition of STAT1 and/or STAT3 aggravated low-dose pH1N1 infection, induced lung damage, and decreased survival rate. Appropriate activation of STAT1/3 provided survival benefits and pathological improvement during low-dose pH1N1 infection. These results demonstrate that high-dose pH1N1 infection induces robust and sustained neutrophil infiltration, imbalanced macrophage polarization, excessive and earlier cytokine storm, and STAT1/3 activation, which are associated with pulmonary dysregulated proinflammatory responses and progress of acute lung injury. The severe innate immune responses may be the threshold at which protective functions give way to immunopathology, and assessing the magnitude of host innate immune responses is necessary in adjunctive immunomodulatory therapy for alleviating influenza-induced pneumonia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Diacerein attenuate LPS-induced acute lung injury via inhibiting ER stress and apoptosis: Impact on the crosstalk between SphK1/S1P, TLR4/NFκB/STAT3, and NLRP3/IL-1β signaling pathways</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36055546/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36055546/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Aims:&lt;/em&gt; Acute lung injury (ALI) is a life-threatening clinical problem with high mortality rate and limited treatments or preventive options that represents a major challenge for clinicians. Diacerein (DIA) is a multi-target anthraquinone derivative with potent anti-inflammatory action. The aim of this study is to assess the protective effect of DIA and its potential molecular targets against lipopolysaccharide (LPS)-induced ALI in rats.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Materials and methods:&lt;/em&gt; Adult male Sprague-Dawley rats were orally administrated DIA (50 mg/kg) for 5 consecutive days followed by a single intraperitoneal injection of LPS (5mg/kg).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Key findings:&lt;/em&gt; DIA mitigated oxidative lung injury in LPS-challenged rats via significantly decreasing lung wet/dry (W/D) ratio, inflammatory cells infiltration, and lipid peroxidation, with concomitant elevation in enzymatic and non-enzymatic antioxidant levels in lung tissue. Likewise, DIA alleviated endoplasmic reticulum stress and markedly halted inflammation triggered by LPS challenge in pulmonary tissue by suppressing NLRP3/IL-1β and TLR4/NF-κB signaling with parallel decrease in proinflammatory cytokine levels. Interestingly, DIA down regulated Sphk1/S1P axis, reduced GSK-3β and STAT3 proteins expression, and markedly decreased caspase-3 besides increasing Bcl-2 levels in lung tissue of LPS-challenged animals. These biochemical findings was simultaneously associated with marked improvement in histological alterations of lung tissue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Significance:&lt;/em&gt; These findings verify the protective effect of DIA against LPS-induced ALI through targeting oxidative stress, endoplasmic reticulum stress, and apoptosis. Importantly, DIA halted the hyperinflammatory state triggered by LPS via multi-faceted inhibitory effect on different signaling pathways, hence DIA could potentially reduce mortality in patients with ALI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zanubrutinib ameliorates lipopolysaccharide-induced acute lung injury via regulating macrophage polarization</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35973369/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35973369/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Zanubrutinib could relieve LPS induced lung injuries in mice.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;JAK2/STAT1 and TLR4/MyD88/NF-κB pathway is involved in Zanubrutinib -mediated M1 macrophage polarization in RAW264.7 cells.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Zanubrutinib promotes M2 macrophage activation through regulating JAK/STAT6 and PI3K/AKT pathway in RAW264.7 cells.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acute lung injury (ALI) is a disease characterized by pulmonary diffusion dysfunction and its exacerbation stage is acute respiratory distress syndrome (ARDS), which may develop to multiple organ failure and seriously threatens human health. ALI has high mortality rates and few effective treatments, thus effective protection measures for ALI are becoming increasingly important. Macrophages play a key regulatory role in the pathogenesis of ALI, and the degree of macrophage polarization is closely related to the severity and prognosis of ALI. In this study, we evaluated the effects of Zanubrutinib (ZB), a BTK small molecule inhibitor approved by the FDA for the treatment of cell lymphoma, on macrophage polarization and acute lung injury. In the in vivo study, we constructed a mouse model of Lipopolysaccharide (LPS)-induced acute lung injury and found that ZB could improve the acute injury of mouse lungs by inhibiting the secretion of proinflammatory factors and promoting the secretion of anti-inflammatory factors, reduce the number of inflammatory cells in alveolar lavage fluid, and then alleviate the inflammatory response. In vivo and in vitro studies have shown that ZB could inhibit the M1 macrophage polarization and promote the M2 macrophage polarization. Subsequent mechanistic studies revealed that ZB could inhibit the macrophage M1 polarization via targeting BTK activation and inhibiting JAK2/STAT1 and TLR4/MyD88/NF-κB signaling pathways, and promote the macrophage M2 polarization by promoting the activation of STAT6 and PI3K / Akt signaling pathways. In summary, ZB has shown therapeutic effect in LPS-induced acute lung injury in mice, which provides a potential candidate drug to treat acute lung injury.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Piceatannol-mediated JAK2/STAT3 signaling pathway inhibition contributes to the alleviation of oxidative injury and collagen synthesis during pulmonary fibrosis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35932616/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35932616/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlight&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Piceatannol lightened oxidative injury and collagen synthesis in lung tissues during pulmonary fibrosis.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Piceatannol inhibited the activation and collagen synthesis of TGF-β-induced lung fibroblasts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;JAK2 activation abolished the effects of piceatannol in TGF-β-induced lung fibroblasts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pulmonary fibrosis (PF) is characterized by oxidative injury and excessive collagen synthesis in lung fibroblasts, causing impaired pulmonary function and chronic lung injury. Piceatannol, a dietary polyphenol, possesses vital pharmacological effects in metabolic disorders, cancers, cardiovascular disease and infectious disease; however, its role in PF is still not completely elucidated. Mice (8 to 10 weeks old) were administered bleomycin (BLM) intratracheally (2 U/kg) to establish an in vivo PF model. Murine primary lung fibroblasts were isolated and stimulated with TGF-β (10 ng/mL) for 48 h to induce its activation. Meanwhile, mice or primary lung fibroblasts were treated with different doses of piceatannol to observe its protective roles. Pulmonary function and arterial blood gas were detected to assess pulmonary physiological status. Collagen deposition and the mRNA levels of profibrotic genes were determined by H&amp;amp;E staining and RT-PCR. Meanwhile, the protein and mRNA markers, as well as end-product of oxidative stress were detected in vivo and in vitro. The results showed that pulmonary function was significantly impaired in BLM-induced mice, accompanied by elevated oxidative stress and excessive collagen synthesis. Piceatannol significantly improved pulmonary function and decreased oxidative injury as well as collagen synthesis in mice with PF. Mechanically, piceatannol treatment significantly inhibited the activation of JAK2/STAT3 signaling pathway in BLM-induced mice and TGF-β-induced lung fibroblasts. Additional findings also demonstrated that coumermycin A1 (C-A1), an agonist of JAK2, could abolish the effects of piceatannol on TGF-β-induced lung fibroblasts and reactivated the phosphorylation STAT3. Taken together, our study demonstrated that piceatannol could protect against oxidative injury and collagen synthesis during PF in a JAK2/STAT3 signaling pathway-dependent manner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SHF Acts as a Novel Tumor Suppressor in Glioblastoma Multiforme by Disrupting STAT3 Dimerization</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35843865/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35843865/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sustained activation of signal transducer and activator of transcription 3 (STAT3) is a critical contributor in tumorigenesis and chemoresistance, thus making it an attractive cancer therapeutic target. Here, SH2 domain-containing adapter protein F (SHF) is identified as a tumor suppressor in glioblastoma Multiforme (GBM) and its negative regulation of STAT3 activity is characterized. Mechanically, SHF selectively binds and inhibits acetylated STAT3 dimerization without affecting STAT3 phosphorylation or acetylation. Additionally, by blocking STAT3-DNMT1 (DNA Methyltransferase 1) interaction, SHF relieves methylation of tumor suppressor genes. The SH2 domain is documented to be essential for SHF&amp;rsquo;s actions on STAT3, and almost entirely replaces the functions of SHF on STAT3 independently. Moreover, the peptide C16 a peptide derived from the STAT3-binding sites of SHF inhibits STAT3 dimerization and STAT3/DNMT1 interaction, and achieves remarkable growth inhibition in GBM cells in vitro and in vivo. These findings strongly identify targeting of the SHF/STAT3 interaction as a promising strategy for developing an optimal STAT3 inhibitor and provide early evidence of the potential clinical efficacy of STAT3 inhibitors such as C16 in GBM.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inhibition of the JAK/STAT Pathway with Baricitinib Reduces the Multiple Organ Dysfunction Caused by Hemorrhagic Shock in Rats</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35837955/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35837955/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Objective:&lt;/em&gt; The aim of this study was to investigate (a) the effects of the Janus kinase (JAK)/signal transducer and activator of transcription (STAT) pathway inhibitor (baricitinib) on the MODS in a rat model of hemorrhagic shock (HS) and (b) whether treatment with baricitinib attenuates the activation of JAK/STAT, NF-κB and NLRP3 caused by HS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Post-traumatic MODS, which is in part due to excessive systemic inflammation, is associated with high morbidity and mortality. The JAK/STAT pathway is a regulator of numerous growth factor and cytokine receptors and, hence, is considered a potential master regulator of many inflammatory signaling processes. However, its role in trauma-hemorrhage is unknown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; An acute HS rat model was performed to determine the effect of baricitinib on MODS. The activation of JAK/STAT, NF-κB and NLRP3 pathways were analyzed by western blotting in the kidney and liver.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; We demonstrate here for the first time that treatment with baricitinib (during resuscitation following severe hemorrhage) attenuates the organ injury and dysfunction and the activation of JAK/STAT, NF-κB and NLRP3 pathways caused by HS in the rat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; Our results point to a role of the JAK/STAT pathway in the pathophysiology of the organ injury and dysfunction caused by trauma/hemorrhage and indicate that JAK inhibitors, such as baricitinib, may be repurposed for the treatment of the MODS after trauma and/or hemorrhage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LINC00893 inhibits the progression of prostate cancer through miR-3173-5p/SOCS3/JAK2/STAT3 pathway</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35818076/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35818076/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Prostate cancer (PCa) is one of the most common malignant tumors in the male urinary system. In recent years, the morbidity and mortality of PCa have been increasing due to the limited effects of existing treatment strategies. Long non-coding RNA (lncRNA) LINC00893 was reported to inhibit the proliferation and metastasis of papillary thyroid cancer cells, but its role in PCa has not been reported. This study aims to investigate the role and underlying mechanism of LINC00893 in regulating the progression of PCa cells.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; We first compared LINC00893 expression levels between PCa tissues and normal prostate tissues through TCGA database. The relative LINC00893 expression levels were further validated in 66 pairs of PCa tissues and para-cancerous normal tissues, as well as in PCa cell lines. Gain-of-function experiment was performed by transfecting PCa cell with LINC00893 expression vector, and CCK (Cell count kit)-8, 5-Ethynyl-2&amp;rsquo;-deoxyuridine (EdU) incorporation, colony information and transwell assays were conducted to assess the functional phenotypes. Dual-luciferase reporter, RNA-binding protein immunoprecipitation (RIP) and RNA pull-down assays were performed to evaluate the molecular interactions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; LINC00893 was downregulated in PCa tissues and cell lines, and patients with low expression of LINC00893 were associated with a poorer overall survival rate. LINC00893 overexpression hindered the proliferation, epithelial-mesenchymal transition (EMT) as well as the migratory ability of PCa cells, and suppressed the tumorigenesis of PCa cells in nude mice. We further demonstrated that LINC00893 acted as a sponge for miR-3173-5p and inhibited its activity, which in turn regulated the suppressor of cytokine signaling 3 (SOCS3)/Janus Kinase 2 (JAK2)/signal transducer and activator of transcription 3 (STAT3) signaling axis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; Our study demonstrated that LINC00893 suppresses the progression of PCa cells through targeting miR-3173-5p/SOCS3/JAK2/STAT3 axis. Our data uncovers a novel tumor-suppressor role of LINC00893 in PCa, which may serve as a potential strategy for targeted therapy in PCa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ACT001 suppressing M1 polarization against inflammation via NF-κB and STAT1 signaling pathways alleviates acute lung injury in mice</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35728304/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35728304/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ACT001 conferred potent protection against LPS-induced acute lung injury in mice.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ACT001 inhibited M1 macrophage polarization, limiting its pro-inflammatory activity.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ACT001 suppressed NF-κB and STAT1 signaling by targeting IKKβ as well as STAT1.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ACT001 has been shown to exhibit excellent antitumor and anti-fibrosis activities. However, the role of ACT001 in acute lung injury (ALI) and the underlying mechanism remains largely unclear. The present study aimed to investigate the protective effects of ACT001 on ALI and explore the potential mechanisms. Herein, we firstly established the ALI mouse model induced by intratracheal instillation of lipopolysaccharide (LPS). ACT001 treatment significantly alleviated histopathological changes of lung tissues with lower infiltration of pulmonary M1 macrophages in ALI mice. Then, we performed in vitro experiment and found that ACT001 treatment effectively inhibited the M1 phenotype of RAW264.7 and THP-1.. Next, we performed pull-down and mass spectrometry analysis to screen the interacting proteins of ACT001, identifying IKKβ and STAT1 as the critical target proteins of ACT001. And ACT001 treatment significantly suppressed the NF-κB and STAT1 pathways, thereby inhibiting the M1 polarization against inflammation in vivo and in vitro. Finally, we used IMD 0354 (IMD) and Fludarabine (Flud) to specifically block the activity of IKKβ and STAT1, and stimulated macrophages through IKKβ and STAT1 overexpression. Our data clearly showed that ACT001-induced decrease of the M1 polarization was blocked by IMD and Flud treatment, and reversed by IKKβ and STAT1 overexpression in RAW264.7 cells. In conclusion, we discovered that ACT001 significantly alleviates inflammation and limits M1 phenotype of pulmonary macrophages via suppressing NF-κB and STAT1 signaling pathways, providing new insights for the development of drugs to treat ALI/ARDS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>High phosphate-induced progressive proximal tubular injury is associated with the activation of Stat3/Kim-1 signaling pathway and macrophage recruitment</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35713543/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35713543/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dietary phosphate intake in the Western population greatly exceeds the recommended dietary allowance and is linked to enhanced cardiovascular and all-cause mortality. It is unclear whether a chronic high phosphate diet (HPD) causes kidney injury in healthy individuals. Here, we show that feeding a 2% HPD in C57BL/6N mice for one up to six months resulted in hyperphosphatemia, hyperphosphaturia, increased plasma levels of fibroblast growth factor (FGF) 23, and parathyroid hormone (PTH) compared to mice on a 0.8% phosphate diet. Kidney injury was already noted after two months of HPD characterized by loss of proximal tubular (PT) cell polarity, flattened epithelia, disruption of brush border membranes, vacuolization, increased PT cell proliferation, marked interstitial mononuclear infiltration, and progressive accumulation of collagen fibers. HPD increased Stat3 activation and Kim-1 expression in PT epithelial cells and enhanced renal synthesis of chemokines recruiting monocytes and macrophages as well as macrophage related factors. Enhanced recruitment of F4/80+ macrophages around injured PT lesions was timely associated with increased Kim-1 synthesis, tubular MCP-1 expression, and degree of PT injury score. Likewise, tubulointerstitial fibrosis was associated with activation of Stat3/Kim-1 signaling pathway. The stimulation of human proximal tubular cells with high phosphate activated Stat3 signaling and induced HAVCR1 and CCL2 expression. We conclude that high phosphate results in progressive proximal tubular injury, indicating that high dietary phosphate intake may affect kidney health and therefore represents an underestimated health problem for the general population.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gut dysbiosis promotes prostate cancer progression and docetaxel resistance via activating NF-κB-IL6-STAT3 axis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35710492/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35710492/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; The gut microbiota is reportedly involved in the progression and chemoresistance of various human malignancies. However, the underlying mechanisms behind how it exerts some effect on prostate cancer, as an extra-intestinal tumor, in a contact-independent way remain elusive and deserve exploration. Antibiotic exposure, one of the various factors affecting the gut microbiota community and capable of causing gut dysbiosis, is associated with multiple disorders. This study aims to preliminarily clarify the link between gut dysbiosis and prostate cancer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; First, we discovered that perturbing the gut microbiota by consuming broad-spectrum antibiotics in water promoted the growth of subcutaneous and orthotopic tumors in mice. Fecal microbiota transplantation could transmit the effect of antibiotic exposure on tumor growth. Then, 16S rRNA sequencing for mouse feces indicated that the relative abundance of Proteobacteria was significantly higher after antibiotic exposure. Meanwhile, intratumoral lipopolysaccharide (LPS) profoundly increased under the elevation of gut permeability. Both in vivo and in vitro experiments revealed that the NF-κB-IL6-STAT3 axis activated by intratumoral LPS facilitated prostate cancer proliferation and docetaxel chemoresistance. Finally, 16S rRNA sequencing of patients&amp;rsquo; fecal samples revealed that Proteobacteria was enriched in patients with metastatic prostate cancer and was positively correlated with plasma IL6 level, regional lymph node metastasis status, and distant metastasis status. The receiver operating characteristic (ROC) curves showed that the relative abundance of Proteobacteria had better performance than the prostate-specific antigen (PSA) level in predicting the probability of distant metastasis in prostate cancer (area under the ROC curve, 0.860; p &amp;lt; 0.001).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/em&gt; Collectively, this research demonstrated that gut dysbiosis, characterized by the enrichment of Proteobacteria due to antibiotic exposure, resulted in the elevation of gut permeability and intratumoral LPS, promoting the development of prostate cancer via the NF-κB-IL6-STAT3 axis in mice. Considering findings from human patients, Proteobacteria might act as an intestinal biomarker for progressive prostate cancer. Video Abstract.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stat3/IL-6 signaling mediates sustained pneumonia induced by Agiostrongylus cantonensis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35617354/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35617354/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Angiostrongylus cantonensis (AC) is well-documented that parasitizes the host brain and causes eosinophilic meningitis. The migration route of AC in permissive hosts is well demonstrated, while in nonpermissive hosts, it remains to be fully defined. In the present study, we exploited live imaging technology, morphological and pathological configuration analysis, and molecular biological technologies to explore the migration route of AC and the accompanying tissue damage in nonpermissive and permissive hosts. Our data indicated that, in nonpermissive host mouse, AC larvae migrated from intestinal wall to liver at 2 hours post-infection (hpi), from liver to lung at 4 hpi and then from lung to brain at 8 hpi. AC larval migration caused fatal lung injury (pneumonia) during acute and early infection phases, along with significant activation of Stat3/IL-6 signaling. In addition, AC induce sustained interstitial pneumonia in mouse and rat and pulmonary fibrosis only in rat during late infection phase. Moreover, during the early and late infection phases, Th2 cytokine expression and Stat3 and IL-6 signaling were persistently enhanced and myeloid macrophage cells were notably enriched in host lung, and administration of Stat3 and IL-6 inhibitors (C188-9 and LMT-28) attenuated AC infection-induced acute pneumonia in mice. Overall, we are the first to provide direct and systemic laboratory evidence of AC migration route in a nonpermissive host and report that infection with a high dose of AC larvae could result in acute and fatal pneumonia through Stat3/IL-6 signaling in mice. These findings may present a feasible to rational strategy to minimize the pathogenesis induced by AC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Canonical and noncanonical regulatory roles for JAK2 in the pathogenesis of rheumatoid arthritis-associated interstitial lung disease and idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35522243/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35522243/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis (IPF) and rheumatoid arthritis-associated interstitial lung disease (RA-ILD) are two fibrotic interstitial lung diseases that share the usual interstitial pneumonia (UIP) injury pattern. Here, we report that RNA sequencing of lung biopsies from patients with RA-ILD and IPF revealed shared and distinct disease-causing pathways. Analysis of transcriptomic data identified a JAK2 related JAK/STAT signaling pathway gene signature that distinguishes RA-UIP from idiopathic UIP. This was further confirmed by immunohistostaining, which identified JAK2 phosphorylation with two distinct forms of activation: a cytoplasmic form of JAK2 activation in most IPF cases (13/20) and a nuclear form of p-JAK2 in RA-UIP (5/5) and a minority of IPF (6/20) cases. Further immunohistostaining identified STAT5A&amp;amp;B as the downstream transcriptional activator for JAK2-mediated canonical signal transduction and phosphorylation of Tyr41 on histone H3 (H3Y41ph) as the downstream epigenetic regulation site for JAK2-mediated noncanonical signal transduction. Gene Set Enrichment Analysis (GSEA) of the RNA-Seq data further supported this shared pathogenic mechanism for the two diseases with the enrichment of STAT5A&amp;amp;B target gene sets as well as the JAK2 regulated H3Y41ph target gene set. This regulatory role of JAK2 in the pathogenesis of pulmonary fibrosis was further demonstrated by the attenuation of bleomycin-induced murine pulmonary fibrosis using a JAK2-selective pharmacological inhibitor CEP33779. In vitro studies with normal and IPF derived lung fibroblasts revealed a central role for JAK2 as an essential intermediary molecule in TGF-β-mediated myofibroblast trans-differentiation, proliferation, and extracellular matrix protein production. These observations support a crucial role for JAK2 as an intermediary molecule in fibrotic lung disease development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lactylation-driven METTL3-mediated RNA m6A modification promotes immunosuppression of tumor-infiltrating myeloid cells</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35320754/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35320754/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;H3K18 lactylation increases Mettl3 expression in tumor-infiltrating myeloid cells&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;METTL3-mediated m&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;A modification on Jak1 mRNA promotes its protein translation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;METTL3/m&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;A/JAK1/STAT3 axis strengthens immunosuppressive functions of myeloid cells&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lactylation on zinc-finger domain of METTL3 enhances its capture of m&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;A-modified RNA&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Combined Transcriptomic and Proteomic Approach to Reveal the Effect of Mogroside V on OVA-Induced Pulmonary Inflammation in Mice</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35371026/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35371026/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mogroside V is a bioactive ingredient extracted from the natural food Siraitia grosvenorii which possesses functions that stimulate lung humidification and cough relief activities, but its underlying mechanisms were rarely studied. To estimate its potential protective effect on ovalbumin (OVA)-induced pulmonary inflammation and understand its system-wide mechanism, integrated omics was applied in this study. Mogroside V effectively reduced the levels of IgE, TNF-α, and IL-5 in OVA-induced mice. The results of RNA-seq and data-independent acquisition proteomics approach revealed that 944 genes and 341 proteins were differentially expressed in the normal control group (NC) and ovalbumin-induced control group (OC) and 449 genes and 259 proteins were differentially expressed between the OC and the group treated with 50 mg/kg mogroside V (MV). After a combined analysis of the transcriptome and the proteome, 93 major pathways were screened, and we discovered that mogroside V exerts an anti-inflammation effect in the lung via NF-κB and JAK-STAT, both of which are among the signaling pathways mentioned above. In addition, we found that the key regulatory molecules (Igha, Ighg1, NF-κB, Jak1, and Stat1) in the two pathways were activated in inflammation and inhibited by mogroside V. Thus, mogroside V may be the main bioactivity component in S. grosvenorii that exerts lung humidification and cough relief effects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Poxviruses and paramyxoviruses use a conserved mechanism of STAT1 antagonism to inhibit interferon signaling</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35182467/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35182467/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Poxvirus protein 018 is a virulence factor that inhibits IFN-induced signaling&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;018 binds the STAT1 SH2 domain to block its recruitment to the IFNγ receptor&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The structure of the 018:STAT1 complex reveals a pTyr-independent binding mode&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vaccinia and Nipah viruses acquired a STAT1-binding motif by convergent evolution&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The induction of interferon (IFN)-stimulated genes by STATs is a critical host defense mechanism against virus infection. Here, we report that a highly expressed poxvirus protein, 018, inhibits IFN-induced signaling by binding to the SH2 domain of STAT1, thereby preventing the association of STAT1 with an activated IFN receptor. Despite encoding other inhibitors of IFN-induced signaling, a poxvirus mutant lacking 018 was attenuated in mice. The 2.0 Å crystal structure of the 018:STAT1 complex reveals a phosphotyrosine-independent mode of 018 binding to the SH2 domain of STAT1. Moreover, the STAT1-binding motif of 018 shows similarity to the STAT1-binding proteins from Nipah virus, which, similar to 018, block the association of STAT1 with an IFN receptor. Overall, these results uncover a conserved mechanism of STAT1 antagonism that is employed independently by distinct virus families.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>STAT3 signaling in immunity</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/27185365/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/27185365/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The transcriptional regulator STAT3 has key roles in vertebrate development and mature tissue function including control of inflammation and immunity. Mutations in human STAT3 associate with diseases such as immunodeficiency, autoimmunity and cancer. Strikingly, however, either hyperactivation or inactivation of STAT3 results in human disease, indicating tightly regulated STAT3 function is central to health. Here, we attempt to summarize information on the numerous and distinct biological actions of STAT3, and highlight recent discoveries, with a specific focus on STAT3 function in the immune and hematopoietic systems. Our goal is to spur investigation on mechanisms by which aberrant STAT3 function drives human disease and novel approaches that might be used to modulate disease outcome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The role of STAT3 in autophagy</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/25951043/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/25951043/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Autophagy is an evolutionarily conserved process in eukaryotes that eliminates harmful components and maintains cellular homeostasis in response to a series of extracellular insults. However, these insults may trigger the downstream signaling of another prominent stress responsive pathway, the STAT3 signaling pathway, which has been implicated in multiple aspects of the autophagic process. Recent reports further indicate that different subcellular localization patterns of STAT3 affect autophagy in various ways. For example, nuclear STAT3 fine-tunes autophagy via the transcriptional regulation of several autophagy-related genes such as BCL2 family members, BECN1, PIK3C3, CTSB, CTSL, PIK3R1, HIF1A, BNIP3, and microRNAs with targets of autophagy modulators. Cytoplasmic STAT3 constitutively inhibits autophagy by sequestering EIF2AK2 as well as by interacting with other autophagy-related signaling molecules such as FOXO1 and FOXO3. Additionally, the mitochondrial translocation of STAT3 suppresses autophagy induced by oxidative stress and may effectively preserve mitochondria from being degraded by mitophagy. Understanding the role of STAT3 signaling in the regulation of autophagy may provide insight into the classic autophagy model and also into cancer therapy, especially for the emerging targeted therapy, because a series of targeted agents execute antitumor activities via blocking STAT3 signaling, which inevitably affects the autophagy pathway. Here, we review several of the representative studies and the current understanding in this particular field.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Targeting STAT3 in Cancer Immunotherapy</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/32972405/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/32972405/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a point of convergence for numerous oncogenic signaling pathways, signal transducer and activator of transcription 3 (STAT3) is central in regulating the anti-tumor immune response. STAT3 is broadly hyperactivated both in cancer and non-cancerous cells within the tumor ecosystem and plays important roles in inhibiting the expression of crucial immune activation regulators and promoting the production of immunosuppressive factors. Therefore, targeting the STAT3 signaling pathway has emerged as a promising therapeutic strategy for numerous cancers. In this review, we outline the importance of STAT3 signaling pathway in tumorigenesis and its immune regulation, and highlight the current status for the development of STAT3-targeting therapeutic approaches. We also summarize and discuss recent advances in STAT3-based combination immunotherapy in detail. These endeavors provide new insights into the translational application of STAT3 in cancer and may contribute to the promotion of more effective treatments toward malignancies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
