<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Complement | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/complement/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/complement/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Complement</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Complement</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/complement/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>ADAMTS7-Mediated Complement Factor H Degradation Potentiates Complement Activation to Contributing to Renal Injuries</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36735376/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36735376/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; The dysfunction of complement factor H (CFH), the main soluble complement negative regulator, potentiates various complement-induced renal injuries. However, insights into the underlying mechanism of CFH dysfunction remain limited. In this study, we investigated whether extracellular protease-mediated degradation accounts for CFH dysfunction in complement-mediated renal injuries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; An unbiased interactome of lupus mice kidneys identified CFH-binding protease. In vitro cleavage assay clarified CFH degradation. Pristane-induced SLE or renal ischemia-reperfusion (I/R) injury models were used in wild-type and ADAMTS7-/- mice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; We identified the metalloprotease ADAMTS7 as a CFH-binding protein in lupus kidneys. Moreover, the upregulation of ADAMTS7 correlated with CFH reduction in both lupus mice and patients. Mechanistically, ADAMTS7 is directly bound to CFH complement control protein (CCP) 1-4 domain and degraded CCP 1-7 domain through multiple cleavages. In mice with lupus nephritis or renal I/R injury, ADAMTS7 deficiency alleviated complement activation and related renal pathologies, but without affecting complement-mediated bactericidal activity. Adeno-associated virus-mediated CFH silencing compromised these protective effects of ADAMTS7 knockout against complement-mediated renal injuries in vivo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/em&gt; ADAMTS7-mediated CFH degradation potentiates complement activation and related renal injuries. ADAMTS7 would be a promising anticomplement therapeutic target that does not increase bacterial infection risk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Endothelial-specific loss of Krüppel-Like Factor 4 triggers complement-mediated endothelial injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35483525/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35483525/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thrombotic microangiopathy (TMA) in the kidney represents the most severe manifestation of kidney microvascular endothelial injury. Despite the source of the inciting event, the diverse clinical forms of kidney TMA share dysregulation of endothelial cell transcripts and complement activation. Here, we show that endothelial-specific knockdown of Krüppel-Like Factor 4 (Klf4)ΔEC, an anti-inflammatory and antithrombotic zinc-finger transcription factor, increases the susceptibility to glomerular endothelial injury and microangiopathy in two genetic murine models that included endothelial nitric oxide synthase knockout mice and aged mice (52 weeks), as well as in a pharmacologic model of TMA using Shiga-toxin 2. In all models, Klf4ΔEC mice exhibit increased pro-thrombotic and pro-inflammatory transcripts, as well as increased complement factors C3 and C5b-9 deposition and histologic features consistent with subacute TMA. Interestingly, complement activation in Klf4ΔEC mice was accompanied by reduced expression of a key KLF4 transcriptional target and membrane bound complement regulatory gene, Cd55. To assess a potential mechanism by which KLF4 might regulate CD55 expression, we performed in silico chromatin immunoprecipitation enrichment analysis of the CD55 promotor and found KLF4 binding sites upstream from the CD55 transcription start site. Using patient-derived kidney biopsy specimens, we found glomerular expression of KLF4 and CD55 was reduced in patients with TMA as compared to control biopsies of the unaffected pole of patient kidneys removed due to kidney cancer. Thus, our data support that endothelial Klf4 is necessary for maintenance of a quiescent glomerular endothelial phenotype and its loss increases susceptibility to complement activation and induction of prothrombotic and pro-inflammatory pathways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Complement activation induces excessive T cell cytotoxicity in severe COVID-19</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35032429/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35032429/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Severe COVID-19 is marked by activated, highly cytotoxic CD16&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T cells&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Immune-complex-mediated degranulation of CD16&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T cells causes endothelial cell injury&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;C3a-rich environment in severe COVID-19 promotes differentiation of CD16&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T cells&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Activated CD16&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T cells and complement proteins are associated with fatal outcome&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Severe COVID-19 is linked to both dysfunctional immune response and unrestrained immunopathology, and it remains unclear whether T cells contribute to disease pathology. Here, we combined single-cell transcriptomics and single-cell proteomics with mechanistic studies to assess pathogenic T cell functions and inducing signals. We identified highly activated CD16&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T cells with increased cytotoxic functions in severe COVID-19. CD16 expression enabled immune-complex-mediated, T cell receptor-independent degranulation and cytotoxicity not found in other diseases. CD16&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T cells from COVID-19 patients promoted microvascular endothelial cell injury and release of neutrophil and monocyte chemoattractants. CD16&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T cell clones persisted beyond acute disease maintaining their cytotoxic phenotype. Increased generation of C3a in severe COVID-19 induced activated CD16&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; cytotoxic T cells. Proportions of activated CD16&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T cells and plasma levels of complement proteins upstream of C3a were associated with fatal outcome of COVID-19, supporting a pathological role of exacerbated cytotoxicity and complement activation in COVID-19.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Combating Complement&#39;s Deleterious Effects on Nanomedicine by Conjugating Complement Regulatory Proteins to Nanoparticles</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34910334/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34910334/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Complement opsonization is among the biggest challenges facing nanomedicine. Nearly instantly after injection into blood, nanoparticles are opsonized by the complement protein C3, leading to clearance by phagocytes, fouling of targeting moieties, and release of anaphylatoxins. While surface polymers such as poly(ethylene glycol) (PEG) partially decrease complement opsonization, most nanoparticles still suffer from extensive complement opsonization, especially when linked to targeting moieties. To ameliorate the deleterious effects of complement, two of mammals&amp;rsquo; natural regulators of complement activation (RCAs), Factors H and I, are here conjugated to the surface of nanoparticles. In vitro, Factor H or I conjugation to PEG-coated nanoparticles decrease their C3 opsonization, and markedly reduce nanoparticle uptake by phagocytes. In an in vivo mouse model of sepsis-induced lung injury, Factor I conjugation abrogates nanoparticle uptake by intravascular phagocytes in the lungs, allowing the blood concentration of the nanoparticle to remain elevated much longer. For nanoparticles targeted to the lung&amp;rsquo;s endothelium by conjugation to anti-ICAM antibodies, Factor I conjugation shifts the cell-type distribution away from phagocytes and toward endothelial cells. Finally, Factor I conjugation abrogates the severe anaphylactoid responses common to many nanoparticles, preventing systemic capillary leak and preserving blood flow to visceral organs and the brain. Thus, conjugation of RCAs, like Factor I, to nanoparticles is likely to help in nanomedicine&amp;rsquo;s long battle against complement, improving several key parameters critical for clinical success.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
