<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Muscle | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/muscle/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/muscle/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Muscle</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Muscle</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/muscle/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sphingolipids accumulate in aged muscle, and their reduction counteracts sarcopenia</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/22-12-25-18-47/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/22-12-25-18-47/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Age-related muscle dysfunction and sarcopenia are major causes of physical incapacitation in older adults and currently lack viable treatment strategies. Here we find that sphingolipids accumulate in mouse skeletal muscle upon aging and that both genetic and pharmacological inhibition of sphingolipid synthesis prevent age-related decline in muscle mass while enhancing strength and exercise capacity. Inhibition of sphingolipid synthesis confers increased myogenic potential and promotes protein synthesis. Within the sphingolipid pathway, we show that accumulation of dihydroceramides is the culprit disturbing myofibrillar homeostasis. The relevance of sphingolipid pathways in human aging is demonstrated in two cohorts, the UK Biobank and Helsinki Birth Cohort Study in which gene expression-reducing variants of &lt;em&gt;SPTLC1&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;DEGS1&lt;/em&gt; are associated with improved and reduced fitness of older individuals, respectively. These findings identify sphingolipid synthesis inhibition as an attractive therapeutic strategy for age-related sarcopenia and co-occurring pathologies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extracellular traps from activated vascular smooth muscle cells drive the progression of atherosclerosis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36473863/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36473863/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Extracellular DNA traps (ETs) represent an immune response by which cells release essential materials like chromatin and granular proteins. Previous studies have demonstrated that the transdifferentiation of vascular smooth muscle cells (VSMCs) plays a crucial role in atherosclerosis. This study seeks to investigate the interaction between CD68&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; VSMCs and the formation of ETs and highlight its function in atherosclerosis. Here we show that ETs are inhibited, and atherosclerotic plaque formation is alleviated in male Myh11&lt;sup&gt;Cre&lt;/sup&gt;Pad4&lt;sup&gt;flox/flox&lt;/sup&gt; mice undergoing an adeno-associated-virus-8 (AAV8) mediating overexpression of proprotein convertase subtilisin/kexin type 9 mutation (PCSK9) injection and being challenged with a high-fat diet. Obvious ETs generated from CD68&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; VSMCs are inhibited by Cl-amidine and DNase I in vitro. By utilizing VSMCs-lineage tracing technology and single-cell RNA sequencing (scRNA-seq), we demonstrate that the ETs from CD68&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; VSMCs influence the progress of atherosclerosis by regulating the direction of VSMCs&amp;rsquo; transdifferentiation through STING-SOCS1 or TLR4 signaling pathway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Proteome-wide systems genetics identifies UFMylation as a regulator of skeletal muscle function</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36472367/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36472367/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Improving muscle function has great potential to improve the quality of life. To identify novel regulators of skeletal muscle metabolism and function, we performed a proteomic analysis of gastrocnemius muscle from 73 genetically distinct inbred mouse strains, and integrated the data with previously acquired genomics and &amp;gt;300 molecular/phenotypic traits via quantitative trait loci mapping and correlation network analysis. These data identified thousands of associations between protein abundance and phenotypes and can be accessed online (&lt;a href=&#34;https://muscle.coffeeprot.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://muscle.coffeeprot.com/&lt;/a&gt;) to identify regulators of muscle function. We used this resource to prioritize targets for a functional genomic screen in human bioengineered skeletal muscle. This identified several negative regulators of muscle function including UFC1, an E2 ligase for protein UFMylation. We show UFMylation is up-regulated in a mouse model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis, a disease that involves muscle atrophy. Furthermore, in vivo knockdown of UFMylation increased contraction force, implicating its role as a negative regulator of skeletal muscle function.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
