<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Muscle | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/muscle/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/muscle/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Muscle</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Muscle</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/muscle/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Methyltransferase-like 3 suppresses phenotypic switching of vascular smooth muscle cells by activating autophagosome formation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36564367/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36564367/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prevention of neointima formation is the key to improving long-term outcomes after stenting or coronary artery bypass grafting. RNA N&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;-methyladenosine (m&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;A) methylation has been reported to be involved in the development of various cardiovascular diseases, but whether it has a regulatory effect on neointima formation is unknown. Herein, we revealed that methyltransferase-like 3 (METTL3), the major methyltransferase of m&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;A methylation, was downregulated during vascular smooth muscle cell (VSMC) proliferation and neointima formation. Knockdown of METTL3 facilitated, while overexpression of METTL3 suppressed the proliferation of human aortic smooth muscle cells (HASMCs) by arresting HASMCs at G2/M checkpoint and the phosphorylation of CDC2 (p-CDC2) was inactivated by METTL3. On the other hand, the migration and synthetic phenotype of HASMCs were enhanced by METTL3 knockdown, but inhibited by METTL3 overexpression. The protein levels of matrix metalloproteinase 2 (MMP2), MMP7 and MMP9 were reduced, while the expression level of tissue inhibitor of metalloproteinase 3 was increased in HASMCs with METTL3 overexpression. Moreover, METTL3 promoted the autophagosome formation by upregulating the expression of ATG5 (autophagy-related 5) and ATG7. Knockdown of either ATG5 or ATG7 largely reversed the regulatory effects of METTL3 overexpression on phenotypic switching of HASMCs, as evidenced by increased proliferation and migration, and predisposed to synthetic phenotype. These results indicate that METTL3 inhibits the phenotypic switching of VSMCs by positively regulating ATG5-mediated and ATG7-mediated autophagosome formation. Thus, enhancing the level of RNA m&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;A or the formation of autophagosomes is the promising strategy to delay neointima formation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sphingolipids accumulate in aged muscle, and their reduction counteracts sarcopenia</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/s43587-022-00309-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/s43587-022-00309-6/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Age-related muscle dysfunction and sarcopenia are major causes of physical incapacitation in older adults and currently lack viable treatment strategies. Here we find that sphingolipids accumulate in mouse skeletal muscle upon aging and that both genetic and pharmacological inhibition of sphingolipid synthesis prevent age-related decline in muscle mass while enhancing strength and exercise capacity. Inhibition of sphingolipid synthesis confers increased myogenic potential and promotes protein synthesis. Within the sphingolipid pathway, we show that accumulation of dihydroceramides is the culprit disturbing myofibrillar homeostasis. The relevance of sphingolipid pathways in human aging is demonstrated in two cohorts, the UK Biobank and Helsinki Birth Cohort Study in which gene expression-reducing variants of &lt;em&gt;SPTLC1&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;DEGS1&lt;/em&gt; are associated with improved and reduced fitness of older individuals, respectively. These findings identify sphingolipid synthesis inhibition as an attractive therapeutic strategy for age-related sarcopenia and co-occurring pathologies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extracellular traps from activated vascular smooth muscle cells drive the progression of atherosclerosis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36473863/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36473863/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Extracellular DNA traps (ETs) represent an immune response by which cells release essential materials like chromatin and granular proteins. Previous studies have demonstrated that the transdifferentiation of vascular smooth muscle cells (VSMCs) plays a crucial role in atherosclerosis. This study seeks to investigate the interaction between CD68&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; VSMCs and the formation of ETs and highlight its function in atherosclerosis. Here we show that ETs are inhibited, and atherosclerotic plaque formation is alleviated in male Myh11&lt;sup&gt;Cre&lt;/sup&gt;Pad4&lt;sup&gt;flox/flox&lt;/sup&gt; mice undergoing an adeno-associated-virus-8 (AAV8) mediating overexpression of proprotein convertase subtilisin/kexin type 9 mutation (PCSK9) injection and being challenged with a high-fat diet. Obvious ETs generated from CD68&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; VSMCs are inhibited by Cl-amidine and DNase I in vitro. By utilizing VSMCs-lineage tracing technology and single-cell RNA sequencing (scRNA-seq), we demonstrate that the ETs from CD68&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; VSMCs influence the progress of atherosclerosis by regulating the direction of VSMCs&amp;rsquo; transdifferentiation through STING-SOCS1 or TLR4 signaling pathway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Proteome-wide systems genetics identifies UFMylation as a regulator of skeletal muscle function</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36472367/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36472367/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Improving muscle function has great potential to improve the quality of life. To identify novel regulators of skeletal muscle metabolism and function, we performed a proteomic analysis of gastrocnemius muscle from 73 genetically distinct inbred mouse strains, and integrated the data with previously acquired genomics and &amp;gt;300 molecular/phenotypic traits via quantitative trait loci mapping and correlation network analysis. These data identified thousands of associations between protein abundance and phenotypes and can be accessed online (&lt;a href=&#34;https://muscle.coffeeprot.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://muscle.coffeeprot.com/&lt;/a&gt;) to identify regulators of muscle function. We used this resource to prioritize targets for a functional genomic screen in human bioengineered skeletal muscle. This identified several negative regulators of muscle function including UFC1, an E2 ligase for protein UFMylation. We show UFMylation is up-regulated in a mouse model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis, a disease that involves muscle atrophy. Furthermore, in vivo knockdown of UFMylation increased contraction force, implicating its role as a negative regulator of skeletal muscle function.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JMJD3 activated hyaluronan synthesis drives muscle regeneration in an inflammatory environment</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35926054/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35926054/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Muscle stem cells (MuSCs) reside in a specialized niche that ensures their regenerative capacity. Although we know that innate immune cells infiltrate the niche in response to injury, it remains unclear how MuSCs adapt to this altered environment for initiating repair. Here, we demonstrate that inflammatory cytokine signaling from the regenerative niche impairs the ability of quiescent MuSCs to reenter the cell cycle. The histone H3 lysine 27 (H3K27) demethylase JMJD3, but not UTX, allowed MuSCs to overcome inhibitory inflammation signaling by removing trimethylated H3K27 (H3K27me3) marks at the Has2 locus to initiate production of hyaluronic acid, which in turn established an extracellular matrix competent for integrating signals that direct MuSCs to exit quiescence. Thus, JMJD3-driven hyaluronic acid synthesis plays a proregenerative role that allows MuSC adaptation to inflammation and the initiation of muscle repair.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lockd promotes myoblast proliferation and muscle regeneration via binding with DHX36 to facilitate 5&#39; UTR rG4 unwinding and Anp32e translation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35675771/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35675771/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Lockd&lt;/em&gt; is highly induced in activated satellite cells and promotes cell proliferation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Lockd&lt;/em&gt; interacts with DHX36 and regulates the translation of DHX36-bound mRNAs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Lockd&lt;/em&gt;/DHX36 regulate &lt;em&gt;Anp32e&lt;/em&gt; translation via modulating the 5′ UTR rG4 structure&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Lockd&lt;/em&gt; stabilizes the interaction of DHX36 and EIF3B proteins&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adult muscle stem cells, also known as satellite cells (SCs), play pivotal roles in muscle regeneration, and long non-coding RNA (lncRNA) functions in SCs remain largely unknown. Here, we identify a lncRNA, &lt;em&gt;Lockd&lt;/em&gt;, which is induced in activated SCs upon acute muscle injury. We demonstrate that &lt;em&gt;Lockd&lt;/em&gt; promotes SC proliferation; deletion of &lt;em&gt;Lockd&lt;/em&gt; leads to cell-cycle arrest, and &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt; repression of &lt;em&gt;Lockd&lt;/em&gt; in mouse muscles hinders regeneration process. Mechanistically, we show that &lt;em&gt;Lockd&lt;/em&gt; directly interacts with RNA helicase DHX36 and the 5&amp;rsquo;end of &lt;em&gt;Lockd&lt;/em&gt; possesses the strongest binding with DHX36. Furthermore, we demonstrate that &lt;em&gt;Lockd&lt;/em&gt; stabilizes the interaction between DHX36 and EIF3B proteins; synergistically, this complex unwinds the RNA G-quadruplex (rG4) structure formed at &lt;em&gt;Anp32e&lt;/em&gt; mRNA 5&amp;rsquo; UTR and promotes the translation of ANP32E protein, which is required for myoblast proliferation. Altogether, our findings identify a regulatory &lt;em&gt;Lockd&lt;/em&gt;/DHX36/Anp32e axis that promotes myoblast proliferation and acute-injury-induced muscle regeneration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HCMV-miR-US33-5p promotes apoptosis of aortic vascular smooth muscle cells by targeting EPAS1/SLC3A2 pathway</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35596131/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35596131/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; In patients with acute aortic dissection (AAD), increased vascular smooth muscle cell (VSMC) apoptosis has been found. Human cytomegalovirus (HCMV)-miR-US33-5p was significantly increased in the plasma of patients with AAD. However, the roles of miR-US33-5p in human aortic VSMC (HA-VSMC) apoptosis remain to be elucidated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; In the current study, cell apoptosis was analyzed by flow cytometry, cell proliferation by CCK-8 assay, and differentially expressed genes by RNA sequencing. Luciferase reporter assay was used for binding analysis between miR-US33-5p and endothelial PAS domain protein 1 (EPAS1), and EPAS1 and amino acid transporter heavy chain, member 2 (SLC3A2). The enrichment degree of SLC3A2 promoter DNA was analyzed by chromatin immunoprecipitation assay. Quantitative reverse-transcription polymerase chain reaction (qRT-PCR) and immunoblotting were performed for measuring messenger RNA (mRNA) and protein levels, respectively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; It was found that HCMV infection inhibited proliferation but promoted HA-VSMC apoptosis by upregulating HCMV-miR-US33-5p. Transfection of HCMV-miR-US33-5p mimics the significant effect on several signaling pathways including integrin signaling as shown in the RNA sequencing data. Western blotting analysis confirmed that HCMV-miR-US33-5p mimics suppression of the activity of key factors of the integrin signal pathway including FAK, AKT, CAS, and Rac. Mechanistic study showed that HCMV-miR-US33-5p bound to the 3&amp;rsquo;-untranslated region of EPAS1 to suppress its expression, leading to suppression of SLC3A2 expression, which ultimately promoted cell apoptosis and inhibited cell proliferation. This was confirmed by the findings that silencing EPAS1 significantly reduced the SLC3A2 expression and inhibited proliferation and key factors of integrin signal pathway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; HCMV-miR-US33-5p suppressed proliferation, key factors of integrin signal pathway, and EPAS1/SLC3A2 expression, but promoted HA-VSMC apoptosis. These findings highlighted the importance of HCMV-miR-US33-5p/EPAS1/SCL3A2 signaling and may provide new insights into therapeutic strategies for AAD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reduced Sarcolemmal Membrane Repair Exacerbates Striated Muscle Pathology in a Mouse Model of Duchenne Muscular Dystrophy</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35563723/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35563723/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Duchenne muscular dystrophy (DMD) is a common X-linked degenerative muscle disorder that involves mutations in the DMD gene that frequently reduce the expression of the dystrophin protein, compromising the structural integrity of the sarcolemmal membrane and leaving it vulnerable to injury during cycles of muscle contraction and relaxation. This results in an increased frequency of sarcolemma disruptions that can compromise the barrier function of the membrane and lead to death of the myocyte. Sarcolemmal membrane repair processes can potentially compensate for increased membrane disruptions in DMD myocytes. Previous studies demonstrated that TRIM72, a muscle-enriched tripartite motif (TRIM) family protein also known as mitsugumin 53 (MG53), is a component of the cell membrane repair machinery in striated muscle. To test the importance of membrane repair in striated muscle in compensating for the membrane fragility in DMD, we crossed TRIM72/MG53 knockout mice into the mdx mouse model of DMD. These double knockout (DKO) mice showed compromised sarcolemmal membrane integrity compared to mdx mice, as measured by immunoglobulin G staining and ex vivo muscle laser microscopy wounding assays. We also found a significant decrease in muscle ex vivo contractile function as compared to mdx mice at both 6 weeks and 1.5 years of age. As the DKO mice aged, they developed more extensive fibrosis in skeletal muscles compared to mdx. Our findings indicate that TRIM72/MG53-mediated membrane repair can partially compensate for the sarcolemmal fragility associated with DMD and that the loss of membrane repair results in increased pathology in the DKO mice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
