<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>AMPK/MAPK | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/ampk/mapk/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/ampk/mapk/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>AMPK/MAPK</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>AMPK/MAPK</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/ampk/mapk/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comparative whole-genome transcriptome analysis in renal cell populations reveals high tissue specificity of MAPK/ERK targets in embryonic kidney</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35550069/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35550069/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; MAPK/ERK signaling is a well-known mediator of extracellular stimuli controlling intracellular responses to growth factors and mechanical cues. The critical requirement of MAPK/ERK signaling for embryonic stem cell maintenance is demonstrated, but specific functions in progenitor regulation during embryonic development, and in particular kidney development remain largely unexplored. We previously demonstrated MAPK/ERK signaling as a key regulator of kidney growth through branching morphogenesis and normal nephrogenesis where it also regulates progenitor expansion. Here, we performed RNA sequencing-based whole-genome expression analysis to identify transcriptional MAPK/ERK targets in two distinct renal populations: the ureteric bud epithelium and the nephron progenitors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; Our analysis revealed a large number (5053) of differentially expressed genes (DEGs) in nephron progenitors and significantly less (1004) in ureteric bud epithelium, reflecting likely heterogenicity of cell types. The data analysis identified high tissue-specificity, as only a fraction (362) of MAPK/ERK targets are shared between the two tissues. Tissue-specific MAPK/ERK targets participate in the regulation of mitochondrial energy metabolism in nephron progenitors, which fail to maintain normal mitochondria numbers in the MAPK/ERK-deficient tissue. In the ureteric bud epithelium, a dramatic decline in progenitor-specific gene expression was detected with a simultaneous increase in differentiation-associated genes, which was not observed in nephron progenitors. Our experiments in the genetic model of MAPK/ERK deficiency provide evidence that MAPK/ERK signaling in the ureteric bud maintains epithelial cells in an undifferentiated state. Interestingly, the transcriptional targets shared between the two tissues studied are over-represented by histone genes, suggesting that MAPK/ERK signaling regulates cell cycle progression and stem cell maintenance through chromosome condensation and nucleosome assembly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; Using tissue-specific MAPK/ERK inactivation and RNA sequencing in combination with experimentation in embryonic kidneys, we demonstrate here that MAPK/ERK signaling maintains ureteric bud tip cells, suggesting a regulatory role in collecting duct progenitors. We additionally deliver new mechanistic information on how MAPK/ERK signaling regulates progenitor maintenance through its effects on chromatin accessibility and energy metabolism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hydnocarpin D attenuates lipopolysaccharide-induced acute lung injury via MAPK/NF-κB and Keap1/Nrf2/HO-1 pathway</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35537248/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35537248/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Acute lung injury (ALI) is a complex pulmonary destructive disease with limited therapeutic approaches. Hydnocarpin D (HD) is a flavonolignan isolated from Hydnocarpus wightiana which possesses antioxidant and anti-inflammatory properties. However, whether HD has beneficial effects on ALI as well as its underlying mechanism remains to be elucidated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Purpose:&lt;/em&gt; This study evaluated the protective effect of HD in ALI and the underlying molecular mechanisms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;In vivo&lt;/em&gt;, the role of HD on lipopolysaccharide (LPS)-induced ALI in mice was tested by determination of neutrophil infiltration, levels of inflammatory cytokines, lung histology and edema, vascular and alveolar barrier disruption. In vitro, murine macrophage RAW 264.7 cells were used to investigate the molecular mechanisms RESULTS: Administration of HD protected mice against LPS-induced ALI, including ameliorating the histological alterations in the lung tissues, and decreasing lung edema, protein content of bronchoalveolar lavage fluid, infiltration of inflammatory cell and secretion of cytokines. Moreover, HD blocked the phosphorylation of TLR-4, NF-κB, and ERK in LPS-induced lung injury. &lt;em&gt;In vitro&lt;/em&gt;, HD inhibited LPS-induced oxidative stress and inflammation in RAW 264.7 cells, which largely depend upon the upregulation of antioxidant defensive Nrf2 pathway, thereby suppressing LPS-activated proinflammatory mediator secretion, NLRP3 inflammasome, and MAPK/NF-κB signaling pathway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/em&gt; HD attenuates oxidative stress and inflammation against LPS-induced ALI via MAPK/NF-κB and Keap1/Nrf2/HO-1 pathway, and is a promising novel therapeutic candidate for ALI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Low-dose metformin targets the lysosomal AMPK pathway through PEN2</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35197629/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35197629/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Metformin, the most prescribed antidiabetic medicine, has shown other benefits such as anti-ageing and anticancer effects. For clinical doses of metformin, AMP-activated protein kinase (AMPK) has a major role in its mechanism of action; however, the direct molecular target of metformin remains unknown. Here we show that clinically relevant concentrations of metformin inhibit the lysosomal proton pump v-ATPase, which is a central node for AMPK activation following glucose starvation. We synthesize a photoactive metformin probe and identify PEN2, a subunit of γ-secretase, as a binding partner of metformin with a dissociation constant at micromolar levels. Metformin-bound PEN2 forms a complex with ATP6AP1, a subunit of the v-ATPase, which leads to the inhibition of v-ATPase and the activation of AMPK without effects on cellular AMP levels. Knockout of PEN2 or re-introduction of a PEN2 mutant that does not bind ATP6AP1 blunts AMPK activation. In vivo, liver-specific knockout of Pen2 abolishes metformin-mediated reduction of hepatic fat content, whereas intestine-specific knockout of Pen2 impairs its glucose-lowering effects. Furthermore, knockdown of pen-2 in Caenorhabditis elegans abrogates metformin-induced extension of lifespan. Together, these findings reveal that metformin binds PEN2 and initiates a signalling route that intersects, through ATP6AP1, the lysosomal glucose-sensing pathway for AMPK activation. This ensures that metformin exerts its therapeutic benefits in patients without substantial adverse effects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
