<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>AMPK/MAPK | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/ampk/mapk/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/ampk/mapk/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>AMPK/MAPK</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>AMPK/MAPK</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/ampk/mapk/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kirenol inhibits inflammation challenged by lipopolysaccharide through the AMPK-mTOR-ULK1 autophagy pathway</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36706589/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36706589/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kirenol is a bioactive substance isolated from &lt;em&gt;Herba Siegesbeckiae&lt;/em&gt;. Although the anti-inflammatory activity of kirenol has been well documented, its role in autophagy remains unknown. The present study aimed to investigate the protective role of kirenol on inflammation challenged by lipopolysaccharide (LPS) in acute lung injury (ALI) cell and mouse models and unravel the underlying mechanisms, with a particular focus on autophagy. For this purpose, an ALI cell and mouse models were established, and the effects of kirenol on the expression of molecules related to inflammation and autophagy were examined. The present results revealed that kirenol could significantly inhibit inflammatory cytokines secretion in cells and in the mice injured by LPS; this effect may be attributed to enhanced autophagy as evidenced by the up-regulation of LC3-II and the down-regulation of p62 both in vitro and in vivo. Phosphorylated AMPK and ULK1 increased, while phosphorylated mTOR decreased in the kirenol-treated ALI cell model. Moreover, inhibition of autophagy using AMPK inhibitor or 3-MA or chloroquine (CQ) reversed the anti-inflammatory and autophagy-enhancement effects of kirenol exposure in vitro, indicating that kirenol could enhance autophagy by activating the AMPK-mTOR-ULK1 pathway. The results of RNA sequencing suggested that kirenol was strongly related to the biological functions of acute inflammatory response and the AMPK signaling pathway. Further in vivo ALI mouse model studies demonstrated the protective role of kirenol against lung inflammation, such as improved histopathology, decreased lung edema, and leukocyte infiltration were abolished by 3-MA. These findings implicate that kirenol can inhibit LPS-induced inflammation via the AMPK-mTOR-ULK1 autophagy pathway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cytosolic DNA sensing by cGAS/STING promotes TRPV2-mediated Ca2&#43; release to protect stressed replication forks</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36696898/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36696898/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Replication stress induces TRPV2-mediated Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt; release from the ER&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;STING binds to and represses TRPV2 on the ER in the absence of replication stress&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cytosolic self-DNA-induced cGAMP promotes STING dissociation from TRPV2 and Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt; efflux&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Oncogene-induced replication stress also activates the Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt;-dependent fork protection&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The protection of DNA replication forks under stress is essential for genome maintenance and cancer suppression. One mechanism of fork protection involves an elevation in intracellular Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt; ([Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt;]&lt;sub&gt;i&lt;/sub&gt;), which in turn activates CaMKK2 and AMPK to prevent uncontrolled fork processing by Exo1. How replication stress triggers [Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt;]&lt;sub&gt;i&lt;/sub&gt; elevation is unclear. Here, we report a role of cytosolic self-DNA (cytosDNA) and the ion channel TRPV2 in [Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt;]&lt;sub&gt;i&lt;/sub&gt; induction and fork protection. Replication stress leads to the generation of ssDNA and dsDNA species that, upon translocation into cytoplasm, trigger the activation of the sensor protein cGAS and the production of cGAMP. The subsequent binding of cGAMP to STING causes its dissociation from TRPV2, leading to TRPV2 derepression and Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt; release from the ER, which in turn activates the downstream signaling cascade to prevent fork degradation. This Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt;-dependent genome protection pathway is also activated in response to replication stress caused by oncogene activation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gene set enrichment analysis: a knowledge-based approach for interpreting genome-wide expression profiles</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36693850/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36693850/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MAPK/JNK signaling is pivotal in carcinogenesis. However, ubiquitin-mediated homeostasis of JNK remains to be verified. Here, with results from RNA sequencing (RNA-seq) and luciferase reporter pathway identification, we show that USP14 orchestrates MAPK/JNK signaling and identify USP14 as a deubiquitinase that interacts and stabilizes JNK. USP14 is elevated in colorectal cancer patients and is positively associated with JNK protein and downstream gene expression. USP14 ablation reduces cancer cell proliferation in vitro and colorectal tumorigenesis in vivo by downregulating MAPK/JNK pathway activation. Moreover, USP14 expression is induced by TNF-α, forming a feedback loop with JNK and leading to tumor amplification. Our study suggests that elevated expression of USP14 promotes MAPK/JNK signaling by stabilizing JNK, which in turn augments colorectal carcinogenesis, indicating a potential therapeutic target for colorectal cancer patients with increased USP14 expression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comparative whole-genome transcriptome analysis in renal cell populations reveals high tissue specificity of MAPK/ERK targets in embryonic kidney</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35550069/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35550069/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; MAPK/ERK signaling is a well-known mediator of extracellular stimuli controlling intracellular responses to growth factors and mechanical cues. The critical requirement of MAPK/ERK signaling for embryonic stem cell maintenance is demonstrated, but specific functions in progenitor regulation during embryonic development, and in particular kidney development remain largely unexplored. We previously demonstrated MAPK/ERK signaling as a key regulator of kidney growth through branching morphogenesis and normal nephrogenesis where it also regulates progenitor expansion. Here, we performed RNA sequencing-based whole-genome expression analysis to identify transcriptional MAPK/ERK targets in two distinct renal populations: the ureteric bud epithelium and the nephron progenitors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; Our analysis revealed a large number (5053) of differentially expressed genes (DEGs) in nephron progenitors and significantly less (1004) in ureteric bud epithelium, reflecting likely heterogenicity of cell types. The data analysis identified high tissue-specificity, as only a fraction (362) of MAPK/ERK targets are shared between the two tissues. Tissue-specific MAPK/ERK targets participate in the regulation of mitochondrial energy metabolism in nephron progenitors, which fail to maintain normal mitochondria numbers in the MAPK/ERK-deficient tissue. In the ureteric bud epithelium, a dramatic decline in progenitor-specific gene expression was detected with a simultaneous increase in differentiation-associated genes, which was not observed in nephron progenitors. Our experiments in the genetic model of MAPK/ERK deficiency provide evidence that MAPK/ERK signaling in the ureteric bud maintains epithelial cells in an undifferentiated state. Interestingly, the transcriptional targets shared between the two tissues studied are over-represented by histone genes, suggesting that MAPK/ERK signaling regulates cell cycle progression and stem cell maintenance through chromosome condensation and nucleosome assembly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; Using tissue-specific MAPK/ERK inactivation and RNA sequencing in combination with experimentation in embryonic kidneys, we demonstrate here that MAPK/ERK signaling maintains ureteric bud tip cells, suggesting a regulatory role in collecting duct progenitors. We additionally deliver new mechanistic information on how MAPK/ERK signaling regulates progenitor maintenance through its effects on chromatin accessibility and energy metabolism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hydnocarpin D attenuates lipopolysaccharide-induced acute lung injury via MAPK/NF-κB and Keap1/Nrf2/HO-1 pathway</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35537248/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35537248/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Acute lung injury (ALI) is a complex pulmonary destructive disease with limited therapeutic approaches. Hydnocarpin D (HD) is a flavonolignan isolated from Hydnocarpus wightiana which possesses antioxidant and anti-inflammatory properties. However, whether HD has beneficial effects on ALI as well as its underlying mechanism remains to be elucidated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Purpose:&lt;/em&gt; This study evaluated the protective effect of HD in ALI and the underlying molecular mechanisms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;In vivo&lt;/em&gt;, the role of HD on lipopolysaccharide (LPS)-induced ALI in mice was tested by determination of neutrophil infiltration, levels of inflammatory cytokines, lung histology and edema, vascular and alveolar barrier disruption. In vitro, murine macrophage RAW 264.7 cells were used to investigate the molecular mechanisms RESULTS: Administration of HD protected mice against LPS-induced ALI, including ameliorating the histological alterations in the lung tissues, and decreasing lung edema, protein content of bronchoalveolar lavage fluid, infiltration of inflammatory cell and secretion of cytokines. Moreover, HD blocked the phosphorylation of TLR-4, NF-κB, and ERK in LPS-induced lung injury. &lt;em&gt;In vitro&lt;/em&gt;, HD inhibited LPS-induced oxidative stress and inflammation in RAW 264.7 cells, which largely depend upon the upregulation of antioxidant defensive Nrf2 pathway, thereby suppressing LPS-activated proinflammatory mediator secretion, NLRP3 inflammasome, and MAPK/NF-κB signaling pathway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/em&gt; HD attenuates oxidative stress and inflammation against LPS-induced ALI via MAPK/NF-κB and Keap1/Nrf2/HO-1 pathway, and is a promising novel therapeutic candidate for ALI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Activation of AMPK/NRF2 Pathway in Lung Epithelial Cells Is Involved in the Protective Effects of Kinsenoside on Lipopolysaccharide-Induced Acute Lung Injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35340214/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35340214/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The disorder of mitochondrial dynamic equilibrium of lung epithelial cell is one of the critical causes of acute lung injury (ALI). Kinsenoside (Kin) serves as an active small-molecule component derived from traditional medicinal herb displaying multiple pharmacological actions in cancers, hyperglycemia, and liver disease. The objective of this study was to investigate the effects of Kin on lipopolysaccharide- (LPS-) induced ALI and further explore possible molecular mechanisms. Kin was administered orally (100 mg/kg/day) for 7 consecutive days before LPS instillation (5 mg/kg). After 12 hours, pathological injury, inflammatory response, and oxidative stress were detected. The results demonstrated that Kin significantly alleviated lung pathological injury and decreased the infiltration of inflammatory cells and the release of inflammatory mediators in bronchoalveolar lavage fluid (BALF), apart from inhibiting the production of reactive oxygen species (ROS) and lipid peroxidation. Meanwhile, Kin also promoted mitochondrial fusion and restrained mitochondrial fission in mice with ALI. In terms of mechanism, Kin pretreatment increased the phosphorylation of AMP-activated protein kinase (AMPK) and the protein level of nuclear factor erythroid 2-related factor 2 (NRF2). In &lt;em&gt;Ampk-α&lt;/em&gt; knockout mice challenged with LPS, Kin lost its pulmonary protective effects, accompanied by lower NRF2 level. &lt;em&gt;In vitro&lt;/em&gt; experiments further unveiled that either AMPK inhibition by Compound C or NRF2 knockdown by siRNA abolished the protective roles of Kin in LPS-treated A549 lung epithelial cells. And NRF2 activator TAT-14 could reverse the effects of &lt;em&gt;Ampk-α&lt;/em&gt; deficiency. In conclusion, Kin possesses the ability to prevent LPS-induced ALI by modulating mitochondrial dynamic equilibrium in lung epithelial cell in an AMPK/NRF2-dependent manner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TIGAR drives colorectal cancer ferroptosis resistance through ROS/AMPK/SCD1 pathway</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35271998/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35271998/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Colorectal cancer (CRC) is the third most commonly diagnosed malignancy and major cause of cancer death in the world. Ferroptosis is a recently identified type of regulated cell death. Increasing evidence has shown that ferroptosis plays an important regulatory role in the occurrence and development of cancer. This study identified TIGAR as a potential regulator of ferroptosis resistance in the development of CRC. We showed that TIGAR expression in CRC tissues is significantly higher than that in adjacent normal tissues. Knockdown of TIGAR significantly caused an increase in erastin-induced ferroptosis in SW620 and HCT116 cells. Notably, knockdown of TIGAR significantly decreased GSH/GSSG ratio, increased lipid peroxidation production, and facilitated the accumulation of lipid peroxidation product malondialdehyde (MDA), and rendered CRC cells more sensitive to erastin induced ferroptosis. Furthermore, TIGAR inhibition repressed SCD1 expression in a redox and AMPK-dependent manner. Thus, these results suggest that TIGAR induces ferroptosis resistance in CRC cells via the ROS/AMPK/SCD1 signaling pathway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Low-dose metformin targets the lysosomal AMPK pathway through PEN2</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35197629/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35197629/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Metformin, the most prescribed antidiabetic medicine, has shown other benefits such as anti-ageing and anticancer effects. For clinical doses of metformin, AMP-activated protein kinase (AMPK) has a major role in its mechanism of action; however, the direct molecular target of metformin remains unknown. Here we show that clinically relevant concentrations of metformin inhibit the lysosomal proton pump v-ATPase, which is a central node for AMPK activation following glucose starvation. We synthesize a photoactive metformin probe and identify PEN2, a subunit of γ-secretase, as a binding partner of metformin with a dissociation constant at micromolar levels. Metformin-bound PEN2 forms a complex with ATP6AP1, a subunit of the v-ATPase, which leads to the inhibition of v-ATPase and the activation of AMPK without effects on cellular AMP levels. Knockout of PEN2 or re-introduction of a PEN2 mutant that does not bind ATP6AP1 blunts AMPK activation. In vivo, liver-specific knockout of Pen2 abolishes metformin-mediated reduction of hepatic fat content, whereas intestine-specific knockout of Pen2 impairs its glucose-lowering effects. Furthermore, knockdown of pen-2 in Caenorhabditis elegans abrogates metformin-induced extension of lifespan. Together, these findings reveal that metformin binds PEN2 and initiates a signalling route that intersects, through ATP6AP1, the lysosomal glucose-sensing pathway for AMPK activation. This ensures that metformin exerts its therapeutic benefits in patients without substantial adverse effects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Buformin alleviates sepsis-induced acute lung injury via inhibiting NLRP3-mediated pyroptosis through an AMPK-dependent pathway</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35132999/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35132999/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; NOD-like receptor family pyrin domain containing 3 (NLRP3)-mediated macrophage pyroptosis plays an important role in sepsis-induced acute lung injury (ALI). Inhibition of pyroptosis may be a way to alleviate inflammation as well as tissue damage triggered after lipopolysaccharide (LPS) stimulation. The aim of the present study was to explore whether buformin (BF), a hypoglycemic agent, could alleviate sepsis-induced ALI by inhibiting pyroptosis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; Wildtype C57BL/6 mice were randomly divided into control group, BF group, LPS group and LPS+BF group. BF group and LPS+BF group were pretreated with BF at a dose of 25 mg/kg, and the changes were observed. In addition, BF was used to interfere with THP-1 cells. The therapeutic effect of BF has been verified by intraperitoneal injection of BF in vivo after LPS stimulation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; Inflammation and injury was significantly reduced in BF pretreated mice, and the indexes related to pyroptosis were suppressed. The phosphorylation of AMP-activated protein kinase (AMPK) in lung tissues of mice in the BF and LPS+BF groups was significantly higher. In THP-1 cells, the AMPK inhibitor, Compound C was added to demonstrate that BF worked via AMPK to inhibit NLRP3 inflammasome. It was further demonstrated that BF up-regulated autophagy, which in turn promoted NLRP3 inflammasome degradation. On the other hand, BF decreased NLRP3 mRNA level by increasing nuclear factor-erythroid 2 related factor 2 (Nrf2). And BF showed a therapeutic effect after LPS challenge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/em&gt; Our study confirmed that BF inhibited NLRP3-mediated pyroptosis in sepsis-induced ALI by up-regulating autophagy and Nrf2 protein level through an AMPK-dependent pathway. This provides a new strategy for clinical mitigation of sepsis-induced ALI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nanocurcumin Potently Inhibits SARS-CoV-2 Spike Protein-Induced Cytokine Storm by Deactivation of MAPK/NF-κB Signaling in Epithelial Cells</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35112841/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35112841/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interleukin-mediated deep cytokine storm, an aggressive inflammatory response to SARS-CoV-2 virus infection in COVID-19 patients, is correlated directly with lung injury, multi-organ failure, and poor prognosis of severe COVID-19 patients. Curcumin (CUR), a phenolic antioxidant compound obtained from turmeric (&lt;em&gt;Curcuma longa L.&lt;/em&gt;), is well-known for its strong anti-inflammatory activity. However, its &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt; efficacy is constrained due to poor bioavailability. Herein, we report that CUR-encapsulated polysaccharide nanoparticles (CUR-PS-NPs) potently inhibit the release of cytokines, chemokines, and growth factors associated with damage of SARS-CoV-2 spike protein (CoV2-SP)-stimulated liver Huh7.5 and lung A549 epithelial cells. Treatment with CUR-PS-NPs effectively attenuated the interaction of ACE2 and CoV2-SP. The effects of CUR-PS-NPs were linked to reduced NF-κB/MAPK signaling which in turn decreased CoV2-SP-mediated phosphorylation of p38 MAPK, p42/44 MAPK, and p65/NF-κB as well as nuclear p65/NF-κB expression. The findings of the study strongly indicate that organic NPs of CUR can be used to control hyper-inflammatory responses and prevent lung and liver injuries associated with CoV2-SP-mediated cytokine storm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A novel nordihydroguaiaretic acid analog, compound 3a, alleviates acute lung injury by exerting antiapoptotic and antiinflammatory effects</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35085517/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35085517/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acute lung injury (ALI) is a continuum of pulmonary changes caused by various lung insults. Previously, we synthesized a series of nordihydroguaiaretic acid analogs; of these, compound 3a exhibited excellent antioxidant capacity in a murine model of middle cerebral artery occlusion. However, it remains unclear whether compound 3a can modulate lipopolysaccharide (LPS)-induced ALI. ALI was induced via tracheal LPS administration, and the pathological changes were assessed. The level of inflammation was verified by immunofluorescence and immunohistochemical analyses. Apoptosis was measured by terminal deoxynucleotidyl transferase dUTP nick-end labeling assays and Western blotting. Changes in the levels of mitogen-activated protein kinase (MAPK)/nuclear factor-κB (NF-κB) pathway proteins were assessed by immunofluorescence assays and Western blotting. In vitro, RAW 264.7 cells were treated with compound 3a prior to LPS challenge, and the intracellular level of inflammation was assessed by quantitative PCR (qPCR). Relevant proteins were detected via immunofluorescence assays and Western blotting. Mice developed extensive lung inflammation by 24 h after LPS challenge. Histological examination revealed signs typical of ALI. Preadministration of compound 3a markedly ameliorated the histopathological changes and reduced fluid exudation into the alveolar space. Compound 3a also greatly reduced the levels of inflammation and apoptosis both in vivo and in vitro. Moreover, compound 3a markedly reduced phosphorylation of MAPK/NF-κB pathway-related proteins and p65 translocation, consistent with the in vitro observations. In summary, administration of compound 3a prior to LPS suppressed ALI via inhibition of the MAPK/NF-κB pathway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The dynamic interplay between AMPK/NFκB signaling and NLRP3 is a new therapeutic target in inflammation: Emerging role of dapagliflozin in overcoming lipopolysaccharide-mediated lung injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35032769/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35032769/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;AMPK/NFκB and NLRP3 interplay is a new therapeutic target in inflammation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dapagliflozin mitigated lipopolysaccharide-mediated lung injury.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dapagliflozin anti-inflammatory effects were mediated through AMPK/NFĸB regulation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dapagliflozin inhibited NLRP3 inflammasome and caspase-1 activity.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acute lung injury (ALI) is one the most common causes of morbidity and mortality in critically ill patients. In this study, we examined for first time the role of dapagliflozin (DPGZ) in lipopolysaccharide (LPS)-induced ALI in rats and determined the underlying molecular mechanisms by evaluating the effects of DPGZ on adenosine monophosphate kinase (AMPK), nuclear transcription factor kappa B, nucleotide-binding and oligomerization domain-like receptor 3 inflammasome activation. Treatment of acute lung injured rats with either low dose (5 mg/kg) or high dose (10 mg/kg) DPGZ significantly decreased oxidative stress by decreasing malondialdehyde and nitric oxide tissue levels with a significant increase in spectrophotometric measurements of superoxide dismutase, catalase, and reduced glutathione levels. DPGZ treatment resulted in a significant anti-inflammatory effect as indicated by suppression in myeloperoxidase activity, MCP-1, IL-1β, IL-18, and TNF-α levels. DPGZ treatment also increased p-AMPK/t-AMPK with a significant reduction in NF-kB P65 binding activity and NFĸB p65 (pSer536) levels. These effects of DPGZ were accompanied by a significant reduction in NLRP3 levels and NLRP3 gene expression and a significant decrease in caspase-1 activity, which were also confirmed by histopathological examinations. We conclude that DPGZ antioxidant and anti-inflammatory activity may occur through regulation of AMPK/NFĸB pathway and inhibition of NLRP3 activation. These results suggest that DPGZ represents a promising intervention for the treatment of ALI, particularly in patients with type 2 diabetes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ATXN2-mediated translation of TNFR1 promotes esophageal squamous cell carcinoma via m6A-dependent manner</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34995801/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34995801/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;N&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;-methyladenosine (m&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;A) is the most prevalent RNA modification, and the effect of its dysregulation on esophageal squamous cell carcinoma (ESCC) development remains unclear. Here, by performing transcriptome-wide m&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;A sequencing in 16 ESCC tissue samples, we identified the key roles of m&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;A in TNFRSF1A (also known as TNFR1)-mediated MAPK and NF-κB activation in ESCC. Mechanistically, a functional protein involved in m&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;A methylation, ATXN2, is identified that augments the translation of TNFRSF1A by binding to m&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;A-modified TNFRSF1A mRNA. Upregulation of the TNFRSF1A protein level, a vital upstream switch for TNFRSF1A-mediated signaling events, activates the NF-κB and MAPK pathways and thus promotes ESCC development. Furthermore, TNFRSF1A m&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;A modifications and protein levels are upregulated in ESCC, and high levels of TNFRSF1A m&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;A and protein are correlated with poor ESCC patient survival. These results collectively indicate that the m&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;A-TNFRSF1A axis is critical for ESCC development and thus may serve as a potential druggable target.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Astragaloside IV pre-treatment attenuates PM2.5-induced lung injury in rats: Impact on autophagy, apoptosis and inflammation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35026504/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35026504/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Autophagy flux inhibition is a critical mechanism of PM2.5-induced lung toxicity in rats.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PM2.5 triggered pulmonary inflammation by tipping the balance between autophagy and apoptosis.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Astragaloside IV increased autophagic flux and inhibited apoptosis and inflammation by activation of the AMPK/mTOR signaling pathway in a PM2.5-induced rat lung toxicity model.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Fine particulate matter (PM2.5) with an aerodynamic diameter of less than 2.5 μm, exerts serious lung toxicity. At present, effective prevention measures and treatment modalities for pulmonary toxicity caused by PM2.5 are lacking. Astragaloside IV (AS-IV) is a natural product that has received increasing attention from researchers for its unique biological functions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Purpose:&lt;/em&gt; To investigate the protective effects of AS-IV on PM2.5-induced pulmonary toxicity and identify its potential mechanisms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; The rat model of PM2.5-induced lung toxicity was created by intratracheal instillation of PM2.5 dust suspension. The investigation was performed with AS-IV or in combination with autophagic flux inhibitor (Chloroquine) or AMP-sensitive protein kinase (AMPK)-specific inhibitor (Compound C). Apoptosis was detected by terminal deoxy-nucleotidyl transferase dUTP nick end labeling (TUNEL) and western blotting. Autophagy was detected by immunofluorescence staining, autophagic flux measurement, western blotting, and transmission electron microscopy. The AMPK/mTOR pathway was analyzed by western blotting. Inflammation was analyzed by western blotting and suspension array.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; AS-IV prevented histopathological injury, inflammation, autophagy dysfunction, apoptosis, and changes in AMPK levels induced by PM2.5. AS-IV increased autophagic flux and inhibited apoptosis and inflammation by activating the AMPK/ mammalian target of rapamycin (mTOR) pathway. However, AS-IV had no protective effect on PM2.5-induced lung injury following treatment with Compound C or Chloroquine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/em&gt; AS-IV prevented PM2.5-induced lung toxicity by restoring the balance among autophagy, apoptosis, and inflammation in rats by activating the AMPK/mTOR signaling pathway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the molecular mechanisms of the inhibition of acrolein-induced BEAS-2B cytotoxicity by luteolin using network pharmacology and cell biology technology</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34958803/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34958803/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acrolein is a highly reactive unsaturated hazardous air pollutant, which is extremely irritating to the respiratory tract. Luteolin, an active flavonoid compound, possesses multiple biological activities. The purpose of this study was to evaluate the mechanism of the inhibition of acrolein-induced human bronchial epithelial (BEAS-2B) cells cytotoxicity by luteolin using network pharmacology and cell biology technology. Firstly, network pharmacology results indicated that oxidative stress processes might play an important role in luteolin inhibiting lung injury. Next, it was verified at the cellular level. Reactive oxygen species (ROS) generation increased, glutathione (GSH) level decreased after exposure to acrolein. MAPK signaling pathways were activated, which activated downstream IκBα/NF-κB signaling pathways. Meanwhile, acrolein caused oxidative DNA damage and double-strand breaks, induced DNA damage response (DDR) and apoptosis. These adverse effects were significantly reversed by luteolin, which inhibited the activation of MAPK/IκBα/NF-κB and DDR pathways, and reduced the ratio of Bax/Bcl-2. Moreover, luteolin also had a similar effect to antioxidant N-acetyl cysteine (NAC) in the regulation of signaling transduction mechanisms, which indicated that the regulation of oxidative stress played an important role in the process. These results provide an experimental basis for elucidating the molecular mechanisms of the inhibition of acrolein-induced BEAS-2B cytotoxicity with luteolin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Protective effect of pteryxin on LPS-induced acute lung injury via modulating MAPK/NF-κB pathway and NLRP3 inflammasome activation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34942323/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34942323/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ethnopharmacological relevance:&lt;/em&gt; Peucedanum praeruptorum seed root is a common medicinal herb with antipyretic, expectorant, antitussive, and therapeutic effects against bronchitis and furuncle. The roots of this herb contain many coumarin compounds, including pteryxin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Aim of this study:&lt;/em&gt; To investigate whether pteryxin can alleviate the LPS-induced lung injury and the mechanism involved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Material and methods:&lt;/em&gt; Male BALB/C mice were orally given sodium carboxymethylcellulose (CMC-Na) (0.5%, 1mL/100g) and pteryxin (suspended in CMC-Na; 0.5%) at 5, 10, 25 mg/kg once daily for 7 days. Subsequently, the mice received a single intratracheal instillation of 5 mg/kg LPS or saline as the control. After 8 hours, the mice were sacrificed to collect bronchoalveolar lavage fluid (BALF) and lung tissues. These samples were used to determine the lung W/D (wet/dry) weight ratio, total protein (TP) levels, inflammatory cytokines (IL-6, TNF-α, and IL-1β) and expression of protein involved in MAPK/NF-κB pathway and NLRP3 inflammasome. H&amp;amp;E staining was carried out on tissue sections to explore the pathological alterations induced by LPS. The protein expression of F4/80 and NLRP3 in lung tissues was analyzed using immunohistochemical staining. The binding of pteryxin to target proteins (MAPK, NF-κB and NLRP3) was determined based on molecular docking tests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; Treatment with pteryxin reduced the lung W/D weight ratio, total protein (TP) level and levels of inflammatory cytokines (TNFα, IL-6 and IL-1 β) significantly. Therefore, it ameliorated LPS-induced inflammatory response in BALB/C mice. Moreover, pteryxin suppressed LPS-induced upregulation of proteins involved in MAPK/NF-κB signaling pathway and NLRP3 inflammasome activation. The expression level of F4/80 and NLRP3 was also downregulated by pteryxin pretreatment in lung tissues. Docking analysis revealed that pteryxin bound to target proteins (MAPK, NF- κB and NLRP3) with a fit-well pattern .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/em&gt; Pteryxin may attenuate LPS-induced acute lung injury by dampening MAPK/NF-κB signaling and NLRP 3 inflammasome activation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LncEDCH1 improves mitochondrial function to reduce muscle atrophy by interacting with SERCA2</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35024244/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35024244/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Skeletal muscle is a regulator of the body&amp;rsquo;s energy expenditure and metabolism. Abnormal regulation of skeletal muscle-specific genes leads to various muscle diseases. Long non-coding RNAs (lncRNAs) have been demonstrated to play important roles in muscle growth and muscle atrophy. To explore the potential function of muscle-associated lncRNA, we analyzed our previous RNA-sequencing data and selected the lncRNA (&lt;em&gt;LncEDCH1&lt;/em&gt;) as the research object. In this study, we report that &lt;em&gt;LncEDCH1&lt;/em&gt; is specifically enriched in skeletal muscle, and its transcriptional activity is positively regulated by transcription factor SP1. &lt;em&gt;LncEDCH1&lt;/em&gt; regulates myoblast proliferation and differentiation &lt;em&gt;in vitro&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;em&gt;In vivo&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;LncEDCH1&lt;/em&gt; reduces intramuscular fat deposition, activates slow-twitch muscle phenotype, and inhibits muscle atrophy. Mechanistically, &lt;em&gt;LncEDCH1&lt;/em&gt; binds to sarcoplasmic/ER calcium ATPase 2 (SERCA2) protein to enhance SERCA2 protein stability and increase SERCA2 activity. Meanwhile, &lt;em&gt;LncEDCH1&lt;/em&gt; improves mitochondrial efficiency possibly through a SERCA2-mediated activation of the AMPK pathway. Our findings provide a strategy for using &lt;em&gt;LncEDCH1&lt;/em&gt; as an effective regulator for the treatment of muscle atrophy and energy metabolism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
