<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>AMPK/MAPK | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/ampk/mapk/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/ampk/mapk/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>AMPK/MAPK</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>AMPK/MAPK</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/ampk/mapk/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cytosolic DNA sensing by cGAS/STING promotes TRPV2-mediated Ca2&#43; release to protect stressed replication forks</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/23-01-25-15-54/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/23-01-25-15-54/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Replication stress induces TRPV2-mediated Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt; release from the ER&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;STING binds to and represses TRPV2 on the ER in the absence of replication stress&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cytosolic self-DNA-induced cGAMP promotes STING dissociation from TRPV2 and Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt; efflux&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Oncogene-induced replication stress also activates the Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt;-dependent fork protection&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The protection of DNA replication forks under stress is essential for genome maintenance and cancer suppression. One mechanism of fork protection involves an elevation in intracellular Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt; ([Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt;]&lt;sub&gt;i&lt;/sub&gt;), which in turn activates CaMKK2 and AMPK to prevent uncontrolled fork processing by Exo1. How replication stress triggers [Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt;]&lt;sub&gt;i&lt;/sub&gt; elevation is unclear. Here, we report a role of cytosolic self-DNA (cytosDNA) and the ion channel TRPV2 in [Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt;]&lt;sub&gt;i&lt;/sub&gt; induction and fork protection. Replication stress leads to the generation of ssDNA and dsDNA species that, upon translocation into cytoplasm, trigger the activation of the sensor protein cGAS and the production of cGAMP. The subsequent binding of cGAMP to STING causes its dissociation from TRPV2, leading to TRPV2 derepression and Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt; release from the ER, which in turn activates the downstream signaling cascade to prevent fork degradation. This Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt;-dependent genome protection pathway is also activated in response to replication stress caused by oncogene activation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gene set enrichment analysis: a knowledge-based approach for interpreting genome-wide expression profiles</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36693850/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36693850/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MAPK/JNK signaling is pivotal in carcinogenesis. However, ubiquitin-mediated homeostasis of JNK remains to be verified. Here, with results from RNA sequencing (RNA-seq) and luciferase reporter pathway identification, we show that USP14 orchestrates MAPK/JNK signaling and identify USP14 as a deubiquitinase that interacts and stabilizes JNK. USP14 is elevated in colorectal cancer patients and is positively associated with JNK protein and downstream gene expression. USP14 ablation reduces cancer cell proliferation in vitro and colorectal tumorigenesis in vivo by downregulating MAPK/JNK pathway activation. Moreover, USP14 expression is induced by TNF-α, forming a feedback loop with JNK and leading to tumor amplification. Our study suggests that elevated expression of USP14 promotes MAPK/JNK signaling by stabilizing JNK, which in turn augments colorectal carcinogenesis, indicating a potential therapeutic target for colorectal cancer patients with increased USP14 expression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comparative whole-genome transcriptome analysis in renal cell populations reveals high tissue specificity of MAPK/ERK targets in embryonic kidney</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35550069/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35550069/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; MAPK/ERK signaling is a well-known mediator of extracellular stimuli controlling intracellular responses to growth factors and mechanical cues. The critical requirement of MAPK/ERK signaling for embryonic stem cell maintenance is demonstrated, but specific functions in progenitor regulation during embryonic development, and in particular kidney development remain largely unexplored. We previously demonstrated MAPK/ERK signaling as a key regulator of kidney growth through branching morphogenesis and normal nephrogenesis where it also regulates progenitor expansion. Here, we performed RNA sequencing-based whole-genome expression analysis to identify transcriptional MAPK/ERK targets in two distinct renal populations: the ureteric bud epithelium and the nephron progenitors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; Our analysis revealed a large number (5053) of differentially expressed genes (DEGs) in nephron progenitors and significantly less (1004) in ureteric bud epithelium, reflecting likely heterogenicity of cell types. The data analysis identified high tissue-specificity, as only a fraction (362) of MAPK/ERK targets are shared between the two tissues. Tissue-specific MAPK/ERK targets participate in the regulation of mitochondrial energy metabolism in nephron progenitors, which fail to maintain normal mitochondria numbers in the MAPK/ERK-deficient tissue. In the ureteric bud epithelium, a dramatic decline in progenitor-specific gene expression was detected with a simultaneous increase in differentiation-associated genes, which was not observed in nephron progenitors. Our experiments in the genetic model of MAPK/ERK deficiency provide evidence that MAPK/ERK signaling in the ureteric bud maintains epithelial cells in an undifferentiated state. Interestingly, the transcriptional targets shared between the two tissues studied are over-represented by histone genes, suggesting that MAPK/ERK signaling regulates cell cycle progression and stem cell maintenance through chromosome condensation and nucleosome assembly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; Using tissue-specific MAPK/ERK inactivation and RNA sequencing in combination with experimentation in embryonic kidneys, we demonstrate here that MAPK/ERK signaling maintains ureteric bud tip cells, suggesting a regulatory role in collecting duct progenitors. We additionally deliver new mechanistic information on how MAPK/ERK signaling regulates progenitor maintenance through its effects on chromatin accessibility and energy metabolism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hydnocarpin D attenuates lipopolysaccharide-induced acute lung injury via MAPK/NF-κB and Keap1/Nrf2/HO-1 pathway</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35537248/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35537248/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Acute lung injury (ALI) is a complex pulmonary destructive disease with limited therapeutic approaches. Hydnocarpin D (HD) is a flavonolignan isolated from Hydnocarpus wightiana which possesses antioxidant and anti-inflammatory properties. However, whether HD has beneficial effects on ALI as well as its underlying mechanism remains to be elucidated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Purpose:&lt;/em&gt; This study evaluated the protective effect of HD in ALI and the underlying molecular mechanisms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;In vivo&lt;/em&gt;, the role of HD on lipopolysaccharide (LPS)-induced ALI in mice was tested by determination of neutrophil infiltration, levels of inflammatory cytokines, lung histology and edema, vascular and alveolar barrier disruption. In vitro, murine macrophage RAW 264.7 cells were used to investigate the molecular mechanisms RESULTS: Administration of HD protected mice against LPS-induced ALI, including ameliorating the histological alterations in the lung tissues, and decreasing lung edema, protein content of bronchoalveolar lavage fluid, infiltration of inflammatory cell and secretion of cytokines. Moreover, HD blocked the phosphorylation of TLR-4, NF-κB, and ERK in LPS-induced lung injury. &lt;em&gt;In vitro&lt;/em&gt;, HD inhibited LPS-induced oxidative stress and inflammation in RAW 264.7 cells, which largely depend upon the upregulation of antioxidant defensive Nrf2 pathway, thereby suppressing LPS-activated proinflammatory mediator secretion, NLRP3 inflammasome, and MAPK/NF-κB signaling pathway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/em&gt; HD attenuates oxidative stress and inflammation against LPS-induced ALI via MAPK/NF-κB and Keap1/Nrf2/HO-1 pathway, and is a promising novel therapeutic candidate for ALI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Activation of AMPK/NRF2 Pathway in Lung Epithelial Cells Is Involved in the Protective Effects of Kinsenoside on Lipopolysaccharide-Induced Acute Lung Injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35340214/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35340214/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The disorder of mitochondrial dynamic equilibrium of lung epithelial cell is one of the critical causes of acute lung injury (ALI). Kinsenoside (Kin) serves as an active small-molecule component derived from traditional medicinal herb displaying multiple pharmacological actions in cancers, hyperglycemia, and liver disease. The objective of this study was to investigate the effects of Kin on lipopolysaccharide- (LPS-) induced ALI and further explore possible molecular mechanisms. Kin was administered orally (100 mg/kg/day) for 7 consecutive days before LPS instillation (5 mg/kg). After 12 hours, pathological injury, inflammatory response, and oxidative stress were detected. The results demonstrated that Kin significantly alleviated lung pathological injury and decreased the infiltration of inflammatory cells and the release of inflammatory mediators in bronchoalveolar lavage fluid (BALF), apart from inhibiting the production of reactive oxygen species (ROS) and lipid peroxidation. Meanwhile, Kin also promoted mitochondrial fusion and restrained mitochondrial fission in mice with ALI. In terms of mechanism, Kin pretreatment increased the phosphorylation of AMP-activated protein kinase (AMPK) and the protein level of nuclear factor erythroid 2-related factor 2 (NRF2). In &lt;em&gt;Ampk-α&lt;/em&gt; knockout mice challenged with LPS, Kin lost its pulmonary protective effects, accompanied by lower NRF2 level. &lt;em&gt;In vitro&lt;/em&gt; experiments further unveiled that either AMPK inhibition by Compound C or NRF2 knockdown by siRNA abolished the protective roles of Kin in LPS-treated A549 lung epithelial cells. And NRF2 activator TAT-14 could reverse the effects of &lt;em&gt;Ampk-α&lt;/em&gt; deficiency. In conclusion, Kin possesses the ability to prevent LPS-induced ALI by modulating mitochondrial dynamic equilibrium in lung epithelial cell in an AMPK/NRF2-dependent manner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TIGAR drives colorectal cancer ferroptosis resistance through ROS/AMPK/SCD1 pathway</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35271998/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35271998/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Colorectal cancer (CRC) is the third most commonly diagnosed malignancy and major cause of cancer death in the world. Ferroptosis is a recently identified type of regulated cell death. Increasing evidence has shown that ferroptosis plays an important regulatory role in the occurrence and development of cancer. This study identified TIGAR as a potential regulator of ferroptosis resistance in the development of CRC. We showed that TIGAR expression in CRC tissues is significantly higher than that in adjacent normal tissues. Knockdown of TIGAR significantly caused an increase in erastin-induced ferroptosis in SW620 and HCT116 cells. Notably, knockdown of TIGAR significantly decreased GSH/GSSG ratio, increased lipid peroxidation production, and facilitated the accumulation of lipid peroxidation product malondialdehyde (MDA), and rendered CRC cells more sensitive to erastin induced ferroptosis. Furthermore, TIGAR inhibition repressed SCD1 expression in a redox and AMPK-dependent manner. Thus, these results suggest that TIGAR induces ferroptosis resistance in CRC cells via the ROS/AMPK/SCD1 signaling pathway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Low-dose metformin targets the lysosomal AMPK pathway through PEN2</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35197629/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35197629/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Metformin, the most prescribed antidiabetic medicine, has shown other benefits such as anti-ageing and anticancer effects. For clinical doses of metformin, AMP-activated protein kinase (AMPK) has a major role in its mechanism of action; however, the direct molecular target of metformin remains unknown. Here we show that clinically relevant concentrations of metformin inhibit the lysosomal proton pump v-ATPase, which is a central node for AMPK activation following glucose starvation. We synthesize a photoactive metformin probe and identify PEN2, a subunit of γ-secretase, as a binding partner of metformin with a dissociation constant at micromolar levels. Metformin-bound PEN2 forms a complex with ATP6AP1, a subunit of the v-ATPase, which leads to the inhibition of v-ATPase and the activation of AMPK without effects on cellular AMP levels. Knockout of PEN2 or re-introduction of a PEN2 mutant that does not bind ATP6AP1 blunts AMPK activation. In vivo, liver-specific knockout of Pen2 abolishes metformin-mediated reduction of hepatic fat content, whereas intestine-specific knockout of Pen2 impairs its glucose-lowering effects. Furthermore, knockdown of pen-2 in Caenorhabditis elegans abrogates metformin-induced extension of lifespan. Together, these findings reveal that metformin binds PEN2 and initiates a signalling route that intersects, through ATP6AP1, the lysosomal glucose-sensing pathway for AMPK activation. This ensures that metformin exerts its therapeutic benefits in patients without substantial adverse effects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
