<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Oxidative Stress | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/oxidative-stress/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/oxidative-stress/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Oxidative Stress</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Oxidative Stress</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/oxidative-stress/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nuclear SPHK2/S1P induces oxidative stress and NLRP3 inflammasome activation via promoting p53 acetylation in lipopolysaccharide-induced acute lung injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36653338/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36653338/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although genomewide RNA expression analysis has become a routine tool in biomedical research, extracting biological insight from such information remains a major challenge. Here, we describe a powerful analytical method called Gene Set Enrichment Analysis (GSEA) for interpreting gene expression data. The method derives its power by focusing on gene sets, that is, groups of genes that share common biological function, chromosomal location, or regulation. We demonstrate how GSEA yields insights into several cancer-related data sets, including leukemia and lung cancer. Notably, where single-gene analysis finds little similarity between two independent studies of patient survival in lung cancer, GSEA reveals many biological pathways in common. The GSEA method is embodied in a freely available software package, together with an initial database of 1,325 biologically defined gene sets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oxidative stress-triggered Wnt signaling perturbation characterizes the tipping point of lung adeno-to-squamous transdifferentiation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36627278/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36627278/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Lkb1&lt;/em&gt; deficiency confers the Kras-mutant lung cancer with strong plasticity and the potential for adeno-to-squamous transdifferentiation (AST). However, it remains largely unknown how &lt;em&gt;Lkb1&lt;/em&gt; deficiency dynamically regulates AST. Using the classical AST mouse model (&lt;em&gt;Kras&lt;sup&gt;LSL-G12D/+&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt;;&lt;em&gt;Lkb1&lt;sup&gt;flox/flox&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, KL), we here comprehensively analyze the temporal transcriptomic dynamics of lung tumors at different stages by dynamic network biomarker (DNB) and identify the tipping point at which the Wnt signaling is abruptly suppressed by the excessive accumulation of reactive oxygen species (ROS) through its downstream effector FOXO3A. Bidirectional genetic perturbation of the Wnt pathway using two different &lt;em&gt;Ctnnb1&lt;/em&gt; conditional knockout mouse strains confirms its essential role in the negative regulation of AST. Importantly, pharmacological activation of the Wnt pathway before but not after the tipping point inhibits squamous transdifferentiation, highlighting the irreversibility of AST after crossing the tipping point. Through comparative transcriptomic analyses of mouse and human tumors, we find that the lineage-specific transcription factors (TFs) of adenocarcinoma and squamous cell carcinoma form a &amp;ldquo;Yin-Yang&amp;rdquo; counteracting network. Interestingly, inactivation of the Wnt pathway preferentially suppresses the adenomatous lineage TF network and thus disrupts the &amp;ldquo;Yin-Yang&amp;rdquo; homeostasis to lean towards the squamous lineage, whereas ectopic expression of NKX2-1, an adenomatous lineage TF, significantly dampens such phenotypic transition accelerated by the Wnt pathway inactivation. The negative correlation between the Wnt pathway and AST is further observed in a large cohort of human lung adenosquamous carcinoma. Collectively, our study identifies the tipping point of AST and highlights an essential role of the ROS-Wnt axis in dynamically orchestrating the homeostasis between adeno- and squamous-specific TF networks at the AST tipping point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MiR-217-5p inhibits smog (PM2.5)-induced inflammation and oxidative stress response of mouse lung tissues and macrophages through targeting STAT1</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36040387/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36040387/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Objective:&lt;/em&gt; To explore the roles of macrophages&amp;rsquo; miR-217-5p in the process of PM2.5 induced acute lung injury.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; GEO database and KEGG pathway enrichment analysis as well as GSEA were used to predicted the miRNA and associated target signals. And then mice and RAW246.7 macrophages treated with PM2.5 to imitate PM2.5 induced acute lung injury environment and then transfected with miR-217-5p NC or miR-217-5p mimic. The levels of inflammatory factors TNF-α and anti-inflammatory factor IL-10 of mice serum were tested by ELISA. And the pathological changes and ROS level of mouse lung tissues were stained by HE and DHE staining. The proteins expression of phosphorylated-STAT1, total-STAT1, TNF-α, IFN-γ as well as p47, gp91, NOX4 in mice or RAW264.7 cells were tested by western blot or immunofluorescence of RAW264.7 cell slides.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; The results of bioinformatics analysis indicated the miR-217 as well as STAT1 were involved PM2.5 associated lung injury. After exposure to PM2.5, the decreased levels of serum TNF-α but not IL-10, consistent with reduced macrophages&amp;rsquo; accumulation as well as decreased ROS levels in lung tissues in miR-217-5p mimic group vs miR-217-5p NC group mice, and moreover, the protein expression levels of phosphorylated&amp;ndash;STAT1, total-STAT1, TNF-α, IFN-γ, p47, gp91 and NOX4 in mouse lung tissues and RTAW246.7 macrophages cells were all significantly reduced with miR-217-5p mimic administration. The above phenomena were reversed by specific STAT1-inhibitor HY-N8107.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; miR-217-5p suppressed the activated STAT1-signal induced inflammation and oxidative stress trigged by PM2.5 in macrophages and resulted in the decreased lung injure caused by PM2.5.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Urinary profile of PAHs and related compounds in women working in beauty salons</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36029813/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36029813/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;First survey of urinary PAHs, 1-OHP and TTMA levels in women working in beauty salons;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;High PAHs, 1-OHP and TTMA levels were detected in urine of beauticians after the work shift.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The urinary PAHs, 1-OHP and TTMA were correlated with “personal care products (PCPs) usage”.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some PAHs were associated with oxidative stress/kidney injury biomarkers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Beauty activities can be considered as a major source of PAHs, 1-OHP and TTMA exposures.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Polycyclic aromatic hydrocarbons (PAHs) are a group of chemical compounds which interest to human biological monitoring researches because of their potential carcinogenic, mutagenic, and teratogenic properties. However, the exposure of female beauticians to these contaminants is not well-reported. For biomonitoring of potential exposure of female cosmeticians to PAHs in beauty salons, urine samples were taken from cosmetologist women (n = 50.00) and housewives (n = 35.00) as the exposure group (EG) and control group (CG), respectively. Next, unmetabolized PAHs levels as well as the concentration of - 1-hydroxypyrene (1-OHP) were analyzed in these specimens. In addition, since benzene has some common source with PAHs, in this study t, t&amp;rsquo;-Muconic acid (TTMA) level was also determined as the metabolite and indicator of exposure to benzene. The results indicated a high detection frequency of the target compounds (PAHs, 1-OHP and TTMA) in the urine specimens of beauticians. The results also showed that there is a significant difference between the concentration of these pollutants in the urine specimens of the exposure and control groups. The median concentration of ΣPAHs, 1-OHP, and TTMA in the before exposure (BE) specimens collected from the exposure group were 337.42 ng/L, 593.92 ng/L, and 247.90 μg/L, respectively. However, a higher concentration of these contaminants was observed in the after exposure specimens with a median concentration of 423.29 ng/L, 745.03 ng/L, and 310.97 μg/L, respectively. In terms of contribution of PAHs compounds in total toxic equivalents, DahA, BaP, and IndP with 59.03, 28.73, and 2.86 % had the largest share. In this study, it was also observed that some kidney damage biomarkers as well as some oxidative stress injury biomarkers are positively and significantly correlated with the urinary values of ∑PAHs. Thus, it can be concluded that high health risks threaten the female beauticians regarding kidney injury and DNA oxidative stress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rhabdomyolysis-induced acute kidney injury and concomitant apoptosis induction via ROS-mediated ER stress is efficaciously counteracted by epigallocatechin gallate</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36028100/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36028100/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rhabdomyolysis induced acute kidney injury (RIAKI) is a life-threatening condition responsible for approximately 19-58% of AKI cases worldwide. We performed an intramuscular injection of glycerol (10 mL/kg) in male wistar rats to induce AKI. Epigallocatechin gallate (EGCG) was administered for 3 consecutive days to evaluate its protective effects. We observed significant downregulation in serum creatinine, blood urea nitrogen (BUN) and LDH at different time points on EGCG treatment groups in a dose-dependent manner. Similarly, H&amp;amp;E staining also revealed that EGCG was able to reduce the formation of damaged tubules and tubular necrosis which was prominently spread throughout the kidney tissue of glycerol treatment group. Concomitantly, we observed upregulated inflammation, ER stress and elevated oxidative stress in the glycerol treated group only, which was significantly normalized upon EGCG treatment in both in vitro and in vivo studies. The occurrence of apoptosis in kidney tubules was found to be relatively higher in glycerol treated group and H2O2 treated HEK-293 cells. The results obtained after EGCG treatment revealed a significant decrease in apoptotic cell population, which was further validated by immunofluorescence staining against p53 and comet assay in HEK-293 cells and p53 IHC in kidney tissues. Western blotting also revealed a systemic downregulation of intrinsic mitochondrial apoptotic pathway markers such as bax, bcl-2, pro and cleaved caspase 3, caspase 9 and PARP1. Additionally, the results for flow cytometry analysis and TUNEL assay corroborated apoptotic equilibrium. Conclusively, we reckon EGCG as a multi-therapeutic natural product that can be used the for treatment of AKI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Acadesine alleviates acute pancreatitis-related lung injury by mediating the barrier protective function of pulmonary microvascular endothelial cells</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35987144/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35987144/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pretreatment with acadesine shows therapeutic potential SAP-ALI in vivo and vitro.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Endothelial injury is critical for the initiation and progression of severe acute pancreatitis-related acute lung injury.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The beneficial effects of acadesine may involve reducing ROS accumulation and inhibiting apoptosis.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Acadesine inhibits the impairment of SAP-ALI by activating the AMPK/Nrf2 pathway.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Severe acute pancreatitis (SAP) is a condition characterized by highly fatal acute inflammation and is usually associated with multiple organ dysfunction syndrome. Acute lung injury (ALI) is the most common complications of SAP, which is the accelerator of other organ dysfunction caused by SAP and the primary cause of early death due to SAP. Acadesine, an adenosine analog and an AMPK activator, has been discovered to modulate glucose and lipid metabolism, and inhibit the production of pro-inflammatory cytokines and iNOS. However, its role in SAP-ALI and its mechanism remains unclear and need to be explored. Herein, we discovered that acadesine mitigated the generation of reactive oxygen species (ROS) in human pulmonary microvascular endothelial cells (HPMECs), alleviated apoptosis and recovered barrier integrity, thereby contributing to anti-inflammatory effects in vitro and in vivo. Moreover, Nrf2 deficiency partially eliminated the effects of acadesine-induced antioxidant effects and thus weakened the protective effects on cells and Nrf2-knockout (Nrf2&lt;Sup&gt;-/-&lt;/Sup&gt;) mice. This study demonstrates that acadesine attenuated SAP-ALI associated inflammation and tissue damage by modulating the Nrf2-dependent antioxidant pathway by triggering AMPK. These findings are of great significance for the treatment of SAP-related lung injury.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CuO-NPs-triggered heterophil extracellular traps exacerbate liver injury in chicks by promoting oxidative stress and inflammatory responses</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35962800/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35962800/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the widespread use of copper oxide nanoparticles (CuO-NPs), their potential toxicity to the environment and biological health has attracted close attention. Heterophil extracellular traps (HETs) are an innate immune mechanism of chicken heterophils against adverse stimuli, but excessive HETs cause damage. Here, we explored the effect and mechanism of CuO-NPs on HETs formation in vitro and further evaluated the potential role of HETs in chicken liver and kidney injury. Heterophils were exposed to 5, 10, and 20 µg/mL of CuO-NPs for 2 h. The results showed that CuO-NPs induced typical HETs formation, which was dependent on NADPH oxidase, P38 and extracellular regulated protein kinases (ERK&lt;sub&gt;1/2&lt;/sub&gt;) pathways, and glycolysis. In in vivo experiments, fluorescence microplate and morphological analysis showed that CuO-NPs elevated the level of HETs in chicken serum and caused liver and kidney damage. Meanwhile, CuO-NPs caused hepatic oxidative stress (MDA, SOD, CAT, and GSH-PX imbalance), and also induced an increase in mRNA expression of their inflammatory and apoptosis-related factors (IL-1β, IL-6, TNF-α, COX-2, iNOS, NLRP3, and Caspase-1, 3, 11). However, these results were significantly altered by DNase I (HETs degradation reagent). In conclusion, the present study demonstrates for the first time that CuO-NPs induce the formation of HETs and that HETs exacerbate pathological damage in chicken liver and kidney by promoting oxidative stress and inflammation, providing insights into immunotoxicity and potential prevention and treatment targets caused by CuO-NPs overexposure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Macrophage SAMSN1 protects against sepsis-induced acute lung injury in mice</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35981417/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35981417/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Objective:&lt;/em&gt; Inflammation and oxidative stress contribute to the progression of sepsis-induced acute lung injury (ALI). SAM domain, SH3 domain and nuclear localization signals 1 (SAMSN1) is a signaling adaptor protein, and mainly regulates inflammatory response of various immune cells. The present study generates macrophage-specific SAMSN1-knockout (Samsn1MKO) and SAMSN1-transgenic (Samsn1MTG) mice to investigate its role and mechanism in sepsis-induced ALI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;Samsn1&lt;sup&gt;MKO&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Samsn1&lt;sup&gt;MTG&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; mice were exposed to lipopolysaccharide (LPS) instillation or cecal ligation and puncture (CLP) surgery to induce sepsis-induced ALI. Bone marrow transplantation, cellular depletion and non-invasive adoptive transfer of bone marrow-derived macrophages (BMDMs) were performed to validate the role of macrophage SAMSN1 in sepsis-induced ALI in vivo. Meanwhile, BMDMs were isolated from Samsn1MKO or Samsn1MTG mice to further clarify the role of SAMSN1 in vitro.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; Macrophage SAMSN1 expression was increased in response to LPS stimulation, and negatively correlated with LPS-induced ALI in mice. Macrophage SAMSN1 deficiency exacerbated, while macrophage SAMSN1 overexpression ameliorated LPS-induced inflammation, oxidative stress and ALI in mice and in BMDMs. Mechanistically, we found that macrophage SAMSN1 overexpression prevented LPS-induced ALI though activating AMP-activated protein kinase α2 (AMPKα2) &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;in vitro&lt;/em&gt;. Further studies revealed that SAMSN1 directly bound to growth factor receptor bound protein 2-associated protein 1 (GAB1) to prevent its protein degradation, and subsequently enhanced protein kinase A (PKA)/AMPKα2 activation in a protein tyrosine phosphatase, non-receptor type 11 (PTPN11, also known as SHP2)-dependent manner. Moreover, we observed that macrophage SAMSN1 overexpression diminished CLP-induced ALI in mice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/em&gt; Our study documents the protective role of macrophage SAMSN1 against sepsis-induced inflammation, oxidative stress and ALI through activating AMPKα2 in a GAB1/SHP2/PKA pathway, and defines it as a promising biomarker and therapeutic target to treat sepsis-induced ALI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CircSV2b participates in oxidative stress regulation through miR-5107-5p-Foxk1-Akt1 axis in Parkinson&#39;s disease</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35973363/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35973363/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CircSV2b in serum exosomes can be used as a biomarker for the diagnosis of PD.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CircSV2b participates in the progress of PD through the ceRNA-Akt1 axis.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CircSV2b overexpression is neuroprotective by resisting oxidative stress injury.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Foxk1 can regulate Akt1 transcription.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a novel type of non-coding RNAs, covalently closed circular RNAs (circRNAs) are ubiquitously expressed in eukaryotes. Emerging studies have indicated that dysregulation of circRNAs was related to neurological diseases. However, the biogenesis, regulation, function, and mechanism of circRNAs in Parkinson&amp;rsquo;s disease (PD) remain largely unclear. In this study, thirty-three differentially expressed circRNAs (DECs) were detected by RNA-sequencing between the MPTP-induced PD mice model and the wild-type mice. Quantitative real-time PCR was used to determine the RNA level of DECs in the striatum (STR), substantia nigra pars compacta (SNpc), and serum exosomes, and it was found that circSV2b was downregulated in PD mice. Then, functional experiments in vivo were employed to explore the effect of circSV2b in PD. For the mechanism study, dual-luciferase reporter, fluorescence in situ hybridization (FISH), RNA immunoprecipitation (RIP), RNA pull-down, gene editing, and CUT &amp;amp; Tag were performed in vitro to confirm that circSV2b directly sponged miR-5107-5p and alleviated the suppression of the expression of the target gene Foxk1, and then positively regulated Akt1 transcription. In vivo, the mechanistic analysis demonstrated that circSV2b overexpression resisted oxidative stress damage through the ceRNA-Akt1 axis in PD models. Taken together, these findings suggested that the miR-5107-5p-Foxk1-Akt1 axis might serve as a key target of circSV2b overexpression in PD treatment, and highlighted the significant change of circSV2b in serum exosomes. Therefore, circSV2b might be a novel biomarker for the diagnosis and treatment of PD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Colchicine improves severe acute pancreatitis-induced acute lung injury by suppressing inflammation, apoptosis and oxidative stress in rats</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36076491/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36076491/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Inflammation, apoptosis and oxidative stress play critical roles in severe acute pancreatitis (SAP).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Colchicine (COL) mitigates severe acute pancreatitis-associated lung injury (SAP-ALI) in rats model.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Colchicine limits inflammation, apoptosis and oxidative stress in SAP-ALI.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Inflammation, apoptosis and oxidative stress contribute to the development of severe acute pancreatitis-associated acute lung injury (SAP-ALI). Currently, there is no curative treatment for SAP-ALI in the clinic. This study investigated the potential therapeutic role and mechanisms of colchicine in a rat model of SAP-ALI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; Male Sprague-Dawley rats were randomized and administrated intragastrically with vehicle saline or colchicine (0.5 mg/kg/day) for seven days, followed by injecting sodium taurocholate to induce SAP-ALI. Together with a healthy control group of rats, their pancreatic and lung tissues and plasma samples were collected for histology, enzyme-linked immunosorbent assay (ELISA), immunoblot, immunohistochemistry, and immunofluorescence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; Compared with the sham controls, the SAP group of rats with vehicle saline treatment displayed severe damages, inflammation with many neutrophil and macrophage infiltrates in pancreatic and lung tissues, accompanied by elevated levels of plasma interleukin-1β (IL-1β), IL-6 and tumor necrosis factor (TNF)-α, which were significantly mitigated in colchicine-treated SAP + COL group of rats. Furthermore, colchicine treatment significantly attenuated nuclear factor kappa-B (NF-κB)-p65, signal transducer and activator of transcription 3 (STAT3) and protein kinase B (AKT) phosphorylation, reduced inducible nitric oxide synthase (iNOS) and 4-Hydroxynonenal expression, ROS production and cell apoptosis by decreasing caspase-3 cleavage, Bax expression, but increasing Bcl-2, nuclear factor erythroid 2-related factor 2 (Nrf2) and heme oxygenase-1 (HO-1) expression in pancreatic and lung tissues, relative to the SAP group of rats.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/em&gt; Colchicine treatment significantly mitigated the severity of SAP-ALI by inhibiting inflammation, oxidative stress and cell apoptosis in rats.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ZNF354C Mediated by DNMT1 Ameliorates Lung Ischemia-Reperfusion Oxidative Stress Injury by Reducing TFPI Promoter Methylation to Upregulate TFPI</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35915612/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35915612/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Pulmonary ischemia reperfusion- (I/R-) induced dysfunction is a significant clinical problem after lung transplantation. In this study, we aim to explore the molecular mechanism of lung I/R injury (LIRI).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; Bioinformatic analysis of gene involved in oxidative stress. A HUVEC oxygen glucose deprivation/reoxygenation (OGD/R) model and I/R mouse model were first established via I/R. The cellular proliferation, migration, reactive oxygen species (ROS), and parameters of lung injury were assessed via CCK-8, EdU staining, Transwell, cellular ROS kit, and H&amp;amp;E staining. We also confirmed related gene expressions and protein levels and the interaction between the tissue factor pathway inhibitor (TFPI) promotor and ZNF354C.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; Bioinformatic analysis results showed TFPI contributed to oxidative stress. OGD/R caused a reduction in cell viability and migration, hypermethylation of TFPI, increased ROS, and downregulation of ZNF354C, TFPI, and DNA methyltransferases (DNMTs) in HUVECs. Besides, ZNF354C could directly bind to the TFPI promoter, enhance proliferation and migration, and inhibit ROS in OGD/R-induced HUVECs by upregulating TFPI. More importantly, we discovered that 5-Aza could reduce TFPI methylation, upregulate TFPI, and enhance the binding of ZNF354C to the TFPI promoter in LIRI. Furthermore, DNMT1 silencing could induce proliferation and migration and prevent ROS in OGD/R-induced HUVECs by upregulating ZNF354C. Additionally, we verified that ZNF354C could alleviate LIRI by preventing DNA methylation &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; ZNF354C overexpression induced proliferation and migration, as well as suppressed ROS in OGD/R-induced HUVECs, and alleviated LIRI in mice by inhibiting TFPI promoter methylation to upregulate TFPI. Therefore, ZNF354C and TFPI methylation might be promising molecular markers for LIRI therapy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ceria nanoparticles prophylactic used for renal ischemia-reperfusion injury treatment by attenuating oxidative stress and inflammatory response</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35926357/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35926357/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Renal ischemia-reperfusion (IR) injury (RIRI) is the leading cause of acute kidney injury (AKI), a common disease with high morbidity and mortality. However, due to the lack of effective diagnostic and therapeutic tools, patients have to resort to conservative treatment. To address this issue, we have developed a novel prophylactic strategy that involves the pre-treatment use of ceria nanoparticles (CNPs) before surgery. Based on our careful study of the three different sizes of CNPs that we synthesized, 46 nm (NP46), 81 nm (NP81), and 118 nm (NP118), we have found that NP118 can be used as effective prophylactic agents against RIRI and subsequent renal fibrosis. In our experiments, the CNPs exhibited excellent antioxidant and anti-inflammatory activities in vitro and effectively protected the kidney against RIRI and renal fibrosis in vivo, as proved by the decreases in renal lesions, serum creatinine, blood urea nitrogen, apoptotic cell, KIM-1 expression, and fibrotic area in CNPs treated samples relative to RIRI group. Mechanistically, not only did the CNPs reduce oxidative stress by regulating the Nrf2 pathway, but they also attenuated RIRI induced inflammatory response by decreasing macrophage infiltration and polarization to M1 phenotype, and reducing pro-inflammatory cytokine and chemokine production. In vitro results further confirmed that CNPs pre-treatment not only dramatically decreased intracellular ROS production in renal tubular epithelial cells and vascular endothelial cells, but also effectively attenuated lipopolysaccharide-induced inflammation in RAW264.7 cells. In addition, we found that one fourth of the NP118 persisted for more than 21 days in IR kidneys, and that out of the three sizes of CNPs, NP118 achieved the best results in all our experiments. Our study provides new insights into the usage and majorization of CNPs as a potential therapy to treat or prevent RIRI and renal fibrosis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Combustion-Derived Particulate PAHs Associated with Small Airway Dysfunction in Elderly Patients with COPD</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35834827/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35834827/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Evidence of the respiratory effects of ambient organic aerosols (e.g., polycyclic aromatic hydrocarbons, PAHs) among patients with chronic diseases is limited. We aimed to assess whether exposure to ambient particle-bound PAHs could worsen small airway functions in patients with chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD) and elucidate the underlying mechanisms involved. Forty-five COPD patients were recruited with four repeated visits in 2014-2015 in Beijing, China. Parameters of pulmonary function and pulmonary/systemic inflammation and oxidative stress were measured at each visit. Linear mixed-effect models were performed to evaluate the associations between PAHs and measurements. In this study, participants experienced an average PAH level of 61.7 ng/m3. Interquartile range increases in exposure to particulate PAHs at prior up to 7 days were associated with reduced small airway functions, namely, decreases of 17.7-35.5% in forced maximal mid-expiratory flow. Higher levels of particulate PAHs were also associated with heightened lung injury and inflammation and oxidative stress. Stronger overall effects were found for PAHs from traffic emissions and coal burning. Exposure to ambient particulate PAHs was capable of impairing small airway functions in elderly patients with COPD, potentially via inflammation and oxidative stress. These findings highlight the importance of control efforts on organic particulate matter from fossil fuel combustion emissions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FGF1 alleviates LPS-induced acute lung injury via suppression of inflammation and oxidative stress</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35764933/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35764933/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Acute lung injury (ALI) and its severe form, acute respiratory distress syndrome (ARDS), are devastating clinical disorders with high mortality, and for which more effective therapies are urgently needed. FGF1, the prototype member of the FGF family, is shown to exert protective effects against injurious stimuli in multiple disease models. Here we aimed to evaluate whether FGF1 pretreatment is protective against LPS-induced ALI and elucidate the potential underlying mechanisms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; For drug-treated groups, C57B/6 mice received a single i.p. injection of FGF1 (1 mg/kg) 1 h before the LPS challenge or not. To induce the ALI model, the mice were treated by intratracheal instillation of LPS (5 mg/kg). Then, histopathological changes in lung tissues were assessed by hematoxylin and eosin staining and transmission electron microscopy. ELISA and qPCR assays were used to detect pro-inflammatory cytokine levels in BALF and lung tissues, respectively. The total number of inflammatory cells (neutrophils and macrophages) in BALF were counted using the Wright-Giemsa method. The expressions of reactive oxygen species (ROS) and malondialdehyde (MDA) were measured using their respective kits. Western blot and immunostaining were used to evaluate the expressions of antioxidants (Nrf-2, HO-1, SOD2, GPX4, and Catalase), as well as the inflammatory and/or apoptosis-related factors (TLR4, NF-κB, and Cleaved- caspase 3).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; FGF1 pretreatment significantly ameliorated the LPS-induced histopathological changes, reduced lung wet/dry ratios, ROS and MDA levels, total BALF protein, inflammatory cell infiltration, proinflammatory cytokine levels, and significantly increased the expression of antioxidant proteins (Nrf-2, HO-1, Catalase, and SOD2). In addition, FGF1 pretreatment significantly reduced the expression of TLR4 and cleaved- caspase 3, inhibited NF-κB activation, and reduced LPS-induced cell apoptosis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; Altogether, our results suggest that FGF1 pretreatment is protective against LPS-induced ALI through mediating anti-inflammatory and antioxidant effects, which may be attributed to the downregulation of TLR4 expression and inhibition of NF-κB activation, as well as promotion of antioxidant defenses. Therefore, FGF1 administration may prove beneficial in preventative strategies for ALI/ARDS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Expression of DEL-1 in alveolar epithelial cells prevents lipopolysaccharide-induced inflammation, oxidative stress, and eosinophil recruitment in acute lung injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35764019/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35764019/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Expression of DEL-1 in alveolar epithelial cells is repressed in ALI mice;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;DEL-1 inhibits LPS-induced lung injury in mice;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;DEL-1 prevents eosinophil recruitment in LPS-induced mice.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bacterial infection is a major cause of acute lung injury (ALI). Developmental endothelial locus-1 (DEL-1) is an immunomodulatory mediator secreted by the endothelial cells. This study aimed to investigate the role of DEL-1 in lipopolysaccharide (LPS)-induced ALI in mouse models and its ability to regulate on eosinophil recruitment. Male C57BL/6 mice were administered an adeno-associated virus (AAV)-mediated DEL-1 overexpression vector via intratracheal injection. Twenty-one days after vector instillation, mice were challenged with LPS (5 mg/kg body weight). Lung injury was evaluated using haematoxylin-eosin staining, flow cytometry, enzyme-linked immunosorbnent assay, quantitative real-time polymerase chain reaction, western blotting, immunohistochemistry and immunofluorescence analyses. DEL-1 was expressed in alveolar epithelial cells of mice. Compared with that in the control group, DEL-1 was expressed at low levels in the lungs of LPS-challenged mice. LPS injured the lungs in mice, as evidenced by an increase in alveolar wall thickness, inflammatory cell infiltration in the stroma, and alveolar collapse. AAV-mediated DEL-1 overexpression attenuated LPS-induced lung injury and inhibited the release of TNF-α, IL-6, and IL-1β. DEL-1 overexpression also attenuated LPS-induced oxidative stress by decreasing lactic dehydrogenase (LDH), myeloperoxidase (MPO), malondialdehyde (MDA), and reactive oxygen species (ROS) activities and increasing superoxide dismutase (SOD) activity. In addition, DEL-1 prevented eosinophil recruitment into lung tissues and inhibited eotaxin production. This study revealed the beneficial role of DEL-1 in preventing LPS-induced ALI in mice. Therefore, DEL-1 can protect lung tissues against LPS-induced inflammation, oxidative stress, and eosinophil recruitment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Liquiritigenin protects against myocardial ischemic by inhibiting oxidative stress, apoptosis, and L-type Ca2&#43; channels</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35747908/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35747908/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Liquiritigenin (Lq) offers cytoprotective effects against various cardiac injuries, but its beneficial effects on myocardial ischemic (MI) injury and the related mechanisms remain unclear. In the in vivo study, an animal model of MI was induced by intraperitoneal injection of isoproterenol (Iso, 85 mg/kg). ECG, heart rate, serum levels of CK and CK-MB, histopathological changes, and reactive oxygen species (ROS) levels were all measured. In vitro, H9c2 cells were divided into four groups and treated for 24 hr with liquiritigenin (30 μmol/L and 100 μmol/L) followed with CoCl&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; (800 μmol/L) for another 24 hr. Cell viability, apoptosis, mitochondrial membrane potential, and intracellular Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt; concentration ([Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt; ]&lt;sub&gt;i&lt;/sub&gt;) were then assessed. The L-type Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt; current (I&lt;sub&gt;Ca-L&lt;/sub&gt;) was detected using a patch clamp technique on isolated rat ventricular myocytes. The myocyte contraction and Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt; transients were measured using an IonOptix detection system. The remarkable cardiac injury and generation of intracellular ROS induced by Iso were alleviated via treatment with Lq. CoCl&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; administration induced cell apoptosis, mitochondrial dysfunction, and Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt; overload in H9c2; Lq reduces these deleterious effects of CoCl&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;. Meanwhile, Lq blocked I&lt;sub&gt;Ca-L&lt;/sub&gt; in a dose-dependent manner. The half-maximal inhibitory concentration of Lq was 110.87 μmol/L. Lq reversibly reduced the amplitude of cell contraction as well as the Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt; transients. The results show that Lq protects against MI injury by antioxidation, antiapoptosis, counteraction mitochondrial dysfunction, and inhibition of I&lt;sub&gt;Ca-L&lt;/sub&gt;, thus damping intracellular Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New mechanism of nephrotoxicity of triptolide: Oxidative stress promotes cGAS-STING signaling pathway</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35697291/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35697291/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Triptolide activates the cGAS-STING signaling pathway in kidney tubular cells in vivo and in vitro.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;STING inhibitor C176 had protective effects in TPL-induced nephrocyte damage.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Triptolide induced an enhancement in protein levels of BACH1, while the expression of HMOX1 was reduced.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Oxidative stress-induced mtDNA damage and DNA leakage were the causes of the activation of cGAS-STING signaling pathway.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Triptolide (TPL) is a bioactive component extracted from the traditional Chinese herb Tripterygium wilfordii Hook F., and has multiple pharmacological activities, such as anti-tumor activity. However, severe adverse effects and toxicity, especially nephrotoxicity, limit its clinical application. It has been demonstrated that mitochondrial defect is a major toxic effects of TPL. In this study, we show that triptolide activated the cGAS-STING signaling pathway in kidney tubular cells in vivo and in vitro. Renal injury models were established in BALB/c mice and human tubular epithelial cells using TPL. We found that TPL enhanced the phosphorylation levels of STING, TBK1 and IRF3, and upregulated the expression of IFNβ, which is the production of cGAS-STING signaling pathway. STING inhibitor C176 had protective effects in TPL-induced nephrocyte damage. STING siRNA down regulated the expression level of IFNβ. In addition, triptolide induced an increase in protein levels of the transcription factor BACH1, while transcriptional expression of the antioxidant enzyme HMOX1 was reduced due to the increased expression of BACH1. Furthermore, oxidative stress-induced mtDNA damage and DNA leakage caused activation of the cGAS-STING signaling pathway. Altogether, cGAS-STING signaling pathway involved in TPL induced nephrotoxicity. Inhibiting cGAS-STING over-activation may be a new strategy for alleviating renal injury of triptolide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Citraconate inhibits ACOD1 (IRG1) catalysis, reduces interferon responses and oxidative stress, and modulates inflammation and cell metabolism</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35655026/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35655026/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although the immunomodulatory and cytoprotective properties of itaconate have been studied extensively, it is not known whether its naturally occurring isomers mesaconate and citraconate have similar properties. Here, we show that itaconate is partially converted to mesaconate intracellularly and that mesaconate accumulation in macrophage activation depends on prior itaconate synthesis. When added to human cells in supraphysiological concentrations, all three isomers reduce lactate levels, whereas itaconate is the strongest succinate dehydrogenase (SDH) inhibitor. In cells infected with influenza A virus (IAV), all three isomers profoundly alter amino acid metabolism, modulate cytokine/chemokine release and reduce interferon signalling, oxidative stress and the release of viral particles. Of the three isomers, citraconate is the strongest electrophile and nuclear factor-erythroid 2-related factor 2 (NRF2) agonist. Only citraconate inhibits catalysis of itaconate by cis-aconitate decarboxylase (ACOD1), probably by competitive binding to the substrate-binding site. These results reveal mesaconate and citraconate as immunomodulatory, anti-oxidative and antiviral compounds, and citraconate as the first naturally occurring ACOD1 inhibitor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fudosteine attenuates acute lung injury in septic mice by inhibiting pyroptosis via the TXNIP/NLRP3/GSDMD pathway</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35609679/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35609679/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a dearth of effective pharmacotherapies for sepsis-induced acute lung injury/acute respiratory distress syndrome (ALI/ARDS) to which oxidative stress and excessive inflammation are major contributors. We hypothesized that fudosteine, a cysteine derivative, may protect against sepsis-induced ALI/ARDS given its anti-oxidant capacity. This study aimed to investigate the effects and mechanisms of fudosteine in a mouse model of sepsis-induced ALI. Sepsis was induced by cecal ligation and puncture (CLP). The intragastrical administration of fudosteine (25 mg/kg, 50 mg/kg, and 100 mg/kg) dose-dependently decreased proinflammatory cytokine levels in bronchoalveolar lavage fluid (BALF) and serum and reduced BALF/serum albumin and lung wet/dry weight ratios in septic mice. The lung injury score was significantly lowered by fudosteine [&lt;em&gt;e.g.&lt;/em&gt;, 0.18 ± 0.03 (100 mg/kg) vs. 0.42 ± 0.03 (CLP), &lt;em&gt;P&lt;/em&gt; &amp;lt; 0.0001]. Fudosteine also reduced the biomarkers of lung epithelial injury in BALF and markedly improved oxidative stress indicators in lung tissues [&lt;em&gt;e.g.&lt;/em&gt;, malondialdehyde: 337.70 ± 23.78 (100 mg/kg) vs. 686.40 ± 28.36 (CLP) nmol/mg protein, &lt;em&gt;P&lt;/em&gt; &amp;lt; 0.0001]. Lung tissue transcriptomics analyses revealed suppressed inflammatory responses and oxidative stress with fudosteine and the involvement of the inflammasome and pyroptosis pathways. Western blot analyses indicated that fudosteine inhibited the sepsis-induced activation of gasdermin D (GSDMD) and caspase-1 and the upregulation of thioredoxin-interacting protein (TXNIP), nucleotide-binding domain, leucine-rich repeat-containing receptor, pyrin domain-containing-3 (NLRP3), and apoptosis-associated speck-like protein containing a caspase recruitment domain (ASC). Fudosteine therefore protects against sepsis-induced ALI in mice, and the inhibition of pyroptosis via the TXNIP/NLRP3/GSDMD pathway may be an underlying mechanism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DDAH1 Promotes Lung Endothelial Barrier Repair by Decreasing Leukocyte Transendothelial Migration and Oxidative Stress in Explosion-Induced Lung Injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35620579/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35620579/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Explosion-induced injury is the most commonly encountered wound in modern warfare and incidents. The vascular inflammatory response and subsequent oxidative stress are considered the key causes of morbidity and mortality among those in blast lung injury. It has been reported dimethylarginine dimethylaminohydrolase 1 (DDAH1) plays important roles in regulating vascular endothelial injury repair and angiogenesis, but its role in explosion-induced injury remains to be explained. To explore the mechanism of vascular injury in blast lung, 40 C57BL/6 wild type mice and 40 DDAH1 knockout mice were randomly equally divided into control group and blast group, respectively. Body weight, lung weight, and dry weight of the lungs were recorded. Diffuse vascular leakage was detected by Evans blue test. The serum inflammatory factors, nitric oxide (NO) contents, and ADMA level were determined through ELISA. Hematoxylin-eosin staining and ROS detection were performed for histopathological changes. Western blot was used to detect the proteins related to oxidative stress, cell adhesion molecules and leukocyte transendothelial migration, vascular injury, endothelial barrier dysfunction, and the DDAH1/ADMA/eNOS signaling pathway. We found that DDAH1 deficiency aggravated explosion-induced body weight reduction, lung weight promotion, diffuse vascular leakage histopathological changes, and the increased levels of inflammatory-related factors. Additionally, DDAH1 deficiency also increased ROS generation, MDA, and IRE-1α expression. Regarding vascular endothelial barrier dysfunction, DDAH1 deficiency increased the expression of ICAM-1, Itgal, Rac2, VEGF, MMP9, vimentin, and N-cadherin, while lowering the expression of occludin, CD31, and dystrophin. DDAH1 deficiency also exacerbated explosion-induced increase of ADMA and decrease of eNOS activity and NO contents. Our results indicated that explosion could induce severe lung injury and pulmonary vascular insufficiency, whereas DDAH1 could promote lung endothelial barrier repair and reduce inflammation and oxidative stress by inhibiting ADMA signaling which in turn increased eNOS activity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FMRP protects the lung from xenobiotic stress by facilitating the integrated stress response</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35319067/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35319067/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Altered purine metabolism at reperfusion affects clinical outcome in lung transplantation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35450941/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35450941/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Introduction:&lt;/em&gt; Lung transplantation is an established treatment for patients with end-stage lung disease. However, ischaemia reperfusion injury remains a barrier to achieving better survival outcomes. Here, we aim to investigate the metabolomic and transcriptomic profiles in human lungs before and after reperfusion, to identify mechanisms relevant to clinical outcome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; We analysed 67 paired human lung tissue samples collected from 2008 to 2011, at the end of cold preservation and 2 hours after reperfusion. Gene expression analysis was performed with R. Pathway analysis was conducted with Ingenuity Pathway Analysis. MetaboAnalyst and OmicsNet were used for metabolomics analysis and omics data integration, respectively. Association of identified metabolites with transplant outcome was investigated with Kaplan-Meier estimate and Cox proportional hazard models.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; Activation of energy metabolism and reduced antioxidative biochemicals were found by metabolomics. Upregulation of genes related to cytokines and inflammatory mediators, together with major signalling pathways were revealed by transcriptomics. Purine metabolism was identified as the most significantly enriched pathway at reperfusion, based on integrative analysis of the two omics data sets. Elevated expression of purine nucleoside phosphorylase (PNP) could be attributed to activation of multiple transcriptional pathways. PNP catabolised reactions were evidenced by changes in related metabolites, especially decreased levels of inosine and increased levels of uric acid. Multivariable analyses showed significant association of inosine and uric acid levels with intensive care unit length of stay and ventilation time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/em&gt; Oxidative stress, especially through purine metabolism pathway, is a major metabolic event during reperfusion and may contribute to the ischaemia reperfusion injury of lung grafts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Targeting Nrf2 in ischemia-reperfusion alleviation: From signaling networks to therapeutic targeting</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/35460707/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/35460707/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Oxidative stress, inflammation and apoptosis result from I/R injury.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nrf2 induction decreases ROS production to ameliorate oxidative stress.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nrf2 overexpression prevents inflammation and apoptosis in I/R.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nrf2 upregulation improves cell viability in I/R.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kaempferol, honokiol and isoquercetin among others, induce Nrf2 in I/R injury treatment.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The nuclear factor erythroid 2-related factor 2 (Nrf2) is a master regulator of redox balance and it responds to various cell stresses that oxidative stress is the most well-known one. The Nrf2 should undergo nuclear translocation to exert its protective impacts and decrease ROS production. On the other hand, ischemic/reperfusion (I/R) injury is a pathological event resulting from low blood flow to an organ and followed by reperfusion. The I/R induces cell injury and organ dysfunction. The present review focuses on Nrf2 function in alleviation of I/R injury. Stimulating of Nrf2 signaling ameliorates I/R injury in various organs including lung, liver, brain, testis and heart. The Nrf2 enhances activity of antioxidant enzymes to reduce ROS production and prevent oxidative stress-mediated cell death. Besides, Nrf2 reduces inflammation via decreasing levels of pro-inflammatory factors including IL-6, IL-1β and TNF-α. Nrf2 signaling is beneficial in preventing apoptosis and increasing cell viability. Nrf2 induces autophagy to prevent apoptosis during I/R injury. Furthermore, it can interact with other molecular pathways including PI3K/Akt, NF-κB, miRNAs, lncRNAs and GSK-3β among others, to ameliorate I/R injury. The therapeutic agents, most of them are phytochemicals such as resveratrol, berberine and curcumin, induce Nrf2 signaling in I/R injury alleviation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Geraniol Ameliorates Doxorubicin-Mediated Kidney Injury through Alteration of Antioxidant Status, Inflammation, and Apoptosis: Potential Roles of NF-κB and Nrf2/Ho-1</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35458182/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35458182/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Doxorubicin-mediated kidney impairment is a serious problem in cancer treatment. Accordingly, this work investigated the ability of geraniol to modulate doxorubicin-induced kidney damage using a rat model. Rats were randomly assigned to four groups: control, doxorubicin (20 mg/kg, intraperitoneal, i.p.), doxorubicin plus 100 mg/kg of geraniol, and doxorubicin plus 200 mg/kg of geraniol. A single doxorubicin injection triggered kidney impairment, as evidenced by the altered serum creatinine, blood urea nitrogen, and albumin values; it also caused histological changes in the kidney architecture. Additionally, doxorubicin enhanced lipid peroxidation while lowering reduced glutathione, catalase activity, and the expression of glutathione peroxidase and superoxide dismutase. Interestingly, pre-treatment with geraniol rescued doxorubicin-induced alterations in kidney antioxidant parameters, enzymatic activity, and the expression of inflammatory and apoptosis-mediating gene and proteins. Moreover, prophylactic treatment with geraniol preserved most kidney histological characteristics in a dose-dependent manner. These findings support that geraniol could protect against doxorubicin-mediated kidney dysfunction. However, further research is needed to clarify the mechanisms of geraniol&amp;rsquo;s protective effects against doxorubicin-mediated kidney dysfunction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meldonium Ameliorates Hypoxia-Induced Lung Injury and Oxidative Stress by Regulating Platelet-Type Phosphofructokinase-Mediated Glycolysis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35450040/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35450040/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hypoxic environments at high altitudes influence the long-term non-altitude health of residents, by inducing changes in metabolism and the mitochondria, severe lung injury, and endangering life. This study was aimed to determine whether meldonium can ameliorate hypoxia-induced lung injury and investigate its possible molecular mechanisms. We used Swiss mice and exposed type Ⅱ alveolar epithelial cell to hypobaric hypoxic conditions to induce lung injury and found that meldonium has significant preventive effect, which was associated with the regulation of glycolysis. We found using human proteome microarrays assay, molecular docking, immunofluorescence and pull-down assay that the target protein of meldonium is a platelet-type phosphofructokinase (PFKP), which is a rate-limiting enzyme of glycolysis. Also, meldonium promotes the transfer of nuclear factor erythroid 2-related factor 2 (Nrf2) from the cytoplasm to the nucleus, which mitigates oxidative stress and mitochondrial damage under hypoxic condition. Mechanistically, meldonium ameliorates lung injury by targeting PFKP to regulate glycolysis, which promotes Nrf2 translocation from the cytoplasm to the nucleus to alleviate oxidative stress and mitochondrial damage under hypoxic condition. Our study provides a novel potential prevention and treatment strategy against hypoxia-induced lung injury.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alkyl organophosphate flame retardants (OPFRs) induce lung inflammation and aggravate OVA-simulated asthmatic response via the NF-кB signaling pathway</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35358787/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35358787/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;TnBP and TBOEP caused pulmonary damages by inflammation and oxidative stress.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Fkbp5&lt;/em&gt;/&lt;em&gt;Nos3&lt;/em&gt;/MAPK/NF-κB signal pathway was upregulated when exposing to TnBP and TBOEP.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;TnBP aggravated OVA induced asthmatic inflammatory response with overexpression of IgE.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;TnBP facilitated OVA-induced asthma by upregulating PI3K/Akt/NF-кB signaling pathway.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alkyl organophosphate flame retardants (OPFRs), tri-n-butyl phosphate (TnBP) and tris(2-butoxyethyl) phosphate (TBOEP), are ubiquitously detected in indoor and outdoor environments and their inhalation may result in lung damage. This study examined pulmonary toxicity after exposure to TnBP or TBOEP and investigated aggravation of inflammation and immunoreaction by TnBP in an ovalbumin (OVA)-induced mice model. Transcriptomics were used to further reveal the underlying mechanism. Exposure to TnBP or TBOEP resulted in pathological damage, including edema and thickened alveolar septum. In comparison with the control, enhanced levels of superoxide dismutase (SOD) (&lt;em&gt;p&lt;/em&gt; &amp;lt; 0.01 in TnBP (High) group and &lt;em&gt;p&lt;/em&gt; &amp;lt; 0.05 in TBOEP (High) group), glutathione peroxidase (GSH-px) (&lt;em&gt;p&lt;/em&gt; &amp;lt; 0.05), malondialdehyde (MDA) (&lt;em&gt;p&lt;/em&gt; &amp;lt; 0.01), and cytokines under a dose-dependent relationship were noted, and the expression of the Fkbp5/Nos3/MAPK/NF-кB signaling pathway (&lt;em&gt;p&lt;/em&gt; &amp;lt; 0.01) was upregulated in the TnBP and TBOEP groups. Moreover, the combined exposure of TnBP and OVA exacerbated the allergic inflammatory response, including airway hyperresponsiveness, leukocytosis, cellular exudation and infiltration, secretion of inflammatory mediators, and higher expression of IgE (&lt;em&gt;p&lt;/em&gt; &amp;lt; 0.01). Transcriptomics results demonstrated that the PI3K/Akt/NF-кB signal pathway was involved in TnBP-aggravated asthmatic mice. Exposure to TnBP or TBOEP resulted in oxidative damage and leukocyte-induced lung injury. TnBP can further facilitate OVA-induced asthma through an inflammatory response. This study is the first to reveal the pulmonary toxicity and potential mechanism induced by OPFRs through an in-vivo model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beneficial effects of aloperine on inflammation and oxidative stress by suppressing necroptosis in lipopolysaccharide-induced acute lung injury mouse model</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35397283/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35397283/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rationale:&lt;/em&gt; Alveolar epithelial cell death, inflammation, and oxidative stress are typical features of acute lung injury (ALI). Aloperine (Alo), an alkaloid isolated from Sophora alopecuroides, has been reported to display various biological effects, such as anti-inflammatory, immunoregulatory, and anti-oxidant properties. In this study, we investigated the effects and mechanisms of Alo in treating a lipopolysaccharide (LPS)-induced ALI in a murine model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; The effects of Alo in LPS-induced ALI were investigated in C57BL/6 mice. The RIPK1 inhibitor (Nec-1) and the RIPK3 inhibitor (GSK&#39;872) were used to evaluate the relationship of necroptosis, NF-κB activation, and PDC subunits in LPS-treated mouse alveolar epithelial cells (MLE-12). Then the effects of Alo on necroptosis, inflammation, and oxidative stress of LPS-stimulated MLE-12 cells were evaluated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; Alo significantly attenuated histopathological lung injuries and reduced lung wet/dry ratio in LPS-induced ALI mice. Alo also remarkedly reduced total protein and neutrophils recruitment in bronchoalveolar lavage fluid of ALI mice. Meanwhile, Alo ameliorated the LPS-induced necroptosis in the lungs of ALI mice. The RIPK3 inhibitor GSK&#39;872, but not the RIPK1 inhibitor Nec-1, reversed LPS-induced p65 phosphorylation and translocation to the nucleus in MLE-12 cells. GSK&#39;872 also reversed the LPS-induced increase in ROS and binding of RIPK3 and PDC subunits in MLE-12 cells. Moreover, Alo down-regulated the levels of p-RIPK1, p-RIPK3, p-MLKL, p-p65, the translocation of p65 to the nucleus, and reduced the expression of IL-6 and IL-8 in LPS-stimulated MLE-12 cells. Alo also inhibited the binding of RIPK3 and PDC-E1α, PDC-E1β, PDC-E2, and PDC-E3 and the ROS production in LPS-treated MLE-12 cells.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/em&gt; The present study validated the beneficial effects of Alo on LPS-induced ALI , suggesting Alo may be a new drug candidate against ALI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deep learning approach identified a gene signature predictive of the severity of renal damage caused by chronic cadmium accumulation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35405588/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35405588/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Modeling chronic Cd induced nephrotoxicity in normal and diabetic conditions in mice.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mechanisms underlying Cd induced renal injury revealed via transcriptome profiling.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gene signature predictive of the susceptibility to Cd nephrotoxicity by deep learning.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Epidemiology studies have indicated that environmental cadmium exposure, even at low levels, will result in chronic cadmium accumulation in the kidney with profound adverse consequences and that the diabetic population is more susceptible. However, the underlying mechanisms are yet not fully understood. In the present study, we applied an animal model to study chronic cadmium exposure-induced renal injury and performed whole transcriptome profiling studies. Repetitive CdCl&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; exposure resulted in cadmium accumulation and remarkable renal injuries in the animals. The diabetic ob/ob mice manifested increased severity of renal injury compared with the wild type C57BL/6 J littermate controls. RNA-Seq data showed that cadmium treatment induced dramatic gene expression changes in a dose-dependent manner. Among the differentially expressed genes include the apoptosis hallmark genes which significantly demarcated the treatment effects. Pathway enrichment and network analyses revealed biological oxidation (mainly glucuronidation) as one of the major stress responses induced by cadmium treatment. We next implemented a deep learning algorithm in conjunction with cloud computing and discovered a gene signature that can predict the degree of renal injury induced by cadmium treatment. The present study provided, for the first time, a comprehensive mechanistic understanding of chronic cadmium-induced nephrotoxicity in normal and diabetic populations at the whole genome level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aerosolized vitamin E acetate causes oxidative injury in mice and in alveolar macrophages</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35318859/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35318859/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GSPE Protects against Bleomycin-Induced Pulmonary Fibrosis in Mice via Ameliorating Epithelial Apoptosis through Inhibition of Oxidative Stress</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35355866/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35355866/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis (IPF) is a chronic, progressive interstitial lung disease of unknown cause which leads to alveolar epithelial cell apoptosis followed by basement membrane disruption and accumulation of extracellular matrix, destroying the lung architecture. Oxidative stress is involved in the development of alveolar injury, inflammation, and fibrosis. Oxidative stress-mediated alveolar epithelial cell (AEC) apoptosis is suggested to be a key process in the pathogenesis of IPF. Therefore, the present study investigated whether grape seed proanthocyanidin extract (GSPE) could inhibit the development of pulmonary fibrosis via ameliorating epithelial apoptosis through the inhibition of oxidative stress. We found that GSPE significantly ameliorated the histological changes and the level of collagen deposition in bleomycin (BLM)-induced lungs. Moreover, GSPE attenuated lung inflammation by reducing the total number of cells in bronchoalveolar lavage (BAL) fluid and decreasing the expression of IL-6. We observed that the levels of H2O2 leading to oxidative stress were increased following BLM instillation, which significantly decreased with GSPE treatment both in vivo and in vitro. These findings showed that GSPE attenuated BLM-induced epithelial apoptosis in the mouse lung and A549 alveolar epithelial cell through the inhibition of oxidative stress. Furthermore, GSPE could attenuate mitochondrial-associated cell apoptosis via decreasing the Bax/Bcl-2 ratio. The present study demonstrates that GSPE could ameliorate bleomycin-induced pulmonary fibrosis in mice via inhibition of epithelial apoptosis through the inhibition of oxidative stress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PINK1/Parkin-mediated mitophagy is activated to protect against AFB1-induced kidney damage in mice</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35304092/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35304092/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aflatoxin B&lt;sub&gt;1&lt;/sub&gt; (AFB&lt;sub&gt;1&lt;/sub&gt;) is a toxic food pollutant that has extensive deleterious impacts on the kidney. Oxidative stress represents the primary mechanism of AFB&lt;sub&gt;1&lt;/sub&gt; nephrotoxicity and can also cause mitochondrial damage. Damaged mitochondria can trigger apoptosis leading to kidney injury. PINK1/Parkin-mediated mitophagy can alleviate mitochondrial injury to maintain cellular homeostasis, however, its role in AFB&lt;sub&gt;1&lt;/sub&gt;-induced kidney damage is unknown. To investigate the effect of PINK1/Parkin-mediated mitophagy on kidney impairment triggered by AFB&lt;sub&gt;1&lt;/sub&gt;, 40 male wild-type (WT) C57BL/6N mice were first assigned to 4 groups and orally exposed to AFB&lt;sub&gt;1&lt;/sub&gt; at 0, 0.5, 0.75, and 1 mg/kg body weight (BW) for 28 days. The results revealed that AFB&lt;sub&gt;1&lt;/sub&gt; induced kidney damage, oxidative stress, mitochondrial damage, apoptosis and activated PINK1/Parkin-mediated mitophagy with a dose-dependent effect. Then, 20 male WT C57BL/6N mice and 20 male Parkin knockout (Parkin&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt;) C57BL/6N mice were assigned to 4 groups and orally exposed to AFB&lt;sub&gt;1&lt;/sub&gt; at 0, 1, 0, and 1 mg/kg BW for 28 days. The results revealed that Parkin&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt; suppressed mitophagy and exacerbated kidney damage, oxidative stress, mitochondrial damage, and apoptosis under AFB&lt;sub&gt;1&lt;/sub&gt; exposure. The aforementioned evidences demonstrate that PINK1/Parkin-mediated mitophagy is activated by AFB&lt;sub&gt;1&lt;/sub&gt; and protects against kidney damage in mice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>High Mobility Group Box 1: Biological Functions and Relevance in Oxidative Stress Related Chronic Diseases</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/35269471/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/35269471/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the early 1970s, a group of non-histone nuclear proteins with high electrophoretic mobility was discovered and named high-mobility group (HMG) proteins. High-mobility group box 1 (HMGB1) is the most studied HMG protein that detects and coordinates cellular stress response. The biological function of HMGB1 depends on its subcellular localization and expression. It plays a critical role in the nucleus and cytoplasm as DNA chaperone, chromosome gatekeeper, autophagy maintainer, and protector from apoptotic cell death. HMGB1 also functions as an extracellular alarmin acting as a damage-associated molecular pattern molecule (DAMP). Recent findings describe HMGB1 as a sophisticated signal of danger, with a pleiotropic function, which is useful as a clinical biomarker for several disorders. HMGB1 has emerged as a mediator in acute and chronic inflammation. Furthermore, HMGB1 targeting can induce beneficial effects on oxidative stress related diseases. This review focus on HMGB1 redox status, localization, mechanisms of release, binding with receptors, and its activities in different oxidative stress-related chronic diseases. Since a growing number of reports show the key role of HMGB1 in socially relevant pathological conditions, to our knowledge, for the first time, here we analyze the scientific literature, evaluating the number of publications focusing on HMGB1 in humans and animal models, per year, from 2006 to 2021 and the number of records published, yearly, per disease and category (studies on humans and animal models).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Molecular hydrogen is a promising therapeutic agent for pulmonary disease</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35187885/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35187885/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Molecular hydrogen exerts biological effects on nearly all organs. It has anti-oxidative, anti-inflammatory, and anti-aging effects and contributes to the regulation of autophagy and cell death. As the primary organ for gas exchange, the lungs are constantly exposed to various harmful environmental irritants. Short- or long-term exposure to these harmful substances often results in lung injury, causing respiratory and lung diseases. Acute and chronic respiratory diseases have high rates of morbidity and mortality and have become a major public health concern worldwide. For example, coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) caused by severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 (SARS-CoV-2) has become a global pandemic. An increasing number of studies have revealed that hydrogen may protect the lungs from diverse diseases, including acute lung injury, chronic obstructive pulmonary disease, asthma, lung cancer, pulmonary arterial hypertension, and pulmonary fibrosis. In this review, we highlight the multiple functions of hydrogen and the mechanisms underlying its protective effects in various lung diseases, with a focus on its roles in disease pathogenesis and clinical significance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Acute cardiovascular effects of inhaled ambient particulate matter: Chemical composition-related oxidative stress, endothelin-1, blood pressure, and ST-segment changes in Wistar rats</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35157883/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35157883/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Experimental evidence of particle composition as cardiovascular potency determinant.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ambient particle inhalation, ROS/RNS-related perturbations in endothelin isoforms.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PM-related molecular-level and relevant physiological/functional level changes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Particle composition-led key mechanistic events explain BP/S-T segment changes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Short-term increases in particulate matter (PM) are associated with heightened morbidity and mortality from cardiovascular causes. Inhalation of PM is known to increase endothelin (ET)-1 levels. Yet, less is known about particle composition-related changes at the molecular level including the endothelinergic system and relationship with cardiovascular function changes. In this work, adult Wistar male rats were exposed for 4 h by nose-only inhalation to clean air, Ottawa urban particles (EHC-93, 48 mg/m&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;) and water-leached (EHC-93L, 49 mg/m&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;) particles, to examine the effect of particle compositional changes on oxidative stress, circulating ETs, blood pressure, and heart electrophysiology. Particle deposition in the respiratory compartment was estimated at 85 μg (25 ng/cm&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;). Lung cell proliferation was low in both treatment groups, indicating absence of acute injury. Inhalation of EHC-93 caused statistically significant elevations (&lt;em&gt;p&lt;/em&gt; &amp;lt; 0.05) of oxidative stress markers, ET-1, ET-3, blood pressure, and a decrease of ST-segment duration in the ECG at 1.5 days post-exposure. Leached particles (EHC-93L) caused rapid but transient elevation (&lt;em&gt;p&lt;/em&gt; &amp;lt; 0.05) of oxidative stress, ET-1, ET-2, and ET-3 at earlier time points, with no changes in blood pressure or ST-segment. These results demonstrate that inhalation of urban particles at an internal dose inadequate to cause acute lung injury can induce oxidative stress, enhance vasoactive endothelins, leading to vasopressor response, affecting cardiac electrophysiology in Wistar rats, consistent with the cardiovascular impacts of ambient particles in human populations. Change in particle potency after removal of soluble species, notably cadmium, zinc and polar organics suggests that the toxicodynamics of cardiovascular effects can be modified by physicochemical properties of particles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dexamethasone-loaded ROS-responsive poly(thioketal) nanoparticles suppress inflammation and oxidative stress of acute lung injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35415281/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35415281/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A therapeutic nanoplatform with ROS-responsiveness was developed for the regulation of inflammation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;NPs composed of low Mw of PPADT and high Mw of PTKU were loaded with dexamethasone to obtain a self-adaptive system.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Dex-loaded NPs significantly decreased lung inflammation, and reduced lung injury and mortality &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acute lung injury (ALI) is associated with excessive inflammatory response, leading to acute respiratory distress syndrome (ARDS) without timely treatment. A fewer effective drugs are available currently to treat the ALI/ARDS. Herein, a therapeutic nanoplatform with reactive oxygen species (ROS)-responsiveness was developed for the regulation of inflammation. Dexamethasone acetate (Dex) was encapsulated into poly(thioketal) polymers to form polymeric nanoparticles (NPs) (PTKNPs@Dex). The NPs were composed of poly(1,4-phenyleneacetonedimethylene thioketal) (PPADT) and polythioketal urethane (PTKU), in which the thioketal bonds could be cleaved by the high level of ROS at the ALI site. The PTKNPs@Dex could accumulate in the pulmonary inflammatory sites and release the encapsulated payloads rapidly, leading to the decreased ROS level, less generation of pro-inflammatory cytokines, and reduced lung injury and mortality of mice. RNA sequencing (RNA-seq) analysis showed that the therapeutic efficacy of the NPs was associated with the modulation of many immune and inflammation-linked pathways. These findings provide a newly developed nanoplatform for the efficient treatment of ALI/ARDS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SENP7 senses oxidative stress to sustain metabolic fitness and antitumor functions of CD8&#43; T cells</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35143421/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35143421/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The functional integrity of CD8&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T cells is tightly coupled to metabolic reprogramming, but how oxidative stress directs CD8&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T cell metabolic fitness in the tumor microenvironment (TME) remains elusive. Here, we report that SUMO-specific protease 7 (SENP7) senses oxidative stress to maintain the CD8&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T cell metabolic state and antitumor functions. SENP7-deficient CD8&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T cells exhibited decreased glycolysis and oxidative phosphorylation, resulting in attenuated proliferation in vitro and dampened antitumor functions in vivo. Mechanistically, CD8&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T cell-derived ROS triggered cytosolic SENP7-mediated PTEN deSUMOylation, thereby promoting PTEN degradation and preventing PTEN-dependent metabolic defects. Importantly, lowering T cell-intrinsic ROS restricted SENP7 cytosolic translocation and repressed CD8&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T cell metabolic and functional activity in human colorectal cancer samples. Our findings reveal that SENP7, as an oxidative stress sensor, sustains CD8&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T cell metabolic fitness and effector functions and unveil an oxidative stress-sensing machinery in tumor-infiltrating CD8&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T cells.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
