<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Oxidative Stress | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/oxidative-stress/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/oxidative-stress/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Oxidative Stress</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Oxidative Stress</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/oxidative-stress/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oxidative stress-triggered Wnt signaling perturbation characterizes the tipping point of lung adeno-to-squamous transdifferentiation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36627278/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36627278/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Lkb1&lt;/em&gt; deficiency confers the Kras-mutant lung cancer with strong plasticity and the potential for adeno-to-squamous transdifferentiation (AST). However, it remains largely unknown how &lt;em&gt;Lkb1&lt;/em&gt; deficiency dynamically regulates AST. Using the classical AST mouse model (&lt;em&gt;Kras&lt;sup&gt;LSL-G12D/+&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt;;&lt;em&gt;Lkb1&lt;sup&gt;flox/flox&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, KL), we here comprehensively analyze the temporal transcriptomic dynamics of lung tumors at different stages by dynamic network biomarker (DNB) and identify the tipping point at which the Wnt signaling is abruptly suppressed by the excessive accumulation of reactive oxygen species (ROS) through its downstream effector FOXO3A. Bidirectional genetic perturbation of the Wnt pathway using two different &lt;em&gt;Ctnnb1&lt;/em&gt; conditional knockout mouse strains confirms its essential role in the negative regulation of AST. Importantly, pharmacological activation of the Wnt pathway before but not after the tipping point inhibits squamous transdifferentiation, highlighting the irreversibility of AST after crossing the tipping point. Through comparative transcriptomic analyses of mouse and human tumors, we find that the lineage-specific transcription factors (TFs) of adenocarcinoma and squamous cell carcinoma form a &amp;ldquo;Yin-Yang&amp;rdquo; counteracting network. Interestingly, inactivation of the Wnt pathway preferentially suppresses the adenomatous lineage TF network and thus disrupts the &amp;ldquo;Yin-Yang&amp;rdquo; homeostasis to lean towards the squamous lineage, whereas ectopic expression of NKX2-1, an adenomatous lineage TF, significantly dampens such phenotypic transition accelerated by the Wnt pathway inactivation. The negative correlation between the Wnt pathway and AST is further observed in a large cohort of human lung adenosquamous carcinoma. Collectively, our study identifies the tipping point of AST and highlights an essential role of the ROS-Wnt axis in dynamically orchestrating the homeostasis between adeno- and squamous-specific TF networks at the AST tipping point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MiR-217-5p inhibits smog (PM2.5)-induced inflammation and oxidative stress response of mouse lung tissues and macrophages through targeting STAT1</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36040387/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36040387/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Objective:&lt;/em&gt; To explore the roles of macrophages&amp;rsquo; miR-217-5p in the process of PM2.5 induced acute lung injury.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; GEO database and KEGG pathway enrichment analysis as well as GSEA were used to predicted the miRNA and associated target signals. And then mice and RAW246.7 macrophages treated with PM2.5 to imitate PM2.5 induced acute lung injury environment and then transfected with miR-217-5p NC or miR-217-5p mimic. The levels of inflammatory factors TNF-α and anti-inflammatory factor IL-10 of mice serum were tested by ELISA. And the pathological changes and ROS level of mouse lung tissues were stained by HE and DHE staining. The proteins expression of phosphorylated-STAT1, total-STAT1, TNF-α, IFN-γ as well as p47, gp91, NOX4 in mice or RAW264.7 cells were tested by western blot or immunofluorescence of RAW264.7 cell slides.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; The results of bioinformatics analysis indicated the miR-217 as well as STAT1 were involved PM2.5 associated lung injury. After exposure to PM2.5, the decreased levels of serum TNF-α but not IL-10, consistent with reduced macrophages&amp;rsquo; accumulation as well as decreased ROS levels in lung tissues in miR-217-5p mimic group vs miR-217-5p NC group mice, and moreover, the protein expression levels of phosphorylated&amp;ndash;STAT1, total-STAT1, TNF-α, IFN-γ, p47, gp91 and NOX4 in mouse lung tissues and RTAW246.7 macrophages cells were all significantly reduced with miR-217-5p mimic administration. The above phenomena were reversed by specific STAT1-inhibitor HY-N8107.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; miR-217-5p suppressed the activated STAT1-signal induced inflammation and oxidative stress trigged by PM2.5 in macrophages and resulted in the decreased lung injure caused by PM2.5.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Urinary profile of PAHs and related compounds in women working in beauty salons</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36029813/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36029813/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;First survey of urinary PAHs, 1-OHP and TTMA levels in women working in beauty salons;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;High PAHs, 1-OHP and TTMA levels were detected in urine of beauticians after the work shift.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The urinary PAHs, 1-OHP and TTMA were correlated with “personal care products (PCPs) usage”.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some PAHs were associated with oxidative stress/kidney injury biomarkers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Beauty activities can be considered as a major source of PAHs, 1-OHP and TTMA exposures.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Polycyclic aromatic hydrocarbons (PAHs) are a group of chemical compounds which interest to human biological monitoring researches because of their potential carcinogenic, mutagenic, and teratogenic properties. However, the exposure of female beauticians to these contaminants is not well-reported. For biomonitoring of potential exposure of female cosmeticians to PAHs in beauty salons, urine samples were taken from cosmetologist women (n = 50.00) and housewives (n = 35.00) as the exposure group (EG) and control group (CG), respectively. Next, unmetabolized PAHs levels as well as the concentration of - 1-hydroxypyrene (1-OHP) were analyzed in these specimens. In addition, since benzene has some common source with PAHs, in this study t, t&amp;rsquo;-Muconic acid (TTMA) level was also determined as the metabolite and indicator of exposure to benzene. The results indicated a high detection frequency of the target compounds (PAHs, 1-OHP and TTMA) in the urine specimens of beauticians. The results also showed that there is a significant difference between the concentration of these pollutants in the urine specimens of the exposure and control groups. The median concentration of ΣPAHs, 1-OHP, and TTMA in the before exposure (BE) specimens collected from the exposure group were 337.42 ng/L, 593.92 ng/L, and 247.90 μg/L, respectively. However, a higher concentration of these contaminants was observed in the after exposure specimens with a median concentration of 423.29 ng/L, 745.03 ng/L, and 310.97 μg/L, respectively. In terms of contribution of PAHs compounds in total toxic equivalents, DahA, BaP, and IndP with 59.03, 28.73, and 2.86 % had the largest share. In this study, it was also observed that some kidney damage biomarkers as well as some oxidative stress injury biomarkers are positively and significantly correlated with the urinary values of ∑PAHs. Thus, it can be concluded that high health risks threaten the female beauticians regarding kidney injury and DNA oxidative stress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rhabdomyolysis-induced acute kidney injury and concomitant apoptosis induction via ROS-mediated ER stress is efficaciously counteracted by epigallocatechin gallate</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36028100/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36028100/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rhabdomyolysis induced acute kidney injury (RIAKI) is a life-threatening condition responsible for approximately 19-58% of AKI cases worldwide. We performed an intramuscular injection of glycerol (10 mL/kg) in male wistar rats to induce AKI. Epigallocatechin gallate (EGCG) was administered for 3 consecutive days to evaluate its protective effects. We observed significant downregulation in serum creatinine, blood urea nitrogen (BUN) and LDH at different time points on EGCG treatment groups in a dose-dependent manner. Similarly, H&amp;amp;E staining also revealed that EGCG was able to reduce the formation of damaged tubules and tubular necrosis which was prominently spread throughout the kidney tissue of glycerol treatment group. Concomitantly, we observed upregulated inflammation, ER stress and elevated oxidative stress in the glycerol treated group only, which was significantly normalized upon EGCG treatment in both in vitro and in vivo studies. The occurrence of apoptosis in kidney tubules was found to be relatively higher in glycerol treated group and H2O2 treated HEK-293 cells. The results obtained after EGCG treatment revealed a significant decrease in apoptotic cell population, which was further validated by immunofluorescence staining against p53 and comet assay in HEK-293 cells and p53 IHC in kidney tissues. Western blotting also revealed a systemic downregulation of intrinsic mitochondrial apoptotic pathway markers such as bax, bcl-2, pro and cleaved caspase 3, caspase 9 and PARP1. Additionally, the results for flow cytometry analysis and TUNEL assay corroborated apoptotic equilibrium. Conclusively, we reckon EGCG as a multi-therapeutic natural product that can be used the for treatment of AKI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Acadesine alleviates acute pancreatitis-related lung injury by mediating the barrier protective function of pulmonary microvascular endothelial cells</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35987144/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35987144/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pretreatment with acadesine shows therapeutic potential SAP-ALI in vivo and vitro.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Endothelial injury is critical for the initiation and progression of severe acute pancreatitis-related acute lung injury.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The beneficial effects of acadesine may involve reducing ROS accumulation and inhibiting apoptosis.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Acadesine inhibits the impairment of SAP-ALI by activating the AMPK/Nrf2 pathway.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Severe acute pancreatitis (SAP) is a condition characterized by highly fatal acute inflammation and is usually associated with multiple organ dysfunction syndrome. Acute lung injury (ALI) is the most common complications of SAP, which is the accelerator of other organ dysfunction caused by SAP and the primary cause of early death due to SAP. Acadesine, an adenosine analog and an AMPK activator, has been discovered to modulate glucose and lipid metabolism, and inhibit the production of pro-inflammatory cytokines and iNOS. However, its role in SAP-ALI and its mechanism remains unclear and need to be explored. Herein, we discovered that acadesine mitigated the generation of reactive oxygen species (ROS) in human pulmonary microvascular endothelial cells (HPMECs), alleviated apoptosis and recovered barrier integrity, thereby contributing to anti-inflammatory effects in vitro and in vivo. Moreover, Nrf2 deficiency partially eliminated the effects of acadesine-induced antioxidant effects and thus weakened the protective effects on cells and Nrf2-knockout (Nrf2&lt;Sup&gt;-/-&lt;/Sup&gt;) mice. This study demonstrates that acadesine attenuated SAP-ALI associated inflammation and tissue damage by modulating the Nrf2-dependent antioxidant pathway by triggering AMPK. These findings are of great significance for the treatment of SAP-related lung injury.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CuO-NPs-triggered heterophil extracellular traps exacerbate liver injury in chicks by promoting oxidative stress and inflammatory responses</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35962800/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35962800/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the widespread use of copper oxide nanoparticles (CuO-NPs), their potential toxicity to the environment and biological health has attracted close attention. Heterophil extracellular traps (HETs) are an innate immune mechanism of chicken heterophils against adverse stimuli, but excessive HETs cause damage. Here, we explored the effect and mechanism of CuO-NPs on HETs formation in vitro and further evaluated the potential role of HETs in chicken liver and kidney injury. Heterophils were exposed to 5, 10, and 20 µg/mL of CuO-NPs for 2 h. The results showed that CuO-NPs induced typical HETs formation, which was dependent on NADPH oxidase, P38 and extracellular regulated protein kinases (ERK&lt;sub&gt;1/2&lt;/sub&gt;) pathways, and glycolysis. In in vivo experiments, fluorescence microplate and morphological analysis showed that CuO-NPs elevated the level of HETs in chicken serum and caused liver and kidney damage. Meanwhile, CuO-NPs caused hepatic oxidative stress (MDA, SOD, CAT, and GSH-PX imbalance), and also induced an increase in mRNA expression of their inflammatory and apoptosis-related factors (IL-1β, IL-6, TNF-α, COX-2, iNOS, NLRP3, and Caspase-1, 3, 11). However, these results were significantly altered by DNase I (HETs degradation reagent). In conclusion, the present study demonstrates for the first time that CuO-NPs induce the formation of HETs and that HETs exacerbate pathological damage in chicken liver and kidney by promoting oxidative stress and inflammation, providing insights into immunotoxicity and potential prevention and treatment targets caused by CuO-NPs overexposure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Macrophage SAMSN1 protects against sepsis-induced acute lung injury in mice</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35981417/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35981417/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Objective:&lt;/em&gt; Inflammation and oxidative stress contribute to the progression of sepsis-induced acute lung injury (ALI). SAM domain, SH3 domain and nuclear localization signals 1 (SAMSN1) is a signaling adaptor protein, and mainly regulates inflammatory response of various immune cells. The present study generates macrophage-specific SAMSN1-knockout (Samsn1MKO) and SAMSN1-transgenic (Samsn1MTG) mice to investigate its role and mechanism in sepsis-induced ALI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;Samsn1&lt;sup&gt;MKO&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Samsn1&lt;sup&gt;MTG&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; mice were exposed to lipopolysaccharide (LPS) instillation or cecal ligation and puncture (CLP) surgery to induce sepsis-induced ALI. Bone marrow transplantation, cellular depletion and non-invasive adoptive transfer of bone marrow-derived macrophages (BMDMs) were performed to validate the role of macrophage SAMSN1 in sepsis-induced ALI in vivo. Meanwhile, BMDMs were isolated from Samsn1MKO or Samsn1MTG mice to further clarify the role of SAMSN1 in vitro.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; Macrophage SAMSN1 expression was increased in response to LPS stimulation, and negatively correlated with LPS-induced ALI in mice. Macrophage SAMSN1 deficiency exacerbated, while macrophage SAMSN1 overexpression ameliorated LPS-induced inflammation, oxidative stress and ALI in mice and in BMDMs. Mechanistically, we found that macrophage SAMSN1 overexpression prevented LPS-induced ALI though activating AMP-activated protein kinase α2 (AMPKα2) &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;in vitro&lt;/em&gt;. Further studies revealed that SAMSN1 directly bound to growth factor receptor bound protein 2-associated protein 1 (GAB1) to prevent its protein degradation, and subsequently enhanced protein kinase A (PKA)/AMPKα2 activation in a protein tyrosine phosphatase, non-receptor type 11 (PTPN11, also known as SHP2)-dependent manner. Moreover, we observed that macrophage SAMSN1 overexpression diminished CLP-induced ALI in mice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/em&gt; Our study documents the protective role of macrophage SAMSN1 against sepsis-induced inflammation, oxidative stress and ALI through activating AMPKα2 in a GAB1/SHP2/PKA pathway, and defines it as a promising biomarker and therapeutic target to treat sepsis-induced ALI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CircSV2b participates in oxidative stress regulation through miR-5107-5p-Foxk1-Akt1 axis in Parkinson&#39;s disease</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35973363/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35973363/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CircSV2b in serum exosomes can be used as a biomarker for the diagnosis of PD.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CircSV2b participates in the progress of PD through the ceRNA-Akt1 axis.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CircSV2b overexpression is neuroprotective by resisting oxidative stress injury.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Foxk1 can regulate Akt1 transcription.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a novel type of non-coding RNAs, covalently closed circular RNAs (circRNAs) are ubiquitously expressed in eukaryotes. Emerging studies have indicated that dysregulation of circRNAs was related to neurological diseases. However, the biogenesis, regulation, function, and mechanism of circRNAs in Parkinson&amp;rsquo;s disease (PD) remain largely unclear. In this study, thirty-three differentially expressed circRNAs (DECs) were detected by RNA-sequencing between the MPTP-induced PD mice model and the wild-type mice. Quantitative real-time PCR was used to determine the RNA level of DECs in the striatum (STR), substantia nigra pars compacta (SNpc), and serum exosomes, and it was found that circSV2b was downregulated in PD mice. Then, functional experiments in vivo were employed to explore the effect of circSV2b in PD. For the mechanism study, dual-luciferase reporter, fluorescence in situ hybridization (FISH), RNA immunoprecipitation (RIP), RNA pull-down, gene editing, and CUT &amp;amp; Tag were performed in vitro to confirm that circSV2b directly sponged miR-5107-5p and alleviated the suppression of the expression of the target gene Foxk1, and then positively regulated Akt1 transcription. In vivo, the mechanistic analysis demonstrated that circSV2b overexpression resisted oxidative stress damage through the ceRNA-Akt1 axis in PD models. Taken together, these findings suggested that the miR-5107-5p-Foxk1-Akt1 axis might serve as a key target of circSV2b overexpression in PD treatment, and highlighted the significant change of circSV2b in serum exosomes. Therefore, circSV2b might be a novel biomarker for the diagnosis and treatment of PD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Colchicine improves severe acute pancreatitis-induced acute lung injury by suppressing inflammation, apoptosis and oxidative stress in rats</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36076491/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36076491/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Inflammation, apoptosis and oxidative stress play critical roles in severe acute pancreatitis (SAP).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Colchicine (COL) mitigates severe acute pancreatitis-associated lung injury (SAP-ALI) in rats model.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Colchicine limits inflammation, apoptosis and oxidative stress in SAP-ALI.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Inflammation, apoptosis and oxidative stress contribute to the development of severe acute pancreatitis-associated acute lung injury (SAP-ALI). Currently, there is no curative treatment for SAP-ALI in the clinic. This study investigated the potential therapeutic role and mechanisms of colchicine in a rat model of SAP-ALI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; Male Sprague-Dawley rats were randomized and administrated intragastrically with vehicle saline or colchicine (0.5 mg/kg/day) for seven days, followed by injecting sodium taurocholate to induce SAP-ALI. Together with a healthy control group of rats, their pancreatic and lung tissues and plasma samples were collected for histology, enzyme-linked immunosorbent assay (ELISA), immunoblot, immunohistochemistry, and immunofluorescence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; Compared with the sham controls, the SAP group of rats with vehicle saline treatment displayed severe damages, inflammation with many neutrophil and macrophage infiltrates in pancreatic and lung tissues, accompanied by elevated levels of plasma interleukin-1β (IL-1β), IL-6 and tumor necrosis factor (TNF)-α, which were significantly mitigated in colchicine-treated SAP + COL group of rats. Furthermore, colchicine treatment significantly attenuated nuclear factor kappa-B (NF-κB)-p65, signal transducer and activator of transcription 3 (STAT3) and protein kinase B (AKT) phosphorylation, reduced inducible nitric oxide synthase (iNOS) and 4-Hydroxynonenal expression, ROS production and cell apoptosis by decreasing caspase-3 cleavage, Bax expression, but increasing Bcl-2, nuclear factor erythroid 2-related factor 2 (Nrf2) and heme oxygenase-1 (HO-1) expression in pancreatic and lung tissues, relative to the SAP group of rats.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/em&gt; Colchicine treatment significantly mitigated the severity of SAP-ALI by inhibiting inflammation, oxidative stress and cell apoptosis in rats.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ZNF354C Mediated by DNMT1 Ameliorates Lung Ischemia-Reperfusion Oxidative Stress Injury by Reducing TFPI Promoter Methylation to Upregulate TFPI</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35915612/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35915612/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Pulmonary ischemia reperfusion- (I/R-) induced dysfunction is a significant clinical problem after lung transplantation. In this study, we aim to explore the molecular mechanism of lung I/R injury (LIRI).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; Bioinformatic analysis of gene involved in oxidative stress. A HUVEC oxygen glucose deprivation/reoxygenation (OGD/R) model and I/R mouse model were first established via I/R. The cellular proliferation, migration, reactive oxygen species (ROS), and parameters of lung injury were assessed via CCK-8, EdU staining, Transwell, cellular ROS kit, and H&amp;amp;E staining. We also confirmed related gene expressions and protein levels and the interaction between the tissue factor pathway inhibitor (TFPI) promotor and ZNF354C.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; Bioinformatic analysis results showed TFPI contributed to oxidative stress. OGD/R caused a reduction in cell viability and migration, hypermethylation of TFPI, increased ROS, and downregulation of ZNF354C, TFPI, and DNA methyltransferases (DNMTs) in HUVECs. Besides, ZNF354C could directly bind to the TFPI promoter, enhance proliferation and migration, and inhibit ROS in OGD/R-induced HUVECs by upregulating TFPI. More importantly, we discovered that 5-Aza could reduce TFPI methylation, upregulate TFPI, and enhance the binding of ZNF354C to the TFPI promoter in LIRI. Furthermore, DNMT1 silencing could induce proliferation and migration and prevent ROS in OGD/R-induced HUVECs by upregulating ZNF354C. Additionally, we verified that ZNF354C could alleviate LIRI by preventing DNA methylation &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; ZNF354C overexpression induced proliferation and migration, as well as suppressed ROS in OGD/R-induced HUVECs, and alleviated LIRI in mice by inhibiting TFPI promoter methylation to upregulate TFPI. Therefore, ZNF354C and TFPI methylation might be promising molecular markers for LIRI therapy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ceria nanoparticles prophylactic used for renal ischemia-reperfusion injury treatment by attenuating oxidative stress and inflammatory response</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35926357/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35926357/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Renal ischemia-reperfusion (IR) injury (RIRI) is the leading cause of acute kidney injury (AKI), a common disease with high morbidity and mortality. However, due to the lack of effective diagnostic and therapeutic tools, patients have to resort to conservative treatment. To address this issue, we have developed a novel prophylactic strategy that involves the pre-treatment use of ceria nanoparticles (CNPs) before surgery. Based on our careful study of the three different sizes of CNPs that we synthesized, 46 nm (NP46), 81 nm (NP81), and 118 nm (NP118), we have found that NP118 can be used as effective prophylactic agents against RIRI and subsequent renal fibrosis. In our experiments, the CNPs exhibited excellent antioxidant and anti-inflammatory activities in vitro and effectively protected the kidney against RIRI and renal fibrosis in vivo, as proved by the decreases in renal lesions, serum creatinine, blood urea nitrogen, apoptotic cell, KIM-1 expression, and fibrotic area in CNPs treated samples relative to RIRI group. Mechanistically, not only did the CNPs reduce oxidative stress by regulating the Nrf2 pathway, but they also attenuated RIRI induced inflammatory response by decreasing macrophage infiltration and polarization to M1 phenotype, and reducing pro-inflammatory cytokine and chemokine production. In vitro results further confirmed that CNPs pre-treatment not only dramatically decreased intracellular ROS production in renal tubular epithelial cells and vascular endothelial cells, but also effectively attenuated lipopolysaccharide-induced inflammation in RAW264.7 cells. In addition, we found that one fourth of the NP118 persisted for more than 21 days in IR kidneys, and that out of the three sizes of CNPs, NP118 achieved the best results in all our experiments. Our study provides new insights into the usage and majorization of CNPs as a potential therapy to treat or prevent RIRI and renal fibrosis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Combustion-Derived Particulate PAHs Associated with Small Airway Dysfunction in Elderly Patients with COPD</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35834827/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35834827/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Evidence of the respiratory effects of ambient organic aerosols (e.g., polycyclic aromatic hydrocarbons, PAHs) among patients with chronic diseases is limited. We aimed to assess whether exposure to ambient particle-bound PAHs could worsen small airway functions in patients with chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD) and elucidate the underlying mechanisms involved. Forty-five COPD patients were recruited with four repeated visits in 2014-2015 in Beijing, China. Parameters of pulmonary function and pulmonary/systemic inflammation and oxidative stress were measured at each visit. Linear mixed-effect models were performed to evaluate the associations between PAHs and measurements. In this study, participants experienced an average PAH level of 61.7 ng/m3. Interquartile range increases in exposure to particulate PAHs at prior up to 7 days were associated with reduced small airway functions, namely, decreases of 17.7-35.5% in forced maximal mid-expiratory flow. Higher levels of particulate PAHs were also associated with heightened lung injury and inflammation and oxidative stress. Stronger overall effects were found for PAHs from traffic emissions and coal burning. Exposure to ambient particulate PAHs was capable of impairing small airway functions in elderly patients with COPD, potentially via inflammation and oxidative stress. These findings highlight the importance of control efforts on organic particulate matter from fossil fuel combustion emissions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FGF1 alleviates LPS-induced acute lung injury via suppression of inflammation and oxidative stress</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35764933/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35764933/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Acute lung injury (ALI) and its severe form, acute respiratory distress syndrome (ARDS), are devastating clinical disorders with high mortality, and for which more effective therapies are urgently needed. FGF1, the prototype member of the FGF family, is shown to exert protective effects against injurious stimuli in multiple disease models. Here we aimed to evaluate whether FGF1 pretreatment is protective against LPS-induced ALI and elucidate the potential underlying mechanisms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; For drug-treated groups, C57B/6 mice received a single i.p. injection of FGF1 (1 mg/kg) 1 h before the LPS challenge or not. To induce the ALI model, the mice were treated by intratracheal instillation of LPS (5 mg/kg). Then, histopathological changes in lung tissues were assessed by hematoxylin and eosin staining and transmission electron microscopy. ELISA and qPCR assays were used to detect pro-inflammatory cytokine levels in BALF and lung tissues, respectively. The total number of inflammatory cells (neutrophils and macrophages) in BALF were counted using the Wright-Giemsa method. The expressions of reactive oxygen species (ROS) and malondialdehyde (MDA) were measured using their respective kits. Western blot and immunostaining were used to evaluate the expressions of antioxidants (Nrf-2, HO-1, SOD2, GPX4, and Catalase), as well as the inflammatory and/or apoptosis-related factors (TLR4, NF-κB, and Cleaved- caspase 3).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; FGF1 pretreatment significantly ameliorated the LPS-induced histopathological changes, reduced lung wet/dry ratios, ROS and MDA levels, total BALF protein, inflammatory cell infiltration, proinflammatory cytokine levels, and significantly increased the expression of antioxidant proteins (Nrf-2, HO-1, Catalase, and SOD2). In addition, FGF1 pretreatment significantly reduced the expression of TLR4 and cleaved- caspase 3, inhibited NF-κB activation, and reduced LPS-induced cell apoptosis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; Altogether, our results suggest that FGF1 pretreatment is protective against LPS-induced ALI through mediating anti-inflammatory and antioxidant effects, which may be attributed to the downregulation of TLR4 expression and inhibition of NF-κB activation, as well as promotion of antioxidant defenses. Therefore, FGF1 administration may prove beneficial in preventative strategies for ALI/ARDS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Expression of DEL-1 in alveolar epithelial cells prevents lipopolysaccharide-induced inflammation, oxidative stress, and eosinophil recruitment in acute lung injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35764019/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35764019/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Expression of DEL-1 in alveolar epithelial cells is repressed in ALI mice;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;DEL-1 inhibits LPS-induced lung injury in mice;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;DEL-1 prevents eosinophil recruitment in LPS-induced mice.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bacterial infection is a major cause of acute lung injury (ALI). Developmental endothelial locus-1 (DEL-1) is an immunomodulatory mediator secreted by the endothelial cells. This study aimed to investigate the role of DEL-1 in lipopolysaccharide (LPS)-induced ALI in mouse models and its ability to regulate on eosinophil recruitment. Male C57BL/6 mice were administered an adeno-associated virus (AAV)-mediated DEL-1 overexpression vector via intratracheal injection. Twenty-one days after vector instillation, mice were challenged with LPS (5 mg/kg body weight). Lung injury was evaluated using haematoxylin-eosin staining, flow cytometry, enzyme-linked immunosorbnent assay, quantitative real-time polymerase chain reaction, western blotting, immunohistochemistry and immunofluorescence analyses. DEL-1 was expressed in alveolar epithelial cells of mice. Compared with that in the control group, DEL-1 was expressed at low levels in the lungs of LPS-challenged mice. LPS injured the lungs in mice, as evidenced by an increase in alveolar wall thickness, inflammatory cell infiltration in the stroma, and alveolar collapse. AAV-mediated DEL-1 overexpression attenuated LPS-induced lung injury and inhibited the release of TNF-α, IL-6, and IL-1β. DEL-1 overexpression also attenuated LPS-induced oxidative stress by decreasing lactic dehydrogenase (LDH), myeloperoxidase (MPO), malondialdehyde (MDA), and reactive oxygen species (ROS) activities and increasing superoxide dismutase (SOD) activity. In addition, DEL-1 prevented eosinophil recruitment into lung tissues and inhibited eotaxin production. This study revealed the beneficial role of DEL-1 in preventing LPS-induced ALI in mice. Therefore, DEL-1 can protect lung tissues against LPS-induced inflammation, oxidative stress, and eosinophil recruitment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Liquiritigenin protects against myocardial ischemic by inhibiting oxidative stress, apoptosis, and L-type Ca2&#43; channels</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35747908/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35747908/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Liquiritigenin (Lq) offers cytoprotective effects against various cardiac injuries, but its beneficial effects on myocardial ischemic (MI) injury and the related mechanisms remain unclear. In the in vivo study, an animal model of MI was induced by intraperitoneal injection of isoproterenol (Iso, 85 mg/kg). ECG, heart rate, serum levels of CK and CK-MB, histopathological changes, and reactive oxygen species (ROS) levels were all measured. In vitro, H9c2 cells were divided into four groups and treated for 24 hr with liquiritigenin (30 μmol/L and 100 μmol/L) followed with CoCl&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; (800 μmol/L) for another 24 hr. Cell viability, apoptosis, mitochondrial membrane potential, and intracellular Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt; concentration ([Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt; ]&lt;sub&gt;i&lt;/sub&gt;) were then assessed. The L-type Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt; current (I&lt;sub&gt;Ca-L&lt;/sub&gt;) was detected using a patch clamp technique on isolated rat ventricular myocytes. The myocyte contraction and Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt; transients were measured using an IonOptix detection system. The remarkable cardiac injury and generation of intracellular ROS induced by Iso were alleviated via treatment with Lq. CoCl&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; administration induced cell apoptosis, mitochondrial dysfunction, and Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt; overload in H9c2; Lq reduces these deleterious effects of CoCl&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;. Meanwhile, Lq blocked I&lt;sub&gt;Ca-L&lt;/sub&gt; in a dose-dependent manner. The half-maximal inhibitory concentration of Lq was 110.87 μmol/L. Lq reversibly reduced the amplitude of cell contraction as well as the Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt; transients. The results show that Lq protects against MI injury by antioxidation, antiapoptosis, counteraction mitochondrial dysfunction, and inhibition of I&lt;sub&gt;Ca-L&lt;/sub&gt;, thus damping intracellular Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
