<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Oxidative Stress | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/oxidative-stress/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/oxidative-stress/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Oxidative Stress</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Oxidative Stress</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/oxidative-stress/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>MiR-217-5p inhibits smog (PM2.5)-induced inflammation and oxidative stress response of mouse lung tissues and macrophages through targeting STAT1</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36040387/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36040387/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Objective:&lt;/em&gt; To explore the roles of macrophages&amp;rsquo; miR-217-5p in the process of PM2.5 induced acute lung injury.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; GEO database and KEGG pathway enrichment analysis as well as GSEA were used to predicted the miRNA and associated target signals. And then mice and RAW246.7 macrophages treated with PM2.5 to imitate PM2.5 induced acute lung injury environment and then transfected with miR-217-5p NC or miR-217-5p mimic. The levels of inflammatory factors TNF-α and anti-inflammatory factor IL-10 of mice serum were tested by ELISA. And the pathological changes and ROS level of mouse lung tissues were stained by HE and DHE staining. The proteins expression of phosphorylated-STAT1, total-STAT1, TNF-α, IFN-γ as well as p47, gp91, NOX4 in mice or RAW264.7 cells were tested by western blot or immunofluorescence of RAW264.7 cell slides.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; The results of bioinformatics analysis indicated the miR-217 as well as STAT1 were involved PM2.5 associated lung injury. After exposure to PM2.5, the decreased levels of serum TNF-α but not IL-10, consistent with reduced macrophages&amp;rsquo; accumulation as well as decreased ROS levels in lung tissues in miR-217-5p mimic group vs miR-217-5p NC group mice, and moreover, the protein expression levels of phosphorylated&amp;ndash;STAT1, total-STAT1, TNF-α, IFN-γ, p47, gp91 and NOX4 in mouse lung tissues and RTAW246.7 macrophages cells were all significantly reduced with miR-217-5p mimic administration. The above phenomena were reversed by specific STAT1-inhibitor HY-N8107.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; miR-217-5p suppressed the activated STAT1-signal induced inflammation and oxidative stress trigged by PM2.5 in macrophages and resulted in the decreased lung injure caused by PM2.5.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Urinary profile of PAHs and related compounds in women working in beauty salons</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36029813/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36029813/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;First survey of urinary PAHs, 1-OHP and TTMA levels in women working in beauty salons;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;High PAHs, 1-OHP and TTMA levels were detected in urine of beauticians after the work shift.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The urinary PAHs, 1-OHP and TTMA were correlated with “personal care products (PCPs) usage”.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some PAHs were associated with oxidative stress/kidney injury biomarkers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Beauty activities can be considered as a major source of PAHs, 1-OHP and TTMA exposures.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Polycyclic aromatic hydrocarbons (PAHs) are a group of chemical compounds which interest to human biological monitoring researches because of their potential carcinogenic, mutagenic, and teratogenic properties. However, the exposure of female beauticians to these contaminants is not well-reported. For biomonitoring of potential exposure of female cosmeticians to PAHs in beauty salons, urine samples were taken from cosmetologist women (n = 50.00) and housewives (n = 35.00) as the exposure group (EG) and control group (CG), respectively. Next, unmetabolized PAHs levels as well as the concentration of - 1-hydroxypyrene (1-OHP) were analyzed in these specimens. In addition, since benzene has some common source with PAHs, in this study t, t&amp;rsquo;-Muconic acid (TTMA) level was also determined as the metabolite and indicator of exposure to benzene. The results indicated a high detection frequency of the target compounds (PAHs, 1-OHP and TTMA) in the urine specimens of beauticians. The results also showed that there is a significant difference between the concentration of these pollutants in the urine specimens of the exposure and control groups. The median concentration of ΣPAHs, 1-OHP, and TTMA in the before exposure (BE) specimens collected from the exposure group were 337.42 ng/L, 593.92 ng/L, and 247.90 μg/L, respectively. However, a higher concentration of these contaminants was observed in the after exposure specimens with a median concentration of 423.29 ng/L, 745.03 ng/L, and 310.97 μg/L, respectively. In terms of contribution of PAHs compounds in total toxic equivalents, DahA, BaP, and IndP with 59.03, 28.73, and 2.86 % had the largest share. In this study, it was also observed that some kidney damage biomarkers as well as some oxidative stress injury biomarkers are positively and significantly correlated with the urinary values of ∑PAHs. Thus, it can be concluded that high health risks threaten the female beauticians regarding kidney injury and DNA oxidative stress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rhabdomyolysis-induced acute kidney injury and concomitant apoptosis induction via ROS-mediated ER stress is efficaciously counteracted by epigallocatechin gallate</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36028100/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36028100/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rhabdomyolysis induced acute kidney injury (RIAKI) is a life-threatening condition responsible for approximately 19-58% of AKI cases worldwide. We performed an intramuscular injection of glycerol (10 mL/kg) in male wistar rats to induce AKI. Epigallocatechin gallate (EGCG) was administered for 3 consecutive days to evaluate its protective effects. We observed significant downregulation in serum creatinine, blood urea nitrogen (BUN) and LDH at different time points on EGCG treatment groups in a dose-dependent manner. Similarly, H&amp;amp;E staining also revealed that EGCG was able to reduce the formation of damaged tubules and tubular necrosis which was prominently spread throughout the kidney tissue of glycerol treatment group. Concomitantly, we observed upregulated inflammation, ER stress and elevated oxidative stress in the glycerol treated group only, which was significantly normalized upon EGCG treatment in both in vitro and in vivo studies. The occurrence of apoptosis in kidney tubules was found to be relatively higher in glycerol treated group and H2O2 treated HEK-293 cells. The results obtained after EGCG treatment revealed a significant decrease in apoptotic cell population, which was further validated by immunofluorescence staining against p53 and comet assay in HEK-293 cells and p53 IHC in kidney tissues. Western blotting also revealed a systemic downregulation of intrinsic mitochondrial apoptotic pathway markers such as bax, bcl-2, pro and cleaved caspase 3, caspase 9 and PARP1. Additionally, the results for flow cytometry analysis and TUNEL assay corroborated apoptotic equilibrium. Conclusively, we reckon EGCG as a multi-therapeutic natural product that can be used the for treatment of AKI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Colchicine improves severe acute pancreatitis-induced acute lung injury by suppressing inflammation, apoptosis and oxidative stress in rats</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36076491/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36076491/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Inflammation, apoptosis and oxidative stress play critical roles in severe acute pancreatitis (SAP).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Colchicine (COL) mitigates severe acute pancreatitis-associated lung injury (SAP-ALI) in rats model.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Colchicine limits inflammation, apoptosis and oxidative stress in SAP-ALI.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Inflammation, apoptosis and oxidative stress contribute to the development of severe acute pancreatitis-associated acute lung injury (SAP-ALI). Currently, there is no curative treatment for SAP-ALI in the clinic. This study investigated the potential therapeutic role and mechanisms of colchicine in a rat model of SAP-ALI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; Male Sprague-Dawley rats were randomized and administrated intragastrically with vehicle saline or colchicine (0.5 mg/kg/day) for seven days, followed by injecting sodium taurocholate to induce SAP-ALI. Together with a healthy control group of rats, their pancreatic and lung tissues and plasma samples were collected for histology, enzyme-linked immunosorbent assay (ELISA), immunoblot, immunohistochemistry, and immunofluorescence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; Compared with the sham controls, the SAP group of rats with vehicle saline treatment displayed severe damages, inflammation with many neutrophil and macrophage infiltrates in pancreatic and lung tissues, accompanied by elevated levels of plasma interleukin-1β (IL-1β), IL-6 and tumor necrosis factor (TNF)-α, which were significantly mitigated in colchicine-treated SAP + COL group of rats. Furthermore, colchicine treatment significantly attenuated nuclear factor kappa-B (NF-κB)-p65, signal transducer and activator of transcription 3 (STAT3) and protein kinase B (AKT) phosphorylation, reduced inducible nitric oxide synthase (iNOS) and 4-Hydroxynonenal expression, ROS production and cell apoptosis by decreasing caspase-3 cleavage, Bax expression, but increasing Bcl-2, nuclear factor erythroid 2-related factor 2 (Nrf2) and heme oxygenase-1 (HO-1) expression in pancreatic and lung tissues, relative to the SAP group of rats.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/em&gt; Colchicine treatment significantly mitigated the severity of SAP-ALI by inhibiting inflammation, oxidative stress and cell apoptosis in rats.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
