<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Kidney | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/kidney/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/kidney/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Kidney</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Kidney</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/kidney/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gasdermins and pyroptosis in the kidney</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/36596918/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/36596918/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pyroptosis is a form of regulated cell death that is mediated by the membrane-targeting, pore-forming gasdermin family of proteins. Pyroptosis was initially described as a caspase 1- and inflammasome-dependent cell death pathway typified by the loss of membrane integrity and the secretion of cytokines such as IL-1β. However, gasdermins are now recognized as the principal effectors of this form of regulated cell death; activated gasdermins insert into cell membranes, where they form pores that result in the secretion of cytokines, alarmins and damage-associated molecular patterns and cause cell membrane rupture. It is now evident that gasdermins can be activated by inflammasome- and caspase-independent mechanisms in multiple cell types and that crosstalk occurs between pyroptosis and other cell death pathways. Although they are important for host antimicrobial defence, a growing body of evidence supports the notion that pyroptosis and gasdermins have pathological roles in cancer and several non-microbial diseases involving the gut, liver and skin. The well-documented roles of inflammasome activity and apoptosis pathways in kidney diseases suggests that gasdermins and pyroptosis may also be involved to some extent. However, despite some evidence for involvement of pyroptosis in the context of acute kidney injury and chronic kidney disease, our understanding of gasdermin biology and pyroptosis in the kidney remains limited.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Role of necroptosis in kidney health and disease</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/36596919/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/36596919/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Key points&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Necroptosis is a form of programmed cell death that leads to cell lysis and an inflammatory response in neighbouring tissues; dysregulation of the pathway is widely implicated in kidney diseases.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The core regulators of the necroptosis pathway are the kinases, RIPK1 and RIPK3, and the executioner pseudokinase, MLKL; each of these proteins is regulated by diverse interactions and modifications.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Most experimental studies of necroptosis in kidney diseases have been performed in rodent models of disease; further studies are therefore essential to define the contribution of this cell death mode to human kidney diseases.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RIPK1 inhibitors are currently being explored in clinical trials to treat neuronal and inflammatory diseases, but so far, the results have not been convincing; future trials are required to establish the viability of targeting necroptosis in kidney diseases.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cell death, particularly that of tubule epithelial cells, contributes critically to the pathophysiology of kidney disease. A body of evidence accumulated over the past 15 years has ascribed a central pathophysiological role to a particular form of regulated necrosis, termed necroptosis, to acute tubular necrosis, nephron loss and maladaptive renal fibrogenesis. Unlike apoptosis, which is a non-immunogenic process, necroptosis results in the release of cellular contents and cytokines, which triggers an inflammatory response in neighbouring tissue. This necroinflammatory environment can lead to severe organ dysfunction and cause lasting tissue injury in the kidney. Despite evidence of a link between necroptosis and various kidney diseases, there are no available therapeutic options to target this process. Greater understanding of the molecular mechanisms, triggers and regulators of necroptosis in acute and chronic kidney diseases may identify shortcomings in current approaches to therapeutically target necroptosis regulators and lead to the development of innovative therapeutic approaches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lycopene Attenuates Di(2-ethylhexyl) Phthalate-Induced Mitochondrial Damage and Inflammation in Kidney via cGAS-STING Signaling</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36583613/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36583613/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Di(2-ethylhexyl) phthalate (DEHP) is a highly harmful and persistent environmental pollutant. Due to its unique chemical composition, it frequently dissolves and enters the environment to endanger human and animal health. Lycopene is a natural bioactive component that can potentially reduce the risk of environmental factor-induced chronic diseases. The present study sought to explore the role and underlying mechanism of lycopene (LYC) on DEHP-induced renal inflammatory response and apoptosis. In this study, mice were orally treated with LYC (5 mg/kg BW/day) and/or DEHP (500 or 1000 mg/kg BW/day) for 28 days. Our results indicated that LYC prevented DEHP-induced histopathological alterations and ultrastructural injuries, including decreased mitochondrial membrane potential (ΔΨm), PINK1/Parkin pathway-mediated mitophagy, and mitochondrial energetic deficit. When damaged mitochondria release mitochondrial DNA (mtDNA) into cytosol, LYC can alleviate inflammation and apoptosis caused by DEHP exposure by activating the cyclic GMP-AMP synthase-stimulator of interferon gene (cGAS-STING) signal pathway. Collectively, our data demonstrate that LYC can reduce mitophagy caused by DEHP exposure by activating the PINK1/Parkin pathway and then reduce renal inflammation and apoptosis through the cGAS-STING pathway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The transcription factor ATF4 mediates endoplasmic reticulum stress related podocyte injury and slit diaphragm defects</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36587794/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36587794/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mutations in &lt;em&gt;OSGEP&lt;/em&gt; and four other genes that encode subunits of the KEOPS complex cause Galloway-Mowat syndrome, a severe, inherited kidney-neurological disease. The complex catalyzes an essential posttranscriptional modification of tRNA and its loss of function induces endoplasmic reticulum (ER) stress. Here, using Drosophila melanogaster garland nephrocytes and cultured human podocytes, we aimed to elucidate the molecular pathogenic mechanisms of KEOPS related glomerular disease and to test pharmacological inhibition of ER stress related signaling as a therapeutic principle. We found that ATF4, an ER stress mediating transcription factor, or its fly orthologue Crc, were upregulated in both fly nephrocytes and human podocytes. Knockdown of Tcs3, a fly orthologue of OSGEP, caused slit diaphragm defects, recapitulating the human kidney phenotype. &lt;em&gt;OSGEP&lt;/em&gt; cDNA with mutations found in patients lacked the capacity for rescue. Genetic interaction studies in Tcs3 deficient nephrocytes revealed that Crc mediates not only cell injury, but surprisingly also slit diaphragm defects, and that genetic or pharmacological inhibition of Crc activation attenuates both phenotypes. These findings are conserved in human podocytes where ATF4 inhibition improved the viability of podocytes with OSGEP knockdown, with chemically-induced ER stress, and where ATF4 target genes and pro-apoptotic gene clusters are upregulated upon OSGEP knockdown. Thus, our data identify ATF4 mediated signaling as a molecular link between ER stress, slit diaphragm defects, podocyte injury, and suggest that modulation of ATF4 signaling may be a potential therapeutic target for certain podocyte diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1,2-Bis(2-aminophenoxy)ethane- N, N, N&#39;, N&#39;-tetraacetic Acid Acetoxymethyl Ester Loaded Reactive Oxygen Species Responsive Hyaluronic Acid-Bilirubin Nanoparticles for Acute Kidney Injury Therapy via Alleviating Calcium Overload Mediated Endoplasmic Reticulum Stress</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36574627/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36574627/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Calcium overload is one of the early determinants of the core cellular events that contribute to the pathogenesis of acute kidney injury (AKI), which include oxidative stress, ATP depletion, calcium overload, and inflammatory response with self-amplifying and interactive feedback loops that ultimately lead to cellular injury and renal failure. Excluding adjuvant therapy, there are currently no approved pharmacotherapies for the treatment of AKI. Using an adipic dihydride linker, we modified the hyaluronic acid polymer chain with a potent antioxidant, bilirubin, to produce an amphiphilic conjugate. Subsequently, we developed a kidney-targeted and reactive oxygen species (ROS)-responsive drug delivery system based on the flash nanocomplexation method to deliver a well-known intracellular calcium chelator, 1,2-bis(2-aminophenoxy)ethane-N,N,N&amp;rsquo;,N&amp;rsquo;-tetraacetic acid acetoxymethyl ester (BAPTA-AM, BA), with the goal of rescuing renal cell damage via rapidly scavenging of intracellularly overloaded Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt;. In the ischemia-reperfusion (I/R) induced AKI rat model, a single dose of as-prepared formulation (BA 100 μg·kg&lt;sup&gt;-1&lt;/sup&gt;) 6 h post-reperfusion significantly reduced renal function indicators by more than 60% within 12 h, significantly alleviated tissular pathological changes, ameliorated tissular oxidative damage, significantly inhibited apoptosis of renal tubular cells and the expression of renal tubular marker kidney injury molecule 1, etc., thus greatly reducing the risk of kidney failure. Mechanistically, the treatment with BA-loaded NPs significantly inhibited the activation of the ER stress cascade response (IRE1-TRAF2-JNK, ATF4-CHOP, and ATF6 axis) and regulated the downstream apoptosis-related pathway while also reducing the inflammatory response. The BA-loaded NPs hold great promise as a potential therapy for I/R injury-related diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Nephroprotective Effects of Hibiscus sabdariffa Leaf and Ellagic Acid in Vitro and in Vivo Models of Hyperuricemic Nephropathy</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36562602/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36562602/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hyperuricemic nephropathy (HN) is caused by urate crystals that get deposited in the kidney and contribute to renal fibrosis. Uric acid (UA) has been proven to directly cause renal mesangial cell oxidative stress and fibrosis in the pathogenesis of HN. Some antioxidants can be used as chemopreventive agents of HN. &lt;em&gt;Hibiscus sabdariffa&lt;/em&gt; leaf extracts (HLE), rich in polyphenol, have been shown to possess hypoglycemic, antioxidant, hypolipidemic, antiatherosclerotic, and anticancer effects. The aim of the study is to examine the inhibitory effect of HLE and its main component ellagic acid (EA) on renal fibrosis. &lt;em&gt;In vitro&lt;/em&gt;, mouse renal glomerular mesangial SV40MES13 cells pretreated with UA were demonstrated to trigger obvious morphological changes and viability loss, as well as affect matrix metalloproteinases (MMPs) activities. Noncytotoxic doses of HLE and EA abolished the UA-induced cell injury and MMP-2/9 secretion. In addition, HLE and EA exhibited antioxidant and anti-inflammatory effects on the UA-treated cells with a reduction in transforming growth factor-beta (TGF-β) production. Next, the UA-activated pro-fibrotic factors, extracellular matrix (ECM) deposition, and epithelial-mesenchymal-transition (EMT) were inhibited by HLE or EA. Mechanistic assays indicated that antifibrotic effects of HLE might be mediated via TGF-β/Smad signaling, as confirmed by the transfection of Smad7 siRNA. &lt;em&gt;In vivo&lt;/em&gt;, HLE and EA supplementations significantly alleviated HN development, which may result from inhibiting adenine-induced TGF-β production accompanying oxidative stress and inflammation, as well as fibrogenesis. Our data imply that EA-enriched HLE regulates the TGF-β/Smad signaling, which in turn led to reduced renal mesangial cell injury and fibrosis in HN and provided a new mechanism for its nephroprotective activity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The transcription factor Fosl1 preserves Klotho expression and protects from acute kidney injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36565807/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36565807/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Increased expression of AP-1 transcription factor components has been reported in acute kidney injury (AKI). However, the role of specific components, such as Fosl1, in tubular cells or AKI is unknown. Upstream regulator analysis of murine nephrotoxic AKI transcriptomics identified AP-1 as highly upregulated. Among AP-1 canonical components, Fosl1 was found to be upregulated in two transcriptomics datasets from nephrotoxic murine AKI induced by folic acid or cisplatin and from proximal tubular cells exposed to TWEAK, a cytokine mediator of AKI. Fosl1 was minimally expressed in the kidneys of control uninjured mice. Increased Fosl1 protein was localized to proximal tubular cell nuclei in AKI. In human AKI, FOSL1 was found present in proximal tubular cells in kidney sections and in urine along with increased urinary FOSL1 mRNA. Selective Fosl1 deficiency in proximal tubular cells (Fosl1Δtub) increased the severity of murine cisplatin- or folate-induced AKI as characterized by lower kidney function, more severe kidney inflammation and Klotho downregulation. Indeed, elevated AP-1 activity was observed after cisplatin-induced AKI in Fosl1Δtub mice compared to wild type mice. More severe Klotho downregulation preceded more severe kidney dysfunction. The Klotho promoter was enriched in Fosl1 binding sites and Fosl1 bound to the Klotho promoter in cisplatin-AKI. In cultured proximal tubular cells, Fosl1 targeting increased the proinflammatory response and downregulated Klotho. In vivo, recombinant Klotho administration protected Fosl1Δtub mice from cisplatin-AKI. Thus, increased proximal tubular Fosl1 expression during AKI is an adaptive response, preserves Klotho. and limits the severity of tubular cell injury and AKI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kir4.2 mediates proximal potassium effects on glutaminase activity and kidney injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36543132/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36543132/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;K&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; deficiency causes kidney-specific injury and inflammation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Injury effects are dependent on the proximal K&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; channel Kir4.2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kir4.2 mediates activation of the ammoniagenesis pathway under low-K&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; conditions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kidney deletion of glutaminase prevents low-K&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt;-mediated kidney injury&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Summary&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inadequate potassium (K&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt;) consumption correlates with increased mortality and poor cardiovascular outcomes. Potassium effects on blood pressure have been described previously; however, whether or not low K&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; independently affects kidney disease progression remains unclear. Here, we demonstrate that dietary K&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; deficiency causes direct kidney injury. Effects depend on reduced blood K&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; and are kidney specific. In response to reduced K&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt;, the channel Kir4.2 mediates altered proximal tubule (PT) basolateral K&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; flux, causing intracellular acidosis and activation of the enzyme glutaminase and the ammoniagenesis pathway. Deletion of either Kir4.2 or glutaminase protects from low-K&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; injury. Reduced K&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt;also mediates injury and fibrosis in a model of aldosteronism. These results demonstrate that the PT epithelium, like the distal nephron, is K&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; sensitive, with reduced blood K&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; causing direct PT injury. Kir4.2 and glutaminase are essential mediators of this injury process, and we identify their potential for future targeting in the treatment of chronic kidney disease.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tubular epithelial cells-derived small extracellular vesicle-VEGF-A promotes peritubular capillary repair in ischemic kidney injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36528739/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36528739/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Peritubular capillaries (PTCs) are closely related to renal tubules in structure and function, and both are pivotal regulators in the development and progression of acute kidney injury (AKI). However, the mechanisms that underlie the interaction between PTCs and tubules during AKI remain unclear. Here we explored a new mode of tubulovascular crosstalk mediated by small extracellular vesicles (sEV) after AKI. In response to renal ischemia/reperfusion (I/R) injury, endothelial proliferation of PTCs and tubular expression of vascular endothelial growth factor-A (VEGF-A) were increased, accompanied by a remarkable redistribution of cytoplasmic VEGF-A to the basolateral side of tubular cells. Meanwhile, the secretion mode of VEGF-A was converted in the injured tubular cells, which showed a much greater tendency to secrete VEGF-A via sEV other than the free form. Interestingly, tubular cell-derived VEGF-A-enriched sEV (sEV-VEGF-A) turned out to promote endothelial proliferation which was regulated by VEGF receptors 1 and 2. Furthermore, inhibition of renal sEV secretion by Rab27a knockdown resulted in a significant decrease in the proliferation of peritubular endothelial cells in vivo. Importantly, taking advantage of the newly recognized endogenous repair response of PTCs, exogenous supplementation of VEGF-A + sEV efficiently recused PTC rarefaction, improved renal perfusion, and halted the AKI to CKD transition. Taken together, our study uncovered a novel intrinsic repair response after AKI through renal tubule-PTC crosstalk via sEV-VEGF-A, which could be exploited as a promising therapeutic angiogenesis strategy in diseases with ischemia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cerium oxide-based nanozyme suppresses kidney calcium oxalate crystal depositions via reversing hyperoxaluria-induced oxidative stress damage</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36482378/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36482378/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oxidative stress damage to renal epithelial cells is the main pathological factor of calcium oxalate calculi formation. The development of medicine that could alleviate oxidative damage has become the key to the prevention and treatment of urolithiasis. Herein, porous nanorods CeO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; nanoparticles (CNPs) were selected from CeO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; with different morphologies as an antioxidant reagent to suppress kidney calcium oxalate crystal depositions with excellent oxidation resistance due to its larger specific surface area. The reversible transformation from Ce&lt;sup&gt;3+&lt;/sup&gt; to Ce&lt;sup&gt;4+&lt;/sup&gt; could catalyze the decomposition of excess free radicals and act as a biological antioxidant enzyme basing on its strong ability to scavenge free radicals. The protection capability of CNP&lt;sub&gt;S&lt;/sub&gt; against oxalate-induced damage and the effect of CNP&lt;sub&gt;S&lt;/sub&gt; on calcium oxalate crystallization were studied. CNP&lt;sub&gt;S&lt;/sub&gt; could effectively reduce reactive oxygen species production, restore mitochondrial membrane potential polarity, recover cell cycle progression, reduce cell death, and inhibit the formation of calcium oxalate crystals on the cell surface in vitro. The results of high-throughput sequencing of mRNA showed that CNPs could protect renal epithelial cells from oxidative stress damage caused by high oxalate by suppressing the expression gene of cell surface adhesion proteins. In addition, CNP&lt;sub&gt;S&lt;/sub&gt; can significantly reduce the pathological damage of renal tubules and inhibit the deposition of calcium oxalate crystals in rat kidneys while having no significant side effect on other organs and physiological indicators in vivo. Our results provide a new strategy for CNP&lt;sub&gt;S&lt;/sub&gt; as a potential for clinical prevention of crystalline kidney injury and crystal deposition.
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Targeting endogenous kidney regeneration using anti-IL11 therapy in acute and chronic models of kidney disease</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36470928/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36470928/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The kidney has large regenerative capacity, but this is compromised when kidney damage is excessive and renal tubular epithelial cells (TECs) undergo SNAI1-driven growth arrest. Here we investigate the role of IL11 in TECs, kidney injury and renal repair. IL11 stimulation of TECs induces ERK- and p90RSK-mediated GSK3β inactivation, SNAI1 upregulation and pro-inflammatory gene expression. Mice with acute kidney injury upregulate IL11 in TECs leading to SNAI1 expression and kidney dysfunction, which is not seen in Il11 deleted mice or in mice administered a neutralizing IL11 antibody in either preemptive or treatment modes. In acute kidney injury, anti-TGFβ reduces renal fibrosis but exacerbates inflammation and tubule damage whereas anti-IL11 reduces all pathologies. Mice with TEC-specific deletion of Il11ra1 have reduced pathogenic signaling and are protected from renal injury-induced inflammation, fibrosis, and failure. In a model of chronic kidney disease, anti-IL11 therapy promotes TEC proliferation and parenchymal regeneration, reverses fibroinflammation and restores renal mass and function. These data highlight IL11-induced mesenchymal transition of injured TECs as an important renal pathology and suggest IL11 as a therapeutic target for restoring stalled endogenous regeneration in the diseased kidney.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Low dimensional nanomaterials for treating acute kidney injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/36456976/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/36456976/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acute kidney injury (AKI) is one of the most common severe complications among hospitalized patients. In the absence of specific drugs to treat AKI, hemodialysis remains the primary clinical treatment for AKI patients. AKI treatment has received significant attention recently due to the excellent drug delivery capabilities of low-dimensional nanomaterials (LDNs) and their unique therapeutic effects. Diverse LDNs have been proposed to treat AKI, with promising results and the potential for future clinical application. This article aims to provide an overview of the pathogenesis of AKI and the recent advances in the treatment of AKI using different types of LDNs. In addition, it is intended to provide theoretical support for the design of LDNs and implications for AKI treatment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FFAR4 improves the senescence of tubular epithelial cells by AMPK/SirT3 signaling in acute kidney injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36450712/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36450712/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acute kidney injury (AKI) is a serious clinical complication with high morbidity and mortality rates. Despite substantial progress in understanding the mechanism of AKI, no effective therapy is available for treatment or prevention. We previously found that G protein-coupled receptor (GPCR) family member free fatty acid receptor 4 (FFAR4) agonist TUG891 alleviated kidney dysfunction and tubular injury in AKI mice. However, the versatile role of FFAR4 in kidney has not been well characterized. In the study, the expression of FFAR4 was abnormally decreased in tubular epithelial cells (TECs) of cisplatin, cecal ligation/perforation and ischemia/reperfusion injury-induced AKI mice, respectively. Systemic and conditional TEC-specific knockout of FFAR4 aggravated renal function and pathological damage, whereas FFAR4 activation by TUG-891 alleviated the severity of disease in cisplatin-induced AKI mice. Notably, FFAR4, as a key determinant, was firstly explored to regulate cellular senescence both in injured kidneys of AKI mice and TECs, which was indicated by senescence-associated β-galactosidase (SA-β-gal) activity, marker protein p53, p21, Lamin B1, phospho-histone H2A.X, phospho-Rb expression, and secretory phenotype IL-6 level. Mechanistically, pharmacological activation and overexpression of FFAR4 reversed the decrease of aging-related SirT3 protein, where FFAR4 regulated SirT3 expression to exhibit anti-senescent effect via Gq subunit-mediated CaMKKβ/AMPK signaling in cisplatin-induced mice and TECs. These findings highlight the original role of tubular FFAR4 in cellular senescence via AMPK/SirT3 signaling and identify FFAR4 as a potential drug target against AKI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chromatin accessibility dynamics dictate renal tubular epithelial cell response to injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36443310/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36443310/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Renal tubular epithelial cells (TECs) can initiate an adaptive response to completely recover from mild acute kidney injury (AKI), whereas severe injury often leads to persistence of maladaptive repair and progression to kidney fibrosis. Through profiling of active DNA regulatory elements by ATAC-seq, we reveal widespread, dynamic changes in the chromatin accessibility of TECs after ischemia–reperfusion injury. We show that injury-specific domains of regulatory chromatin become accessible prior to gene activation, creating poised chromatin states to activate the consequent gene expression program and injury response. We further identify RXRα as a key transcription factor in promoting adaptive repair. Activation of RXRα by bexarotene, an FDA-approved RXRα agonist, restores the chromatin state and gene expression program to protect TECs against severe kidney injury. Together, our findings elucidate a chromatin-mediated mechanism underlying differential responses of TECs to varying injuries and identify RXRα as a therapeutic target of acute kidney injury.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sirt3 mitigates LPS-induced mitochondrial damage in renal tubular epithelial cells by deacetylating YME1L1</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36433732/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36433732/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acute kidney injury (AKI) is often secondary to sepsis. Increasing evidence suggests that mitochondrial dysfunction contributes to the pathological process of AKI. In this study, we aimed to examine the regulatory roles of Sirt3 in Lipopolysaccharide (LPS)-induced mitochondrial damage in renal tubular epithelial cells (TECs). Sirt3 knockout mice were intraperitoneally injected with LPS, and cultured TECs were stimulated with LPS to evaluate the effects of Sirt3 on mitochondrial structure and function in TECs. Electron microscopy was used to assess mitochondrial morphology. Immunofluorescence staining was performed to detect protein expression and examine mitochondrial morphology. Western blotting was used to quantify protein expression. We observed that LPS increased apoptosis, induced disturbances in mitochondrial function and dynamics, and downregulated Sirt3 expression in a sepsis-induced AKI mouse model and human proximal tubular (HK-2) cells in vitro. Sirt3 deficiency further exacerbated LPS-induced renal pathological damage, apoptosis and disturbances in mitochondrial function and dynamics. On the contrary, Sirt3 overexpression in HK-2 cells alleviated these lesions. Functional studies revealed that Sirt3 overexpression alleviated LPS-induced mitochondrial damage and apoptosis in TECs by promoting OPA1-mediated mitochondrial fusion through the deacetylation of i-AAA protease (YME1L1), an upstream regulatory molecule of OPA1. Our study has identified Sirt3 as a vital factor that protects against LPS-induced mitochondrial damage and apoptosis in TECs via the YME1L1-OPA1 signaling pathway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Renal Endothelial Cell-Targeted Extracellular Vesicles Protect the Kidney from Ischemic Injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36416304/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36416304/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Endothelial cell injury plays a critical part in ischemic acute kidney injury (AKI) and participates in the progression of AKI. Targeting renal endothelial cell therapy may ameliorate vascular injury and further improve the prognosis of ischemic AKI. Here, P-selectin as a biomarker of ischemic AKI in endothelial cells is identified and P-selectin binding peptide (PBP)-engineered extracellular vesicles (PBP-EVs) with imaging and therapeutic functions are developed. The results show that PBP-EVs exhibit a selective targeting tendency to injured kidneys, while providing spatiotemporal information for the early diagnosis of AKI by quantifying the expression of P-selectin in the kidneys by molecular imaging. Meanwhile, PBP-EVs reveal superior nephroprotective functions in the promotion of renal repair and inhibition of fibrosis by alleviating inflammatory infiltration, improving reparative angiogenesis, and ameliorating maladaptive repair of the renal parenchyma. In conclusion, PBP-EVs, as an ischemic AKI theranostic system that is designed in this study, provide a spatiotemporal diagnosis in the early stages of AKI to help guide personalized therapy and exhibit superior nephroprotective effects, offering proof-of-concept data to design EV-based theranostic strategies to promote renal recovery and further improve long-term outcomes following AKI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A human kidney and liver organoid-based multi-organ-on-a-chip model to study the therapeutic effects and biodistribution of mesenchymal stromal cell-derived extracellular vesicles</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36382606/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36382606/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mesenchymal stromal cell (MSC)-derived small extracellular vesicles (sEVs) show therapeutic potential in multiple disease models, including kidney injury. Clinical translation of sEVs requires further preclinical and regulatory developments, including elucidation of the biodistribution and mode of action (MoA). Biodistribution can be determined using labelled sEVs in animal models which come with ethical concerns, are time-consuming and expensive, and may not well represent human physiology. We hypothesised that, based on developments in microfluidics and human organoid technology, in vitro multi-organ-on-a-chip (MOC) models allow us to study effects of sEVs in modelled human organs like kidney and liver in a semi-systemic manner. Human kidney- and liver organoids combined by microfluidic channels maintained physiological functions, and a kidney injury model was established using hydrogenperoxide. MSC-sEVs were isolated, and their size, density and potential contamination were analysed. These sEVs stimulated recovery of the renal epithelium after injury. Microscopic analysis shows increased accumulation of PKH67-labelled sEVs not only in injured kidney cells, but also in the unharmed liver organoids, compared to healthy control conditions. In conclusion, this new MOC model recapitulates therapeutic efficacy and biodistribution of MSC-sEVs as observed in animal models. Its human background allows for in-depth analysis of the MoA and identification of potential side effects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Effects of folic acid on oxidative damage of kidney in lead-exposed rats</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36458173/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36458173/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Introduction:&lt;/em&gt; Lead (Pb) has many applications in daily life, but in recent years, various problems caused by lead exposure have aroused people&amp;rsquo;s concern. Folic acid is widely found in fruits and has received more attention for its antioxidant function. However, the role of folic acid in lead-induced kidney injury in rats is unclear. This study was designed to investigate the effects of folic acid on oxidative stress and endoplasmic reticulum stress in the kidney of rats caused by lead exposure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; Forty specific pathogen-free male Rattus norvegicus rats were randomly divided into control, lead, intervention, and folic acid groups. The levels of SOD, GSH-Px, GSH, and MDA were measured by biochemical kits. The protein levels of Nrf2, HO-1, CHOP, and GRP78 were measured by immunofluorescence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; This study showed that lead exposure increased the blood levels of lead in mice. However, the intervention of folic acid decreased the levels of lead, but the difference was not statistically significant. Lead exposure causes oxidative stress by decreasing kidney SOD, GSH-Px, and GSH levels and increasing MDA levels. However, folic acid alleviated the oxidative damage caused by lead exposure by increasing the levels of GSH-Px and GSH and decreasing the levels of MDA. Immunofluorescence results showed that folic acid intervention downregulated the upregulation of kidney Nrf2, HO-1, GRP78, and CHOP expression caused by lead exposure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Discussion:&lt;/em&gt; Overall, folic acid alleviates kidney oxidative stress induced by lead exposure by regulating Nrf2 and HO-1, while regulating CHOP and GRP78 to mitigate apoptosis caused by excessive endoplasmic reticulum stress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Organ Crosstalk in Acute Kidney Injury: Evidence and Mechanisms</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/36431113/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/36431113/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acute kidney injury (AKI) is becoming a public health problem worldwide. AKI is usually considered a complication of lung, heart, liver, gut, and brain disease, but recent findings have supported that injured kidney can also cause dysfunction of other organs, suggesting organ crosstalk existence in AKI. However, the organ crosstalk in AKI and the underlying mechanisms have not been broadly reviewed or fully investigated. In this review, we summarize recent clinical and laboratory findings of organ crosstalk in AKI and highlight the related molecular mechanisms. Moreover, their crosstalk involves inflammatory and immune responses, hemodynamic change, fluid homeostasis, hormone secretion, nerve reflex regulation, uremic toxin, and oxidative stress. Our review provides important clues for the intervention for AKI and investigates important therapeutic potential from a new perspective.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Translation Rescue by Targeting Ppp1r15a through Its Upstream Open Reading Frame in Sepsis-Induced Acute Kidney Injury in a Murine Model</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36283811/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36283811/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Translation shutdown is a hallmark of late-phase, sepsis-induced kidney injury. Methods for controlling protein synthesis in the kidney are limited. Reversing translation shutdown requires dephosphorylation of the eukaryotic initiation factor 2 (eIF2) subunit eIF2α; this is mediated by a key regulatory molecule, protein phosphatase 1 regulatory subunit 15A (Ppp1r15a), also known as GADD34.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; To study protein synthesis in the kidney in a murine endotoxemia model and investigate the feasibility of translation control &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt; by boosting the protein expression of Ppp1r15a, we combined multiple tools, including ribosome profiling (Ribo-seq), proteomics, polyribosome profiling, and antisense oligonucleotides, and a newly generated Ppp1r15a knock-in mouse model and multiple mutant cell lines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; We report that translation shutdown in established sepsis-induced kidney injury is brought about by excessive eIF2α phosphorylation and sustained by blunted expression of the counter-regulatory phosphatase Ppp1r15a. We determined the blunted Ppp1r15a expression persists because of the presence of an upstream open reading frame (uORF). Overcoming this barrier with genetic and antisense oligonucleotide approaches enabled the overexpression of Ppp1r15a, which salvaged translation and improved kidney function in an endotoxemia model. Loss of this uORF also had broad effects on the composition and phosphorylation status of the immunopeptidome-peptides associated with the MHC-that extended beyond the eIF2α axis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; We found Ppp1r15a is translationally repressed during late-phase sepsis because of the existence of an uORF, which is a prime therapeutic candidate for this strategic rescue of translation in late-phase sepsis. The ability to accurately control translation dynamics during sepsis may offer new paths for the development of therapies at codon-level precision.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gallic, ellagic acids and their oral combined administration induce kidney, lung, and heart injury after acute exposure in Wistar rats</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36272503/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36272503/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gallic (GA) and ellagic (EA) acids are present in foods, medicinal plants, teas, and dietary supplements. An acute toxicological study was conducted by oral administration of both compounds alone (200, 1000, and 2000 mg/kg) and combined (2000 mg/kg) and their effects on the electron transport chain (ETC) and the ROS production in kidney mitochondria further evaluated. All treatments induced a dose-dependent heart, lung, and kidney injury. However, the intensity of these effects varied according to the substance, with greater cardiac and renal toxicity for EA and pulmonary injury for GA, while the combination attenuated the toxicity of the isolated molecules. All substances inhibited the activity of complexes II, III, and IV of the ETC from renal mitochondria. However, no changes were observed regarding mitochondrial ROS production. These compounds have a non-negligible inherent deleterious potential, so their uncontrolled use at high doses (≥200 mg/kg) could cause undesirable effects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Haemolytic uraemic syndrome</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/36272423/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/36272423/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Haemolytic uraemic syndrome (HUS) is a heterogeneous group of diseases that result in a common pathology, thrombotic microangiopathy, which is classically characterised by the triad of non-immune microangiopathic haemolytic anaemia, thrombocytopenia, and acute kidney injury. In this Seminar, different causes of HUS are discussed, the most common being Shiga toxin-producing Escherichia coli HUS. Identifying the underlying thrombotic microangiopathy trigger can be challenging but is imperative if patients are to receive personalised disease-specific treatment. The quintessential example is complement-mediated HUS, which once carried an extremely high mortality but is now treated with anti-complement therapies with excellent long-term outcomes. Unfortunately, the high cost of anti-complement therapies all but precludes their use in low-income countries. For many other forms of HUS, targeted therapies are yet to be identified.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kidney-Targeted Nanoparticles Loaded with the Natural Antioxidant Rosmarinic Acid for Acute Kidney Injury Treatment</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36253133/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36253133/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acute kidney injury (AKI) is a common clinical disease with high morbidity and mortality, and with a lack of effective drugs for treatment. Oxidative stress is very important in the occurrence and progression of AKI, and antioxidants use is one of the promising treatments. Rosmarinic acid (RA) is a ubiquitous natural polyphenol with powerful antioxidant and anti-inflammatory activities. Due to its inherent characteristic with poor water solubility and inferior bioavailability, its clinical application is impeded. Hence, the authors design a nanoparticle for effectively delivering RA, which is a chemical complex of RA and fourth-generation poly-amidoamine-based amphiphilic polymer (G4-PAMAM). The nanoparticle is modified with l-serine due to the specific interaction between kidney injury molecule-1 (Kim-1) and serine, which eventually generates a promising AKI kidney-targeting nanoparticle (S-G-R). The S-G-R is rapidly cumulated and long-term retained in ischemia-reperfusion-induced AKI kidneys, especially in the damaged renal tubular cells. The S-G-R exhibits more excellent antioxidative and antiapoptotic effects in vitro and has a more outstanding ability to improve the renal function, repair damaged renal tissue, and decrease oxidative stress, inflammatory response and apoptosis of tubular cells in vivo. Overall, this study might develop a safe and effective targeting strategy for the therapy of AKI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comprehensive single-cell transcriptional profiling defines shared and unique epithelial injury responses during kidney fibrosis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36265491/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36265491/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The underlying cellular events driving kidney fibrogenesis and metabolic dysfunction are incompletely understood. Here, we employed single-cell combinatorial indexing RNA sequencing to analyze 24 mouse kidneys from two fibrosis models. We profiled 309,666 cells in one experiment, representing 50 cell types/states encompassing epithelial, endothelial, immune, and stromal populations. Single-cell analysis identified diverse injury states of the proximal tubule, including two distinct early-phase populations with dysregulated lipid and amino acid metabolism, respectively. Lipid metabolism was defective in the chronic phase but was transiently activated in the very early stages of ischemia-induced injury, where we discovered increased lipid deposition and increased fatty acid β-oxidation. Perilipin 2 was identified as a surface marker of intracellular lipid droplets, and its knockdown in vitro disrupted cell energy state maintenance during lipid accumulation. Surveying epithelial cells across nephron segments identified shared and unique injury responses. Stromal cells exhibited high heterogeneity and contributed to fibrogenesis by epithelial-stromal crosstalk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Activation of Stimulator of IFN Genes (STING) Causes Proteinuria and Contributes to Glomerular Diseases</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36198430/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36198430/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; The signaling molecule stimulator of IFN genes (STING) was identified as a crucial regulator of the DNA-sensing cyclic GMP-AMP synthase (cGAS)-STING pathway, and this signaling pathway regulates inflammation and energy homeostasis under conditions of obesity, kidney fibrosis, and AKI. However, the role of STING in causing CKD, including diabetic kidney disease (DKD) and Alport syndrome, is unknown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; To investigate whether STING activation contributes to the development and progression of glomerular diseases such as DKD and Alport syndrome, immortalized human and murine podocytes were differentiated for 14 days and treated with a STING-specific agonist. We used diabetic db/db mice, mice with experimental Alport syndrome, C57BL/6 mice, and STING knockout mice to assess the role of the STING signaling pathway in kidney failure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;In vitro&lt;/em&gt;, murine and human podocytes express all of the components of the cGAS-STING pathway. &lt;em&gt;In vivo&lt;/em&gt;, activation of STING renders C57BL/6 mice susceptible to albuminuria and podocyte loss. STING is activated at baseline in mice with experimental DKD and Alport syndrome. STING activation occurs in the glomerular but not the tubulointerstitial compartment in association with autophagic podocyte death in Alport syndrome mice and with apoptotic podocyte death in DKD mouse models. Genetic or pharmacologic inhibition of STING protects from progression of kidney disease in mice with DKD and Alport syndrome and increases lifespan in Alport syndrome mice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/em&gt; The activation of the STING pathway acts as a mediator of disease progression in DKD and Alport syndrome. Targeting STING may offer a therapeutic option to treat glomerular diseases of metabolic and nonmetabolic origin or prevent their development, progression, or both.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RNA N6 -methyladenosine modifications and potential targeted therapeutic strategies in kidney disease</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/36196023/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/36196023/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Epigenetic modifications have received increasing attention and have been shown to be extensively involved in kidney development and disease progression. Among them, the most common RNA modification, N&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;-methyladenosine (m&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;A), has been shown to dynamically and reversibly exert its functions in multiple ways, including splicing, export, decay and translation initiation efficiency to regulate mRNA fate. Moreover, m&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;A has also been reported to exert biological effects by destabilizing base pairing to modulate various functions of RNAs. Most importantly, an increasing number of kidney diseases, such as renal cell carcinoma, acute kidney injury and chronic kidney disease, have been found to be associated with aberrant m&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;A patterns. In this review, we comprehensively review the critical roles of m&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;A in kidney diseases and discuss the possibilities and relevance of m&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;A-targeted epigenetic therapy, with an integrated comprehensive description of the detailed alterations in specific loci that contribute to cellular processes that are associated with kidney diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tubular cell polyploidy protects from lethal acute kidney injury but promotes consequent chronic kidney disease</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36195583/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36195583/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acute kidney injury (AKI) is frequent, often fatal and, for lack of specific therapies, can leave survivors with chronic kidney disease (CKD). We characterize the distribution of tubular cells (TC) undergoing polyploidy along AKI by DNA content analysis and single cell RNA-sequencing. Furthermore, we study the functional roles of polyploidization using transgenic models and drug interventions. We identify YAP1-driven TC polyploidization outside the site of injury as a rapid way to sustain residual kidney function early during AKI. This survival mechanism comes at the cost of senescence of polyploid TC promoting interstitial fibrosis and CKD in AKI survivors. However, targeting TC polyploidization after the early AKI phase can prevent AKI-CKD transition without influencing AKI lethality. Senolytic treatment prevents CKD by blocking repeated TC polyploidization cycles. These results revise the current pathophysiological concept of how the kidney responds to acute injury and identify a novel druggable target to improve prognosis in AKI survivors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extended longevity geometrically-inverted proximal tubule organoids</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36215909/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36215909/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This study reports the cellular self-organization of primary human renal proximal tubule epithelial cells (RPTECs) around a minimal Matrigel scaffold to produce basal-in and apical-out proximal tubule organoids (tubuloids). These tubuloids are produced and maintained in hanging drop cultures for 90+ days, the longest such culture of any kind reported to date. The tubuloids upregulate maturity markers, such as aquaporin-1 (AQP1) and megalin (LRP2), and exhibit less mesenchymal and proliferation markers, such as vimentin and Ki67, compared to 2D cultures. They also experience changes over time as revealed by a comparison of gene expression patterns of cells in 2D culture and in day 31 and day 67 tubuloids. Gene expression analysis and immunohistochemistry reveal an increase in the expression of megalin, an endocytic receptor that can directly bind and uptake protein or potentially assist protein uptake. The tubuloids, including day 90 tubuloids, uptake fluorescent albumin and reveal punctate fluorescent patterns, suggesting functional endocytic uptake through these receptors. Furthermore, the tubuloids release kidney injury molecule-1 (KIM-1), a common biomarker for kidney injury, when exposed to albumin in both dose- and time-dependent manners. While this study focuses on potential applications for modeling proteinuric kidney disease, the tubuloids may have broad utility for studies where apical proximal tubule cell access is required.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nanodrugs alleviate acute kidney injury: Manipulate RONS at kidney</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/36203963/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/36203963/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;AKI is a common clinical acute syndrome with high morbidity and mortality but without effective clinical drug available.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hypoxia and accumulation of toxic substances are key pathological features of various heterogeneous AKI.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Excessive RONS is the core of the pathological mechanism of AKI.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The development of nanodrugs is expected to achieve successful treatment in AKI.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently, there are no clinical drugs available to treat acute kidney injury (AKI). Given the high prevalence and high mortality rate of AKI, the development of drugs to effectively treat AKI is a huge unmet medical need and a research hotspot. Although existing evidence fully demonstrates that reactive oxygen and nitrogen species (RONS) burst at the AKI site is a major contributor to AKI progression, the heterogeneity, complexity, and unique physiological structure of the kidney make most antioxidant and anti-inflammatory small molecule drugs ineffective because of the lack of kidney targeting and side effects. Recently, nanodrugs with intrinsic kidney targeting through the control of size, shape, and surface properties have opened exciting prospects for the treatment of AKI. Many antioxidant nanodrugs have emerged to address the limitations of current AKI treatments. In this review, we systematically summarized for the first time about the emerging nanodrugs that exploit the pathological and physiological features of the kidney to overcome the limitations of traditional small-molecule drugs to achieve high AKI efficacy. First, we analyzed the pathological structural characteristics of AKI and the main pathological mechanism of AKI: hypoxia, harmful substance accumulation-induced RONS burst at the renal site despite the multifactorial initiation and heterogeneity of AKI. Subsequently, we introduced the strategies used to improve renal targeting and reviewed advances of nanodrugs for AKI: nano-RONS-sacrificial agents, antioxidant nanozymes, and nanocarriers for antioxidants and anti-inflammatory drugs. These nanodrugs have demonstrated excellent therapeutic effects, such as greatly reducing oxidative stress damage, restoring renal function, and low side effects. Finally, we discussed the challenges and future directions for translating nanodrugs into clinical AKI treatment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LC3 lipidation is essential for TFEB activation during the lysosomal damage response to kidney injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32989250/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32989250/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Erratum in:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author Correction: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nature.com/articles/s41556-022-01017-4&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;LC3 lipidation is essential for TFEB activation during the lysosomal damage response to kidney injury&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sensing and clearance of dysfunctional lysosomes is critical for cellular homeostasis. Here we show that transcription factor EB (TFEB)-a master transcriptional regulator of lysosomal biogenesis and autophagy-is activated during the lysosomal damage response, and its activation is dependent on the function of the ATG conjugation system, which mediates LC3 lipidation. In addition, lysosomal damage triggers LC3 recruitment on lysosomes, where lipidated LC3 interacts with the lysosomal calcium channel TRPML1, facilitating calcium efflux essential for TFEB activation. Furthermore, we demonstrate the presence and importance of this TFEB activation mechanism in kidneys in a mouse model of oxalate nephropathy accompanying lysosomal damage. A proximal tubule-specific TFEB-knockout mouse exhibited progression of kidney injury induced by oxalate crystals. Together, our results reveal unexpected mechanisms of TFEB activation by LC3 lipidation and their physiological relevance during the lysosomal damage response.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lycopene attenuates the inflammation and apoptosis in aristolochic acid nephropathy by targeting the Nrf2 antioxidant system</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36198206/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36198206/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lycopene improves renal dysfunction in mice with aristolochic acid nephropathy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lycopene inhibits oxidative stress, inflammation, and apoptosis in the kidney of mice with aristolochic acid nephropathy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Activation of Nrf2 antioxidant signaling pathway is critical to inhibit the development of renal inflammatory response.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lycopene activates the Nrf2 antioxidant system and then inhibits apoptosis.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lycopene (LYC) is a carotenoid, has antioxidant properties. This study investigated whether lycopene attenuates aristolochic acids (AAs) -induced chronic kidney disease. In this experiment, lycopene was used to intervene C57BL/6 mice with renal injury induced by aristolochic acid exposure. The histomorphological changes and serological parameters of the kidney were measured in order to assess the alleviating effect of lycopene on renal injury in aristolochic acid nephropathy. In vitro and in vivo experiments were carried out to verify the main mechanism of action and drug targets of lycopene in improving aristolochic acid nephropathy (AAN) and by various experimental methods such as ELISA, immunohistochemistry, immunofluorescence, Western-blot and qRT-PCR. The results showed that oxidative stress injury was induced in the kidney of mice after AAI exposure, resulting in inflammatory response and tubular epithelial cell apoptosis. The results showed that the Nrf2/HO-1 antioxidant signaling pathway was inhibited after AAI exposure. AAI induces oxidative stress injury in the kidney, which ultimately leads to inflammation and tubular epithelial cell apoptosis. After LYC intervened in the body, it activated Nrf2 nuclear translocation and its downstream HO-1 and NQO1 antioxidant signaling pathways. LYC inhibited ROS production by renal tubular epithelial cells, and alleviated mitochondrial damage. LYC further modulated the TNF-α/NF-κB signaling cascade, thereby reduced the accumulation of inflammatory factors in the renal interstitium. Moreover, LYC was able to up-regulate the expression of Bcl-2, down-regulate Bax expression and inhibit the activation of cleaved forms of Caspase-9 and Caspase-3, which finally attenuated the apoptosis of the mitochondrial pathway induced by AAI exposure. It was concluded that lycopene was able to activate the Nrf2 antioxidant signaling pathway to maintain the homeostasis of renal oxidative stress and ultimately attenuated renal inflammatory response and apoptosis. These results suggested that lycopene can be used as a drug to relieve AAN.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Associations between nephron number and podometrics in human kidneys</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36175177/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36175177/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Podocyte loss and resultant nephron loss are common processes in the development of glomerulosclerosis and chronic kidney disease. While the cortical distribution of glomerulosclerosis is known to be non-uniform, the relationship between the numbers of non-sclerotic glomeruli (NSG), podometrics and zonal differences in podometrics remain incompletely understood. To help define this, we studied autopsy kidneys from 50 adults with median age 68 years and median eGFR 73.5 mL/min/1.73m&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; without apparent glomerular disease in a cross-sectional analysis. The number of NSG per kidney was estimated using the physical dissector/fractionator combination, while podometrics were estimated using model-based stereology. The number of NSG per kidney was directly correlated with podocyte number per tuft and podocyte density. Each additional 100,000 NSG per kidney was associated with 26 more podocytes per glomerulus and 16 podocytes per 10&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt; μm&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; increase in podocyte density. These associations were independent of clinical factors and cortical zone. While podocyte number per glomerulus was similar in the three zones, superficial glomeruli were the smallest and had the highest podocyte density but smallest podocytes. Increasing age and hypertension were associated with lower podocyte number, with age mostly affecting superficial glomeruli, and hypertension mostly affecting juxtamedullary glomeruli. Thus, in this first study to report a direct correlation between the number of NSG and podometrics, we suggest that podocyte number is decreasing in NSG of individuals losing nephrons. However, another possible interpretation may be that more nephrons might protect against further podocyte loss.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A protein encoded by circular ZNF609 RNA induces acute kidney injury by activating the AKT/mTOR autophagy pathway</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36110046/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36110046/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Erratum in:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cell.com/molecular-therapy-family/molecular-therapy/fulltext/S1525-0016%2822%2900610-4&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;A protein encoded by circular ZNF609 RNA induces acute kidney injury by activating the AKT/mTOR-autophagy pathway&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Autophagy plays a crucial role in the development and progression of ischemic acute kidney injury (AKI). However, the function and mechanism of circular RNAs (circRNAs) in the regulation of autophagy in ischemic AKI remain unexplored. Herein, we find that circ-ZNF609, originating from the ZNF609 locus, is highly expressed in the kidney after ischemia/reperfusion injury, and urinary circ-ZNF609 is a moderate predictor for AKI in heart disease patients. Overexpression of circ-ZNF609 can activate AKT3/mTOR signaling and induce autophagy flux impairment and cell apoptosis while inhibiting proliferation in HK-2 cells, which is blocked by silencing circ-ZNF609. Mechanistically, circ-ZNF609 encodes a functional protein consisting of 250 amino acids (aa), termed ZNF609-250aa, the overexpression of which can activate AKT3/mTOR signaling and induce autophagy flux impairment and cell apoptosis in HK-2 cells in vitro and in AKI kidneys in vivo. The blockade of AKT and mTOR signaling with pharmacological inhibitors is capable of reversing ZNF609-250aa-induced autophagy flux impairment and cell apoptosis in HK-2 cells. The present study demonstrates that highly expressed circ-ZNF609-encoded ZNF609-250aa induces cell apoptosis and AKI by impairing the autophagy flux via an AKT/mTOR-dependent mechanism. These findings imply that targeting circ-ZNF609 may be a novel therapy for ischemic AKI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Injectable adhesive self-healing biocompatible hydrogel for haemostasis, wound healing, and postoperative tissue adhesion prevention in nephron-sparing surgery</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36100176/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36100176/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Statement of significance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Extended warm ischemia time during nephron sparing surgery negatively affected postoperative renal function due to the need for hemostasis at the wound with abundant blood supply, and postoperative wound healing and additional adhesions caused by the surgical procedure deserve attention. Based on the efficient and stable adhesion properties of hydrogels and the ability to promote wound healing. Herein, a series of adhesive self-healing biocompatible hydrogels were prepared based on free-radical polymerization of acryloyl-6-aminocaproic acid (AA) and N-acryloyl 2-glycine (NAG) and the ionic coordination between Ca2+ with the abundant carboxyl groups in AA and NAG. AA/NAG/Ca hydrogel showed hemostasis property in nephron sparing surgery model, promote kidney wound healing, and could perform anti-postoperative adhesion efficacy in an abdomen-caecum adhesion model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nephron-sparing surgery is a well-established treatment in patients with T1a renal cell carcinoma; however, the complex suturing process prolongs warm ischaemia time, affects the preservation of normal renal parenchymal function, and causes avoidable postoperative tissue adhesion complications, including chronic abdominal pain, intestinal obstruction, and female infertility. Hence, the design of multifunctional biomaterials with haemostasis, postoperative wound management, and postoperative tissue adhesion prevention properties for nephron-sparing surgeries is urgently needed. In this study, a series of injectable adhesive multifunctional biocompatible hydrogels were designed based on the free-radical polymerisation of monomers acryloyl-6-aminocaproic acid (AA) and N-acryloyl 2-glycine (NAG), and the ionic coordination between Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt; and the abundant carboxyl groups in AA and NAG. AA/NAG/Ca (AA, NAG, and Ca refer to acryloyl-6-aminocaproic acid, N-acryloyl 2-glycine and calcium chloride, respectively) hydrogel exhibited good mechanical properties, swelling and adhesion properties, flexibility, in vitro blood-clotting ability, and cytocompatibility. In vivo experiments on liver injury models and rat/rabbit nephron-sparing surgery models elucidated that the AA/NAG/Ca hydrogel had haemostasis performance and wound healing properties that led to short bleeding time, reduced bleeding volume, and well-organised nephron structures. An abdomen-caecum adhesion model indicated that the AA/NAG/Ca hydrogel showed excellent anti-adhesion properties. In summary, this multifunctional hydrogel exhibited potential for improving haemostasis and wound management in nephron-sparing surgeries, showing potential for clinical application. STATEMENT OF SIGNIFICANCE: Extended warm ischemia time during nephron sparing surgery negatively affected postoperative renal function due to the need for hemostasis at the wound with abundant blood supply, and postoperative wound healing and additional adhesions caused by the surgical procedure deserve attention. Based on the efficient and stable adhesion properties of hydrogels and the ability to promote wound healing. Herein, a series of adhesive self-healing biocompatible hydrogels were prepared based on free-radical polymerization of acryloyl-6-aminocaproic acid (AA) and N-acryloyl 2-glycine (NAG) and the ionic coordination between Ca2+ with the abundant carboxyl groups in AA and NAG. AA/NAG/Ca hydrogel showed hemostasis property in nephron sparing surgery model, promote kidney wound healing, and could perform anti-postoperative adhesion efficacy in an abdomen-caecum adhesion model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Roles and current applications of S-nitrosoglutathione in anti-infective biomaterials</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/36105674/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/36105674/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bacterial infections can compromise the physical and biological functionalities of humans and pose a huge economical and psychological burden on infected patients. Nitric oxide (NO) is a broad-spectrum antimicrobial agent, whose mechanism of action is not affected by bacterial resistance. S-nitrosoglutathione (GSNO), an endogenous donor and carrier of NO, has gained increasing attention because of its potent antibacterial activity and efficient biocompatibility. Significant breakthroughs have been made in the application of GSNO in biomaterials. This review is based on the existing evidence that comprehensively summarizes the progress of antimicrobial GSNO applications focusing on their anti-infective performance, underlying antibacterial mechanisms, and application in anti-infective biomaterials. We provide an accurate overview of the roles and applications of GSNO in antibacterial biomaterials and shed new light on the avenues for future studies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Insulin-like growth factor binding protein 7 promotes acute kidney injury by alleviating poly ADP ribose polymerase 1 degradation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35752325/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35752325/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The novel biomarker, insulin-like growth factor binding protein 7 (IGFBP7), is used clinically to predict different types of acute kidney injury (AKI) and has drawn significant attention as a urinary biomarker. However, as a secreted protein in the circulation of patients with AKI, it is unclear whether IGFBP7 acts as a key regulator in AKI progression, and if mechanisms underlying its upregulation still need to be determined. Here we found that IGFBP7 is highly expressed in the blood and urine of patients and mice with AKI, possibly via a c-Jun-dependent mechanism, and is positively correlated with kidney dysfunction. Global knockout of IGFBP7 ameliorated kidney dysfunction, inflammatory responses, and programmed cell death in murine models of cisplatin-, kidney ischemia/reperfusion-, and lipopolysaccharide-induced AKI. IGFBP7 mainly originated from kidney tubular epithelial cells. Conditional knockout of IGFBP7 from the kidney protected against AKI. By contrast, rescue of IGFBP7 expression in IGFBP7-knockout mice restored kidney damage and inflammation. IGFBP7 function was determined in vitro using recombinant IGFBP7 protein, IGFBP7 knockdown, or overexpression. Additionally, IGFBP7 was found to bind to poly [ADP-ribose] polymerase 1 (PARP1) and inhibit its degradation by antagonizing the E3 ubiquitin ligase ring finger protein 4 (RNF4). Thus, IGFBP7 in circulation acts as a biomarker and key mediator of AKI by inhibiting RNF4/PARP1-mediated tubular injury and inflammation. Hence, over-activation of the IGFBP7/PARP1 axis represents a promising target for AKI treatment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The PINK1/PARK2/optineurin pathway of mitophagy is activated for protection in septic acute kidney injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33137712/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33137712/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sepsis is the major cause of acute kidney injury (AKI) associated with high mortality rates. Mitochondrial dysfunction contributes to the pathophysiology of septic AKI. Mitophagy is an important mitochondrial quality control mechanism that selectively eliminates damaged mitochondria, but its role and regulation in septic AKI remain largely unknown. Here, we demonstrate the induction of mitophagy in mouse models of septic AKI induced by lipopolysaccharide (LPS) treatment or by cecal ligation and puncture. Mitophagy was also induced in cultured proximal tubular epithelial cells exposed to LPS. Induction of mitophagy under these experimental setting was suppressed by pink1 or park2 knockout, indicating the role of the PINK1/PARK2 pathway of mitophagy in septic AKI. In addition, sepsis induced more severe kidney injury and cell apoptosis in pink1 or park2 knockout mice than in wild-type mice, suggesting a beneficial role of mitophagy in septic AKI. Furthermore, in cultured renal tubular cells treated with LPS, knockdown of pink1 or park2 inhibited mitochondrial accumulation of the autophagy adaptor optineurin (OPTN) and silencing Optn inhibited LPS-induced mitophagy. Taken together, these findings suggest that the PINK1/PARK2 pathway of mitophagy plays an important role in mitochondrial quality control, tubular cell survival, and renal function in septic AKI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nuclear receptor PXR targets AKR1B7 to protect mitochondrial metabolism and renal function in AKI</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32404507/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32404507/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acute kidney injury (AKI) is a worldwide public health problem with no specific and satisfactory therapies in clinic. The nuclear pregnane X receptor (PXR) is involved in the progression of multiple diseases, including metabolic diseases, atherosclerosis, hypertension, liver injury, etc. However, its role in kidney injury remains to be understood. In this study, we have investigated the role of PXR in AKI and underlying mechanism(s) involved in its function. PXR was robustly down-regulated and negatively correlated with renal dysfunction in human and animal kidneys with AKI. Silencing PXR in rats enhanced cisplatin-induced AKI and induced severe mitochondrial abnormalities, whereas activating PXR protected against AKI. Using luciferase reporter assays, genomic manipulation, and proteomics data analysis on the kidneys of PXR&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt; rats, we determined that PXR targeted Aldo-keto reductase family 1, member B7 (AKR1B7) to improve mitochondrial function, thereby ameliorating AKI. We confirmed the protective role of PXR against kidney injury using genomic and pharmacologic approaches in an ischemia/reperfusion model of AKI. These findings demonstrate that disabling the PXR/AKR1B7/mitochondrial metabolism axis is an important factor that can contribute to AKI, whereas reestablishing this axis can be useful for treating AKI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wnt/β-catenin signaling mediates both heart and kidney injury in type 2 cardiorenal syndrome</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/30770217/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/30770217/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Erratum in:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Corrigendum to Zhao Y, Wang C, Hong X, et al. &lt;a href=&#34;https://linkinghub.elsevier.com/retrieve/pii/S0085253822006226&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Wnt/β-catenin signaling mediates both heart and kidney injury in type 2 cardiorenal syndrome&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Kidney Int. 2019;95:815-829.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In type 2 cardiorenal syndrome, chronic heart failure is thought to cause or promote chronic kidney disease; however, the underlying mechanisms remain poorly understood. We investigated the role of Wnt signaling in heart and kidney injury in a mouse model of cardiac hypertrophy and heart failure induced by transverse aortic constriction (TAC). At 8 weeks after TAC, cardiac hypertrophy, inflammation, and fibrosis were prominent, and echocardiography confirmed impaired cardiac function. The cardiac lesions were accompanied by upregulation of multiple Wnt ligands and activation of β-catenin, as well as activation of the renin-angiotensin system (RAS). Wnt3a induced multiple components of the RAS in primary cardiomyocytes and cardiac fibroblasts in vitro. TAC also caused proteinuria and kidney fibrosis, accompanied by klotho depletion and β-catenin activation in the kidney. Pharmacologic blockade of β-catenin with a small molecule inhibitor or the RAS with losartan ameliorated cardiac injury, restored heart function, and mitigated the renal lesions. Serum from TAC mice was sufficient to activate β-catenin and trigger tubular cell injury in vitro, indicating a role for circulating factors. Multiple inflammatory cytokines were upregulated in the circulation of TAC mice, and tumor necrosis factor-α was able to inhibit klotho, induce β-catenin activation, and cause tubular cell injury in vitro. These studies identify Wnt/β-catenin signaling as a common pathogenic mediator of heart and kidney injury in type 2 cardiorenal syndrome after TAC. Targeting this pathway could be a promising therapeutic strategy to protect both organs in cardiorenal syndrome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Single-cell transcriptomics of the mouse kidney reveals potential cellular targets of kidney disease</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/29622724/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/29622724/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Touring the kidney, cell by cell&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our kidneys play a critical role in keeping us healthy, a fact of which we are reminded several times each day. This organ&amp;rsquo;s cellular complexity has hindered progress in understanding the mechanisms underlying chronic kidney disease, which affects 10% of the world&amp;rsquo;s population. Using single-cell transcriptional profiling, Park et al. produced a comprehensive cell atlas of the healthy mouse kidney (see the Perspective by Humphreys). An unexpected cell type in the collecting duct appears to be a transitional state between two known cell types. The transition from one cell type to the other is regulated by the Notch signaling pathway and is associated with metabolic acidosis. The authors also find that genetically distinct kidney diseases with common clinical features share common cellular origins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our understanding of kidney disease pathogenesis is limited by an incomplete molecular characterization of the cell types responsible for the organ’s multiple homeostatic functions. To help fill this knowledge gap, we characterized 57,979 cells from healthy mouse kidneys by using unbiased single-cell RNA sequencing. On the basis of gene expression patterns, we infer that inherited kidney diseases that arise from distinct genetic mutations but share the same phenotypic manifestation originate from the same differentiated cell type. We also found that the collecting duct in kidneys of adult mice generates a spectrum of cell types through a newly identified transitional cell. Computational cell trajectory analysis and in vivo lineage tracing revealed that intercalated cells and principal cells undergo transitions mediated by the Notch signaling pathway. In mouse and human kidney disease, these transitions were shifted toward a principal cell fate and were associated with metabolic acidosis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Targeting neural reflex circuits in immunity to treat kidney disease</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/28970585/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/28970585/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Key Points&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Neural circuits that control immunity and inflammation provide novel targets for the treatment of kidney disease and hypertension&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Activation of the cholinergic anti-inflammatory pathway (CAP) blocks splenic-dependent systemic inflammation and acute kidney injury (AKI); non-invasive, nonpharmacological approaches to activate the CAP include ultrasound application and vagus nerve stimulation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Neural circuits that directly regulate kidney function or carry sensory feedback from the kidney to the central nervous system could provide additional mechanisms for bidirectional neuroimmunomodulation of kidney disease&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Interactions between neural circuits and the immune system have important roles in the pathogenesis of hypertension and renal fibrosis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Further defining neuroimmunomodulatory pathways in hypertension could enable the development of selective neuronal stimulatory or inhibitory strategies for lowering blood pressure that could potentially be more effective than renal denervation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Optogenetic tools provide unprecedented opportunities to dissect the neural pathways that control immunity and inflammation and enable the identification of novel approaches to therapy for kidney diseases&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Neural pathways regulate immunity and inflammation via the inflammatory reflex and specific molecular targets can be modulated by stimulating neurons. Neuroimmunomodulation by nonpharmacological methods is emerging as a novel therapeutic strategy for inflammatory diseases, including kidney diseases and hypertension. Electrical stimulation of vagus neurons or treatment with pulsed ultrasound activates the cholinergic anti-inflammatory pathway (CAP) and protects mice from acute kidney injury (AKI). Direct innervation of the kidney, by afferent and efferent neurons, might have a role in modulating and responding to inflammation in various diseases, either locally or by providing feedback to regions of the central nervous system that are important in the inflammatory reflex pathway. Increased sympathetic drive to the kidney has a role in the pathogenesis of hypertension, and selective modulation of neuroimmune interactions in the kidney could potentially be more effective for lowering blood pressure and treating inflammatory kidney diseases than renal denervation. Use of optogenetic tools for selective stimulation of specific neurons has enabled the identification of neural circuits in the brain that modulate kidney function via activation of the CAP. In this Review we discuss evidence for a role of neural circuits in the control of renal inflammation as well as the therapeutic potential of targeting these circuits in the settings of AKI, kidney fibrosis and hypertension.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
