<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Kidney | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/kidney/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/kidney/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Kidney</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Kidney</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/kidney/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>FFAR4 improves the senescence of tubular epithelial cells by AMPK/SirT3 signaling in acute kidney injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36450712/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36450712/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acute kidney injury (AKI) is a serious clinical complication with high morbidity and mortality rates. Despite substantial progress in understanding the mechanism of AKI, no effective therapy is available for treatment or prevention. We previously found that G protein-coupled receptor (GPCR) family member free fatty acid receptor 4 (FFAR4) agonist TUG891 alleviated kidney dysfunction and tubular injury in AKI mice. However, the versatile role of FFAR4 in kidney has not been well characterized. In the study, the expression of FFAR4 was abnormally decreased in tubular epithelial cells (TECs) of cisplatin, cecal ligation/perforation and ischemia/reperfusion injury-induced AKI mice, respectively. Systemic and conditional TEC-specific knockout of FFAR4 aggravated renal function and pathological damage, whereas FFAR4 activation by TUG-891 alleviated the severity of disease in cisplatin-induced AKI mice. Notably, FFAR4, as a key determinant, was firstly explored to regulate cellular senescence both in injured kidneys of AKI mice and TECs, which was indicated by senescence-associated β-galactosidase (SA-β-gal) activity, marker protein p53, p21, Lamin B1, phospho-histone H2A.X, phospho-Rb expression, and secretory phenotype IL-6 level. Mechanistically, pharmacological activation and overexpression of FFAR4 reversed the decrease of aging-related SirT3 protein, where FFAR4 regulated SirT3 expression to exhibit anti-senescent effect via Gq subunit-mediated CaMKKβ/AMPK signaling in cisplatin-induced mice and TECs. These findings highlight the original role of tubular FFAR4 in cellular senescence via AMPK/SirT3 signaling and identify FFAR4 as a potential drug target against AKI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Renal Endothelial Cell-Targeted Extracellular Vesicles Protect the Kidney from Ischemic Injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36416304/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36416304/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Endothelial cell injury plays a critical part in ischemic acute kidney injury (AKI) and participates in the progression of AKI. Targeting renal endothelial cell therapy may ameliorate vascular injury and further improve the prognosis of ischemic AKI. Here, P-selectin as a biomarker of ischemic AKI in endothelial cells is identified and P-selectin binding peptide (PBP)-engineered extracellular vesicles (PBP-EVs) with imaging and therapeutic functions are developed. The results show that PBP-EVs exhibit a selective targeting tendency to injured kidneys, while providing spatiotemporal information for the early diagnosis of AKI by quantifying the expression of P-selectin in the kidneys by molecular imaging. Meanwhile, PBP-EVs reveal superior nephroprotective functions in the promotion of renal repair and inhibition of fibrosis by alleviating inflammatory infiltration, improving reparative angiogenesis, and ameliorating maladaptive repair of the renal parenchyma. In conclusion, PBP-EVs, as an ischemic AKI theranostic system that is designed in this study, provide a spatiotemporal diagnosis in the early stages of AKI to help guide personalized therapy and exhibit superior nephroprotective effects, offering proof-of-concept data to design EV-based theranostic strategies to promote renal recovery and further improve long-term outcomes following AKI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comprehensive single-cell transcriptional profiling defines shared and unique epithelial injury responses during kidney fibrosis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36265491/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36265491/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The underlying cellular events driving kidney fibrogenesis and metabolic dysfunction are incompletely understood. Here, we employed single-cell combinatorial indexing RNA sequencing to analyze 24 mouse kidneys from two fibrosis models. We profiled 309,666 cells in one experiment, representing 50 cell types/states encompassing epithelial, endothelial, immune, and stromal populations. Single-cell analysis identified diverse injury states of the proximal tubule, including two distinct early-phase populations with dysregulated lipid and amino acid metabolism, respectively. Lipid metabolism was defective in the chronic phase but was transiently activated in the very early stages of ischemia-induced injury, where we discovered increased lipid deposition and increased fatty acid β-oxidation. Perilipin 2 was identified as a surface marker of intracellular lipid droplets, and its knockdown in vitro disrupted cell energy state maintenance during lipid accumulation. Surveying epithelial cells across nephron segments identified shared and unique injury responses. Stromal cells exhibited high heterogeneity and contributed to fibrogenesis by epithelial-stromal crosstalk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Insulin-like growth factor binding protein 7 promotes acute kidney injury by alleviating poly ADP ribose polymerase 1 degradation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35752325/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35752325/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The novel biomarker, insulin-like growth factor binding protein 7 (IGFBP7), is used clinically to predict different types of acute kidney injury (AKI) and has drawn significant attention as a urinary biomarker. However, as a secreted protein in the circulation of patients with AKI, it is unclear whether IGFBP7 acts as a key regulator in AKI progression, and if mechanisms underlying its upregulation still need to be determined. Here we found that IGFBP7 is highly expressed in the blood and urine of patients and mice with AKI, possibly via a c-Jun-dependent mechanism, and is positively correlated with kidney dysfunction. Global knockout of IGFBP7 ameliorated kidney dysfunction, inflammatory responses, and programmed cell death in murine models of cisplatin-, kidney ischemia/reperfusion-, and lipopolysaccharide-induced AKI. IGFBP7 mainly originated from kidney tubular epithelial cells. Conditional knockout of IGFBP7 from the kidney protected against AKI. By contrast, rescue of IGFBP7 expression in IGFBP7-knockout mice restored kidney damage and inflammation. IGFBP7 function was determined in vitro using recombinant IGFBP7 protein, IGFBP7 knockdown, or overexpression. Additionally, IGFBP7 was found to bind to poly [ADP-ribose] polymerase 1 (PARP1) and inhibit its degradation by antagonizing the E3 ubiquitin ligase ring finger protein 4 (RNF4). Thus, IGFBP7 in circulation acts as a biomarker and key mediator of AKI by inhibiting RNF4/PARP1-mediated tubular injury and inflammation. Hence, over-activation of the IGFBP7/PARP1 axis represents a promising target for AKI treatment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The PINK1/PARK2/optineurin pathway of mitophagy is activated for protection in septic acute kidney injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33137712/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33137712/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sepsis is the major cause of acute kidney injury (AKI) associated with high mortality rates. Mitochondrial dysfunction contributes to the pathophysiology of septic AKI. Mitophagy is an important mitochondrial quality control mechanism that selectively eliminates damaged mitochondria, but its role and regulation in septic AKI remain largely unknown. Here, we demonstrate the induction of mitophagy in mouse models of septic AKI induced by lipopolysaccharide (LPS) treatment or by cecal ligation and puncture. Mitophagy was also induced in cultured proximal tubular epithelial cells exposed to LPS. Induction of mitophagy under these experimental setting was suppressed by pink1 or park2 knockout, indicating the role of the PINK1/PARK2 pathway of mitophagy in septic AKI. In addition, sepsis induced more severe kidney injury and cell apoptosis in pink1 or park2 knockout mice than in wild-type mice, suggesting a beneficial role of mitophagy in septic AKI. Furthermore, in cultured renal tubular cells treated with LPS, knockdown of pink1 or park2 inhibited mitochondrial accumulation of the autophagy adaptor optineurin (OPTN) and silencing Optn inhibited LPS-induced mitophagy. Taken together, these findings suggest that the PINK1/PARK2 pathway of mitophagy plays an important role in mitochondrial quality control, tubular cell survival, and renal function in septic AKI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nuclear receptor PXR targets AKR1B7 to protect mitochondrial metabolism and renal function in AKI</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32404507/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32404507/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acute kidney injury (AKI) is a worldwide public health problem with no specific and satisfactory therapies in clinic. The nuclear pregnane X receptor (PXR) is involved in the progression of multiple diseases, including metabolic diseases, atherosclerosis, hypertension, liver injury, etc. However, its role in kidney injury remains to be understood. In this study, we have investigated the role of PXR in AKI and underlying mechanism(s) involved in its function. PXR was robustly down-regulated and negatively correlated with renal dysfunction in human and animal kidneys with AKI. Silencing PXR in rats enhanced cisplatin-induced AKI and induced severe mitochondrial abnormalities, whereas activating PXR protected against AKI. Using luciferase reporter assays, genomic manipulation, and proteomics data analysis on the kidneys of PXR&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt; rats, we determined that PXR targeted Aldo-keto reductase family 1, member B7 (AKR1B7) to improve mitochondrial function, thereby ameliorating AKI. We confirmed the protective role of PXR against kidney injury using genomic and pharmacologic approaches in an ischemia/reperfusion model of AKI. These findings demonstrate that disabling the PXR/AKR1B7/mitochondrial metabolism axis is an important factor that can contribute to AKI, whereas reestablishing this axis can be useful for treating AKI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Single-cell transcriptomics of the mouse kidney reveals potential cellular targets of kidney disease</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/29622724/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/29622724/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Touring the kidney, cell by cell&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our kidneys play a critical role in keeping us healthy, a fact of which we are reminded several times each day. This organ&amp;rsquo;s cellular complexity has hindered progress in understanding the mechanisms underlying chronic kidney disease, which affects 10% of the world&amp;rsquo;s population. Using single-cell transcriptional profiling, Park et al. produced a comprehensive cell atlas of the healthy mouse kidney (see the Perspective by Humphreys). An unexpected cell type in the collecting duct appears to be a transitional state between two known cell types. The transition from one cell type to the other is regulated by the Notch signaling pathway and is associated with metabolic acidosis. The authors also find that genetically distinct kidney diseases with common clinical features share common cellular origins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our understanding of kidney disease pathogenesis is limited by an incomplete molecular characterization of the cell types responsible for the organ’s multiple homeostatic functions. To help fill this knowledge gap, we characterized 57,979 cells from healthy mouse kidneys by using unbiased single-cell RNA sequencing. On the basis of gene expression patterns, we infer that inherited kidney diseases that arise from distinct genetic mutations but share the same phenotypic manifestation originate from the same differentiated cell type. We also found that the collecting duct in kidneys of adult mice generates a spectrum of cell types through a newly identified transitional cell. Computational cell trajectory analysis and in vivo lineage tracing revealed that intercalated cells and principal cells undergo transitions mediated by the Notch signaling pathway. In mouse and human kidney disease, these transitions were shifted toward a principal cell fate and were associated with metabolic acidosis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
