<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Kidney | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/kidney/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/kidney/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Kidney</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Kidney</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/kidney/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>TFEB-mediated lysosomal exocytosis alleviates high fat diet-induced lipotoxicity in the kidney</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36649084/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36649084/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Obesity is a major risk factor for end-stage kidney disease. We previously found that lysosomal dysfunction and impaired autophagic flux contributed to lipotoxicity in obesity-related kidney disease, both in humans and experimental animal models. However, the regulatory factors involved in countering renal lipotoxicity are largely unknown. Here we found that palmitic acid (PA) strongly promoted dephosphorylation and nuclear translocation of transcription factor EB (TFEB) by inhibiting the mechanistic target of rapamycin kinase complex 1 (MTORC1) pathway in a Rag GTPase-dependent manner, although these effects gradually diminished after extended treatment. We then investigated the role of TFEB in the pathogenesis of obesity-related kidney disease. Proximal tubular epithelial cell (PTEC)-specific Tfeb-deficient mice fed a high-fat diet (HFD) exhibited greater phospholipid accumulation in enlarged lysosomes, which manifested as multilamellar bodies (MLBs). Activated TFEB mediated lysosomal exocytosis of phospholipids, which help reduce MLB accumulation in PTECs. Furthermore, HFD-fed PTEC-specific Tfeb-deficient mice showed autophagic stagnation and exacerbated injury upon renal ischemia-reperfusion. Finally, higher body mass index was associated with increased vacuolation and decreased nuclear TFEB in the proximal tubules of chronic kidney disease patients. These results indicate a critical role of TFEB-mediated lysosomal exocytosis in counteracting renal lipotoxicity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GPR97 deficiency ameliorates renal interstitial fibrosis in mouse hypertensive nephropathy</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36635422/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36635422/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hypertensive nephropathy (HTN) ranks as the second-leading cause of end-stage renal disease (ESRD). Accumulating evidence suggests that persistent hypertension injures tubular cells, leading to tubulointerstitial fibrosis (TIF), which is involved in the pathogenesis of HTN. G protein-coupled receptors (GPCRs) are implicated in many important pathological and physiological processes and act as important drug targets. In this study, we explored the intrarenal mechanisms underlying hypertension-associated TIF, and particularly, the potential role of GPR97, a member of the adhesion GPCR subfamily, in TIF. A deoxycorticosterone acetate (DOCA)/salt-induced hypertensive mouse model was used. We revealed a significantly upregulated expression of GPR97 in the kidneys, especially in renal tubules, of the hypertensive mice and 10 patients with biopsy-proven hypertensive kidney injury. GPR97-/- mice showed markedly elevated blood pressure, which was comparable to that of wild-type mice following DOCA/salt treatment, but dramatically ameliorated renal injury and TIF. In NRK-52E cells, we demonstrated that knockdown of GPR97 suppressed the activation of TGF-β signaling by disturbing small GTPase RhoA-mediated cytoskeletal reorganization, thus inhibiting clathrin-mediated endocytosis of TGF-β receptors and subsequent Smad activation. Collectively, this study demonstrates that GPR97 contributes to hypertension-associated TIF at least in part by facilitating TGF-β signaling, suggesting that GPR97 is a pivotal intrarenal factor for TIF progression under hypertensive conditions, and therapeutic strategies targeting GPR97 may improve the outcomes of patients with HTN.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LONP1 targets HMGCS2 to protect mitochondrial function and attenuate chronic kidney disease</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36629048/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36629048/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mitochondria comprise the central metabolic hub of cells and their imbalance plays a pathogenic role in chronic kidney disease (CKD). Here, we studied Lon protease 1 (LONP1), a major mitochondrial protease, as its role in CKD pathogenesis is unclear. LONP1 expression was decreased in human patients and mice with CKD, and tubular-specific Lonp1 overexpression mitigated renal injury and mitochondrial dysfunction in two different models of CKD, but these outcomes were aggravated by Lonp1 deletion. These results were confirmed in renal tubular epithelial cells in vitro. Mechanistically, LONP1 downregulation caused mitochondrial accumulation of the LONP1 substrate, 3-hydroxy-3-methylglutaryl-CoA synthase 2 (HMGCS2), which disrupted mitochondrial function and further accelerated CKD progression. Finally, computer-aided virtual screening was performed, which identified a novel LONP1 activator. Pharmacologically, the LONP1 activator attenuated renal fibrosis and mitochondrial dysfunction. Collectively, these results imply that LONP1 is a promising therapeutic target for treating CKD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sesamolin Attenuates Kidney Injury, Intestinal Barrier Dysfunction, and Gut Microbiota Imbalance in High-Fat and High-Fructose Diet-Fed Mice</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36630317/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36630317/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This study investigated the effects of sesamolin on kidney injury, intestinal barrier dysfunction, and gut microbiota imbalance in high-fat and high-fructose (HF-HF) diet-fed mice and explored the underlying correlations among them. The results indicated that sesamolin suppressed metabolic disorders and increased renal function parameters. Histological evaluation showed that sesamolin mitigated renal epithelial cell degeneration and brush border damage. Meanwhile, sesamolin inhibited the endotoxin-mediated induction of the Toll-like receptor 4-related IKKα/NF-κB p65 pathway activation. Additionally, sesamolin mitigated intestinal barrier dysfunction and improved the composition of gut microbiota. The correlation results further indicated that changes in the dominant phyla, including &lt;em&gt;Firmicutes&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Deferribacterota&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Desulfobacterota&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Bacteroidota&lt;/em&gt;, were more highly correlated with a reduction in endotoxemia and metabolic disorders, as well as decreases in intestinal proinflammatory response and related renal risk biomarkers. The results of this study suggest that sesamolin attenuates kidney injuries, which might be associated with its effects on the reduction of endotoxemia and related metabolic disorders through the restoration of the intestinal barrier and the modulation of gut microbiota. Thus, sesamolin may be a potential dietary supplement for protection against obesity-associated kidney injury.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Single-cell transcriptomics reveals a mechanosensitive injury signaling pathway in early diabetic nephropathy</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36627643/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36627643/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Diabetic nephropathy (DN) is the leading cause of end-stage renal disease, and histopathologic glomerular lesions are among the earliest structural alterations of DN. However, the signaling pathways that initiate these glomerular alterations are incompletely understood.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; To delineate the cellular and molecular basis for DN initiation, we performed single-cell and bulk RNA sequencing of renal cells from type 2 diabetes mice (BTBR ob/ob) at the early stage of DN.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; Analysis of differentially expressed genes revealed glucose-independent responses in glomerular cell types. The gene regulatory network upstream of glomerular cell programs suggested the activation of mechanosensitive transcriptional pathway MRTF-SRF predominantly taking place in mesangial cells. Importantly, activation of MRTF-SRF transcriptional pathway was also identified in DN glomeruli in independent patient cohort datasets. Furthermore, ex vivo kidney perfusion suggested that the regulation of MRTF-SRF is a common mechanism in response to glomerular hyperfiltration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; Overall, our study presents a comprehensive single-cell transcriptomic landscape of early DN, highlighting mechanosensitive signaling pathways as novel targets of diabetic glomerulopathy.Finally, using a radiolabelled analogue and a filter-binding assay, we show that erastin binds directly to VDAC2. These results demonstrate that ligands to VDAC proteins can induce non-apoptotic cell death selectively in some tumour cells harbouring activating mutations in the RAS-RAF-MEK pathway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gasdermins and pyroptosis in the kidney</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/36596918/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/36596918/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pyroptosis is a form of regulated cell death that is mediated by the membrane-targeting, pore-forming gasdermin family of proteins. Pyroptosis was initially described as a caspase 1- and inflammasome-dependent cell death pathway typified by the loss of membrane integrity and the secretion of cytokines such as IL-1β. However, gasdermins are now recognized as the principal effectors of this form of regulated cell death; activated gasdermins insert into cell membranes, where they form pores that result in the secretion of cytokines, alarmins and damage-associated molecular patterns and cause cell membrane rupture. It is now evident that gasdermins can be activated by inflammasome- and caspase-independent mechanisms in multiple cell types and that crosstalk occurs between pyroptosis and other cell death pathways. Although they are important for host antimicrobial defence, a growing body of evidence supports the notion that pyroptosis and gasdermins have pathological roles in cancer and several non-microbial diseases involving the gut, liver and skin. The well-documented roles of inflammasome activity and apoptosis pathways in kidney diseases suggests that gasdermins and pyroptosis may also be involved to some extent. However, despite some evidence for involvement of pyroptosis in the context of acute kidney injury and chronic kidney disease, our understanding of gasdermin biology and pyroptosis in the kidney remains limited.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Role of necroptosis in kidney health and disease</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/36596919/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/36596919/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Key points&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Necroptosis is a form of programmed cell death that leads to cell lysis and an inflammatory response in neighbouring tissues; dysregulation of the pathway is widely implicated in kidney diseases.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The core regulators of the necroptosis pathway are the kinases, RIPK1 and RIPK3, and the executioner pseudokinase, MLKL; each of these proteins is regulated by diverse interactions and modifications.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Most experimental studies of necroptosis in kidney diseases have been performed in rodent models of disease; further studies are therefore essential to define the contribution of this cell death mode to human kidney diseases.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RIPK1 inhibitors are currently being explored in clinical trials to treat neuronal and inflammatory diseases, but so far, the results have not been convincing; future trials are required to establish the viability of targeting necroptosis in kidney diseases.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cell death, particularly that of tubule epithelial cells, contributes critically to the pathophysiology of kidney disease. A body of evidence accumulated over the past 15 years has ascribed a central pathophysiological role to a particular form of regulated necrosis, termed necroptosis, to acute tubular necrosis, nephron loss and maladaptive renal fibrogenesis. Unlike apoptosis, which is a non-immunogenic process, necroptosis results in the release of cellular contents and cytokines, which triggers an inflammatory response in neighbouring tissue. This necroinflammatory environment can lead to severe organ dysfunction and cause lasting tissue injury in the kidney. Despite evidence of a link between necroptosis and various kidney diseases, there are no available therapeutic options to target this process. Greater understanding of the molecular mechanisms, triggers and regulators of necroptosis in acute and chronic kidney diseases may identify shortcomings in current approaches to therapeutically target necroptosis regulators and lead to the development of innovative therapeutic approaches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lycopene Attenuates Di(2-ethylhexyl) Phthalate-Induced Mitochondrial Damage and Inflammation in Kidney via cGAS-STING Signaling</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36583613/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36583613/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Di(2-ethylhexyl) phthalate (DEHP) is a highly harmful and persistent environmental pollutant. Due to its unique chemical composition, it frequently dissolves and enters the environment to endanger human and animal health. Lycopene is a natural bioactive component that can potentially reduce the risk of environmental factor-induced chronic diseases. The present study sought to explore the role and underlying mechanism of lycopene (LYC) on DEHP-induced renal inflammatory response and apoptosis. In this study, mice were orally treated with LYC (5 mg/kg BW/day) and/or DEHP (500 or 1000 mg/kg BW/day) for 28 days. Our results indicated that LYC prevented DEHP-induced histopathological alterations and ultrastructural injuries, including decreased mitochondrial membrane potential (ΔΨm), PINK1/Parkin pathway-mediated mitophagy, and mitochondrial energetic deficit. When damaged mitochondria release mitochondrial DNA (mtDNA) into cytosol, LYC can alleviate inflammation and apoptosis caused by DEHP exposure by activating the cyclic GMP-AMP synthase-stimulator of interferon gene (cGAS-STING) signal pathway. Collectively, our data demonstrate that LYC can reduce mitophagy caused by DEHP exposure by activating the PINK1/Parkin pathway and then reduce renal inflammation and apoptosis through the cGAS-STING pathway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The transcription factor ATF4 mediates endoplasmic reticulum stress related podocyte injury and slit diaphragm defects</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36587794/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36587794/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mutations in &lt;em&gt;OSGEP&lt;/em&gt; and four other genes that encode subunits of the KEOPS complex cause Galloway-Mowat syndrome, a severe, inherited kidney-neurological disease. The complex catalyzes an essential posttranscriptional modification of tRNA and its loss of function induces endoplasmic reticulum (ER) stress. Here, using Drosophila melanogaster garland nephrocytes and cultured human podocytes, we aimed to elucidate the molecular pathogenic mechanisms of KEOPS related glomerular disease and to test pharmacological inhibition of ER stress related signaling as a therapeutic principle. We found that ATF4, an ER stress mediating transcription factor, or its fly orthologue Crc, were upregulated in both fly nephrocytes and human podocytes. Knockdown of Tcs3, a fly orthologue of OSGEP, caused slit diaphragm defects, recapitulating the human kidney phenotype. &lt;em&gt;OSGEP&lt;/em&gt; cDNA with mutations found in patients lacked the capacity for rescue. Genetic interaction studies in Tcs3 deficient nephrocytes revealed that Crc mediates not only cell injury, but surprisingly also slit diaphragm defects, and that genetic or pharmacological inhibition of Crc activation attenuates both phenotypes. These findings are conserved in human podocytes where ATF4 inhibition improved the viability of podocytes with OSGEP knockdown, with chemically-induced ER stress, and where ATF4 target genes and pro-apoptotic gene clusters are upregulated upon OSGEP knockdown. Thus, our data identify ATF4 mediated signaling as a molecular link between ER stress, slit diaphragm defects, podocyte injury, and suggest that modulation of ATF4 signaling may be a potential therapeutic target for certain podocyte diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1,2-Bis(2-aminophenoxy)ethane- N, N, N&#39;, N&#39;-tetraacetic Acid Acetoxymethyl Ester Loaded Reactive Oxygen Species Responsive Hyaluronic Acid-Bilirubin Nanoparticles for Acute Kidney Injury Therapy via Alleviating Calcium Overload Mediated Endoplasmic Reticulum Stress</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36574627/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36574627/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Calcium overload is one of the early determinants of the core cellular events that contribute to the pathogenesis of acute kidney injury (AKI), which include oxidative stress, ATP depletion, calcium overload, and inflammatory response with self-amplifying and interactive feedback loops that ultimately lead to cellular injury and renal failure. Excluding adjuvant therapy, there are currently no approved pharmacotherapies for the treatment of AKI. Using an adipic dihydride linker, we modified the hyaluronic acid polymer chain with a potent antioxidant, bilirubin, to produce an amphiphilic conjugate. Subsequently, we developed a kidney-targeted and reactive oxygen species (ROS)-responsive drug delivery system based on the flash nanocomplexation method to deliver a well-known intracellular calcium chelator, 1,2-bis(2-aminophenoxy)ethane-N,N,N&amp;rsquo;,N&amp;rsquo;-tetraacetic acid acetoxymethyl ester (BAPTA-AM, BA), with the goal of rescuing renal cell damage via rapidly scavenging of intracellularly overloaded Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt;. In the ischemia-reperfusion (I/R) induced AKI rat model, a single dose of as-prepared formulation (BA 100 μg·kg&lt;sup&gt;-1&lt;/sup&gt;) 6 h post-reperfusion significantly reduced renal function indicators by more than 60% within 12 h, significantly alleviated tissular pathological changes, ameliorated tissular oxidative damage, significantly inhibited apoptosis of renal tubular cells and the expression of renal tubular marker kidney injury molecule 1, etc., thus greatly reducing the risk of kidney failure. Mechanistically, the treatment with BA-loaded NPs significantly inhibited the activation of the ER stress cascade response (IRE1-TRAF2-JNK, ATF4-CHOP, and ATF6 axis) and regulated the downstream apoptosis-related pathway while also reducing the inflammatory response. The BA-loaded NPs hold great promise as a potential therapy for I/R injury-related diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Nephroprotective Effects of Hibiscus sabdariffa Leaf and Ellagic Acid in Vitro and in Vivo Models of Hyperuricemic Nephropathy</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36562602/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36562602/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hyperuricemic nephropathy (HN) is caused by urate crystals that get deposited in the kidney and contribute to renal fibrosis. Uric acid (UA) has been proven to directly cause renal mesangial cell oxidative stress and fibrosis in the pathogenesis of HN. Some antioxidants can be used as chemopreventive agents of HN. &lt;em&gt;Hibiscus sabdariffa&lt;/em&gt; leaf extracts (HLE), rich in polyphenol, have been shown to possess hypoglycemic, antioxidant, hypolipidemic, antiatherosclerotic, and anticancer effects. The aim of the study is to examine the inhibitory effect of HLE and its main component ellagic acid (EA) on renal fibrosis. &lt;em&gt;In vitro&lt;/em&gt;, mouse renal glomerular mesangial SV40MES13 cells pretreated with UA were demonstrated to trigger obvious morphological changes and viability loss, as well as affect matrix metalloproteinases (MMPs) activities. Noncytotoxic doses of HLE and EA abolished the UA-induced cell injury and MMP-2/9 secretion. In addition, HLE and EA exhibited antioxidant and anti-inflammatory effects on the UA-treated cells with a reduction in transforming growth factor-beta (TGF-β) production. Next, the UA-activated pro-fibrotic factors, extracellular matrix (ECM) deposition, and epithelial-mesenchymal-transition (EMT) were inhibited by HLE or EA. Mechanistic assays indicated that antifibrotic effects of HLE might be mediated via TGF-β/Smad signaling, as confirmed by the transfection of Smad7 siRNA. &lt;em&gt;In vivo&lt;/em&gt;, HLE and EA supplementations significantly alleviated HN development, which may result from inhibiting adenine-induced TGF-β production accompanying oxidative stress and inflammation, as well as fibrogenesis. Our data imply that EA-enriched HLE regulates the TGF-β/Smad signaling, which in turn led to reduced renal mesangial cell injury and fibrosis in HN and provided a new mechanism for its nephroprotective activity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chimeric efferocytic receptors improve apoptotic cell clearance and alleviate inflammation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36563662/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36563662/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Design of chimeric receptors for efferocytosis (CHEF) to enhance efferocytosis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Boosting efferocytosis via CHEF attenuates multiple inflammatory insults &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Protein folding and misfolded protein degradation are rate-limiting steps in efferocytosis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CHEF expression can improve outcomes in ongoing disease&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our bodies turn over billions of cells daily via apoptosis and are in turn cleared by phagocytes via the process of &amp;ldquo;efferocytosis.&amp;rdquo; Defects in efferocytosis are now linked to various inflammatory diseases. Here, we designed a strategy to boost efferocytosis, denoted &amp;ldquo;chimeric receptor for efferocytosis&amp;rdquo; (CHEF). We fused a specific signaling domain within the cytoplasmic adapter protein ELMO1 to the extracellular phosphatidylserine recognition domains of the efferocytic receptors BAI1 or TIM4, generating BELMO and TELMO, respectively. CHEF-expressing phagocytes display a striking increase in efferocytosis. In mouse models of inflammation, BELMO expression attenuates colitis, hepatotoxicity, and nephrotoxicity. In mechanistic studies, BELMO increases ER-resident enzymes and chaperones to overcome protein-folding-associated toxicity, which was further validated in a model of ER-stress-induced renal ischemia-reperfusion injury. Finally, TELMO introduction after onset of kidney injury significantly reduced fibrosis. Collectively, these data advance a concept of chimeric efferocytic receptors to boost efferocytosis and dampen inflammation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The transcription factor Fosl1 preserves Klotho expression and protects from acute kidney injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36565807/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36565807/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Increased expression of AP-1 transcription factor components has been reported in acute kidney injury (AKI). However, the role of specific components, such as Fosl1, in tubular cells or AKI is unknown. Upstream regulator analysis of murine nephrotoxic AKI transcriptomics identified AP-1 as highly upregulated. Among AP-1 canonical components, Fosl1 was found to be upregulated in two transcriptomics datasets from nephrotoxic murine AKI induced by folic acid or cisplatin and from proximal tubular cells exposed to TWEAK, a cytokine mediator of AKI. Fosl1 was minimally expressed in the kidneys of control uninjured mice. Increased Fosl1 protein was localized to proximal tubular cell nuclei in AKI. In human AKI, FOSL1 was found present in proximal tubular cells in kidney sections and in urine along with increased urinary FOSL1 mRNA. Selective Fosl1 deficiency in proximal tubular cells (Fosl1Δtub) increased the severity of murine cisplatin- or folate-induced AKI as characterized by lower kidney function, more severe kidney inflammation and Klotho downregulation. Indeed, elevated AP-1 activity was observed after cisplatin-induced AKI in Fosl1Δtub mice compared to wild type mice. More severe Klotho downregulation preceded more severe kidney dysfunction. The Klotho promoter was enriched in Fosl1 binding sites and Fosl1 bound to the Klotho promoter in cisplatin-AKI. In cultured proximal tubular cells, Fosl1 targeting increased the proinflammatory response and downregulated Klotho. In vivo, recombinant Klotho administration protected Fosl1Δtub mice from cisplatin-AKI. Thus, increased proximal tubular Fosl1 expression during AKI is an adaptive response, preserves Klotho. and limits the severity of tubular cell injury and AKI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kir4.2 mediates proximal potassium effects on glutaminase activity and kidney injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36543132/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36543132/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;K&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; deficiency causes kidney-specific injury and inflammation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Injury effects are dependent on the proximal K&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; channel Kir4.2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kir4.2 mediates activation of the ammoniagenesis pathway under low-K&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; conditions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kidney deletion of glutaminase prevents low-K&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt;-mediated kidney injury&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Summary&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inadequate potassium (K&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt;) consumption correlates with increased mortality and poor cardiovascular outcomes. Potassium effects on blood pressure have been described previously; however, whether or not low K&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; independently affects kidney disease progression remains unclear. Here, we demonstrate that dietary K&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; deficiency causes direct kidney injury. Effects depend on reduced blood K&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; and are kidney specific. In response to reduced K&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt;, the channel Kir4.2 mediates altered proximal tubule (PT) basolateral K&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; flux, causing intracellular acidosis and activation of the enzyme glutaminase and the ammoniagenesis pathway. Deletion of either Kir4.2 or glutaminase protects from low-K&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; injury. Reduced K&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt;also mediates injury and fibrosis in a model of aldosteronism. These results demonstrate that the PT epithelium, like the distal nephron, is K&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; sensitive, with reduced blood K&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; causing direct PT injury. Kir4.2 and glutaminase are essential mediators of this injury process, and we identify their potential for future targeting in the treatment of chronic kidney disease.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tubular epithelial cells-derived small extracellular vesicle-VEGF-A promotes peritubular capillary repair in ischemic kidney injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36528739/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36528739/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Peritubular capillaries (PTCs) are closely related to renal tubules in structure and function, and both are pivotal regulators in the development and progression of acute kidney injury (AKI). However, the mechanisms that underlie the interaction between PTCs and tubules during AKI remain unclear. Here we explored a new mode of tubulovascular crosstalk mediated by small extracellular vesicles (sEV) after AKI. In response to renal ischemia/reperfusion (I/R) injury, endothelial proliferation of PTCs and tubular expression of vascular endothelial growth factor-A (VEGF-A) were increased, accompanied by a remarkable redistribution of cytoplasmic VEGF-A to the basolateral side of tubular cells. Meanwhile, the secretion mode of VEGF-A was converted in the injured tubular cells, which showed a much greater tendency to secrete VEGF-A via sEV other than the free form. Interestingly, tubular cell-derived VEGF-A-enriched sEV (sEV-VEGF-A) turned out to promote endothelial proliferation which was regulated by VEGF receptors 1 and 2. Furthermore, inhibition of renal sEV secretion by Rab27a knockdown resulted in a significant decrease in the proliferation of peritubular endothelial cells in vivo. Importantly, taking advantage of the newly recognized endogenous repair response of PTCs, exogenous supplementation of VEGF-A + sEV efficiently recused PTC rarefaction, improved renal perfusion, and halted the AKI to CKD transition. Taken together, our study uncovered a novel intrinsic repair response after AKI through renal tubule-PTC crosstalk via sEV-VEGF-A, which could be exploited as a promising therapeutic angiogenesis strategy in diseases with ischemia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cerium oxide-based nanozyme suppresses kidney calcium oxalate crystal depositions via reversing hyperoxaluria-induced oxidative stress damage</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36482378/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36482378/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oxidative stress damage to renal epithelial cells is the main pathological factor of calcium oxalate calculi formation. The development of medicine that could alleviate oxidative damage has become the key to the prevention and treatment of urolithiasis. Herein, porous nanorods CeO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; nanoparticles (CNPs) were selected from CeO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; with different morphologies as an antioxidant reagent to suppress kidney calcium oxalate crystal depositions with excellent oxidation resistance due to its larger specific surface area. The reversible transformation from Ce&lt;sup&gt;3+&lt;/sup&gt; to Ce&lt;sup&gt;4+&lt;/sup&gt; could catalyze the decomposition of excess free radicals and act as a biological antioxidant enzyme basing on its strong ability to scavenge free radicals. The protection capability of CNP&lt;sub&gt;S&lt;/sub&gt; against oxalate-induced damage and the effect of CNP&lt;sub&gt;S&lt;/sub&gt; on calcium oxalate crystallization were studied. CNP&lt;sub&gt;S&lt;/sub&gt; could effectively reduce reactive oxygen species production, restore mitochondrial membrane potential polarity, recover cell cycle progression, reduce cell death, and inhibit the formation of calcium oxalate crystals on the cell surface in vitro. The results of high-throughput sequencing of mRNA showed that CNPs could protect renal epithelial cells from oxidative stress damage caused by high oxalate by suppressing the expression gene of cell surface adhesion proteins. In addition, CNP&lt;sub&gt;S&lt;/sub&gt; can significantly reduce the pathological damage of renal tubules and inhibit the deposition of calcium oxalate crystals in rat kidneys while having no significant side effect on other organs and physiological indicators in vivo. Our results provide a new strategy for CNP&lt;sub&gt;S&lt;/sub&gt; as a potential for clinical prevention of crystalline kidney injury and crystal deposition.
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Targeting endogenous kidney regeneration using anti-IL11 therapy in acute and chronic models of kidney disease</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36470928/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36470928/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The kidney has large regenerative capacity, but this is compromised when kidney damage is excessive and renal tubular epithelial cells (TECs) undergo SNAI1-driven growth arrest. Here we investigate the role of IL11 in TECs, kidney injury and renal repair. IL11 stimulation of TECs induces ERK- and p90RSK-mediated GSK3β inactivation, SNAI1 upregulation and pro-inflammatory gene expression. Mice with acute kidney injury upregulate IL11 in TECs leading to SNAI1 expression and kidney dysfunction, which is not seen in Il11 deleted mice or in mice administered a neutralizing IL11 antibody in either preemptive or treatment modes. In acute kidney injury, anti-TGFβ reduces renal fibrosis but exacerbates inflammation and tubule damage whereas anti-IL11 reduces all pathologies. Mice with TEC-specific deletion of Il11ra1 have reduced pathogenic signaling and are protected from renal injury-induced inflammation, fibrosis, and failure. In a model of chronic kidney disease, anti-IL11 therapy promotes TEC proliferation and parenchymal regeneration, reverses fibroinflammation and restores renal mass and function. These data highlight IL11-induced mesenchymal transition of injured TECs as an important renal pathology and suggest IL11 as a therapeutic target for restoring stalled endogenous regeneration in the diseased kidney.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Low dimensional nanomaterials for treating acute kidney injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/36456976/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/36456976/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acute kidney injury (AKI) is one of the most common severe complications among hospitalized patients. In the absence of specific drugs to treat AKI, hemodialysis remains the primary clinical treatment for AKI patients. AKI treatment has received significant attention recently due to the excellent drug delivery capabilities of low-dimensional nanomaterials (LDNs) and their unique therapeutic effects. Diverse LDNs have been proposed to treat AKI, with promising results and the potential for future clinical application. This article aims to provide an overview of the pathogenesis of AKI and the recent advances in the treatment of AKI using different types of LDNs. In addition, it is intended to provide theoretical support for the design of LDNs and implications for AKI treatment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neutrophil Extracellular Traps Induce Glomerular Endothelial Cell Dysfunction and Pyroptosis in Diabetic Kidney Disease</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36095260/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36095260/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Diabetic kidney disease (DKD) is the leading cause of end-stage renal disease. Neutrophil extracellular traps (NETs) are a network structure composed of loose chromatin and embedded with multiple proteins. Here, we observed increased NETs deposition in the glomeruli of DKD patients and diabetic mice (streptozotocin-induced or db/db mice). After NETs were degraded with DNase I, diabetic mice exhibited attenuated glomerulopathy and glomerular endothelial cells (GECs) injury. We also observed alleviated glomerulopathy and GECs injury in peptidylarginine deiminase 4-knockout mice with streptozotocin-induced diabetes. In vitro, NETs-induced GECs pyroptosis was characterized by pore formation in the cell membrane, dysregulation of multiple genes involved in cell membrane function, and increased expression of pyroptosis-related proteins. Strengthening the GECs surface charge by oleylamine significantly inhibited NETs-induced GECs pyroptosis. These findings suggest that the GECs charge-related pyroptosis is involved in DKD progression, which is promoted by NETs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FFAR4 improves the senescence of tubular epithelial cells by AMPK/SirT3 signaling in acute kidney injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36450712/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36450712/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acute kidney injury (AKI) is a serious clinical complication with high morbidity and mortality rates. Despite substantial progress in understanding the mechanism of AKI, no effective therapy is available for treatment or prevention. We previously found that G protein-coupled receptor (GPCR) family member free fatty acid receptor 4 (FFAR4) agonist TUG891 alleviated kidney dysfunction and tubular injury in AKI mice. However, the versatile role of FFAR4 in kidney has not been well characterized. In the study, the expression of FFAR4 was abnormally decreased in tubular epithelial cells (TECs) of cisplatin, cecal ligation/perforation and ischemia/reperfusion injury-induced AKI mice, respectively. Systemic and conditional TEC-specific knockout of FFAR4 aggravated renal function and pathological damage, whereas FFAR4 activation by TUG-891 alleviated the severity of disease in cisplatin-induced AKI mice. Notably, FFAR4, as a key determinant, was firstly explored to regulate cellular senescence both in injured kidneys of AKI mice and TECs, which was indicated by senescence-associated β-galactosidase (SA-β-gal) activity, marker protein p53, p21, Lamin B1, phospho-histone H2A.X, phospho-Rb expression, and secretory phenotype IL-6 level. Mechanistically, pharmacological activation and overexpression of FFAR4 reversed the decrease of aging-related SirT3 protein, where FFAR4 regulated SirT3 expression to exhibit anti-senescent effect via Gq subunit-mediated CaMKKβ/AMPK signaling in cisplatin-induced mice and TECs. These findings highlight the original role of tubular FFAR4 in cellular senescence via AMPK/SirT3 signaling and identify FFAR4 as a potential drug target against AKI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chromatin accessibility dynamics dictate renal tubular epithelial cell response to injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36443310/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36443310/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Renal tubular epithelial cells (TECs) can initiate an adaptive response to completely recover from mild acute kidney injury (AKI), whereas severe injury often leads to persistence of maladaptive repair and progression to kidney fibrosis. Through profiling of active DNA regulatory elements by ATAC-seq, we reveal widespread, dynamic changes in the chromatin accessibility of TECs after ischemia–reperfusion injury. We show that injury-specific domains of regulatory chromatin become accessible prior to gene activation, creating poised chromatin states to activate the consequent gene expression program and injury response. We further identify RXRα as a key transcription factor in promoting adaptive repair. Activation of RXRα by bexarotene, an FDA-approved RXRα agonist, restores the chromatin state and gene expression program to protect TECs against severe kidney injury. Together, our findings elucidate a chromatin-mediated mechanism underlying differential responses of TECs to varying injuries and identify RXRα as a therapeutic target of acute kidney injury.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sirt3 mitigates LPS-induced mitochondrial damage in renal tubular epithelial cells by deacetylating YME1L1</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36433732/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36433732/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acute kidney injury (AKI) is often secondary to sepsis. Increasing evidence suggests that mitochondrial dysfunction contributes to the pathological process of AKI. In this study, we aimed to examine the regulatory roles of Sirt3 in Lipopolysaccharide (LPS)-induced mitochondrial damage in renal tubular epithelial cells (TECs). Sirt3 knockout mice were intraperitoneally injected with LPS, and cultured TECs were stimulated with LPS to evaluate the effects of Sirt3 on mitochondrial structure and function in TECs. Electron microscopy was used to assess mitochondrial morphology. Immunofluorescence staining was performed to detect protein expression and examine mitochondrial morphology. Western blotting was used to quantify protein expression. We observed that LPS increased apoptosis, induced disturbances in mitochondrial function and dynamics, and downregulated Sirt3 expression in a sepsis-induced AKI mouse model and human proximal tubular (HK-2) cells in vitro. Sirt3 deficiency further exacerbated LPS-induced renal pathological damage, apoptosis and disturbances in mitochondrial function and dynamics. On the contrary, Sirt3 overexpression in HK-2 cells alleviated these lesions. Functional studies revealed that Sirt3 overexpression alleviated LPS-induced mitochondrial damage and apoptosis in TECs by promoting OPA1-mediated mitochondrial fusion through the deacetylation of i-AAA protease (YME1L1), an upstream regulatory molecule of OPA1. Our study has identified Sirt3 as a vital factor that protects against LPS-induced mitochondrial damage and apoptosis in TECs via the YME1L1-OPA1 signaling pathway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Renal Endothelial Cell-Targeted Extracellular Vesicles Protect the Kidney from Ischemic Injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36416304/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36416304/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Endothelial cell injury plays a critical part in ischemic acute kidney injury (AKI) and participates in the progression of AKI. Targeting renal endothelial cell therapy may ameliorate vascular injury and further improve the prognosis of ischemic AKI. Here, P-selectin as a biomarker of ischemic AKI in endothelial cells is identified and P-selectin binding peptide (PBP)-engineered extracellular vesicles (PBP-EVs) with imaging and therapeutic functions are developed. The results show that PBP-EVs exhibit a selective targeting tendency to injured kidneys, while providing spatiotemporal information for the early diagnosis of AKI by quantifying the expression of P-selectin in the kidneys by molecular imaging. Meanwhile, PBP-EVs reveal superior nephroprotective functions in the promotion of renal repair and inhibition of fibrosis by alleviating inflammatory infiltration, improving reparative angiogenesis, and ameliorating maladaptive repair of the renal parenchyma. In conclusion, PBP-EVs, as an ischemic AKI theranostic system that is designed in this study, provide a spatiotemporal diagnosis in the early stages of AKI to help guide personalized therapy and exhibit superior nephroprotective effects, offering proof-of-concept data to design EV-based theranostic strategies to promote renal recovery and further improve long-term outcomes following AKI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A human kidney and liver organoid-based multi-organ-on-a-chip model to study the therapeutic effects and biodistribution of mesenchymal stromal cell-derived extracellular vesicles</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36382606/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36382606/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mesenchymal stromal cell (MSC)-derived small extracellular vesicles (sEVs) show therapeutic potential in multiple disease models, including kidney injury. Clinical translation of sEVs requires further preclinical and regulatory developments, including elucidation of the biodistribution and mode of action (MoA). Biodistribution can be determined using labelled sEVs in animal models which come with ethical concerns, are time-consuming and expensive, and may not well represent human physiology. We hypothesised that, based on developments in microfluidics and human organoid technology, in vitro multi-organ-on-a-chip (MOC) models allow us to study effects of sEVs in modelled human organs like kidney and liver in a semi-systemic manner. Human kidney- and liver organoids combined by microfluidic channels maintained physiological functions, and a kidney injury model was established using hydrogenperoxide. MSC-sEVs were isolated, and their size, density and potential contamination were analysed. These sEVs stimulated recovery of the renal epithelium after injury. Microscopic analysis shows increased accumulation of PKH67-labelled sEVs not only in injured kidney cells, but also in the unharmed liver organoids, compared to healthy control conditions. In conclusion, this new MOC model recapitulates therapeutic efficacy and biodistribution of MSC-sEVs as observed in animal models. Its human background allows for in-depth analysis of the MoA and identification of potential side effects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Effects of folic acid on oxidative damage of kidney in lead-exposed rats</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36458173/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36458173/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Introduction:&lt;/em&gt; Lead (Pb) has many applications in daily life, but in recent years, various problems caused by lead exposure have aroused people&amp;rsquo;s concern. Folic acid is widely found in fruits and has received more attention for its antioxidant function. However, the role of folic acid in lead-induced kidney injury in rats is unclear. This study was designed to investigate the effects of folic acid on oxidative stress and endoplasmic reticulum stress in the kidney of rats caused by lead exposure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; Forty specific pathogen-free male Rattus norvegicus rats were randomly divided into control, lead, intervention, and folic acid groups. The levels of SOD, GSH-Px, GSH, and MDA were measured by biochemical kits. The protein levels of Nrf2, HO-1, CHOP, and GRP78 were measured by immunofluorescence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; This study showed that lead exposure increased the blood levels of lead in mice. However, the intervention of folic acid decreased the levels of lead, but the difference was not statistically significant. Lead exposure causes oxidative stress by decreasing kidney SOD, GSH-Px, and GSH levels and increasing MDA levels. However, folic acid alleviated the oxidative damage caused by lead exposure by increasing the levels of GSH-Px and GSH and decreasing the levels of MDA. Immunofluorescence results showed that folic acid intervention downregulated the upregulation of kidney Nrf2, HO-1, GRP78, and CHOP expression caused by lead exposure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Discussion:&lt;/em&gt; Overall, folic acid alleviates kidney oxidative stress induced by lead exposure by regulating Nrf2 and HO-1, while regulating CHOP and GRP78 to mitigate apoptosis caused by excessive endoplasmic reticulum stress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Organ Crosstalk in Acute Kidney Injury: Evidence and Mechanisms</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/36431113/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/36431113/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acute kidney injury (AKI) is becoming a public health problem worldwide. AKI is usually considered a complication of lung, heart, liver, gut, and brain disease, but recent findings have supported that injured kidney can also cause dysfunction of other organs, suggesting organ crosstalk existence in AKI. However, the organ crosstalk in AKI and the underlying mechanisms have not been broadly reviewed or fully investigated. In this review, we summarize recent clinical and laboratory findings of organ crosstalk in AKI and highlight the related molecular mechanisms. Moreover, their crosstalk involves inflammatory and immune responses, hemodynamic change, fluid homeostasis, hormone secretion, nerve reflex regulation, uremic toxin, and oxidative stress. Our review provides important clues for the intervention for AKI and investigates important therapeutic potential from a new perspective.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Translation Rescue by Targeting Ppp1r15a through Its Upstream Open Reading Frame in Sepsis-Induced Acute Kidney Injury in a Murine Model</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36283811/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36283811/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Translation shutdown is a hallmark of late-phase, sepsis-induced kidney injury. Methods for controlling protein synthesis in the kidney are limited. Reversing translation shutdown requires dephosphorylation of the eukaryotic initiation factor 2 (eIF2) subunit eIF2α; this is mediated by a key regulatory molecule, protein phosphatase 1 regulatory subunit 15A (Ppp1r15a), also known as GADD34.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; To study protein synthesis in the kidney in a murine endotoxemia model and investigate the feasibility of translation control &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt; by boosting the protein expression of Ppp1r15a, we combined multiple tools, including ribosome profiling (Ribo-seq), proteomics, polyribosome profiling, and antisense oligonucleotides, and a newly generated Ppp1r15a knock-in mouse model and multiple mutant cell lines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; We report that translation shutdown in established sepsis-induced kidney injury is brought about by excessive eIF2α phosphorylation and sustained by blunted expression of the counter-regulatory phosphatase Ppp1r15a. We determined the blunted Ppp1r15a expression persists because of the presence of an upstream open reading frame (uORF). Overcoming this barrier with genetic and antisense oligonucleotide approaches enabled the overexpression of Ppp1r15a, which salvaged translation and improved kidney function in an endotoxemia model. Loss of this uORF also had broad effects on the composition and phosphorylation status of the immunopeptidome-peptides associated with the MHC-that extended beyond the eIF2α axis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; We found Ppp1r15a is translationally repressed during late-phase sepsis because of the existence of an uORF, which is a prime therapeutic candidate for this strategic rescue of translation in late-phase sepsis. The ability to accurately control translation dynamics during sepsis may offer new paths for the development of therapies at codon-level precision.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gallic, ellagic acids and their oral combined administration induce kidney, lung, and heart injury after acute exposure in Wistar rats</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36272503/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36272503/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gallic (GA) and ellagic (EA) acids are present in foods, medicinal plants, teas, and dietary supplements. An acute toxicological study was conducted by oral administration of both compounds alone (200, 1000, and 2000 mg/kg) and combined (2000 mg/kg) and their effects on the electron transport chain (ETC) and the ROS production in kidney mitochondria further evaluated. All treatments induced a dose-dependent heart, lung, and kidney injury. However, the intensity of these effects varied according to the substance, with greater cardiac and renal toxicity for EA and pulmonary injury for GA, while the combination attenuated the toxicity of the isolated molecules. All substances inhibited the activity of complexes II, III, and IV of the ETC from renal mitochondria. However, no changes were observed regarding mitochondrial ROS production. These compounds have a non-negligible inherent deleterious potential, so their uncontrolled use at high doses (≥200 mg/kg) could cause undesirable effects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Haemolytic uraemic syndrome</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/36272423/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/36272423/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Haemolytic uraemic syndrome (HUS) is a heterogeneous group of diseases that result in a common pathology, thrombotic microangiopathy, which is classically characterised by the triad of non-immune microangiopathic haemolytic anaemia, thrombocytopenia, and acute kidney injury. In this Seminar, different causes of HUS are discussed, the most common being Shiga toxin-producing Escherichia coli HUS. Identifying the underlying thrombotic microangiopathy trigger can be challenging but is imperative if patients are to receive personalised disease-specific treatment. The quintessential example is complement-mediated HUS, which once carried an extremely high mortality but is now treated with anti-complement therapies with excellent long-term outcomes. Unfortunately, the high cost of anti-complement therapies all but precludes their use in low-income countries. For many other forms of HUS, targeted therapies are yet to be identified.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kidney-Targeted Nanoparticles Loaded with the Natural Antioxidant Rosmarinic Acid for Acute Kidney Injury Treatment</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36253133/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36253133/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acute kidney injury (AKI) is a common clinical disease with high morbidity and mortality, and with a lack of effective drugs for treatment. Oxidative stress is very important in the occurrence and progression of AKI, and antioxidants use is one of the promising treatments. Rosmarinic acid (RA) is a ubiquitous natural polyphenol with powerful antioxidant and anti-inflammatory activities. Due to its inherent characteristic with poor water solubility and inferior bioavailability, its clinical application is impeded. Hence, the authors design a nanoparticle for effectively delivering RA, which is a chemical complex of RA and fourth-generation poly-amidoamine-based amphiphilic polymer (G4-PAMAM). The nanoparticle is modified with l-serine due to the specific interaction between kidney injury molecule-1 (Kim-1) and serine, which eventually generates a promising AKI kidney-targeting nanoparticle (S-G-R). The S-G-R is rapidly cumulated and long-term retained in ischemia-reperfusion-induced AKI kidneys, especially in the damaged renal tubular cells. The S-G-R exhibits more excellent antioxidative and antiapoptotic effects in vitro and has a more outstanding ability to improve the renal function, repair damaged renal tissue, and decrease oxidative stress, inflammatory response and apoptosis of tubular cells in vivo. Overall, this study might develop a safe and effective targeting strategy for the therapy of AKI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comprehensive single-cell transcriptional profiling defines shared and unique epithelial injury responses during kidney fibrosis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36265491/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36265491/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The underlying cellular events driving kidney fibrogenesis and metabolic dysfunction are incompletely understood. Here, we employed single-cell combinatorial indexing RNA sequencing to analyze 24 mouse kidneys from two fibrosis models. We profiled 309,666 cells in one experiment, representing 50 cell types/states encompassing epithelial, endothelial, immune, and stromal populations. Single-cell analysis identified diverse injury states of the proximal tubule, including two distinct early-phase populations with dysregulated lipid and amino acid metabolism, respectively. Lipid metabolism was defective in the chronic phase but was transiently activated in the very early stages of ischemia-induced injury, where we discovered increased lipid deposition and increased fatty acid β-oxidation. Perilipin 2 was identified as a surface marker of intracellular lipid droplets, and its knockdown in vitro disrupted cell energy state maintenance during lipid accumulation. Surveying epithelial cells across nephron segments identified shared and unique injury responses. Stromal cells exhibited high heterogeneity and contributed to fibrogenesis by epithelial-stromal crosstalk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Activation of Stimulator of IFN Genes (STING) Causes Proteinuria and Contributes to Glomerular Diseases</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36198430/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36198430/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; The signaling molecule stimulator of IFN genes (STING) was identified as a crucial regulator of the DNA-sensing cyclic GMP-AMP synthase (cGAS)-STING pathway, and this signaling pathway regulates inflammation and energy homeostasis under conditions of obesity, kidney fibrosis, and AKI. However, the role of STING in causing CKD, including diabetic kidney disease (DKD) and Alport syndrome, is unknown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; To investigate whether STING activation contributes to the development and progression of glomerular diseases such as DKD and Alport syndrome, immortalized human and murine podocytes were differentiated for 14 days and treated with a STING-specific agonist. We used diabetic db/db mice, mice with experimental Alport syndrome, C57BL/6 mice, and STING knockout mice to assess the role of the STING signaling pathway in kidney failure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;In vitro&lt;/em&gt;, murine and human podocytes express all of the components of the cGAS-STING pathway. &lt;em&gt;In vivo&lt;/em&gt;, activation of STING renders C57BL/6 mice susceptible to albuminuria and podocyte loss. STING is activated at baseline in mice with experimental DKD and Alport syndrome. STING activation occurs in the glomerular but not the tubulointerstitial compartment in association with autophagic podocyte death in Alport syndrome mice and with apoptotic podocyte death in DKD mouse models. Genetic or pharmacologic inhibition of STING protects from progression of kidney disease in mice with DKD and Alport syndrome and increases lifespan in Alport syndrome mice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/em&gt; The activation of the STING pathway acts as a mediator of disease progression in DKD and Alport syndrome. Targeting STING may offer a therapeutic option to treat glomerular diseases of metabolic and nonmetabolic origin or prevent their development, progression, or both.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RNA N6 -methyladenosine modifications and potential targeted therapeutic strategies in kidney disease</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/36196023/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/36196023/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Epigenetic modifications have received increasing attention and have been shown to be extensively involved in kidney development and disease progression. Among them, the most common RNA modification, N&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;-methyladenosine (m&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;A), has been shown to dynamically and reversibly exert its functions in multiple ways, including splicing, export, decay and translation initiation efficiency to regulate mRNA fate. Moreover, m&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;A has also been reported to exert biological effects by destabilizing base pairing to modulate various functions of RNAs. Most importantly, an increasing number of kidney diseases, such as renal cell carcinoma, acute kidney injury and chronic kidney disease, have been found to be associated with aberrant m&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;A patterns. In this review, we comprehensively review the critical roles of m&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;A in kidney diseases and discuss the possibilities and relevance of m&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;A-targeted epigenetic therapy, with an integrated comprehensive description of the detailed alterations in specific loci that contribute to cellular processes that are associated with kidney diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tubular cell polyploidy protects from lethal acute kidney injury but promotes consequent chronic kidney disease</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36195583/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36195583/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acute kidney injury (AKI) is frequent, often fatal and, for lack of specific therapies, can leave survivors with chronic kidney disease (CKD). We characterize the distribution of tubular cells (TC) undergoing polyploidy along AKI by DNA content analysis and single cell RNA-sequencing. Furthermore, we study the functional roles of polyploidization using transgenic models and drug interventions. We identify YAP1-driven TC polyploidization outside the site of injury as a rapid way to sustain residual kidney function early during AKI. This survival mechanism comes at the cost of senescence of polyploid TC promoting interstitial fibrosis and CKD in AKI survivors. However, targeting TC polyploidization after the early AKI phase can prevent AKI-CKD transition without influencing AKI lethality. Senolytic treatment prevents CKD by blocking repeated TC polyploidization cycles. These results revise the current pathophysiological concept of how the kidney responds to acute injury and identify a novel druggable target to improve prognosis in AKI survivors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extended longevity geometrically-inverted proximal tubule organoids</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36215909/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36215909/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This study reports the cellular self-organization of primary human renal proximal tubule epithelial cells (RPTECs) around a minimal Matrigel scaffold to produce basal-in and apical-out proximal tubule organoids (tubuloids). These tubuloids are produced and maintained in hanging drop cultures for 90+ days, the longest such culture of any kind reported to date. The tubuloids upregulate maturity markers, such as aquaporin-1 (AQP1) and megalin (LRP2), and exhibit less mesenchymal and proliferation markers, such as vimentin and Ki67, compared to 2D cultures. They also experience changes over time as revealed by a comparison of gene expression patterns of cells in 2D culture and in day 31 and day 67 tubuloids. Gene expression analysis and immunohistochemistry reveal an increase in the expression of megalin, an endocytic receptor that can directly bind and uptake protein or potentially assist protein uptake. The tubuloids, including day 90 tubuloids, uptake fluorescent albumin and reveal punctate fluorescent patterns, suggesting functional endocytic uptake through these receptors. Furthermore, the tubuloids release kidney injury molecule-1 (KIM-1), a common biomarker for kidney injury, when exposed to albumin in both dose- and time-dependent manners. While this study focuses on potential applications for modeling proteinuric kidney disease, the tubuloids may have broad utility for studies where apical proximal tubule cell access is required.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nanodrugs alleviate acute kidney injury: Manipulate RONS at kidney</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/36203963/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/36203963/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;AKI is a common clinical acute syndrome with high morbidity and mortality but without effective clinical drug available.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hypoxia and accumulation of toxic substances are key pathological features of various heterogeneous AKI.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Excessive RONS is the core of the pathological mechanism of AKI.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The development of nanodrugs is expected to achieve successful treatment in AKI.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently, there are no clinical drugs available to treat acute kidney injury (AKI). Given the high prevalence and high mortality rate of AKI, the development of drugs to effectively treat AKI is a huge unmet medical need and a research hotspot. Although existing evidence fully demonstrates that reactive oxygen and nitrogen species (RONS) burst at the AKI site is a major contributor to AKI progression, the heterogeneity, complexity, and unique physiological structure of the kidney make most antioxidant and anti-inflammatory small molecule drugs ineffective because of the lack of kidney targeting and side effects. Recently, nanodrugs with intrinsic kidney targeting through the control of size, shape, and surface properties have opened exciting prospects for the treatment of AKI. Many antioxidant nanodrugs have emerged to address the limitations of current AKI treatments. In this review, we systematically summarized for the first time about the emerging nanodrugs that exploit the pathological and physiological features of the kidney to overcome the limitations of traditional small-molecule drugs to achieve high AKI efficacy. First, we analyzed the pathological structural characteristics of AKI and the main pathological mechanism of AKI: hypoxia, harmful substance accumulation-induced RONS burst at the renal site despite the multifactorial initiation and heterogeneity of AKI. Subsequently, we introduced the strategies used to improve renal targeting and reviewed advances of nanodrugs for AKI: nano-RONS-sacrificial agents, antioxidant nanozymes, and nanocarriers for antioxidants and anti-inflammatory drugs. These nanodrugs have demonstrated excellent therapeutic effects, such as greatly reducing oxidative stress damage, restoring renal function, and low side effects. Finally, we discussed the challenges and future directions for translating nanodrugs into clinical AKI treatment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LC3 lipidation is essential for TFEB activation during the lysosomal damage response to kidney injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32989250/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32989250/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Erratum in:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author Correction: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nature.com/articles/s41556-022-01017-4&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;LC3 lipidation is essential for TFEB activation during the lysosomal damage response to kidney injury&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sensing and clearance of dysfunctional lysosomes is critical for cellular homeostasis. Here we show that transcription factor EB (TFEB)-a master transcriptional regulator of lysosomal biogenesis and autophagy-is activated during the lysosomal damage response, and its activation is dependent on the function of the ATG conjugation system, which mediates LC3 lipidation. In addition, lysosomal damage triggers LC3 recruitment on lysosomes, where lipidated LC3 interacts with the lysosomal calcium channel TRPML1, facilitating calcium efflux essential for TFEB activation. Furthermore, we demonstrate the presence and importance of this TFEB activation mechanism in kidneys in a mouse model of oxalate nephropathy accompanying lysosomal damage. A proximal tubule-specific TFEB-knockout mouse exhibited progression of kidney injury induced by oxalate crystals. Together, our results reveal unexpected mechanisms of TFEB activation by LC3 lipidation and their physiological relevance during the lysosomal damage response.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lycopene attenuates the inflammation and apoptosis in aristolochic acid nephropathy by targeting the Nrf2 antioxidant system</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36198206/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36198206/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lycopene improves renal dysfunction in mice with aristolochic acid nephropathy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lycopene inhibits oxidative stress, inflammation, and apoptosis in the kidney of mice with aristolochic acid nephropathy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Activation of Nrf2 antioxidant signaling pathway is critical to inhibit the development of renal inflammatory response.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lycopene activates the Nrf2 antioxidant system and then inhibits apoptosis.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lycopene (LYC) is a carotenoid, has antioxidant properties. This study investigated whether lycopene attenuates aristolochic acids (AAs) -induced chronic kidney disease. In this experiment, lycopene was used to intervene C57BL/6 mice with renal injury induced by aristolochic acid exposure. The histomorphological changes and serological parameters of the kidney were measured in order to assess the alleviating effect of lycopene on renal injury in aristolochic acid nephropathy. In vitro and in vivo experiments were carried out to verify the main mechanism of action and drug targets of lycopene in improving aristolochic acid nephropathy (AAN) and by various experimental methods such as ELISA, immunohistochemistry, immunofluorescence, Western-blot and qRT-PCR. The results showed that oxidative stress injury was induced in the kidney of mice after AAI exposure, resulting in inflammatory response and tubular epithelial cell apoptosis. The results showed that the Nrf2/HO-1 antioxidant signaling pathway was inhibited after AAI exposure. AAI induces oxidative stress injury in the kidney, which ultimately leads to inflammation and tubular epithelial cell apoptosis. After LYC intervened in the body, it activated Nrf2 nuclear translocation and its downstream HO-1 and NQO1 antioxidant signaling pathways. LYC inhibited ROS production by renal tubular epithelial cells, and alleviated mitochondrial damage. LYC further modulated the TNF-α/NF-κB signaling cascade, thereby reduced the accumulation of inflammatory factors in the renal interstitium. Moreover, LYC was able to up-regulate the expression of Bcl-2, down-regulate Bax expression and inhibit the activation of cleaved forms of Caspase-9 and Caspase-3, which finally attenuated the apoptosis of the mitochondrial pathway induced by AAI exposure. It was concluded that lycopene was able to activate the Nrf2 antioxidant signaling pathway to maintain the homeostasis of renal oxidative stress and ultimately attenuated renal inflammatory response and apoptosis. These results suggested that lycopene can be used as a drug to relieve AAN.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Associations between nephron number and podometrics in human kidneys</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36175177/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36175177/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Podocyte loss and resultant nephron loss are common processes in the development of glomerulosclerosis and chronic kidney disease. While the cortical distribution of glomerulosclerosis is known to be non-uniform, the relationship between the numbers of non-sclerotic glomeruli (NSG), podometrics and zonal differences in podometrics remain incompletely understood. To help define this, we studied autopsy kidneys from 50 adults with median age 68 years and median eGFR 73.5 mL/min/1.73m&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; without apparent glomerular disease in a cross-sectional analysis. The number of NSG per kidney was estimated using the physical dissector/fractionator combination, while podometrics were estimated using model-based stereology. The number of NSG per kidney was directly correlated with podocyte number per tuft and podocyte density. Each additional 100,000 NSG per kidney was associated with 26 more podocytes per glomerulus and 16 podocytes per 10&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt; μm&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; increase in podocyte density. These associations were independent of clinical factors and cortical zone. While podocyte number per glomerulus was similar in the three zones, superficial glomeruli were the smallest and had the highest podocyte density but smallest podocytes. Increasing age and hypertension were associated with lower podocyte number, with age mostly affecting superficial glomeruli, and hypertension mostly affecting juxtamedullary glomeruli. Thus, in this first study to report a direct correlation between the number of NSG and podometrics, we suggest that podocyte number is decreasing in NSG of individuals losing nephrons. However, another possible interpretation may be that more nephrons might protect against further podocyte loss.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Hippo pathway and its correlation with acute kidney injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/36052554/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/36052554/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acute kidney injury (AKI) is a significant clinical complication with a substantial impact on morbidity and mortality, for which therapeutic options remain limited. The Hippo signaling pathway is an evolutionarily conserved pathway implicated in cell proliferation, dedifferentiation, and apoptosis via phosphorylation and inactivation of its downstream effectors Yes-associated protein (YAP)/transcriptional co-activator with PDZ-binding motif (TAZ). Recent studies have revealed that the Hippo pathway plays a pivotal role in the pathogenesis and repair of AKI. The Hippo pathway can mediate renal dysfunction through modulation of mitochondrial apoptosis under AKI conditions. Transient activation of YAP/TAZ in the acute phase of AKI may benefit renal recovery and regeneration, whereas persistent activation of YAP/TAZ in severe AKI may lead to maladaptive repair and transition to chronic kidney disease. This review aims to summarize recent findings on the associations between the Hippo pathway and AKI and to identify new therapeutic targets and strategies for AKI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A protein encoded by circular ZNF609 RNA induces acute kidney injury by activating the AKT/mTOR autophagy pathway</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36110046/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36110046/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Erratum in:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cell.com/molecular-therapy-family/molecular-therapy/fulltext/S1525-0016%2822%2900610-4&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;A protein encoded by circular ZNF609 RNA induces acute kidney injury by activating the AKT/mTOR-autophagy pathway&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Autophagy plays a crucial role in the development and progression of ischemic acute kidney injury (AKI). However, the function and mechanism of circular RNAs (circRNAs) in the regulation of autophagy in ischemic AKI remain unexplored. Herein, we find that circ-ZNF609, originating from the ZNF609 locus, is highly expressed in the kidney after ischemia/reperfusion injury, and urinary circ-ZNF609 is a moderate predictor for AKI in heart disease patients. Overexpression of circ-ZNF609 can activate AKT3/mTOR signaling and induce autophagy flux impairment and cell apoptosis while inhibiting proliferation in HK-2 cells, which is blocked by silencing circ-ZNF609. Mechanistically, circ-ZNF609 encodes a functional protein consisting of 250 amino acids (aa), termed ZNF609-250aa, the overexpression of which can activate AKT3/mTOR signaling and induce autophagy flux impairment and cell apoptosis in HK-2 cells in vitro and in AKI kidneys in vivo. The blockade of AKT and mTOR signaling with pharmacological inhibitors is capable of reversing ZNF609-250aa-induced autophagy flux impairment and cell apoptosis in HK-2 cells. The present study demonstrates that highly expressed circ-ZNF609-encoded ZNF609-250aa induces cell apoptosis and AKI by impairing the autophagy flux via an AKT/mTOR-dependent mechanism. These findings imply that targeting circ-ZNF609 may be a novel therapy for ischemic AKI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Injectable adhesive self-healing biocompatible hydrogel for haemostasis, wound healing, and postoperative tissue adhesion prevention in nephron-sparing surgery</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36100176/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36100176/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Statement of significance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Extended warm ischemia time during nephron sparing surgery negatively affected postoperative renal function due to the need for hemostasis at the wound with abundant blood supply, and postoperative wound healing and additional adhesions caused by the surgical procedure deserve attention. Based on the efficient and stable adhesion properties of hydrogels and the ability to promote wound healing. Herein, a series of adhesive self-healing biocompatible hydrogels were prepared based on free-radical polymerization of acryloyl-6-aminocaproic acid (AA) and N-acryloyl 2-glycine (NAG) and the ionic coordination between Ca2+ with the abundant carboxyl groups in AA and NAG. AA/NAG/Ca hydrogel showed hemostasis property in nephron sparing surgery model, promote kidney wound healing, and could perform anti-postoperative adhesion efficacy in an abdomen-caecum adhesion model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nephron-sparing surgery is a well-established treatment in patients with T1a renal cell carcinoma; however, the complex suturing process prolongs warm ischaemia time, affects the preservation of normal renal parenchymal function, and causes avoidable postoperative tissue adhesion complications, including chronic abdominal pain, intestinal obstruction, and female infertility. Hence, the design of multifunctional biomaterials with haemostasis, postoperative wound management, and postoperative tissue adhesion prevention properties for nephron-sparing surgeries is urgently needed. In this study, a series of injectable adhesive multifunctional biocompatible hydrogels were designed based on the free-radical polymerisation of monomers acryloyl-6-aminocaproic acid (AA) and N-acryloyl 2-glycine (NAG), and the ionic coordination between Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt; and the abundant carboxyl groups in AA and NAG. AA/NAG/Ca (AA, NAG, and Ca refer to acryloyl-6-aminocaproic acid, N-acryloyl 2-glycine and calcium chloride, respectively) hydrogel exhibited good mechanical properties, swelling and adhesion properties, flexibility, in vitro blood-clotting ability, and cytocompatibility. In vivo experiments on liver injury models and rat/rabbit nephron-sparing surgery models elucidated that the AA/NAG/Ca hydrogel had haemostasis performance and wound healing properties that led to short bleeding time, reduced bleeding volume, and well-organised nephron structures. An abdomen-caecum adhesion model indicated that the AA/NAG/Ca hydrogel showed excellent anti-adhesion properties. In summary, this multifunctional hydrogel exhibited potential for improving haemostasis and wound management in nephron-sparing surgeries, showing potential for clinical application. STATEMENT OF SIGNIFICANCE: Extended warm ischemia time during nephron sparing surgery negatively affected postoperative renal function due to the need for hemostasis at the wound with abundant blood supply, and postoperative wound healing and additional adhesions caused by the surgical procedure deserve attention. Based on the efficient and stable adhesion properties of hydrogels and the ability to promote wound healing. Herein, a series of adhesive self-healing biocompatible hydrogels were prepared based on free-radical polymerization of acryloyl-6-aminocaproic acid (AA) and N-acryloyl 2-glycine (NAG) and the ionic coordination between Ca2+ with the abundant carboxyl groups in AA and NAG. AA/NAG/Ca hydrogel showed hemostasis property in nephron sparing surgery model, promote kidney wound healing, and could perform anti-postoperative adhesion efficacy in an abdomen-caecum adhesion model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Knockout of the Circadian Clock Protein PER1 (Period1) Exacerbates Hypertension and Increases Kidney Injury in Dahl Salt-Sensitive Rats</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36093781/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36093781/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Circadian rhythms play an essential role in physiological function. The molecular clock that underlies circadian physiological function consists of a core group of transcription factors, including the protein PER1 (Period1). Studies in mice show that PER1 plays a role in the regulation of blood pressure and renal sodium handling; however, the results are dependent on the strain being studied. Using male Dahl salt-sensitive (SS) rats with global knockout of PER1 (&lt;em&gt;SS&lt;sup&gt;Per1-/-&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt;), we aim to test the hypothesis that PER1 plays a key role in the regulation of salt-sensitive blood pressure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; The model was generated using CRISPR/Cas9 and was characterized using radiotelemetry and measures of renal function and circadian rhythm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;SS&lt;sup&gt;Per1-/-&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; rats had similar mean arterial pressure when fed a normal 0.4% NaCl diet but developed augmented hypertension after three weeks on a high-salt (4% NaCl) diet. Despite being maintained on a normal 12:12 light:dark cycle, &lt;em&gt;SS&lt;sup&gt;Per1-/-&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; rats exhibited desynchrony mean arterial pressure rhythms on a high-salt diet, as evidenced by increased variability in the time of peak mean arterial pressure. &lt;em&gt;SS&lt;sup&gt;Per1-/-&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; rats excrete less sodium after three weeks on the high-salt diet. Furthermore, &lt;em&gt;SS&lt;sup&gt;Per1-/-&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; rats exhibited decreased creatinine clearance, a measurement of renal function, as well as increased signs of kidney tissue damage. &lt;em&gt;SS&lt;sup&gt;Per1-/-&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; rats also exhibited higher plasma aldosterone levels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; Altogether, our findings demonstrate that loss of PER1 in Dahl SS rats causes an array of deleterious effects, including exacerbation of the development of salt-sensitive hypertension and renal damage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SMPDL3b modulates radiation-induced DNA damage response in renal podocytes</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36094323/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36094323/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The kidneys are radiosensitive and dose-limiting organs for radiotherapy (RT) targeting abdominal and paraspinal tumors. Excessive radiation doses to the kidneys ultimately lead to radiation nephropathy. Our prior work unmasked a novel role for the lipid-modifying enzyme, sphingomyelin phosphodiesterase acid-like 3b (SMPDL3b), in regulating the response of renal podocytes to radiation injury. In this study, we investigated the role of SMPDL3b in DNA double-strand breaks (DSBs) repair in vitro and in vivo. We assessed the kinetics of DSBs recognition and repair along with the ATM pathway and nuclear sphingolipid metabolism in wild-type (WT) and SMPDL3b overexpressing (OE) human podocytes. We also assessed the extent of DNA damage repair in SMPDL3b knock-down (KD) human podocytes, and C57BL6 WT and podocyte-specific SMPDL3b-knock out (KO) mice after radiation injury. We found that SMPDL3b overexpression enhanced DSBs recognition and repair through modulating ATM nuclear shuttling. OE podocytes were protected against radiation-induced apoptosis by increasing the phosphorylation of p53 at serine 15 and attenuating subsequent caspase-3 cleavage. SMPDL3b overexpression prevented radiation-induced alterations in nuclear ceramide-1-phosphate (C1P) and ceramide levels. Interestingly, exogenous C1P pretreatment radiosensitized OE podocytes by delaying ATM nuclear foci formation and DSBs repair. On the other hand, SMPDL3b knock-down, in vitro and in vivo, induced a significant delay in DSBs repair. Additionally, increased activation of apoptosis was induced in podocytes of SMPDL3b-KO mice compared to WT mice at 24 h post-irradiation. Together, our results unravel a novel role for SMPDL3b in radiation-induced DNA damage response. The current work suggests that SMPDL3b modulates nuclear sphingolipid metabolism, ATM nuclear shuttling, and DSBs repair.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>E-prostanoid 3 receptor deficiency on myeloid cells protects against ischemic acute kidney injury via breaking the auto-amplification loop of necroinflammation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36087809/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36087809/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Necroinflammation plays an important role in disease settings such as acute kidney injury (AKI). We and others have elucidated that prostaglandins, which are critically involved in inflammation, may activate E-prostanoid 3 receptor (EP3) at low concentrations. However, how EP3 blockade interacts with regulated cell death and affects AKI remains unknown. In this study, AKI was induced by ischemia-reperfusion (30 minutes/24 hours) in Ep3 knockout (&lt;em&gt;Ep3&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt;), bone marrow chimeric, myeloid conditional EP3 knockout and corresponding control mice. The production of prostaglandins E2 and I2 was markedly increased after ischemia-reperfusion, and either abrogation or antagonism of EP3 ameliorated the injury. EP3 deficiency curbed inflammatory cytokine release, neutrophil infiltration and serum high-mobility group box 1 levels, but additional TLR4 inhibition with TAK-242 did not offer further protection against the injury and inflammation. The protection of &lt;em&gt;Ep3&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; was predominantly mediated by suppressing Mixed Lineage Kinase domain-Like-dependent necroptosis, resulting from the inhibition of cytokine generation and the switching of cell death modality from necroptosis to apoptosis through caspase-8 up-regulation, in part due to the restraint of IL-6/JAK2/STAT3 signaling. EP3 deficiency failed to further alleviate the injury when necroptosis was inhibited. &lt;em&gt;Ep3&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; in bone marrow-derived cells, particularly that in myeloid cells, protected kidneys to the same extent as that of global EP3 deletion. Thus, our results demonstrate that EP3 deficiency especially that on myeloid cells, ameliorates ischemic AKI via curbing inflammation and breaking the auto-amplification loop of necroinflammation. Hence, EP3 may be a promising target for the prevention and/or treatment of AKI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Regulator of calcineurin 1 deletion attenuates mitochondrial dysfunction and apoptosis in acute kidney injury through JNK/Mff signaling pathway</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36071051/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36071051/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ischemia-reperfusion (I/R) induced acute kidney injury (AKI), characterized by excessive mitochondrial damage and cell apoptosis, remains a clinical challenge. Recent studies suggest that regulator of calcineurin 1 (RCAN1) regulates mitochondrial function in different cell types, but the underlying mechanisms require further investigation. Herein, we aim to explore whether RCAN1 involves in mitochondrial dysfunction in AKI and the exact mechanism. In present study, AKI was induced by I/R and cisplatin in RCAN1flox/flox mice and mice with renal tubular epithelial cells (TECs)-specific deletion of RCAN1. The role of RCAN1 in hypoxia-reoxygenation (HR) and cisplatin-induced injury in human renal proximal tubule epithelial cell line HK-2 was also examined by overexpression and knockdown of RCAN1. Mitochondrial function was assessed by transmission electron microscopy, JC-1 staining, MitoSOX staining, ATP production, mitochondrial fission and mitophagy. Apoptosis was detected by TUNEL assay, Annexin V-FITC staining and Western blotting analysis of apoptosis-related proteins. It was found that protein expression of RCAN1 was markedly upregulated in I/R- or cisplatin-induced AKI mouse models, as well as in HR models in HK-2 cells. RCAN1 deficiency significantly reduced kidney damage, mitochondrial dysfunction, and cell apoptosis, whereas RCAN1 overexpression led to the opposite phenotypes. Our in-depth mechanistic exploration demonstrated that RCAN1 increases the phosphorylation of mitochondrial fission factor (Mff) by binding to downstream c-Jun N-terminal kinase (JNK), then promotes dynamin related protein 1 (Drp1) migration to mitochondria, ultimately leads to excessive mitochondrial fission of renal TECs. In conclusion, our study suggests that RCAN1 could induce mitochondrial dysfunction and apoptosis by activating the downstream JNK/Mff signaling pathway. RCAN1 may be a potential therapeutic target for conferring protection against I/R- or cisplatin-AKI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multimodal single cell sequencing implicates chromatin accessibility and genetic background in diabetic kidney disease progression</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36068241/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36068241/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The proximal tubule is a key regulator of kidney function and glucose metabolism. Diabetic kidney disease leads to proximal tubule injury and changes in chromatin accessibility that modify the activity of transcription factors involved in glucose metabolism and inflammation. Here we use single nucleus RNA and ATAC sequencing to show that diabetic kidney disease leads to reduced accessibility of glucocorticoid receptor binding sites and an injury-associated expression signature in the proximal tubule. We hypothesize that chromatin accessibility is regulated by genetic background and closely-intertwined with metabolic memory, which pre-programs the proximal tubule to respond differently to external stimuli. Glucocorticoid excess has long been known to increase risk for type 2 diabetes, which raises the possibility that glucocorticoid receptor inhibition may mitigate the adverse metabolic effects of diabetic kidney disease.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Roles and current applications of S-nitrosoglutathione in anti-infective biomaterials</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/36105674/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/36105674/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bacterial infections can compromise the physical and biological functionalities of humans and pose a huge economical and psychological burden on infected patients. Nitric oxide (NO) is a broad-spectrum antimicrobial agent, whose mechanism of action is not affected by bacterial resistance. S-nitrosoglutathione (GSNO), an endogenous donor and carrier of NO, has gained increasing attention because of its potent antibacterial activity and efficient biocompatibility. Significant breakthroughs have been made in the application of GSNO in biomaterials. This review is based on the existing evidence that comprehensively summarizes the progress of antimicrobial GSNO applications focusing on their anti-infective performance, underlying antibacterial mechanisms, and application in anti-infective biomaterials. We provide an accurate overview of the roles and applications of GSNO in antibacterial biomaterials and shed new light on the avenues for future studies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Factor H related proteins modulate complement activation on kidney cells</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36063874/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36063874/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Complement activation at a particular location is determined by the balance of activating and inhibitory proteins. Factor H is a key regulator of the alternative pathway of complement, and genetic or acquired impairments in Factor H are associated with glomerular injury. The human Factor H–related proteins (FHRs) comprise a family of five proteins that are structurally related to Factor H. Variations in the genes or expression levels of the FHRs are also associated with glomerular disease, although the mechanisms of glomerular protection/injury are incompletely understood. To explore the role of the FHRs on complement regulation/dysregulation in the kidney, we expressed and purified recombinant murine FHRs (FHRs A, B, C and E). These four distinct FHRs contain binding regions with high amino acid sequence homology to binding regions within Factor H, but we observed different interactions of the FHRs with Factor H binding ligands, including heparin and C3d. There was differential binding of the FHRs to the resident kidney cell types (mesangial, glomerular endothelial, podocytes, and tubular epithelial). All four FHRs caused complement dysregulation on kidney cell surfaces &lt;em&gt;in vitro&lt;/em&gt;, although the magnitude of the effect differed among the FHRs and also varied among the different kidney cells. However, only FHR E caused glomerular complement dysregulation when injected &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt; but did not exacerbate injury when injected into mice with ischemic acute kidney injury, an alternative pathway-mediated model. Thus, our experiments demonstrate that the FHRs have unique, and likely context-dependent, effects on the different cell types within the kidney.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An ex vivo culture model of kidney podocyte injury reveals mechanosensitive, synaptopodin-templating, sarcomere-like structures</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36044576/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36044576/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chronic kidney diseases are widespread and incurable. The biophysical mechanisms underlying them are unclear, in part because material systems for reconstituting the microenvironment of relevant kidney cells are limited. A critical question is how kidney podocytes (glomerular epithelial cells) regenerate foot processes of the filtration apparatus following injury. Recently identified sarcomere-like structures (SLSs) with periodically spaced myosin IIA and synaptopodin appear in injured podocytes in vivo. We hypothesized that SLSs template synaptopodin in the initial stages of recovery in response to microenvironmental stimuli and tested this hypothesis by developing an ex vivo culture system that allows control of the podocyte microenvironment. Results supported our hypothesis. SLSs in podocytes that migrated from isolated kidney glomeruli presented periodic synaptopodin-positive clusters that nucleated peripheral, foot process-like extensions. SLSs were mechanoresponsive to actomyosin inhibitors and substrate stiffness. Results suggest SLSs as mechanobiological mediators of podocyte recovery and as potential targets for therapeutic intervention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Urinary profile of PAHs and related compounds in women working in beauty salons</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36029813/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36029813/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;First survey of urinary PAHs, 1-OHP and TTMA levels in women working in beauty salons;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;High PAHs, 1-OHP and TTMA levels were detected in urine of beauticians after the work shift.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The urinary PAHs, 1-OHP and TTMA were correlated with “personal care products (PCPs) usage”.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some PAHs were associated with oxidative stress/kidney injury biomarkers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Beauty activities can be considered as a major source of PAHs, 1-OHP and TTMA exposures.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Polycyclic aromatic hydrocarbons (PAHs) are a group of chemical compounds which interest to human biological monitoring researches because of their potential carcinogenic, mutagenic, and teratogenic properties. However, the exposure of female beauticians to these contaminants is not well-reported. For biomonitoring of potential exposure of female cosmeticians to PAHs in beauty salons, urine samples were taken from cosmetologist women (n = 50.00) and housewives (n = 35.00) as the exposure group (EG) and control group (CG), respectively. Next, unmetabolized PAHs levels as well as the concentration of - 1-hydroxypyrene (1-OHP) were analyzed in these specimens. In addition, since benzene has some common source with PAHs, in this study t, t&amp;rsquo;-Muconic acid (TTMA) level was also determined as the metabolite and indicator of exposure to benzene. The results indicated a high detection frequency of the target compounds (PAHs, 1-OHP and TTMA) in the urine specimens of beauticians. The results also showed that there is a significant difference between the concentration of these pollutants in the urine specimens of the exposure and control groups. The median concentration of ΣPAHs, 1-OHP, and TTMA in the before exposure (BE) specimens collected from the exposure group were 337.42 ng/L, 593.92 ng/L, and 247.90 μg/L, respectively. However, a higher concentration of these contaminants was observed in the after exposure specimens with a median concentration of 423.29 ng/L, 745.03 ng/L, and 310.97 μg/L, respectively. In terms of contribution of PAHs compounds in total toxic equivalents, DahA, BaP, and IndP with 59.03, 28.73, and 2.86 % had the largest share. In this study, it was also observed that some kidney damage biomarkers as well as some oxidative stress injury biomarkers are positively and significantly correlated with the urinary values of ∑PAHs. Thus, it can be concluded that high health risks threaten the female beauticians regarding kidney injury and DNA oxidative stress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Assessing the Global Impact on the Mouse Kidney After Traumatic Brain Injury: A Transcriptomic Study</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36042866/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36042866/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Purpose:&lt;/em&gt; In this study, we use animal models combined with bioinformatics strategies to investigate the potential changes in overall renal transcriptional expression after traumatic brain injury.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; Microarray analysis was performed after kidney acquisition using unilateral controlled cortical impact as the primary mouse TBI model. Multi-oriented gene set enrichment analysis was performed for differentially expressed genes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; The results showed that TBI affected the gene set associated with mitochondria function in kidney cells, and a negative enrichment of gene sets associated with immune cell migration and epidermal development was also observed. Analysis of the disease phenotype gene set revealed that differential expression of mitochondria-related genes was associated with lactate metabolism. Alternatively, activation and adhesion of immune cells associated with the complement system may promote autoinflammation in kidney tissue. The simulated immune cell infiltration analysis showed an increase in the proportion of activated memory CD4 T cells and a decrease in the proportion of resting memory CD4 T cells, suggesting that activated memory CD4 T cell infiltration may be involved in the inflammation of renal tissue and cause damage to renal cells, such as principal cells, mesangial cells and loops of Henle cells.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/em&gt; This study is the first to reveal the effects of brain trauma on the kidney. TBI may affect the expression of mitochondria function-related gene sets in renal cells by increasing lactate. It may also affect renal mesangial cells by inducing increased infiltration of immune cells through mechanisms related to complement system activation or autoimmune antibodies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rhabdomyolysis-induced acute kidney injury and concomitant apoptosis induction via ROS-mediated ER stress is efficaciously counteracted by epigallocatechin gallate</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36028100/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36028100/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rhabdomyolysis induced acute kidney injury (RIAKI) is a life-threatening condition responsible for approximately 19-58% of AKI cases worldwide. We performed an intramuscular injection of glycerol (10 mL/kg) in male wistar rats to induce AKI. Epigallocatechin gallate (EGCG) was administered for 3 consecutive days to evaluate its protective effects. We observed significant downregulation in serum creatinine, blood urea nitrogen (BUN) and LDH at different time points on EGCG treatment groups in a dose-dependent manner. Similarly, H&amp;amp;E staining also revealed that EGCG was able to reduce the formation of damaged tubules and tubular necrosis which was prominently spread throughout the kidney tissue of glycerol treatment group. Concomitantly, we observed upregulated inflammation, ER stress and elevated oxidative stress in the glycerol treated group only, which was significantly normalized upon EGCG treatment in both in vitro and in vivo studies. The occurrence of apoptosis in kidney tubules was found to be relatively higher in glycerol treated group and H2O2 treated HEK-293 cells. The results obtained after EGCG treatment revealed a significant decrease in apoptotic cell population, which was further validated by immunofluorescence staining against p53 and comet assay in HEK-293 cells and p53 IHC in kidney tissues. Western blotting also revealed a systemic downregulation of intrinsic mitochondrial apoptotic pathway markers such as bax, bcl-2, pro and cleaved caspase 3, caspase 9 and PARP1. Additionally, the results for flow cytometry analysis and TUNEL assay corroborated apoptotic equilibrium. Conclusively, we reckon EGCG as a multi-therapeutic natural product that can be used the for treatment of AKI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bioengineered immunomodulatory organelle targeted nanozymes for photodynamic immunometabolic therapy</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35987351/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35987351/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Intelligent nanomedicines integrated with stimuli-responsive components enable on-demand customizable treatment options which would improve therapeutic outcome and reduce systemic toxicity. In this work, we explore the synergistic therapeutic potential of photodynamic therapy and immunometabolic modulation to achieve tumour regression and to trigger an adaptive immunity to prevent tumour recurrence. The therapeutic potential of the fabricated Bioengineered Immunomodulatory Organelle targeted Nanozymes (BIONs) was tested on 3D printed mini-brains which could effectively recapitulate the biologically relevant interactions between glioblastoma cells and macrophages. In the presence of glioblastoma organotypic brain slices, activated BIONs upregulated the cell surface expression of CD86, a costimulatory molecule and CD83, maturation marker, on monocyte derived dendritic cells, suggesting its ability to elicit a strong immune response. Furthermore, the antigen pulsed dendritic cells by chemotaxis and transendothelial migration readily relocate into the draining lymph node where they present the antigenic cargo to enable the proliferation of T lymphocytes. The stealth and tunable catalytic activity of BIONs prevent ROS mediated diseases such as acute kidney injury by providing environment dependent protection without compromising on its promising anti-cancer activity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blocking CHOP-dependent TXNIP shuttling to mitochondria attenuates albuminuria and mitigates kidney injury in nephrotic syndrome</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35994650/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35994650/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Significance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Albuminuria is the hallmark of nephrotic syndrome (NS), a leading cause of chronic kidney disease affecting 500 million people worldwide. Thus, there is a clear need to discover novel drug targets to treat proteinuric kidney disease. We demonstrate that thioredoxin-interacting protein (TXNIP), a redox protein that forms the complex with antioxidant oxidoreductase thioredoxin (Trx), relocates from nucleus to mitochondria when C/EBP homologous protein (CHOP), a major endoplasmic reticulum (ER) stress-associated transcription factor, is induced by albuminuria. TXNIP shuttling to mitochondria is essential for mitochondrial reactive oxygen species (ROS) production, which oxidizes mitochondrial-specific Trx2 and disrupts the association between Trx2-TXNIP and Trx2-ASK1 in mitochondria, leading to NLRP3 inflammasome activation and mitochondria-dependent apoptosis. Thus, TXNIP is a potential target to treat NS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Albuminuria is a hallmark of glomerular disease of various etiologies. It is not only a symptom of glomerular disease but also a cause leading to glomerulosclerosis, interstitial fibrosis, and eventually, a decline in kidney function. The molecular mechanism underlying albuminuria-induced kidney injury remains poorly defined. In our genetic model of nephrotic syndrome (NS), we have identified CHOP (C/EBP homologous protein)-TXNIP (thioredoxin-interacting protein) as critical molecular linkers between albuminuria-induced ER dysfunction and mitochondria dyshomeostasis. TXNIP is a ubiquitously expressed redox protein that binds to and inhibits antioxidant enzyme, cytosolic thioredoxin 1 (Trx1), and mitochondrial Trx2. However, very little is known about the regulation and function of TXNIP in NS. By utilizing &lt;em&gt;Chop&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Txnip&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; mice as well as &lt;sup&gt;68&lt;/sup&gt;Ga-Galuminox, our molecular imaging probe for detection of mitochondrial reactive oxygen species (ROS) in vivo, we demonstrate that CHOP up-regulation induced by albuminuria drives TXNIP shuttling from nucleus to mitochondria, where it is required for the induction of mitochondrial ROS. The increased ROS accumulation in mitochondria oxidizes Trx2, thus liberating TXNIP to associate with mitochondrial nod-like receptor protein 3 (NLRP3) to activate inflammasome, as well as releasing mitochondrial apoptosis signal-regulating kinase 1 (ASK1) to induce mitochondria-dependent apoptosis. Importantly, inhibition of TXNIP translocation and mitochondrial ROS overproduction by CHOP deletion suppresses NLRP3 inflammasome activation and p-ASK1-dependent mitochondria apoptosis in NS. Thus, targeting TXNIP represents a promising therapeutic strategy for the treatment of NS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Targeting Myocardial Mitochondria-STING-Polyamine Axis Prevents Cardiac Hypertrophy in Chronic Kidney Disease</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36061341/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36061341/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HIGHLIGHTS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mitochondrial damage is early and prominent in cardiomyocytes under CKD milieu.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mitochondrial damage stimulates myocardial STING-NFκB pathway to drive hypertrophy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;NFκB transactivates ODC1-PUT metabolic flux in cardiomyocytes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ODC1-PUT metabolic flux is required for STING/NFκB-driven cardiac hypertrophy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Targeting mitochondria-STING-ODC1 axis prevents cardiac hypertrophy in CKD.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chronic kidney disease (CKD) is well recognized as a distinct contributor to cardiac hypertrophy, while the underlying mechanism remains incompletely understood. Here, the authors show that myocardial mitochondrial oxidative damage is early and prominent in CKD and distinctively stimulates the STING-NFκB pathway by releasing mitochondrial DNA to drive cardiac hypertrophy. Furthermore, the authors reveal that ornithine decarboxylase (ODC1)-putrescine metabolic flux is transactivated by NFκB and is required for the STING-NFκB pathway to drive cardiac hypertrophy. Finally, genetic or pharmacologic inhibition of the myocardial mitochondria-STING-NFκB-ODC1 axis significantly prevents CKD-associated cardiac hypertrophy. Therefore, targeting the myocardial mitochoandria-STING-NFκB-ODC1 axis is a promising therapeutic strategy for cardiac hypertrophy in patients with CKD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Immune-mediated tubule atrophy promotes acute kidney injury to chronic kidney disease transition</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35986026/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35986026/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Incomplete repair after acute kidney injury can lead to development of chronic kidney disease. To define the mechanism of this response, we compared mice subjected to identical unilateral ischemia-reperfusion kidney injury with either contralateral nephrectomy (where tubule repair predominates) or contralateral kidney intact (where tubule atrophy predominates). By day 14, the kidneys undergoing atrophy had more macrophages with higher expression of chemokines, correlating with a second wave of proinflammatory neutrophil and T cell recruitment accompanied by increased expression of tubular injury genes and a decreased proportion of differentiated tubules. Depletion of neutrophils and T cells after day 5 reduced tubular cell loss and associated kidney atrophy. In kidney biopsies from patients with acute kidney injury, T cell and neutrophil numbers negatively correlated with recovery of estimated glomerular filtration rate. Together, our findings demonstrate that macrophage persistence after injury promotes a T cell- and neutrophil-mediated proinflammatory milieu and progressive tubule damage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Discovery and evaluation of phenacrylanilide derivatives as novel potential anti-liver fibrosis agents</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36037790/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36037790/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Phenacrylanilide derivates inhibited TGF-β1- induced hepatic stellate cell proliferation and activation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Compound 42 inhibited fibrotic markers expression with lower toxicity.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Administration of compound 42 improved liver fibrosis and inhibited HSC activation in CCl4-induced mouse fibrosis.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Compound 42 regulated unbalanced immune microenvironment &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Liver fibrosis is characterized by the excessive deposition of extracellular matrix components and results from chronic liver injury. At present, there is no approved drug for the treatment of liver fibrosis by the Food and Drug Administration. Here, we have reported a series of novel compounds with phenacrylanilide scaffolds that potently inhibit the transfer growth factor β1 (TGF-β1)-induced activation of LX-2, a hepatic stellate cell (HSC) line. Among them, compound 42 suppressed TGF-β1-induced upregulation of fibrotic markers (α-SMA and fibronectin) and showed excellent safety in vitro. Furthermore, in a carbon tetrachloride (CCl4) -induced liver fibrosis model, 42 at a dose of 30 mg/kg/day through oral administration for 3 weeks effectively improved liver function, restored damaged liver structures, and reduced collagen deposition, with a greater effect than Tranilast. In addition, epithelial-mesenchymal transition (EMT) is inhibited by compound 42 in the process of fibrosis. Meanwhile, the imbalanced immune microenvironment could also be effectively reversed. More interestingly, compound 42 prolongs the survival of CCl4 mice and ameliorates CCl4-induced injury to spleen, kidney, lung and heart. Altogether, these results suggest that 42 could be a potential drug candidate for the treatment of liver fibrosis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sphingosine 1-phosphate signaling in perivascular cells enhances inflammation and fibrosis in the kidney</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35976996/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35976996/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chronic kidney disease (CKD), characterized by sustained inflammation and progressive fibrosis, is highly prevalent and can eventually progress to end-stage kidney disease. However, current treatments to slow CKD progression are limited. Sphingosine 1-phosphate (S1P), a product of sphingolipid catabolism, is a pleiotropic mediator involved in many cellular functions, and drugs targeting S1P signaling have previously been studied particularly for autoimmune diseases. The primary mechanism of most of these drugs is functional antagonism of S1P receptor-1 (S1P1) expressed on lymphocytes and the resultant immunosuppressive effect. Here, we documented the role of local S1P signaling in perivascular cells in the progression of kidney fibrosis using primary kidney perivascular cells and several conditional mouse models. S1P was predominantly produced by sphingosine kinase 2 in kidney perivascular cells and exported via spinster homolog 2 (Spns2). It bound to S1P1 expressed in perivascular cells to enhance production of proinflammatory cytokines/chemokines upon injury, leading to immune cell infiltration and subsequent fibrosis. A small-molecule Spns2 inhibitor blocked S1P transport, resulting in suppression of inflammatory signaling in human and mouse kidney perivascular cells in vitro and amelioration of kidney fibrosis in mice. Our study provides insight into the regulation of inflammation and fibrosis by S1P and demonstrates the potential of Spns2 inhibition as a treatment for CKD and potentially other inflammatory and fibrotic diseases that avoids the adverse events associated with systemic modulation of S1P receptors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Markers of Kidney Tubular Secretion and Risk of Adverse Events in SPRINT Participants with CKD</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35973732/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35973732/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Kidney tubular secretion is an essential mechanism for clearing many common antihypertensive drugs and other metabolites and toxins. It is unknown whether novel measures of tubular secretion are associated with adverse events (AEs) during hypertension treatment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; Among 2089 SPRINT (Systolic Blood Pressure Intervention Trial) participants with baseline eGFR &amp;lt;60 ml/min per 1.73 m2, we created a summary secretion score by averaging across the standardized spot urine-to-plasma ratios of ten novel endogenous tubular secretion measures, with lower urine-to-plasma ratios reflecting worse tubular secretion. Multivariable Cox proportional hazards models were used to evaluate associations between the secretion score and risk of a composite of prespecified serious AEs (hypotension, syncope, bradycardia, AKI, electrolyte abnormalities, and injurious falls). The follow-up protocol for SPRINT routinely assessed two laboratory monitoring AEs (hyperkalemia and hypokalemia).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; Overall, 30% of participants experienced at least one AE during a median follow-up of 3.0 years. In multivariable models adjusted for eGFR and albuminuria, lower (worse) secretion scores at baseline were associated with greater risk of the composite AE outcome (hazard ratio per 1-SD lower secretion score, 1.16; 95% confidence interval, 1.04 to 1.27). In analyses of the individual AEs, lower secretion score was associated with significantly greater risk of AKI, serious electrolyte abnormalities, and ambulatory hyperkalemia. Associations were similar across randomized treatment assignment groups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/em&gt; Among SPRINT participants with CKD, worse tubular secretion was associated with greater risk of AEs, independent of eGFR and albuminuria.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MicroRNAs in kidney injury and disease</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/35974169/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/35974169/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MicroRNAs (miRNAs) are small non-coding RNAs that regulate gene expression by degrading or repressing the translation of their target messenger RNAs. As miRNAs are critical regulators of cellular homeostasis, their dysregulation is a crucial component of cell and organ injury. A substantial body of evidence indicates that miRNAs are involved in the pathophysiology of acute kidney injury (AKI), chronic kidney disease and allograft damage. Different subsets of miRNAs are dysregulated during AKI, chronic kidney disease and allograft rejection, which could reflect differences in the physiopathology of these conditions. miRNAs that have been investigated in AKI include &lt;em&gt;miR-21&lt;/em&gt;, which has an anti-apoptotic role, and &lt;em&gt;miR-214&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;miR-668&lt;/em&gt;, which regulate mitochondrial dynamics. Various miRNAs are downregulated in diabetic kidney disease, including the &lt;em&gt;miR-30&lt;/em&gt; family and &lt;em&gt;miR-146a&lt;/em&gt;, which protect against inflammation and fibrosis. Other miRNAs such as miR-193 and miR-92a induce podocyte dedifferentiation in glomerulonephritis. In transplantation, miRNAs have been implicated in allograft rejection and injury. Further work is needed to identify and validate miRNAs as biomarkers of graft function and of kidney disease development and progression. Use of combinations of miRNAs together with other molecular markers could potentially improve diagnostic or predictive power and facilitate clinical translation. In addition, targeting specific miRNAs at different stages of disease could be a promising therapeutic strategy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chlorogenic Acid Prevents Hyperuricemia Nephropathy via Regulating TMAO-Related Gut Microbes and Inhibiting the PI3K/AKT/mTOR Pathway</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35950815/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35950815/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hyperuricemia is an independent hazard factor of renal injury and can induce renal fibrosis, promoting the development of chronic kidney disease (CKD). This study aimed to explore the probability of chlorogenic acid (CGA) as a potential substance for preventing hyperuricemia nephropathy (HN). Pretreatment with CGA downregulated SUA, BUN, and CR levels, relieved oxidative stress and inflammatory response, alleviated kidney fibrosis, and contributed to the prevention of HN. In the gut microbiota, &lt;em&gt;Blautia&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Enterococcus&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Faecalibaculum&lt;/em&gt; related to trimethylamine N-oxide (TMAO) synthesis were significantly increased in HN rats. In addition, it showed a significant increase in serum TMAO content in HN rats. However, CGA regulated the cascade response of the microbiota-TMAO signaling to reverse the increase of serum TMAO. CGA also decreased the protein expression of protein kinase B (AKT) phosphorylation, phosphatidylinositide 3-kinase (PI3K), and mammalian target of rapamycin (mTOR) by reducing the production of TMAO. CGA delayed kidney fibrosis in HN rats as evidenced by regulating the cascade response of the microbiota-TMAO-PI3K/AKT/mTOR signaling pathway. In summary, CGA can be an excellent candidate for HN prevention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Persistent DNA damage underlies tubular cell polyploidization and progression to chronic kidney disease in kidneys deficient in the DNA repair protein FAN1</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35931300/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35931300/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Defective DNA repair pathways contribute to the development of chronic kidney disease (CKD) in humans. However, the molecular mechanisms underlying DNA damage-induced CKD pathogenesis are not well understood. Here, we investigated the role of tubular cell DNA damage in the pathogenesis of CKD using mice in which the DNA repair protein Fan1 was knocked out. The phenotype of these mice is orthologous to the human DNA damage syndrome, karyomegalic interstitial nephritis (KIN). Inactivation of Fan1 in kidney proximal tubule cells sensitized the kidneys to genotoxic and obstructive injury characterized by replication stress and persistent DNA damage response activity. Accumulation of DNA damage in Fan1 tubular cells induced epithelial dedifferentiation and tubular injury. Characteristic to KIN, cells with chronic DNA damage failed to complete mitosis and underwent polyploidization. In vitro and in vivo studies showed that polyploidization was caused by the overexpression of DNA replication factors CDT1 and CDC6 in FAN1 deficient cells. Mechanistically, inhibiting DNA replication with Roscovitine reduced tubular injury, blocked the development of KIN and mitigated kidney function in these Fan1 knockout mice. Thus, our data delineate a mechanistic pathway by which persistent DNA damage in the kidney tubular cells leads to kidney injury and development of CKD. Furthermore, therapeutic modulation of cell cycle activity may provide an opportunity to mitigate the DNA damage response induced CKD progression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accurate identification of kidney injury progression via a fluorescent biosensor array</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35915355/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35915355/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Identifying the progress of kidney injury may aid the effective treatment and intervention. Herein, we developed a fluorescent biosensor array for instantaneous and accurate identification of the kidney injury progression via &amp;ldquo;doubled&amp;rdquo; signals. The multichannel biosensor array consisted of polydopamine-polyethyleneimine (PDA-PEI) and multicolor-labelled different length of DNAs including AAAAA-Cyanine7 (5A-Cy7), AAAAAAAAAA-Texas Red (10A-Texas Red), and AAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAA-VIC (20A-VIC). Facing to the variety of protein in urine with alterable charge accompanied with different progress of kidney injury, the composition of urine replaces the DNA signal molecules, forming their special fluorescence patterns. Taking the size of protein into consideration, the original three variables induced by the protein charge were extended to six variables induced by the two factors of protein particle size and charge difference, which could provide a more accurate strategy to identify the progress of kidney injury. Notably, this strategy not only opened up new perspective for identification the progress of kidney injury via the size and charge of urine protein, but also improved the resolving power of sensor array by increasing the number of sensor elements for extending their potential application to various diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neutrophil membrane engineered HucMSC sEVs alleviate cisplatin-induced AKI by enhancing cellular uptake and targeting</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35918718/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35918718/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Human umbilical cord mesenchymal stem cells-derived small extracellular vesicles (hucMSC-sEVs) have been demonstrated as a therapeutic agent to prevent and treat cisplatin-induced acute kidney injury (AKI). However, hucMSC-sEVs still face many problems and challenges in the repair and treatment of tissue injury, including short circulation time, insufficient targeting, and low therapeutic efficacy. Therefore, we constructed engineered hybrid vesicles fused with nanovesicles derived from human neutrophil membranes and hucMSC-sEVs, named neutrophil membrane engineered hucMSC-sEVs (NEX). NEX significantly enhanced the targeting of hucMSC-sEVs to injured kidney tissues, improved the impaired renal function via reducing pro-inflammatory cytokines expression, promoted the proliferation of renal tissue cells, and inhibited renal cell apoptosis in vivo. In addition, NEX enhanced hucMSC-sEVs uptake by NRK52E cells, but inhibited its uptake by RAW264.7 cells. Moreover, administration of NEX reduced cellular oxidative stress and promoted proliferation of NRK52E cells treated with cisplatin in vitro. In summary, our findings indicate that this design of a universal approach enhances the targeting and therapeutic efficacy of hucMSC-sEVs in kidney tissue regeneration, and provides new evidence promoting its clinical application.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cellular communication network 2 (connective tissue growth factor) aggravates acute DNA damage and subsequent DNA damage response-senescence-fibrosis following kidney ischemia reperfusion injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35921911/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35921911/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chronic allograft dysfunction with progressive fibrosis of unknown cause remains a major issue after kidney transplantation, characterized by ischemia-reperfusion injury (IRI). One hypothesis to account for this is that spontaneous progressive tubulointerstitial fibrosis following IRI is driven by cellular senescence evolving from a prolonged, unresolved DNA damage response (DDR). Since cellular communication network factor 2 ((CCN2), formerly called connective tissue growth factor), an established mediator of kidney fibrosis, is also involved in senescence-associated pathways, we investigated the relation between CCN2 and cellular senescence following kidney transplantation. Tubular CCN2 overexpression was found to be associated with DDR, loss of kidney function and tubulointerstitial fibrosis in both the early and the late phase in human kidney allograft biopsies. Consistently, CCN2 deficient mice developed reduced senescence and tubulointerstitial fibrosis in the late phase; six weeks after experimental IRI. Moreover, tubular DDR markers and plasma urea were less elevated in CCN2 knockout than in wild-type mice. Finally, CCN2 administration or overexpression in epithelial cells induced upregulation of tubular senescence-associated genes including p21, while silencing of CCN2 alleviated DDR induced by anoxia-reoxygenation injury in cultured proximal tubule epithelial cells. Thus, our observations indicate that inhibition of CCN2 can mitigate IRI-induced acute kidney injury, DNA damage, and the subsequent DDR-senescence-fibrosis sequence. Hence, targeting CCN2 might help to protect the kidney from transplantation-associated post-IRI chronic kidney dysfunction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Class IIa histone deacetylase inhibition ameliorates acute kidney injury by suppressing renal tubular cell apoptosis and enhancing autophagy and proliferation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35935816/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35935816/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Expression and function of histone deacetylases (HDACs) vary with cell types and pathological conditions. Our recent studies showed that pharmacological targeting class IIa HDACs attenuated renal fibrosis, but the effect of class IIa HDAC inhibition on acute kidney injury (AKI) remains unknown. In this study, we found that four class IIa HDACs (4, 5, 7, 9) were highly expressed in the kidney of folic acid (FA) and ischemia/reperfusion (I/R)-induced AKI in mice. Administration of TMP269, a potent and selective class IIa HDAC inhibitor, improved renal function and reduced tubular cell injury and apoptosis, with concomitant suppression of HDAC4 and elevation of acetyl-histone H3. Mechanistical studies showed that TMP269 treatment inhibited FA and I/R-induced caspase-3 cleavage, Bax expression and p53 phosphorylation. Conversely, TMP269 administration preserved expression of E-cadherin, BMP7, Klotho and Bcl-2 in injured kidneys. Moreover, TMP269 was effective in promoting cellular autophagy as indicated by increased expression of Atg7, beclin-1, and LC3II, and promoted renal tubular cell proliferation as shown by increased number of proliferating cell nuclear antigen-positive cells and expression of cyclin E. Finally, blocking class IIa HDACs inhibited FA-and I/R-induced phosphorylation of extracellular signal-regulated kinases 1 and 2, and p38, two signaling pathways associated with the pathogenesis of AKI. Collectively, these results suggest that pharmacological inhibition of class IIa HDACs protects against AKI through ameliorating apoptosis, enhancing autophagy and promoting proliferation of renal tubular cells by targeting multiple signaling pathways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Novel gold-platinum nanoparticles serve as broad-spectrum antioxidants for attenuating ischemia reperfusion injury of the kidney</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35870640/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35870640/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kidney ischemia reperfusion injury (IRI) is a common and inevitable pathological condition in routine urological practices, especially during transplantation. Severe kidney IRI may even induce systemic damage to peripheral organs, and lead to multisystem organ failure. However, no standard clinical treatment option is currently available. It has been reported that kidney IRI is predominantly associated with abnormally increased endogenous reactive oxygen species (ROS). Scavenging excessive ROS may reduce the damage caused by oxidative stress and subsequently alleviate kidney IRI. Here, we reported a simple and efficient one-step synthesis of gold-platinum nanoparticles (AuPt NPs) with a gold core having a loose and branched outer platinum shell with superior ROS scavenging capacity to possibly treat kidney IRI. These AuPt NPs exhibited multiple enzyme-like anti-oxidative properties simultaneously possessing catalase- and peroxidase-like activity. These particles showed excellent cell protective capability, and alleviated kidney IRI both in vitro and in vivo without obvious toxicity, by suppressing cell apoptosis, inflammatory cytokine release, and inflammasome formation. Meanwhile, AuPt NPs also had an effect on inhibiting the transition to chronic kidney disease by reducing kidney fibrosis in the long term. Thus, AuPt NPs might be a good therapeutic agent for kidney IRI management and may be helpful for the development of clinical treatments for kidney IRI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Autophagy promotes GSDME-mediated pyroptosis via intrinsic and extrinsic apoptotic pathways in cobalt chloride-induced hypoxia reoxygenation-acute kidney injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35863214/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35863214/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cobalt ions induced more serious damage in the reoxygenation stage in HRI.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CoCl&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; induced GSDME-mediated pyroptosis in the HRI-AKI model.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CoCl&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;-activated GSDME was cleaved via the intrinsic and extrinsic apoptotic pathways in HRI-AKI.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CoCl&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;-elevated autophagy promoted the induction of apoptosis and GSDME-mediated pyroptosis in HRI-AKI.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cobalt is a transition element that abundantly exists in the environment. Besides direct hypoxia stress, cobalt ions indirectly induce hypoxia-reoxygenation injury (HRI), the main cause of acute kidney injury (AKI), a life-threatening clinical syndrome characterized by the necrosis of the proximal tubular epithelial cells (PTECs) and inflammation. Pyroptosis, a type of inflammatory programmed cell death, might play an essential role in HRI-AKI. However, whether pyroptosis is involved in cobalt chloride (CoCl&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;)-induced HRI-AKI remains unknown. Autophagy is a cellular biological process maintaining cell homeostasis that is involved in cell damage in AKI, yet the underlying regulatory mechanism of autophagy on pyroptosis has not been fully understood. In this study, the in vitro and in vivo models of CoCl&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;-induced HRI-AKI were established with HK-2 cell line and C57BL/6J mouse. Pyroptosis-related markers were detected with western blotting and immunofluorescence assays, and results showed that gasdermin E (GSDME)-mediated pyroptosis was involved in the cell damage in HRI-AKI. Specific chemical inhibitors of caspase 3, caspase 8, and caspase 9 significantly inhibited GSDME-mediated pyroptosis, verifying that GSDME-mediated pyroptosis was induced via the activation of caspase 3/8/9. The western blotting and immunofluorescence assays were adopted to detect the accumulation of the autophagosomes, and results suggested that HRI increased the autophagic level. The effects of autophagy on apoptosis and pyroptosis were evaluated using lentivirus transfection assays to knock down autophagy-specific genes atg5 and fip200, and results demonstrated that autophagy induced GSDME-mediated pyroptosis via apoptotic pathways in HRI-AKI. Our results revealed the involvement of GSDME-mediated pyroptosis in CoCl&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;-induced HRI-AKI and promoted the understanding of the regulatory mechanism of GSDME cleavage. Our study might provide a potential therapeutic target for HRI-AKI, and will be helpful for the risk evaluation of cobalt exposure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ceria nanoparticles prophylactic used for renal ischemia-reperfusion injury treatment by attenuating oxidative stress and inflammatory response</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35926357/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35926357/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Renal ischemia-reperfusion (IR) injury (RIRI) is the leading cause of acute kidney injury (AKI), a common disease with high morbidity and mortality. However, due to the lack of effective diagnostic and therapeutic tools, patients have to resort to conservative treatment. To address this issue, we have developed a novel prophylactic strategy that involves the pre-treatment use of ceria nanoparticles (CNPs) before surgery. Based on our careful study of the three different sizes of CNPs that we synthesized, 46 nm (NP46), 81 nm (NP81), and 118 nm (NP118), we have found that NP118 can be used as effective prophylactic agents against RIRI and subsequent renal fibrosis. In our experiments, the CNPs exhibited excellent antioxidant and anti-inflammatory activities in vitro and effectively protected the kidney against RIRI and renal fibrosis in vivo, as proved by the decreases in renal lesions, serum creatinine, blood urea nitrogen, apoptotic cell, KIM-1 expression, and fibrotic area in CNPs treated samples relative to RIRI group. Mechanistically, not only did the CNPs reduce oxidative stress by regulating the Nrf2 pathway, but they also attenuated RIRI induced inflammatory response by decreasing macrophage infiltration and polarization to M1 phenotype, and reducing pro-inflammatory cytokine and chemokine production. In vitro results further confirmed that CNPs pre-treatment not only dramatically decreased intracellular ROS production in renal tubular epithelial cells and vascular endothelial cells, but also effectively attenuated lipopolysaccharide-induced inflammation in RAW264.7 cells. In addition, we found that one fourth of the NP118 persisted for more than 21 days in IR kidneys, and that out of the three sizes of CNPs, NP118 achieved the best results in all our experiments. Our study provides new insights into the usage and majorization of CNPs as a potential therapy to treat or prevent RIRI and renal fibrosis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plk2-mediated phosphorylation and translocalization of Nrf2 activates anti-inflammation through p53/Plk2/p21cip1 signaling in acute kidney injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35842499/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35842499/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Plk2 is a cellular stress-responsive factor that is induced in response to oxidative stress. However, the roles of Plk2 in acute kidney injury (AKI) have not been clarified. We previously found that Plk2 is an interacting factor of Nrf2 in response to cellular stress, since Plk2 is upregulated in the Nrf2-dependent network. Here, we show that the levels of p53, Plk2, p21&lt;sup&gt;cip1&lt;/sup&gt;, and chromatin-bound Nrf2 were all upregulated in kidney tissues of mice or NRK52E cells treated with either cisplatin or methotrexate. Upregulation of Plk2 by p53 led to an increase of Nrf2 in both soluble and chromatin fractions in cisplatin-treated NRK52E cells. Consistently, depletion of Plk2 suppressed the levels of Nrf2. Of note, Plk2 directly phosphorylated Nrf2 at Ser40, which facilitated its interaction with p21&lt;sup&gt;cip1&lt;/sup&gt; and translocation into the nuclei for the activation of anti-oxidative and anti-inflammatory factors in response to AKI. Together, these findings suggest that Plk2 may serve as an anti-oxidative and anti-inflammatory regulator through the phosphorylation and activation of Nrf2 to protect kidney cells from kidney toxicants and that Plk2 and Nrf2 therefore work cooperatively for the protection and survival of kidney cells from harmful stresses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>14-3-3ζ inhibits maladaptive repair in renal tubules by regulating YAP and reduces renal interstitial fibrosis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35840657/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35840657/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acute kidney injury (AKI) refers to a group of common clinical syndromes characterized by acute renal dysfunction, which may lead to chronic kidney disease (CKD), and this process is called the AKI-CKD transition. The transcriptional coactivator YAP can promote the AKI-CKD transition by regulating the expression of profibrotic factors, and 14-3-3 protein zeta (14-3-3ζ), an important regulatory protein of YAP, may prevent the AKI-CKD transition. We established an AKI-CKD model in mice by unilateral renal ischemia-reperfusion injury and overexpressed 14-3-3ζ in mice using a fluid dynamics-based gene transfection technique. We also overexpressed and knocked down 14-3-3ζ in vitro. In AKI-CKD model mice, 14-3-3ζ expression was significantly increased at the AKI stage. During the development of chronic disease, the expression of 14-3-3ζ tended to decrease, whereas active YAP was consistently overexpressed. In vitro, we found that 14-3-3ζ can combine with YAP, promote the phosphorylation of YAP, inhibit YAP nuclear translocation, and reduce the expression of fibrosis-related proteins. In an in vivo intervention experiment, we found that the overexpression of 14-3-3ζ slowed the process of renal fibrosis in a mouse model of AKI-CKD. These findings suggest that 14-3-3ζ can affect the expression of fibrosis-related proteins by regulating YAP, inhibit the maladaptive repair of renal tubular epithelial cells, and prevent the AKI-CKD transition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exosomal lncRNA TUG1 derived from human urine-derived stem cells attenuates renal ischemia/reperfusion injury by interacting with SRSF1 to regulate ASCL4-mediated ferroptosis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35841017/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35841017/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;LncRNA TUG1 carried by USC-Exo regulates cell ferroptosis.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;LncRNA TUG1 regulates the stability of ACSL4 mRNA by interacting with SRSF1.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;LncRNA TUG1 alleviates IRI-induced AKI by suppressing ACSL4-mediated ferroptosis.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Human urine-derived stem cells (USCs)-derived exosomes (USC-Exo) could improve kidney ischemia/reperfusion injury (IRI), while the underlying mechanisms of this protective effect remain unclear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; Human USCs and USC-Exo were isolated and verified by morphology and specific biomarkers. The effects of USC-Exo on ferroptosis and kidney injury were detected in the IRI-induced acute kidney injury (AKI) model in C57BL/6 mice. The effects of USC-Exo on ferroptosis and lncRNA taurine-upregulated gene 1 (TUG1) were detected in hypoxia/reoxygenation (H/R)-treated human proximal tubular epithelial cells (HK-2). The interaction of SRSF1 and TUG1, ACSL4 was checked via RNA pull-down/RIP and RNA stability assays. The effects of LncRNA TUG1 on SRSF1/ACSL4-mediated ferroptosis were verified in H/R-treated HK-2 cells and the IRI-induced AKI mouse models.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; USC-Exo treatment improved kidney injury and ameliorated ferroptosis in IRI-induced AKI mouse models. USC-Exo were rich in lncRNA TUG1, which suppressed ferroptosis in HK-2 cells exposed to H/R. Mechanistically, lncRNA TUG1 regulates the stability of ACSL4 mRNA by interacting with RNA-binding protein SRSF1. In addition, SRSF1 upregulation or ACSL4 downregulation partially reversed the protective effect of lncRNA TUG1 on ferroptosis in H/R-treated HK-2 cells. Further, ACSL4 upregulation partially reversed TUG1&amp;rsquo;s repression on kidney injury and ferroptosis in IRI-induced AKI mice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/em&gt; Collectively, lncRNA TUG1 carried by USC-Exo regulated ASCL4-mediated ferroptosis by interacting with SRSF1 and then protected IRI-induced AKI. Potentially, USC-Exo rich in lncRNA TUG1 can serve as a promising therapeutic method for IRI-AKI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Phosphatidylinositol 3-Kinase δ Deficiency Protects From Antimyeloperoxidase Vasculitis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35818684/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35818684/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Objective:&lt;/em&gt; Antineutrophil cytoplasmic antibody-associated vasculitis (AAV) is a systemic autoimmune disease in which glomerulonephritis is an important manifestation. Antibodies against myeloperoxidase (MPO) or proteinase 3 are thought to be important in pathogenesis. Phosphoinositide 3-kinase δ (PI3Kδ) mediates a number of effects in lymphocytes, but its role in myeloid cell responses is less clear. Therefore, this study was undertaken to assess this in a preclinical model of glomerulonephritis induced by the transfer of antibodies to MPO.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; D910A mice with inactive PI3Kδ were compared with wild-type controls. Disease protocols allowed for a comparison of experimental groups in the setting of both mild and more severe disease. Adoptive transfer experiments were performed, with flow cytometric analysis of digested kidneys taken at the end of the experiment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; With mild disease, D910A mice had fewer glomerular macrophages, fewer glomerular neutrophils, and reduced albuminuria compared with wild-type controls. With more severe disease, they also had fewer glomerular crescents and lower serum creatinine levels, indicating protection from acute kidney injury. Adoptive transfer experiments showed a defect in the recruitment of D910A monocytes to the diseased kidney.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/em&gt; Mice with inactive PI3Kδ were protected from anti-MPO vasculitis. This is due to cell intrinsic defect in the recruitment of monocytes to the kidney. These findings suggest that PI3Kδ is a potential therapeutic target in AAV.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Single-cell analysis highlights differences in druggable pathways underlying adaptive or fibrotic kidney regeneration</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35821371/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35821371/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The kidney has tremendous capacity to repair after acute injury, however, pathways guiding adaptive and fibrotic repair are poorly understood. We developed a model of adaptive and fibrotic kidney regeneration by titrating ischemic injury dose. We performed detailed biochemical and histological analysis and profiled transcriptomic changes at bulk and single-cell level (&amp;gt; 110,000 cells) over time. Our analysis highlights kidney proximal tubule cells as key susceptible cells to injury. Adaptive proximal tubule repair correlated with fatty acid oxidation and oxidative phosphorylation. We identify a specific maladaptive/profibrotic proximal tubule cluster after long ischemia, which expresses proinflammatory and profibrotic cytokines and myeloid cell chemotactic factors. Druggability analysis highlights pyroptosis/ferroptosis as vulnerable pathways in these profibrotic cells. Pharmacological targeting of pyroptosis/ferroptosis in vivo pushed cells towards adaptive repair and ameliorates fibrosis. In summary, our single-cell analysis defines key differences in adaptive and fibrotic repair and identifies druggable pathways for pharmacological intervention to prevent kidney fibrosis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interleukin 24 promotes cell death in renal epithelial cells and is associated with acute renal injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35801504/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35801504/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ischemia-reperfusion injury is a major cause of acute kidney injury. Many cytokines are involved in the pathogenesis of renal ischemia-reperfusion injury. IL24 is a member of the IL10 family and has gained importance because of its apoptosis-inducing effects in tumor disease besides its immunoregulative function. Littles is known about the role of IL24 in kidney disease. Using a mouse model, we found that IL24 is upregulated in the kidney after renal ischemia-reperfusion injury and that tubular epithelial cells and infiltrating inflammatory cells are the source of IL24. Mice lacking IL24 are protected from renal injury and inflammation. Cell culture studies showed that IL24 induces apoptosis in renal tubular epithelial cells, which is accompanied by an increased endoplasmatic reticulum stress response. Moreover, IL24 induces robust expression of endogenous IL24 in tubular cells, fostering ER-stress and apoptosis. In kidney transplant recipients with delayed graft function and patients at high risk to develop acute kidney injury after cardiac surgery IL24 is upregulated in the kidney and serum. Taken together, IL24 can serve as a biomarker, plays an important mechanistic role involving both extracellular and intracellular targets, and is a promising therapeutic target in patients at risk of or with ischemia-induced acute kidney injury.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>p53/sirtuin 1/NF-κB Signaling Axis in Chronic Inflammation and Maladaptive Kidney Repair After Cisplatin Nephrotoxicity</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35874713/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35874713/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chronic inflammation contributes to maladaptive kidney repair, but its regulation is unclear. Here, we report that sirtuin 1 (SIRT1) is downregulated after repeated low-dose cisplatin (RLDC) injury, and this downregulation leads to p65 acetylation and consequent NF-κB activation resulting in a persistent inflammatory response. RLDC induced the down-regulation of SIRT1 and activation of NF-κB, which were accompanied by chronic tubular damage, tubulointerstitial inflammation, and fibrosis in mice. Inhibition of NF-κB suppressed the production of pro-inflammatory cytokines and fibrotic phenotypes in RLDC-treated renal tubular cells. SIRT1 activation by its agonists markedly reduced the acetylation of p65 (a key component of NF-κB), resulting in the attenuation of the inflammatory and fibrotic responses. Conversely, knockdown of SIRT1 exacerbated these cellular changes. At the upstream, p53 was activated after RLDC treatment to repress SIRT1, resulting in p65 acetylation, NF-κB activation and transcription of inflammatory cytokines. In mice, SIRT1 agonists attenuated RLDC-induced chronic inflammation, tissue damage, and renal fibrosis. Together, these results unveil the p53/SIRT1/NF-κB signaling axis in maladaptive kidney repair following RLDC treatment, where p53 represses SIRT1 to increase p65 acetylation for NF-κB activation, leading to chronic renal inflammation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Methyl eugenol protects the kidney from oxidative damage in mice by blocking the Nrf2 nuclear export signal through activation of the AMPK/GSK3β axis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35794373/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35794373/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Disrupted redox homeostasis contributes to renal ischemia-reperfusion (IR) injury. Abundant natural products can activate nuclear factor erythroid-2-related factor 2 (Nrf2), thereby providing therapeutic benefits. Methyl eugenol (ME), an analog of the phenolic compound eugenol, has the ability to induce Nrf2 activity. In this study, we investigated the protective effects of ME against renal oxidative damage in vivo and in vitro. An IR-induced acute kidney injury (AKI) model was established in mice. ME (20 mg·kg&lt;sup&gt;-1&lt;/sup&gt;·d&lt;sup&gt;-1&lt;/sup&gt;, i.p.) was administered to mice on 5 consecutive days before IR surgery. We showed that ME administration significantly attenuated renal destruction, improved the survival rate, reduced excessive oxidative stress and inhibited mitochondrial lesions in AKI mice. We further demonstrated that ME administration significantly enhanced Nrf2 activity and increased the expression of downstream antioxidative molecules. Similar results were observed in vitro in hypoxia/reoxygenation (HR)-exposed proximal tubule epithelial cells following pretreatment with ME (40 μmol·L&lt;sup&gt;-1&lt;/sup&gt;). In both renal oxidative damage models, ME induced Nrf2 nuclear retention in tubular cells. Using specific inhibitors (CC and DIF-3) and molecular docking, we demonstrated that ME bound to the binding pocket of AMPK with high affinity and activated the AMPK/GSK3β axis, which in turn blocked the Nrf2 nuclear export signal. In addition, ME alleviated the development of renal fibrosis induced by nonfatal IR, which is frequently encountered in the clinic. In conclusion, we demonstrate that ME modulates the AMPK/GSK3β axis to regulate the cytoplasmic-nuclear translocation of Nrf2, resulting in Nrf2 nuclear retention and thereby enhancing antioxidant target gene transcription that protects the kidney from oxidative damage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extracellular vesicles for renal therapeutics: State of the art and future perspective</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/35779658/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/35779658/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kidney diseases are global public health concerns lacking effective treatment.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Both native and bioengineered EVs are prime candidates for next-generation renal therapeutics.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;EVs can be tailored to target specific renal cells and prolong kidney retention for enhanced efficacy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;EVs can act as natural therapeutic agents or smart drug carriers fighting against renal diseases.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the ever-increasing burden of kidney disease, the need for developing new therapeutics to manage this disease has never been greater. Extracellular vesicles (EVs) are natural membranous nanoparticles present in virtually all organisms. Given their excellent delivery capacity in the body, EVs have emerged as a frontier technology for drug delivery and have the potential to usher in a new era of nanomedicine for kidney disease. This review is focused on why EVs are such compelling drug carriers and how to release their fullest potentiality in renal therapeutics. We discuss the unique features of EVs compared to artificial nanoparticles and outline the engineering technologies and steps in developing EV-based therapeutics, with an emphasis on the emerging approaches to target renal cells and prolong kidney retention. We also explore the applications of EVs as natural therapeutics or as drug carriers in the treatment of renal disorders and present our views on the critical challenges in manufacturing EVs as next-generation renal therapeutics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Induction of reactive oxygen species by mechanical stretch drives endothelin production in neonatal pig renal epithelial cells</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35841629/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35841629/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vasoactive endothelin (ET) is generated by ET converting enzyme (ECE)-induced proteolytic processing of pro-molecule big ET to biologically active peptides. H2O2 has been shown to increase the expression of ECE1 via transactivation of its promoter. The present study demonstrates that H2O2 triggered ECE1-dependent ET1-3 production in neonatal pig proximal tubule (PT) epithelial cells. A uniaxial stretch of PT cells decreased catalase, increased NADPH oxidase (NOX)2 and NOX4, and increased H2O2 levels. Stretch also increased cellular ECE1, an effect reversed by EUK-134 (a synthetic superoxide dismutase/catalase mimetic), NOX inhibitor apocynin, and siRNA-mediated knockdown of NOX2 and NOX4. Short-term unilateral ureteral obstruction (UUO), an inducer of renal tubular cell stretch and oxidative stress, increased renal ET1-3 generation and vascular resistance (RVR) in neonatal pigs. Despite removing the obstruction, UUO-induced increase in RVR persisted, resulting in early acute kidney injury (AKI). ET receptor (ETR)-operated Ca2+ entry in renal microvascular smooth muscle (SM) via transient receptor potential channel 3 (TRPC3) channels reduced renal blood flow and increased RVR. Although acute reversible UUO (rUUO) did not change protein expression levels of ETR and TRPC3 in renal microvessels, inhibition of ECE1, ETR, and TRPC3 protected against renal hypoperfusion, RVR increase, and early AKI. These data suggest that mechanical stretch-driven oxyradical generation stimulates ET production in neonatal pig renal epithelial cells. ET activates renal microvascular SM TRPC3, leading to persistent vasoconstriction and reduction in renal blood flow. These mechanisms may underlie rUUO-induced renal insufficiency in infants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kidney targeting of formoterol containing polymeric nanoparticles improves recovery from ischemia reperfusion-induced acute kidney injury in mice</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35779607/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35779607/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The β2 adrenergic receptor agonist, formoterol, is an inducer of mitochondrial biogenesis and restorer of mitochondrial and kidney function in acute and chronic models of kidney injury. Unfortunately, systemic administration of formoterol has the potential for adverse cardiovascular effects, increased heart rate, and decreased blood pressure. To minimize these effects, we developed biodegradable and biocompatible polymeric nanoparticles containing formoterol that target the kidney, thereby decreasing the effective dose, and lessen cardiovascular effects while restoring kidney function after injury. Male C57Bl/6 mice, treated with these nanoparticles daily, had reduced ischemia-reperfusion-induced serum creatinine and kidney cortex kidney injury molecule-1 levels by 78% and 73% respectively, compared to control mice six days after injury. With nanoparticle therapy, kidney cortical mitochondrial number and proteins reduced by ischemic injury, recovered to levels of sham-operated mice. Tubular necrosis was reduced 69% with nanoparticles treatment. Nanoparticles improved kidney recovery even when the dosing frequency was reduced from daily to two days per week. Finally, compared to treatment with formoterol-free drug alone, these nanoparticles did not increase heart rate nor decrease blood pressure. Thus, targeted kidney delivery of formoterol-containing nanoparticles is an improvement in standard formoterol therapy for ischemia-reperfusion-induced acute kidney injuries by decreasing the dose, dosing frequency, and cardiac side effects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Role of Ferroptosis in Acute Kidney Injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/35860360/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/35860360/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ferroptosis is a novel cell death method discovered in recent years. It is usually accompanied by massive accumulations of iron and lipid peroxidation during cell death. Recent studies have shown that ferroptosis is closely associated with the pathophysiological processes of many diseases, such as tumors, neurological diseases, localized ischemia-reperfusion injury, kidney injury, and hematological diseases. How to intervene in the incidence and development of associated diseases by regulating the ferroptosis of cells has become a hot topic of research. This article provides a review of the role of ferroptosis in the pathogenesis and potential treatment of acute kidney injury.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The down-regulation of XBP1, an unfolded protein response effector, promotes acute kidney injury to chronic kidney disease transition</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35765067/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35765067/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; The activation of the unfolded protein response (UPR) is closely linked to the pathogenesis of renal injuries. However, the role of XBP1, a crucial regulator of adaptive UPR, remains unclear during the transition from acute kidney injury (AKI) to chronic kidney disease (CKD).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; We characterized XBP1 expressions in different mouse models of kidney injuries, including unilateral ischemia-reperfusion injury (UIRI), unilateral ureteral obstruction, and adenine-induced CKD, followed by generating proximal tubular XBP1 conditional knockout (XBP1&lt;sup&gt;cKO&lt;/sup&gt;) mice for examining the influences of XBP1. Human proximal tubular epithelial cells (HK-2) were silenced of XBP1 to conduct proteomic analysis and investigate the underlying mechanism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; We showed a tripartite activation of UPR in injured kidneys. XBP1 expressions were attenuated after AKI and inversely correlated with the severity of post-AKI renal fibrosis. XBP1&lt;sup&gt;cKO&lt;/sup&gt; mice exhibited more severe renal fibrosis in the UIRI model than wide-type littermates. Silencing XBP1 induced HK-2 cell cycle arrest in G2M phase, inhibited cell proliferation, and promoted TGF-β1 secretion. Proteomic analysis identified TNF receptor associated protein 1 (Trap1) as the potential downstream target transcriptionally regulated by XBP1s. Trap1 overexpression can alleviate silencing XBP1 induced profibrotic factor expressions and cell cycle arrest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/em&gt; The loss of XBP1 in kidney injury was profibrotic, and the process was mediated by autocrine and paracrine regulations in combination. The present study identified the XBP1-Trap1 axis as an instrumental mechanism responsible for post-AKI fibrosis, which is a novel regulatory pathway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Farnesoid X receptor protects against cisplatin-induced acute kidney injury by regulating the transcription of ferroptosis-related genes</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35767918/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35767918/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The side effects of cisplatin, a widely used chemotherapeutic agent, include nephrotoxicity. Previous studies have reported that cisplatin induces ferroptosis and lipid peroxide accumulation. Ferroptosis, a type of regulated cell death, is characterized by iron-dependent lipid peroxidation. Although previous studies have examined the regulation of ferroptosis in acute kidney injury (AKI), the regulatory mechanism of ferroptosis has not been elucidated. Here, the ability of activated farnesoid X receptor (FXR) to attenuate cisplatin-induced AKI through the regulation of ferroptosis was examined. FXR deficiency exhibited more ferroptosis responses, such as increase in lipid peroxidation, iron content and heme oxygenase 1 protein, and a decrease in glutathione/glutathione disulfide ratio and glutathione peroxidase 4 levels in HK2 cells and mice. Increased blood urea nitrogen, serum creatinine, and ferroptotic responses in the cisplatin-induced AKI mouse model were mitigated upon treatment with the FXR agonist GW4064 but were exacerbated in FXR knockout mice. RNA sequencing analysis revealed that ferroptosis-associated genes were novel targets of FXR. FXR agonist upregulated the expression of lipid and glutathione metabolism-related genes and downregulated cell death-related genes. Additionally, chromatin immunoprecipitation assays, using mice renal tissues, revealed that agonist-activated FXR could bind to its known target genes (Slc51a, Slc51b, Osgin1, and Mafg) and ferroptosis-related genes (Aifm2, Ggt6, and Gsta4). Furthermore, activated FXR-dependent MAFG, a transcriptional repressor, could bind to Hmox1, Nqo1, and Tf in the renal tissues of FXR agonist-treated mice. These findings indicate that activated FXR regulates the transcription of ferroptosis-related genes and protects against cisplatin-induced AKI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inhibition of polycomb repressive complex 2 by targeting EED protects against cisplatin-induced acute kidney injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35734954/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35734954/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Polycomb repressive complex 2 (PRC2) is a multicomponent complex with methyltransferase activity that catalyzes trimethylation of histone H3 at lysine 27 (H3K27me3). Interaction of the epigenetic reader protein EED with EZH2, a catalytic unit of PRC, allosterically stimulates PRC2 activity. In this study, we investigated the role and underlying mechanism of the PRC2 in acute kidney injury (AKI) by using EED226, a highly selective PRC2 inhibitor, to target EED. Administration of EED226 improved renal function, attenuated renal pathological changes, and reduced renal tubular cell apoptosis in a murine model of cisplatin-induced AKI. In cultured renal epithelial cells, treatment with either EED226 or EED siRNA also ameliorated cisplatin-induced apoptosis. Mechanistically, EED226 treatment inhibited cisplatin-induced phosphorylation of p53 and FOXO3a, two transcriptional factors contributing to apoptosis, and preserved expression of Sirtuin 3 and PGC1α, two proteins associated with mitochondrial protection in vivo and in vitro. EED226 was also effective in enhancing renal tubular cell proliferation, suppressing expression of multiple inflammatory cytokines, and reducing infiltration of macrophages to the injured kidney. These data suggest that inhibition of the PRC2 activity by targeting EED can protect against cisplatin-induced AKI by promoting the survival and proliferation of renal tubular cells and inhibiting inflammatory response.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Insulin-like growth factor binding protein 7 promotes acute kidney injury by alleviating poly ADP ribose polymerase 1 degradation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35752325/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35752325/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The novel biomarker, insulin-like growth factor binding protein 7 (IGFBP7), is used clinically to predict different types of acute kidney injury (AKI) and has drawn significant attention as a urinary biomarker. However, as a secreted protein in the circulation of patients with AKI, it is unclear whether IGFBP7 acts as a key regulator in AKI progression, and if mechanisms underlying its upregulation still need to be determined. Here we found that IGFBP7 is highly expressed in the blood and urine of patients and mice with AKI, possibly via a c-Jun-dependent mechanism, and is positively correlated with kidney dysfunction. Global knockout of IGFBP7 ameliorated kidney dysfunction, inflammatory responses, and programmed cell death in murine models of cisplatin-, kidney ischemia/reperfusion-, and lipopolysaccharide-induced AKI. IGFBP7 mainly originated from kidney tubular epithelial cells. Conditional knockout of IGFBP7 from the kidney protected against AKI. By contrast, rescue of IGFBP7 expression in IGFBP7-knockout mice restored kidney damage and inflammation. IGFBP7 function was determined in vitro using recombinant IGFBP7 protein, IGFBP7 knockdown, or overexpression. Additionally, IGFBP7 was found to bind to poly [ADP-ribose] polymerase 1 (PARP1) and inhibit its degradation by antagonizing the E3 ubiquitin ligase ring finger protein 4 (RNF4). Thus, IGFBP7 in circulation acts as a biomarker and key mediator of AKI by inhibiting RNF4/PARP1-mediated tubular injury and inflammation. Hence, over-activation of the IGFBP7/PARP1 axis represents a promising target for AKI treatment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cardiac Spinal Afferent Denervation Attenuates Renal Dysfunction in Rats With Cardiorenal Syndrome Type 2</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35818505/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35818505/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Epicardial application of RTX at the time of MI largely prevented renal dysfunction, attenuated renal congestion, and partially restored renal blood flow in rats with CHF.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RNA sequencing analysis showed that renal injury, inflammation, hypoxia, and apoptosis genes were significantly up-regulated in the renal tissue of CHF rats, which was largely prevented by epicardial RTX at the time of MI.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cardiac afferent ablation by intra–stellate ganglia injection of RTX or unilateral renal denervation 4 weeks after MI had similar renal protective effects on renal tubular damage in CHF rats.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;These data provide evidence for cardiac spinal afferent modulation of renal function and a potential targeted therapy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cardiorenal syndrome type 2 (CRS2) is defined as a chronic cardiovascular disease, usually chronic heart failure (CHF), resulting in chronic kidney disease. We hypothesized that the cardiac spinal afferent reflex (CSAR) plays a critical role in the development of CRS2. Our data suggest that cardiac afferent ablation by resiniferatoxin not only improves cardiac function but also benefits the kidneys and increases long-term survival in the myocardial infarction model of CHF. We also found that renal denervation has a similar reno-protective effect in CHF rats. We believe this novel work contributes to the development of a unique neuromodulation therapy to treat CHF patients.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hypomagnesemia, Hypocalcemia, and Tubulointerstitial Nephropathy Caused by Claudin-16 Autoantibodies</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35728884/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35728884/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Chronic hypomagnesemia is commonly due to diarrhea, alcoholism, and drugs. More rarely, it is caused by genetic defects in the effectors of renal magnesium reabsorption.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; In an adult patient with acquired severe hypomagnesemia, hypocalcemia, tubulointerstitial nephropathy, and rapidly progressing kidney injury, similarities between the patient&amp;rsquo;s presentation and features of genetic disorders of renal magnesium transport prompted us to investigate whether the patient had an acquired autoimmune cause of renal magnesium wasting. To determine if the patient&amp;rsquo;s condition might be explained by autoantibodies directed against claudin-16 or claudin-19, transmembrane paracellular proteins involved in renal magnesium absorption, we conducted experiments with claudin knockout mice and transfected mouse kidney cells expressing human claudin-16 or claudin-19. We also examined effects on renal magnesium handling in rats given intravenous injections of IgG purified from sera from the patient or controls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; Experiments with the knockout mice and &lt;em&gt;in vitro&lt;/em&gt; transfected cells demonstrated that hypomagnesemia in the patient was causally linked to autoantibodies directed against claudin-16, which controls paracellular magnesium reabsorption in the thick ascending limb of Henle&amp;rsquo;s loop. Intravenous injection of IgG purified from the patient&amp;rsquo;s serum induced a marked urinary waste of magnesium in rats. Immunosuppressive treatment combining plasma exchange and rituximab was associated with improvement in the patient&amp;rsquo;s GFR, but hypomagnesemia persisted. The patient was subsequently diagnosed with a renal carcinoma that expressed a high level of claudin-16 mRNA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; Pathogenic claudin-16 autoantibodies represent a novel autoimmune cause of specific renal tubular transport disturbances and tubulointerstitial nephropathy. Screening for autoantibodies targeting claudin-16, and potentially other magnesium transporters or channels in the kidney, may be warranted in patients with acquired unexplained hypomagnesemia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>High phosphate-induced progressive proximal tubular injury is associated with the activation of Stat3/Kim-1 signaling pathway and macrophage recruitment</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35713543/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35713543/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dietary phosphate intake in the Western population greatly exceeds the recommended dietary allowance and is linked to enhanced cardiovascular and all-cause mortality. It is unclear whether a chronic high phosphate diet (HPD) causes kidney injury in healthy individuals. Here, we show that feeding a 2% HPD in C57BL/6N mice for one up to six months resulted in hyperphosphatemia, hyperphosphaturia, increased plasma levels of fibroblast growth factor (FGF) 23, and parathyroid hormone (PTH) compared to mice on a 0.8% phosphate diet. Kidney injury was already noted after two months of HPD characterized by loss of proximal tubular (PT) cell polarity, flattened epithelia, disruption of brush border membranes, vacuolization, increased PT cell proliferation, marked interstitial mononuclear infiltration, and progressive accumulation of collagen fibers. HPD increased Stat3 activation and Kim-1 expression in PT epithelial cells and enhanced renal synthesis of chemokines recruiting monocytes and macrophages as well as macrophage related factors. Enhanced recruitment of F4/80+ macrophages around injured PT lesions was timely associated with increased Kim-1 synthesis, tubular MCP-1 expression, and degree of PT injury score. Likewise, tubulointerstitial fibrosis was associated with activation of Stat3/Kim-1 signaling pathway. The stimulation of human proximal tubular cells with high phosphate activated Stat3 signaling and induced HAVCR1 and CCL2 expression. We conclude that high phosphate results in progressive proximal tubular injury, indicating that high dietary phosphate intake may affect kidney health and therefore represents an underestimated health problem for the general population.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Genetic loci and prioritization of genes for kidney function decline derived from a meta-analysis of 62 longitudinal genome-wide association studies</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35716955/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35716955/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Estimated glomerular filtration rate (eGFR) reflects kidney function. Progressive eGFR-decline can lead to kidney failure, necessitating dialysis or transplantation. Hundreds of loci from genome-wide association studies (GWAS) for eGFR help explain population cross section variability. Since the contribution of these or other loci to eGFR-decline remains largely unknown, we derived GWAS for annual eGFR-decline and meta-analyzed 62 longitudinal studies with eGFR assessed twice over time in all 343,339 individuals and in high-risk groups. We also explored different covariate adjustment. Twelve genome-wide significant independent variants for eGFR-decline unadjusted or adjusted for eGFR-baseline (11 novel, one known for this phenotype), including nine variants robustly associated across models were identified. All loci for eGFR-decline were known for cross-sectional eGFR and thus distinguished a subgroup of eGFR loci. Seven of the nine variants showed variant-by-age interaction on eGFR cross section (further about 350,000 individuals), which linked genetic associations for eGFR-decline with age-dependency of genetic cross-section associations. Clinically important were two to four-fold greater genetic effects on eGFR-decline in high-risk subgroups. Five variants associated also with chronic kidney disease progression mapped to genes with functional in-silico evidence (UMOD, SPATA7, GALNTL5, TPPP). An unfavorable versus favorable nine-variant genetic profile showed increased risk odds ratios of 1.35 for kidney failure (95% confidence intervals 1.03-1.77) and 1.27 for acute kidney injury (95% confidence intervals 1.08-1.50) in over 2000 cases each, with matched controls). Thus, we provide a large data resource, genetic loci, and prioritized genes for kidney function decline, which help inform drug development pipelines revealing important insights into the age-dependency of kidney function genetics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Whole transcriptome sequencing analysis revealed key RNA profiles and toxicity in mice after chronic exposure to microplastics</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35718033/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35718033/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Investigating the long-term effects of microplastics (MPs) in vivo is necessary for evaluating its biological toxicity. Previously, we showed that MPs elicit vascular dysfunctions in atherosclerotic mice. However, the effects of long-term treatment with environmental levels of MPs on biological functions and RNA expression profiles in wild-type mice are unknown. Here, C57BL/6 mice were administered 1000 μg/L MPs through their drinking water for 180 days. Transcriptomic analyses, biochemical analysis, and histopathological examination were conducted to determine the key signals and molecular mechanisms triggered by MPs in vivo using whole transcriptome sequencing, enzyme-linked immunosorbent assay, and histopathological analysis. Notably, our data revealed that MPs aggravated vascular lesions and organ injuries, particularly liver, kidney, and heart injuries. Additionally, MPs exacerbated oxidative injuries by inhibiting the activities of antioxidant enzymes and increasing the levels of the serum biochemistry indicator of organ damage. RNA sequencing of vascular tissues showed that 674 mRNAs, 39 lncRNAs, 196 miRNAs, and 565 circRNAs were abnormally expressed in MPs-treated mice compared with the untreated group. Pathway enrichment analyses identified pathways linked to the toxicity of MPs, including lysosomal, NOD-like receptor, and peroxisome proliferator-activated receptor pathways. Additionally, competing endogenous RNA networks were constructed and hub RNAs were identified using bioinformatics analysis. Taken together, our data suggested that toxicity induced by long-term exposure to MPs continually presents with extensive changes in biological features and global gene expression profiles. Our data provides new insights into the biological toxicity of MPs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Impact of Zinc Supplementation on Critically Ill Patients With Acute Kidney Injury: A Propensity Score Matching Analysis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35769374/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35769374/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Zinc is an essential trace element involved in multiple metabolic processes. Acute kidney injury (AKI) is associated with low plasma zinc, but outcomes with zinc supplementation in critically ill patients with AKI remain unknown. Our objective was to investigate the effectiveness of zinc supplementation in this patient population.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; Critically ill patients with AKI were identified from the Medical Informative Mart for Intensive Care IV database. Prosperity score matching (PSM) was applied to match patients receiving zinc treatment to those without zinc treatment. The association between zinc sulfate use and in-hospital mortality and 30-day mortality, need for renal replacement therapy (RRT), and length of stay was determined by logistic regression and Cox proportional hazards modeling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; A total of 9,811 AKI patients were included in the study. PSM yielded 222 pairs of patients who received zinc treatment and those who did not. Zinc supplementation was associated with reduced in-hospital mortality (HR = 0.48 (95% CI: 0.28, 0.83) &lt;em&gt;P&lt;/em&gt; = 0.009) and 30-day mortality (HR = 0.51 (95% CI, 0.30, 0.86) &lt;em&gt;P&lt;/em&gt; = 0.012). In the subgroup analysis, zinc use was associated with reduced in-hospital mortality in patients with stage 1 AKI and those with sepsis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; Zinc supplementation was associated with improved survival in critically ill patients with AKI. The supplementation was especially effective in those with stage 1 AKI and sepsis. These results need to be verified in randomized controlled trials.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Protecting the Kidney: The Unexpected Logic of Inhibiting a Glucose Transporter</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35689828/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35689828/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;No abstract available.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RP105 protects against ischemic and septic acute kidney injury via suppressing TLR4/NF-κB signaling pathways</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35696803/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35696803/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RP105 is a member of the TLR family and its expression plays a role in cardiovascular disease but the therapeutic impact on acute kidney injury remained unclear.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We have uncovered evidence that RP105 expression in proximal tubular cells plays a kidney protective role during ischemic and septic acute kidney injury.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RP105 reduces tubular cell death, NF-κB activation and inflammatory response during AKI with a mechanism involving interaction with TLR4.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This finding may have clinical translation as kidney protection and inflammation regulation could be achieved through RP105 gene therapy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acute kidney injury (AKI) is a critical and severe clinical disease caused by a variety of factors. Toll-like receptors (TLRs) play a crucial role in pathogenesis of AKI. Radioprotective 105 kDa protein (RP105) is a member of the TLR family, but the role of RP105 in AKI is unknown. In this study, we overexpressed RP105 in renal tissue and cultured proximal tubular cells in which we then induced ischemic and septic AKI. Renal structure injuries were examined by hematoxylin eosin staining, while renal function was assessed by measuring serum blood urea nitrogen (BUN) and creatinine (SCr) levels. The TUNEL assay was used to detect apoptosis induced changes in the expression of RP105, and nuclear factor κB (NF-κB) in renal tissue detected by Western blot. Inflammatory cytokines including iNOS, IL-1β, IL-6, and TNF-α were detected by quantitative real-time PCR. The inflammatory indicators, F4/80 and MPO, were identified by IHC staining. The results showed that expression of the TLR4/NF-kB signaling pathway was enhanced in renal ischemia-reperfusion injury and septic renal injury, and that overexpression of RP105 in renal tissue alleviated ischemic and septic AKI. Moreover, RP105 gene delivery was associated with reduced renal inflammatory cells infiltration and inflammatory cytokines after AKI. RP105 overexpression also inhibited nuclear translocation of NF-κB after AKI in both in vitro and in vivo, and blunted the interaction between Myeloid Differentiation factor 2 (MD2) and TLR4. These results indicated that RP105 protected against renal ischemic and septic AKI injury by suppressing inflammatory responses mediated by TLR4 signaling pathways. This study suggests that the anti-inflammatory roles of RP105 have potential for preventing and treating renal ischemic and septic AKI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New mechanism of nephrotoxicity of triptolide: Oxidative stress promotes cGAS-STING signaling pathway</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35697291/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35697291/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Triptolide activates the cGAS-STING signaling pathway in kidney tubular cells in vivo and in vitro.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;STING inhibitor C176 had protective effects in TPL-induced nephrocyte damage.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Triptolide induced an enhancement in protein levels of BACH1, while the expression of HMOX1 was reduced.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Oxidative stress-induced mtDNA damage and DNA leakage were the causes of the activation of cGAS-STING signaling pathway.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Triptolide (TPL) is a bioactive component extracted from the traditional Chinese herb Tripterygium wilfordii Hook F., and has multiple pharmacological activities, such as anti-tumor activity. However, severe adverse effects and toxicity, especially nephrotoxicity, limit its clinical application. It has been demonstrated that mitochondrial defect is a major toxic effects of TPL. In this study, we show that triptolide activated the cGAS-STING signaling pathway in kidney tubular cells in vivo and in vitro. Renal injury models were established in BALB/c mice and human tubular epithelial cells using TPL. We found that TPL enhanced the phosphorylation levels of STING, TBK1 and IRF3, and upregulated the expression of IFNβ, which is the production of cGAS-STING signaling pathway. STING inhibitor C176 had protective effects in TPL-induced nephrocyte damage. STING siRNA down regulated the expression level of IFNβ. In addition, triptolide induced an increase in protein levels of the transcription factor BACH1, while transcriptional expression of the antioxidant enzyme HMOX1 was reduced due to the increased expression of BACH1. Furthermore, oxidative stress-induced mtDNA damage and DNA leakage caused activation of the cGAS-STING signaling pathway. Altogether, cGAS-STING signaling pathway involved in TPL induced nephrotoxicity. Inhibiting cGAS-STING over-activation may be a new strategy for alleviating renal injury of triptolide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MiR-155 deficiency protects renal tubular epithelial cells from telomeric and genomic DNA damage in cisplatin-induced acute kidney injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35832084/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35832084/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rationale:&lt;/em&gt; Cisplatin nephrotoxicity is an important cause of acute kidney injury (AKI), limiting cisplatin application in cancer therapy. Growing evidence has suggested that genome instability, telomeric dysfunction, and DNA damage were involved in the tubular epithelial cells (TECs) damage in cisplatin-induced AKI (cAKI). However, the exact mechanism is largely unknown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; We subjected miR-155&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt; mice and wild-type controls, as well as HK-2 cells, to cAKI models. We assessed kidney function and injury with standard techniques. The cell apoptosis and DNA damage of TECs were evaluated both &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;in vitro&lt;/em&gt;. Telomeres were measured by the fluorescence &lt;em&gt;in situ&lt;/em&gt; hybridization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; The expression level of miR-155 was upregulated in cAKI. Inhibition of miR-155 expression protected cisplatin-induced AKI both &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;in vitro&lt;/em&gt;. Compared with wild-type mice, miR-155&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt; mice had reduced mortality, improved renal function and pathological damage after cisplatin intervention. Moreover, inhibition of miR-155 expression attenuated TECs apoptosis and DNA damage. These protective effects were caused by increasing expression of telomeric repeat binding factor 1 (TRF1) and cyclin-dependent kinase 12 (CDK12), thereby limiting the telomeric dysfunction and the genomic DNA damage in cAKI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/em&gt; We demonstrated that miR-155 deficiency could significantly attenuate pathological damage and mortality in cAKI through inhibition of TECs apoptosis, genome instability, and telomeric dysfunction, which is possibly regulated by the increasing expression of TRF1 and CDK12. This study will provide a new molecular strategy for the prevention of cAKI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Novel Drug Delivery Technologies and Targets for Renal Disease</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/35652363/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/35652363/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The burden of acute and chronic kidney diseases to the health care system is exacerbated by the high mortality that this disease carries paired with the still limited availability of comprehensive therapies. A reason partially resides in the complexity of the kidney, with multiple potential target cell types and a complex structural environment that complicate strategies to protect and recover renal function after injury. Management of both acute and chronic renal disease, irrespective of the cause, are mainly focused on supportive treatments and renal replacement strategies when needed. Emerging preclinical evidence supports the feasibility of drug delivery technology for the kidney, and recent studies have contributed to building a robust catalog of peptides, proteins, nanoparticles, liposomes, extracellular vesicles, and other carriers that may be fused to therapeutic peptides, proteins, nucleic acids, or small molecule drugs. These fusions can display a precise renal uptake, an enhanced circulating time, and a directed intraorgan biodistribution while protecting their cargo to improve therapeutic efficacy. However, several hurdles that slow the transition towards clinical applications are still in the way, such as solubility, toxicity, and sub-optimal renal targeting. This review will discuss the feasibility and current limitations of drug delivery technologies for the treatment of renal disease, offering an update on their potential and the future directions of these promising strategies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Angiotensin 1-7 mitigates rhabdomyolysis induced renal injury in rats via modulation of TLR-4/NF-kB/iNOS and Nrf-2/heme‑oxygenase-1 signaling pathways</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35654118/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35654118/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RM induced kidney injury may be linked to the depletion of the ACE-2 and Ang1–7.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The ACE-2/Ang1–7/MasR axis may serve as a novel therapeutic option in RM-induced AKI.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;TLR-4/NF-kB/iNOS pathway may be involved in the renoprotective effect of Ang1–7.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Aims:&lt;/em&gt; Rhabdomyolysis (RM) is a critical condition with a high mortality rate, but effective management is still deficient. Till date, there are no studies that have addressed the effect of angiotensin 1-7 in this condition, hence, the rationale of this study was to evaluate the potential protective effect of Angiotensin 1-7 (Ang1-7), on rhabdomyolysis (RM) induced kidney injury in rats and detecting the underlying mechanistic insights.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Main methods:&lt;/em&gt; Forty adult male albino rats were divided into groups; the control group, RM group, RM+Ang1-7 group, and RM+Ang1-7+ A779 group. Sera and urine samples were collected for analysis of renal and muscle injury markers. Kidney tissues were taken for estimation of oxidative, inflammatory, and apoptotic markers as well as angiotensin-II (Ang II) and Ang1-7. Renal histology and expression of inducible nitric oxide synthase-1 (iNOS), real-time PCR for angiotensin-converting enzyme-2 (ACE-2), nuclear erythroid factor-2 (Nrf-2), Toll like receptor 4 (TLR-4) and NF-kB in kidney tissues were also measured.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Key findings:&lt;/em&gt; Induction of RM caused renal oxidative stress injury, inflammation, apoptosis and marked deterioration in kidney functions as well as reduction of Ang1-7 and raised Angiotensin-II level in kidney tissues. Administration of Ang1-7 to the RM group reversed all the affected parameters which were blocked by A779 administration (Mas receptor blocker).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Significance:&lt;/em&gt; We concluded that Ang1-7 could be a potential therapeutic agent that could mitigate RM-induced renal injury. The underlying mechanisms may involve Stimulation of the ACE-2/Ang1-7/MasR axis and modulation of TLR-4/NF-kB/iNOS and Nrf-2/heme‑oxygenase -1 pathways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Caloric restriction reduces the pro-inflammatory eicosanoid 20-hydroxyeicosatetraenoic acid to protect from acute kidney injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35654224/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35654224/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acute kidney injury is a frequent complication in the clinical setting and associated with significant morbidity and mortality. Preconditioning with short-term caloric restriction is highly protective against kidney injury in rodent ischemia reperfusion injury models. However, the underlying mechanisms are unknown hampering clinical translation. Here, we examined the molecular basis of caloric restriction-mediated protection to elucidate the principles of kidney stress resistance. Analysis of an RNAseq dataset after caloric restriction identified Cyp4a12a, a cytochrome exclusively expressed in male mice, to be strongly downregulated after caloric restriction. Kidney ischemia reperfusion injury robustly induced acute kidney injury in male mice and this damage could be markedly attenuated by pretreatment with caloric restriction. In females, damage was significantly less pronounced and preconditioning with caloric restriction had only little effect. Tissue concentrations of the metabolic product of Cyp4a12a, 20-hydroxyeicosatetraenoic acid (20-HETE), were found to be significantly reduced by caloric restriction. Conversely, intraperitoneal supplementation of 20-HETE in preconditioned males partly abrogated the protective potential of caloric restriction. Interestingly, this effect was accompanied by a partial reversal of caloric restriction&amp;ndash;induced changes in protein but not RNA expression pointing towards inflammation, endoplasmic reticulum stress and lipid metabolism. Thus, our findings provide an insight into the mechanisms underlying kidney protection by caloric restriction. Hence, understanding the mediators of preconditioning is an important prerequisite for moving towards translation to the clinical setting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Persistent Activation of Autophagy After Cisplatin Nephrotoxicity Promotes Renal Fibrosis and Chronic Kidney Disease</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35707397/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35707397/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Autophagy, a highly conserved catabolic pathway in eukaryotic cells, contributes to the maintenance of the homeostasis and function of the kidney. Upon acute kidney injury (AKI), autophagy is activated in renal tubular cells to act as an intrinsic protective mechanism. However, the role of autophagy in the development of chronic kidney pathologies including renal fibrosis after AKI remains unclear. In this study, we detected a persistent autophagy activation in mouse kidneys after nephrotoxicity of repeated low dose cisplatin (RLDC) treatment. 3-methyladenine (3-MA) and chloroquine (CQ), respective inhibitors of autophagy at the initiation and degradation stages, blocked autophagic flux and improved kidney repair in post-RLDC mice, as indicated by kidney weight, renal function, and less interstitial fibrosis. &lt;em&gt;In vitro&lt;/em&gt;, RLDC induced a pro-fibrotic phenotype in renal tubular cells, including the production and secretion of pro-fibrotic cytokines. Notably, autophagy inhibitors blocked RLDC-induced secretion of pro-fibrotic cytokines in these cells. Together, the results indicate that persistent autophagy after AKI induces pro-fibrotic cytokines in renal tubular cells, promoting renal fibrosis and chronic kidney disease.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modeling injury and repair in kidney organoids reveals that homologous recombination governs tubular intrinsic repair</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35235339/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35235339/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Erratum in:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Erratum for the Research Article, &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/scitranslmed.add0524&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Modeling injury and repair in kidney organoids reveals that homologous recombination governs tubular intrinsic repair&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; by N. Gupta et al.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kidneys have the capacity for intrinsic repair, preserving kidney architecture with return to a basal state after tubular injury. When injury is overwhelming or repetitive, however, that capacity is exceeded and incomplete repair results in fibrotic tissue replacing normal kidney parenchyma. Loss of nephrons correlates with reduced kidney function, which defines chronic kidney disease (CKD) and confers substantial morbidity and mortality to the worldwide population. Despite the identification of pathways involved in intrinsic repair, limited treatments for CKD exist, partly because of the limited throughput and predictivity of animal studies. Here, we showed that kidney organoids can model the transition from intrinsic to incomplete repair. Single-nuclear RNA sequencing of kidney organoids after cisplatin exposure identified 159 differentially expressed genes and 29 signal pathways in tubular cells undergoing intrinsic repair. Homology-directed repair (HDR) genes including Fanconi anemia complementation group D2 (&lt;em&gt;FANCD2&lt;/em&gt;) and RAD51 recombinase (&lt;em&gt;RAD51&lt;/em&gt;) were transiently up-regulated during intrinsic repair but were down-regulated in incomplete repair. Single cellular transcriptomics in mouse models of obstructive and hemodynamic kidney injury and human kidney samples of immune-mediated injury validated HDR gene up-regulation during tubular repair. Kidney biopsy samples with tubular injury and varying degrees of fibrosis confirmed loss of FANCD2 during incomplete repair. Last, we performed targeted drug screening that identified the DNA ligase IV inhibitor, SCR7, as a therapeutic candidate that rescued FANCD2/RAD51-mediated repair to prevent the progression of CKD in the cisplatin-induced organoid injury model. Our findings demonstrate the translational utility of kidney organoids to identify pathologic pathways and potential therapies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Serum Protein Exposure Activates a Core Regulatory Program Driving Human Proximal Tubule Injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35197326/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35197326/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; The kidneys efficiently filter waste products while retaining serum proteins in the circulation. However, numerous diseases compromise this barrier function, resulting in spillage of serum proteins into the urine (proteinuria). Some studies of glomerular filtration suggest that tubules may be physiologically exposed to nephrotic-range protein levels. Therefore, whether serum components can directly injure the downstream tubular portions of the kidney, which in turn can lead to inflammation and fibrosis, remains controversial.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; We tested the effects of serum protein exposure in human kidney tubule microphysiologic systems and with orthogonal epigenomic approaches since animal models cannot directly assess the effect of serum components on tubules.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; Serum, but not its major protein component albumin, induced tubular injury and secretion of proinflammatory cytokines. Epigenomic comparison of serum-injured tubules and intact kidney tissue revealed canonical stress-inducible regulation of injury-induced genes. Concordant transcriptional changes in microdissected tubulointerstitium were also observed in an independent cohort of patients with proteinuric kidney disease.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; Our results demonstrate a causal role for serum proteins in tubular injury and identify regulatory mechanisms and novel pathways for intervention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The PINK1/PARK2/optineurin pathway of mitophagy is activated for protection in septic acute kidney injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33137712/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33137712/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sepsis is the major cause of acute kidney injury (AKI) associated with high mortality rates. Mitochondrial dysfunction contributes to the pathophysiology of septic AKI. Mitophagy is an important mitochondrial quality control mechanism that selectively eliminates damaged mitochondria, but its role and regulation in septic AKI remain largely unknown. Here, we demonstrate the induction of mitophagy in mouse models of septic AKI induced by lipopolysaccharide (LPS) treatment or by cecal ligation and puncture. Mitophagy was also induced in cultured proximal tubular epithelial cells exposed to LPS. Induction of mitophagy under these experimental setting was suppressed by pink1 or park2 knockout, indicating the role of the PINK1/PARK2 pathway of mitophagy in septic AKI. In addition, sepsis induced more severe kidney injury and cell apoptosis in pink1 or park2 knockout mice than in wild-type mice, suggesting a beneficial role of mitophagy in septic AKI. Furthermore, in cultured renal tubular cells treated with LPS, knockdown of pink1 or park2 inhibited mitochondrial accumulation of the autophagy adaptor optineurin (OPTN) and silencing Optn inhibited LPS-induced mitophagy. Taken together, these findings suggest that the PINK1/PARK2 pathway of mitophagy plays an important role in mitochondrial quality control, tubular cell survival, and renal function in septic AKI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nuclear receptor PXR targets AKR1B7 to protect mitochondrial metabolism and renal function in AKI</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32404507/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32404507/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acute kidney injury (AKI) is a worldwide public health problem with no specific and satisfactory therapies in clinic. The nuclear pregnane X receptor (PXR) is involved in the progression of multiple diseases, including metabolic diseases, atherosclerosis, hypertension, liver injury, etc. However, its role in kidney injury remains to be understood. In this study, we have investigated the role of PXR in AKI and underlying mechanism(s) involved in its function. PXR was robustly down-regulated and negatively correlated with renal dysfunction in human and animal kidneys with AKI. Silencing PXR in rats enhanced cisplatin-induced AKI and induced severe mitochondrial abnormalities, whereas activating PXR protected against AKI. Using luciferase reporter assays, genomic manipulation, and proteomics data analysis on the kidneys of PXR&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt; rats, we determined that PXR targeted Aldo-keto reductase family 1, member B7 (AKR1B7) to improve mitochondrial function, thereby ameliorating AKI. We confirmed the protective role of PXR against kidney injury using genomic and pharmacologic approaches in an ischemia/reperfusion model of AKI. These findings demonstrate that disabling the PXR/AKR1B7/mitochondrial metabolism axis is an important factor that can contribute to AKI, whereas reestablishing this axis can be useful for treating AKI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wnt/β-catenin signaling mediates both heart and kidney injury in type 2 cardiorenal syndrome</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/30770217/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/30770217/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Erratum in:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Corrigendum to Zhao Y, Wang C, Hong X, et al. &lt;a href=&#34;https://linkinghub.elsevier.com/retrieve/pii/S0085253822006226&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Wnt/β-catenin signaling mediates both heart and kidney injury in type 2 cardiorenal syndrome&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Kidney Int. 2019;95:815-829.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In type 2 cardiorenal syndrome, chronic heart failure is thought to cause or promote chronic kidney disease; however, the underlying mechanisms remain poorly understood. We investigated the role of Wnt signaling in heart and kidney injury in a mouse model of cardiac hypertrophy and heart failure induced by transverse aortic constriction (TAC). At 8 weeks after TAC, cardiac hypertrophy, inflammation, and fibrosis were prominent, and echocardiography confirmed impaired cardiac function. The cardiac lesions were accompanied by upregulation of multiple Wnt ligands and activation of β-catenin, as well as activation of the renin-angiotensin system (RAS). Wnt3a induced multiple components of the RAS in primary cardiomyocytes and cardiac fibroblasts in vitro. TAC also caused proteinuria and kidney fibrosis, accompanied by klotho depletion and β-catenin activation in the kidney. Pharmacologic blockade of β-catenin with a small molecule inhibitor or the RAS with losartan ameliorated cardiac injury, restored heart function, and mitigated the renal lesions. Serum from TAC mice was sufficient to activate β-catenin and trigger tubular cell injury in vitro, indicating a role for circulating factors. Multiple inflammatory cytokines were upregulated in the circulation of TAC mice, and tumor necrosis factor-α was able to inhibit klotho, induce β-catenin activation, and cause tubular cell injury in vitro. These studies identify Wnt/β-catenin signaling as a common pathogenic mediator of heart and kidney injury in type 2 cardiorenal syndrome after TAC. Targeting this pathway could be a promising therapeutic strategy to protect both organs in cardiorenal syndrome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Single-cell transcriptomics of the mouse kidney reveals potential cellular targets of kidney disease</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/29622724/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/29622724/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Touring the kidney, cell by cell&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our kidneys play a critical role in keeping us healthy, a fact of which we are reminded several times each day. This organ&amp;rsquo;s cellular complexity has hindered progress in understanding the mechanisms underlying chronic kidney disease, which affects 10% of the world&amp;rsquo;s population. Using single-cell transcriptional profiling, Park et al. produced a comprehensive cell atlas of the healthy mouse kidney (see the Perspective by Humphreys). An unexpected cell type in the collecting duct appears to be a transitional state between two known cell types. The transition from one cell type to the other is regulated by the Notch signaling pathway and is associated with metabolic acidosis. The authors also find that genetically distinct kidney diseases with common clinical features share common cellular origins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our understanding of kidney disease pathogenesis is limited by an incomplete molecular characterization of the cell types responsible for the organ’s multiple homeostatic functions. To help fill this knowledge gap, we characterized 57,979 cells from healthy mouse kidneys by using unbiased single-cell RNA sequencing. On the basis of gene expression patterns, we infer that inherited kidney diseases that arise from distinct genetic mutations but share the same phenotypic manifestation originate from the same differentiated cell type. We also found that the collecting duct in kidneys of adult mice generates a spectrum of cell types through a newly identified transitional cell. Computational cell trajectory analysis and in vivo lineage tracing revealed that intercalated cells and principal cells undergo transitions mediated by the Notch signaling pathway. In mouse and human kidney disease, these transitions were shifted toward a principal cell fate and were associated with metabolic acidosis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Targeting neural reflex circuits in immunity to treat kidney disease</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/28970585/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/28970585/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Key Points&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Neural circuits that control immunity and inflammation provide novel targets for the treatment of kidney disease and hypertension&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Activation of the cholinergic anti-inflammatory pathway (CAP) blocks splenic-dependent systemic inflammation and acute kidney injury (AKI); non-invasive, nonpharmacological approaches to activate the CAP include ultrasound application and vagus nerve stimulation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Neural circuits that directly regulate kidney function or carry sensory feedback from the kidney to the central nervous system could provide additional mechanisms for bidirectional neuroimmunomodulation of kidney disease&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Interactions between neural circuits and the immune system have important roles in the pathogenesis of hypertension and renal fibrosis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Further defining neuroimmunomodulatory pathways in hypertension could enable the development of selective neuronal stimulatory or inhibitory strategies for lowering blood pressure that could potentially be more effective than renal denervation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Optogenetic tools provide unprecedented opportunities to dissect the neural pathways that control immunity and inflammation and enable the identification of novel approaches to therapy for kidney diseases&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Neural pathways regulate immunity and inflammation via the inflammatory reflex and specific molecular targets can be modulated by stimulating neurons. Neuroimmunomodulation by nonpharmacological methods is emerging as a novel therapeutic strategy for inflammatory diseases, including kidney diseases and hypertension. Electrical stimulation of vagus neurons or treatment with pulsed ultrasound activates the cholinergic anti-inflammatory pathway (CAP) and protects mice from acute kidney injury (AKI). Direct innervation of the kidney, by afferent and efferent neurons, might have a role in modulating and responding to inflammation in various diseases, either locally or by providing feedback to regions of the central nervous system that are important in the inflammatory reflex pathway. Increased sympathetic drive to the kidney has a role in the pathogenesis of hypertension, and selective modulation of neuroimmune interactions in the kidney could potentially be more effective for lowering blood pressure and treating inflammatory kidney diseases than renal denervation. Use of optogenetic tools for selective stimulation of specific neurons has enabled the identification of neural circuits in the brain that modulate kidney function via activation of the CAP. In this Review we discuss evidence for a role of neural circuits in the control of renal inflammation as well as the therapeutic potential of targeting these circuits in the settings of AKI, kidney fibrosis and hypertension.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lineage tracing analysis defines erythropoietin-producing cells as a distinct subpopulation of resident fibroblasts with unique behaviors</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35644281/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35644281/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Erythropoietin (Epo) is produced by a subpopulation of resident fibroblasts in the healthy kidney. We have previously demonstrated that, during kidney fibrosis, kidney fibroblasts including Epo-producing cells transdifferentiate into myofibroblasts and lose their Epo-producing ability. However, it remains unclear whether Epo-producing cells survive and transform into myofibroblasts during fibrosis because previous studies did not specifically label Epo-producing cells in pathophysiological conditions. Here, we generated &lt;em&gt;Epo&lt;sup&gt;CreERT2/+&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; mice, a novel mouse strain that enables labeling of Epo-producing cells at desired time points and examined the behaviors of Epo-producing cells under pathophysiological conditions. Lineage-labeled cells that were producing Epo when labeled were found to be a small subpopulation of fibroblasts located in the interstitium of the kidney, and their number increased during phlebotomy-induced anemia. Around half of lineage-labeled cells expressed Epo mRNA, and this percentage was maintained even 16 weeks after recombination, supporting the idea that a distinct subpopulation of cells with Epo-producing ability makes Epo repeatedly. During fibrosis caused by ureteral obstruction, &lt;em&gt;Epo&lt;sup&gt;CreERT2/+&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt;-labeled cells were found to transdifferentiate into myofibroblasts with concomitant loss of Epo-producing ability, and their numbers and the proportion among resident fibroblasts increased during fibrosis, indicating their high proliferative capacity. Finally, we confirmed that &lt;em&gt;Epo&lt;sup&gt;CreERT2/+&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt;-labeled cells that lost their Epo-producing ability during fibrosis regained their ability after kidney repair due to relief of the ureteral obstruction. Thus, our analyses have revealed previously unappreciated characteristic behaviors of Epo-producing cells, which had not been clearly distinguished from those of resident fibroblasts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
