<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>HIV | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/hiv/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/hiv/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>HIV</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>HIV</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/hiv/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Candida albicans can foster gut dysbiosis and systemic inflammation during HIV infection</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36722096/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36722096/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Candida albicans&lt;/em&gt; (&lt;em&gt;C. albicans&lt;/em&gt;) is a ubiquitous fungal commensal component of the human microbiota, and under certain circumstances, such as during an immunocompromised state, it may initiate different types of infection. Moreover, &lt;em&gt;C. albicans&lt;/em&gt; continuously and reciprocally interacts with the host immune system as well as with other elements of the gut microbiota, thus contributing significantly to both gut homeostasis and host immunity. People living with HIV (PLWH), including those receiving antiretroviral therapy, are characterized by a depletion of CD4+ T-cells and dysbiosis in their gut. &lt;em&gt;C. albicans&lt;/em&gt; colonization is frequent in PLWH, causing both a high prevalence and high morbidity. Gut barrier damage and elevated levels of microbial translocation are also fairly common in this population. Herein, we take a closer look at the reciprocity among &lt;em&gt;C. albicans&lt;/em&gt;, gut microbiota, HIV, and the host immune system, thus throwing some light on this complex interplay.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Long-primed germinal centres with enduring affinity maturation and clonal migration</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36131022/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36131022/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Germinal centres are the engines of antibody evolution. Here, using human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) Env protein immunogen priming in rhesus monkeys followed by a long period without further immunization, we demonstrate germinal centre B (B&lt;sub&gt;GC&lt;/sub&gt;) cells that last for at least 6 months. A 186-fold increase in B&lt;sub&gt;GC&lt;/sub&gt; cells was present by week 10 compared with conventional immunization. Single-cell transcriptional profiling showed that both light- and dark-zone germinal centre states were sustained. Antibody somatic hypermutation of B&lt;sub&gt;GC&lt;/sub&gt; cells continued to accumulate throughout the 29-week priming period, with evidence of selective pressure. Env-binding B&lt;sub&gt;GC&lt;/sub&gt; cells were still 49-fold above baseline at 29 weeks, which suggests that they could remain active for even longer periods of time. High titres of HIV-neutralizing antibodies were generated after a single booster immunization. Fully glycosylated HIV trimer protein is a complex antigen, posing considerable immunodominance challenges for B cells. Memory B cells generated under these long priming conditions had higher levels of antibody somatic hypermutation, and both memory B cells and antibodies were more likely to recognize non-immunodominant epitopes. Numerous B&lt;sub&gt;GC&lt;/sub&gt; cell lineage phylogenies spanning more than the 6-month germinal centre period were identified, demonstrating continuous germinal centre activity and selection for at least 191 days with no further antigen exposure. A long-prime, slow-delivery (12 days) immunization approach holds promise for difficult vaccine targets and suggests that patience can have great value for tuning of germinal centres to maximize antibody responses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An in situ analysis pipeline for initial host-pathogen interactions reveals signatures of human colorectal HIV transmission</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36130503/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36130503/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;In situ&lt;/em&gt; quantification pipeline of early host-pathogen interactions in human tissue&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Initial HIV enrichment in mucosal DCs and submucosal macrophages, but not CD4&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T cells&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;HIV preferentially localizes to lymphoid aggregates, mediating submucosal virus entry&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;HIV rapidly alters cellular spatial organization to maximize uptake and infection&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The initial immune response to HIV determines transmission. However, due to technical limitations we still do not have a comparative map of early mucosal transmission events. By combining RNAscope, cyclic immunofluorescence, and image analysis tools, we quantify HIV transmission signatures in intact human colorectal explants within 2 h of topical exposure. We map HIV enrichment to mucosal dendritic cells (DCs) and submucosal macrophages, but not CD4&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T cells, the primary targets of downstream infection. HIV&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; DCs accumulate near and within lymphoid aggregates, which act as early sanctuaries of high viral titers while facilitating HIV passage to the submucosa. Finally, HIV entry induces recruitment and clustering of target cells, facilitating DC- and macrophage-mediated HIV transfer and enhanced infection of CD4&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T cells. These data demonstrate a rapid response to HIV structured to maximize the likelihood of mucosal infection and provide a framework for in situ studies of host-pathogen interactions and immune-mediated pathologies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cul3-KLHL20 E3 ubiquitin ligase plays a key role in the arms race between HIV-1 Nef and host SERINC5 restriction</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35474067/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35474067/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;HIV-1 must counteract various host restrictions to establish productive infection. SERINC5 is a potent restriction factor that blocks HIV-1 entry from virions, but its activity is counteracted by Nef. The SERINC5 and Nef activities are both initiated from the plasma membrane, where SERINC5 is packaged into virions for viral inhibition or downregulated by Nef via lysosomal degradation. However, it is still unclear how SERINC5 is localized to and how its expression is regulated on the plasma membrane. We now report that Cullin 3-KLHL20, a &lt;em&gt;trans&lt;/em&gt;-Golgi network (TGN)-localized E3 ubiquitin ligase, polyubiquitinates SERINC5 at lysine 130 via K33/K48-linked ubiquitination. The K33-linked polyubiquitination determines SERINC5 expression on the plasma membrane, and the K48-linked polyubiquitination contributes to SERINC5 downregulation from the cell surface. Our study reveals an important role of K130 polyubiquitination and K33/K48-linked ubiquitin chains in HIV-1 infection by regulating SERINC5 post-Golgi trafficking and degradation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Combined protein and nucleic acid imaging reveals virus-dependent B cell and macrophage immunosuppression of tissue microenvironments</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35447093/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35447093/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Development of a method (PANINI) for multiplexed nucleic acid and protein imaging&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Identification of orchestrated immune events in response to SIV infection&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IL-10 levels in B cells and macrophages correlate with immunosuppression&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tissue microenvironmental cues can influence SIV viral transcription state&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Understanding the mechanisms of HIV tissue persistence necessitates the ability to visualize tissue microenvironments where infected cells reside; however, technological barriers limit our ability to dissect the cellular components of these HIV reservoirs. Here, we developed protein and nucleic acid in situ imaging (PANINI) to simultaneously quantify DNA, RNA, and protein levels within these tissue compartments. By coupling PANINI with multiplexed ion beam imaging (MIBI), we measured over 30 parameters simultaneously across archival lymphoid tissues from healthy or simian immunodeficiency virus (SIV)-infected nonhuman primates. PANINI enabled the spatial dissection of cellular phenotypes, functional markers, and viral events resulting from infection. SIV infection induced IL-10 expression in lymphoid B cells, which correlated with local macrophage M2 polarization. This highlights a potential viral mechanism for conditioning an immunosuppressive tissue environment for virion production. The spatial multimodal framework here can be extended to decipher tissue responses in other infectious diseases and tumor biology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HIV-1 Vpr drives a tissue residency-like phenotype during selective infection of resting memory T cells</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35417711/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35417711/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cell-to-cell spread makes resting CD4+ T cells permissive to HIV-1 infection&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Resting memory T cells are productively infected by HIV-1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;HIV-1 Vpr drives resting memory T cells to gain characteristics of tissue residency&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vpr induces widespread transcriptional reprogramming of infected T cells&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;HIV-1 replicates in CD4&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T cells, leading to AIDS. Determining how HIV-1 shapes its niche to create a permissive environment is central to informing efforts to limit pathogenesis, disturb reservoirs, and achieve a cure. A key roadblock in understanding HIV-T cell interactions is the requirement to activate T cells in vitro to make them permissive to infection. This dramatically alters T cell biology and virus-host interactions. Here we show that HIV-1 cell-to-cell spread permits efficient, productive infection of resting memory T cells without prior activation. Strikingly, we find that HIV-1 infection primes resting T cells to gain characteristics of tissue-resident memory T cells (T&lt;sub&gt;RM&lt;/sub&gt;), including upregulating key surface markers and the transcription factor Blimp-1 and inducing a transcriptional program overlapping the core T&lt;sub&gt;RM&lt;/sub&gt; transcriptional signature. This reprogramming is driven by Vpr and requires Vpr packaging into virions and manipulation of STAT5. Thus, HIV-1 reprograms resting T cells, with implications for viral replication and persistence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TMEM106A inhibits enveloped virus release from cell surface</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35198896/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35198896/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Type II transmembrane protein TMEM106A can be incorporated into virion particles&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;TMEM106A inhibits enveloped virion release through C-terminal molecular interactions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;HIV-1 envelope protein interacts with TMEM106A and suppresses its antiviral activity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;TMEM106A is an evolutionarily conserved antiviral factor against multiple viruses&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enveloped viruses pose constant threat to hosts from ocean to land. Virion particle release from cell surface is a critical step in the viral life cycle for most enveloped viruses, making it a common antiviral target for the host defense system. Here we report that host factor TMEM106A inhibits the release of enveloped viruses from the cell surface. TMEM106A is a type II transmembrane protein localized on the plasma membrane and can be incorporated into HIV-1 virion particles. Through intermolecular interactions of its C-terminal domains on virion particle and plasma membrane, TMEM106A traps virion particles to the cell surface. HIV-1 Env interacts with TMEM106A to interfere with the intermolecular interactions and partially suppresses its antiviral activity. TMEM106A orthologs from various species displayed potent antiviral activity against multiple enveloped viruses. These results suggest that TMEM106A is an evolutionarily conserved antiviral factor that inhibits the release of enveloped viruses from the cell surface.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Host glycocalyx captures HIV proximal to the cell surface via oligomannose-GlcNAc glycan-glycan interactions to support viral entry</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35108536/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35108536/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Viral glycan shield acts as a cellular attachment factor&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Viral oligomannose initiates host cell attachment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This initial attachment is a specific, non-electrostatic interaction&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Blocking this interaction may present a pan-specific suppression mechanism&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here, we present ultrastructural analyses showing that incoming HIV are captured near the lymphocyte surface in a virion-glycan-dependent manner. Biophysical analyses show that removal of either virion- or cell-associated N-glycans impairs virus-cell binding, and a similar glycan-dependent relationship is observed between purified HIV envelope (Env) and primary T cells. Trimming of N-glycans from either HIV or Env does not inhibit protein-protein interactions. Glycan arrays reveal HIV preferentially binds to N-acetylglucosamine and mannose. Interfering with these glycan-based interactions reduces HIV infectivity. These glycan interactions are distinct from previously reported glycan-lectin and non-specific electrostatic charge-based interactions. Specific glycan-glycan-mediated attachment occurs prior to virus entry and enhances efficiency of infection. Binding and fluorescent imaging data support glycan-glycan interactions as being responsible, at least in part, for initiating contact between HIV and the host cell, prior to viral Env-cellular CD4 engagement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SARS-CoV-2 prolonged infection during advanced HIV disease evolves extensive immune escape</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35120605/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35120605/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Characterizing SARS-CoV-2 evolution in specific geographies may help predict properties of the variants that come from these regions. We mapped neutralization of a SARS-CoV-2 strain that evolved over 6 months from ancestral virus in a person with advanced HIV disease in South Africa; this person was infected prior to emergence of the Beta and Delta variants. We longitudinally tracked the evolved virus and tested it against self-plasma and convalescent plasma from ancestral, Beta, and Delta infections. Early virus was similar to ancestral, but it evolved a multitude of mutations found in Omicron and other variants. It showed substantial but incomplete Pfizer BNT162b2 escape, weak neutralization by self-plasma, and despite pre-dating Delta, it also showed extensive escape of Delta infection-elicited neutralization. This example is consistent with the notion that SARS-CoV-2 evolving in individual immune-compromised hosts, including those with advanced HIV disease, may gain immune escape of vaccines and enhanced escape of Delta immunity, and this has implications for vaccine breakthrough and reinfections.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conformation of HIV-1 Envelope Governs Rhesus CD4 Usage and Simian-Human Immunodeficiency Virus Replication</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35012342/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35012342/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Infection of rhesus macaques with simian-human immunodeficiency viruses (SHIVs) is the preferred model system for vaccine development because SHIVs encode human immunodeficiency virus type 1 (HIV-1) envelope glycoproteins (Envs)-a key target of HIV-1 neutralizing antibodies. Since the goal of vaccines is to prevent new infections, SHIVs encoding circulating HIV-1 Env are desired as challenge viruses. Development of such biologically relevant SHIVs has been challenging, as they fail to infect rhesus macaques, mainly because most circulating HIV-1 Envs do not use rhesus CD4 (rhCD4) receptor for viral entry. Most primary HIV-1 Envs exist in a closed conformation and occasionally transit to a downstream, open conformation through an obligate intermediate conformation. Here, we provide genetic evidence that open Env conformations can overcome the rhCD4 entry barrier and increase replication of SHIVs in rhesus lymphocytes. Consistent with prior studies, we found that circulating HIV-1 Envs do not use rhCD4 efficiently for viral entry. However, by using HIV-1 Envs with single amino acid substitutions that alter their conformational state, we found that transitions to intermediate and open Env conformations allow usage of physiological levels of rhCD4 for viral entry. We engineered these single amino acid substitutions in the transmitted/founder HIV-1BG505 Envs encoded by SHIV-BG505 and found that open Env conformation enhances SHIV replication in rhesus lymphocytes. Lastly, CD4-mediated SHIV pulldown, sensitivity to soluble CD4, and fusogenicity assays indicated that open Env conformation promotes efficient rhCD4 binding and viral-host membrane fusion. These findings identify the conformational state of HIV-1 Env as a major determinant for rhCD4 usage, viral fusion, and SHIV replication.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Importance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rhesus macaques are a critical animal model for preclinical testing of HIV-1 vaccine and prevention approaches. However, HIV-1 does not replicate in rhesus macaques, and thus, chimeric simian-human immunodeficiency viruses (SHIVs), which encode HIV-1 envelope glycoproteins (Envs), are used as surrogate challenge viruses to infect rhesus macaques for modeling HIV-1 infection. Development of SHIVs encoding Envs from clinically relevant, circulating HIV-1 variants has been extremely challenging, as such SHIVs replicate poorly, if at all, in rhesus lymphocytes. This is most probably because many circulating HIV-1 Envs do not use rhesus CD4 efficiently for viral entry. In this study, we identified conformational state of HIV-1 envelope as a key determinant for rhesus CD4 usage, viral-host membrane fusion, and SHIV replication in rhesus lymphocytes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
