<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>HIV | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/hiv/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/hiv/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>HIV</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>HIV</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/hiv/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Long-primed germinal centres with enduring affinity maturation and clonal migration</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36131022/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36131022/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Germinal centres are the engines of antibody evolution. Here, using human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) Env protein immunogen priming in rhesus monkeys followed by a long period without further immunization, we demonstrate germinal centre B (B&lt;sub&gt;GC&lt;/sub&gt;) cells that last for at least 6 months. A 186-fold increase in B&lt;sub&gt;GC&lt;/sub&gt; cells was present by week 10 compared with conventional immunization. Single-cell transcriptional profiling showed that both light- and dark-zone germinal centre states were sustained. Antibody somatic hypermutation of B&lt;sub&gt;GC&lt;/sub&gt; cells continued to accumulate throughout the 29-week priming period, with evidence of selective pressure. Env-binding B&lt;sub&gt;GC&lt;/sub&gt; cells were still 49-fold above baseline at 29 weeks, which suggests that they could remain active for even longer periods of time. High titres of HIV-neutralizing antibodies were generated after a single booster immunization. Fully glycosylated HIV trimer protein is a complex antigen, posing considerable immunodominance challenges for B cells. Memory B cells generated under these long priming conditions had higher levels of antibody somatic hypermutation, and both memory B cells and antibodies were more likely to recognize non-immunodominant epitopes. Numerous B&lt;sub&gt;GC&lt;/sub&gt; cell lineage phylogenies spanning more than the 6-month germinal centre period were identified, demonstrating continuous germinal centre activity and selection for at least 191 days with no further antigen exposure. A long-prime, slow-delivery (12 days) immunization approach holds promise for difficult vaccine targets and suggests that patience can have great value for tuning of germinal centres to maximize antibody responses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An in situ analysis pipeline for initial host-pathogen interactions reveals signatures of human colorectal HIV transmission</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36130503/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36130503/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;In situ&lt;/em&gt; quantification pipeline of early host-pathogen interactions in human tissue&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Initial HIV enrichment in mucosal DCs and submucosal macrophages, but not CD4&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T cells&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;HIV preferentially localizes to lymphoid aggregates, mediating submucosal virus entry&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;HIV rapidly alters cellular spatial organization to maximize uptake and infection&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The initial immune response to HIV determines transmission. However, due to technical limitations we still do not have a comparative map of early mucosal transmission events. By combining RNAscope, cyclic immunofluorescence, and image analysis tools, we quantify HIV transmission signatures in intact human colorectal explants within 2 h of topical exposure. We map HIV enrichment to mucosal dendritic cells (DCs) and submucosal macrophages, but not CD4&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T cells, the primary targets of downstream infection. HIV&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; DCs accumulate near and within lymphoid aggregates, which act as early sanctuaries of high viral titers while facilitating HIV passage to the submucosa. Finally, HIV entry induces recruitment and clustering of target cells, facilitating DC- and macrophage-mediated HIV transfer and enhanced infection of CD4&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T cells. These data demonstrate a rapid response to HIV structured to maximize the likelihood of mucosal infection and provide a framework for in situ studies of host-pathogen interactions and immune-mediated pathologies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
