<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Gene Editing | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/gene-editing/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/gene-editing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Gene Editing</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Gene Editing</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/gene-editing/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Diverse virus-encoded CRISPR-Cas systems include streamlined genome editors</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36423580/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36423580/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CRISPR pathways encoded in diverse bacteriophage are hypercompact anti-viral systems&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Phage-encoded CRISPR systems encompass all known CRISPR-Cas types&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Casλ enzyme’s compact structure is capable of plant and human cell genome editing&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These findings reveal a new source of CRISPR-Cas enzymes with value as genome editors&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CRISPR-Cas systems are host-encoded pathways that protect microbes from viral infection using an adaptive RNA-guided mechanism. Using genome-resolved metagenomics, we find that CRISPR systems are also encoded in diverse bacteriophages, where they occur as divergent and hypercompact anti-viral systems. Bacteriophage-encoded CRISPR systems belong to all six known CRISPR-Cas types, though some lack crucial components, suggesting alternate functional roles or host complementation. We describe multiple new Cas9-like proteins and 44 families related to type V CRISPR-Cas systems, including the Casλ RNA-guided nuclease family. Among the most divergent of the new enzymes identified, Casλ recognizes double-stranded DNA using a uniquely structured CRISPR RNA (crRNA). The Casλ-RNA-DNA structure determined by cryoelectron microscopy reveals a compact bilobed architecture capable of inducing genome editing in mammalian, Arabidopsis, and hexaploid wheat cells. These findings reveal a new source of CRISPR-Cas enzymes in phages and highlight their value as genome editors in plant and human cells.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GPSAdb: a comprehensive web resource for interactive exploration of genetic perturbation RNA-seq datasets</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36416261/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36416261/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gene knock-out/down methods are commonly used to explore the functions of genes of interest, but a database that systematically collects perturbed data is not available currently. Manual curation of all the available human cell line perturbed RNA-seq datasets enabled us to develop a comprehensive human perturbation database-&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gpsadb.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;GPSAdb&lt;/a&gt;. The current version of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gpsadb.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;GPSAdb&lt;/a&gt; collected 3048 RNA-seq datasets associated with 1458 genes, which were knocked out/down by siRNA, shRNA, CRISPR/Cas9, or CRISPRi. The database provides full exploration of these datasets and generated 6096 new perturbed gene sets (up and down separately). &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gpsadb.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;GPSAdb&lt;/a&gt; integrated the gene sets and developed an online tool, genetic perturbation similarity analysis (GPSA), to identify candidate causal perturbations from differential gene expression data. In summary, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gpsadb.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;GPSAdb&lt;/a&gt; is a powerful platform that aims to assist life science researchers to easily access and analyze public perturbed data and explore differential gene expression data in depth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The phenotypic landscape of essential human genes</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36347254/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36347254/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Image-based pooled screen of 5,072 essential genes reveals multidimensional phenotypes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Phenotypic clustering of cell image parameters defines diverse co-functional genes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Live-cell pooled imaging screen identifies genes required for chromosome segregation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A resource defining the phenotypic consequences of disrupting core cellular processes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Understanding the basis for cellular growth, proliferation, and function requires determining the roles of essential genes in diverse cellular processes, including visualizing their contributions to cellular organization and morphology. Here, we combined pooled CRISPR-Cas9-based functional screening of 5,072 fitness-conferring genes in human HeLa cells with microscopy-based imaging of DNA, the DNA damage response, actin, and microtubules. Analysis of &amp;gt;31 million individual cells identified measurable phenotypes for &amp;gt;90% of gene knockouts, implicating gene targets in specific cellular processes. Clustering of phenotypic similarities based on hundreds of quantitative parameters further revealed co-functional genes across diverse cellular activities, providing predictions for gene functions and associations. By conducting pooled live-cell screening of ∼450,000 cell division events for 239 genes, we additionally identified diverse genes with functional contributions to chromosome segregation. Our work establishes a resource detailing the consequences of disrupting core cellular processes that represents the functional landscape of essential human genes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Precise DNA cleavage using CRISPR-SpRYgests</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36203014/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36203014/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Methods for in vitro DNA cleavage and molecular cloning remain unable to precisely cleave DNA directly adjacent to bases of interest. Restriction enzymes (REs) must bind specific motifs, whereas wild-type CRISPR–Cas9 or CRISPR–Cas12 nucleases require protospacer adjacent motifs (PAMs). Here we explore the utility of our previously reported near-PAMless SpCas9 variant, named SpRY, to serve as a universal DNA cleavage tool for various cloning applications. By performing SpRY DNA digests (SpRYgests) using more than 130 guide RNAs (gRNAs) sampling a wide diversity of PAMs, we discovered that SpRY is PAMless in vitro and can cleave DNA at practically any sequence, including sites refractory to cleavage with wild-type SpCas9. We illustrate the versatility and effectiveness of SpRYgests to improve the precision of several cloning workflows, including those not possible with REs or canonical CRISPR nucleases. We also optimize a rapid and simple one-pot gRNA synthesis protocol to streamline SpRYgest implementation. Together, SpRYgests can improve various DNA engineering applications that benefit from precise DNA breaks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Programmable RNA sensing for cell monitoring and manipulation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36198803/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36198803/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;RNA is a central and universal mediator of genetic information underlying the diversity of cell types and cell states, which together shape tissue organization and organismal function across species and lifespans. Despite numerous advances in RNA sequencing technologies and the massive accumulation of transcriptome datasets across the life sciences1,2, the dearth of technologies that use RNAs to observe and manipulate cell types remains a bottleneck in biology and medicine. Here we describe CellREADR (Cell access through RNA sensing by Endogenous ADAR), a programmable RNA-sensing technology that leverages RNA editing mediated by ADAR to couple the detection of cell-defining RNAs with the translation of effector proteins. Viral delivery of CellREADR conferred specific cell-type access in mouse and rat brains and in ex vivo human brain tissues. Furthermore, CellREADR enabled the recording and control of specific types of neurons in behaving mice. CellREADR thus highlights the potential for RNA-based monitoring and editing of animal cells in ways that are specific, versatile, simple and generalizable across organ systems and species, with wide applications in biology, biotechnology and programmable RNA medicine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guide RNA engineering enables efficient CRISPR editing with a miniature Syntrophomonas palmitatica Cas12f1 nuclease</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36170834/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36170834/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gene therapy is limited by inefficient delivery of large clustered regularly interspaced short palindromic repeat (CRISPR) effectors, such as Cas9 and Cas12a nucleases. Cas12f nucleases are currently one of the most compact CRISPR genome editors. However, the available toolkit of efficient Cas12f editors is limited. Here, we report the characterization and engineering of a miniature CRISPR-Cas12f system from Syntrophomonas palmitatica (SpaCas12f1, 497 amino acids). We show that CRISPR-SpaCas12f1 cleaves double-stranded DNA (dsDNA) with 5&amp;rsquo; T-rich PAM specificity and is naturally active for genome editing in bacteria. We identify that CRISPR-SpaCas12f1 trans-activating CRISPR RNA (tracrRNA) harbors a unique head-to-toe hairpin structure, and the natural hairpin structure is a key factor in restricting genome editing by SpaCas12f1 in human cells. Systematical engineering of SpaCas12f1 guide RNA transforms CRISPR-SpaCas12f1 into an efficient genome editor comparable to Francisella novicida CRISPR-Cas12a. Our findings expand the mini CRISPR toolbox, paving the way for therapeutic applications of CRISPR-SpaCas12f1 and engineering compact genome manipulation technologies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>High-throughput functional variant screens via in vivo production of single-stranded DNA</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33906944/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33906944/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Creating and characterizing individual genetic variants remains limited in scale, compared to the tremendous variation both existing in nature and envisioned by genome engineers. Here we introduce retron library recombineering (RLR), a methodology for high-throughput functional screens that surpasses the scale and specificity of CRISPR-Cas methods. We use the targeted reverse-transcription activity of retrons to produce single-stranded DNA (ssDNA) in vivo, incorporating edits at &amp;gt;90% efficiency and enabling multiplexed applications. RLR simultaneously introduces many genomic variants, producing pooled and barcoded variant libraries addressable by targeted deep sequencing. We use RLR for pooled phenotyping of synthesized antibiotic resistance alleles, demonstrating quantitative measurement of relative growth rates. We also perform RLR using the sheared genomic DNA of an evolved bacterium, experimentally querying millions of sequences for causal variants, demonstrating that RLR is uniquely suited to utilize large pools of natural variation. Using ssDNA produced in vivo for pooled experiments presents avenues for exploring variation across the genome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Significance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We report a methodology for the pooled construction of mutants bearing precise genomic sequence variations and multiplex phenotypic characterization of these mutants using next-generation sequencing (NGS). Unlike existing techniques depending on CRISPR-Cas–directed genomic breaks for genome editing, this strategy instead uses single-stranded DNA produced by a retron element for recombineering. This enables libraries of millions of elements to be constructed and offers relaxed design constraints which permit natural DNA or random variation to be used as inputs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
