<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blood | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/blood/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/blood/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Blood</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Blood</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/blood/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>A genome-wide transcriptomic analysis of protein-coding genes in human blood cells</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/31857451/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/31857451/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blood is the predominant source for molecular analyses in humans, both in clinical and research settings. It is the target for many therapeutic strategies, emphasizing the need for comprehensive molecular maps of the cells constituting human blood. In this study, we performed a genome-wide transcriptomic analysis of protein-coding genes in sorted blood immune cell populations to characterize the expression levels of each individual gene across the blood cell types. All data are presented in an interactive, open-access Blood Atlas as part of the Human Protein Atlas and are integrated with expression profiles across all major tissues to provide spatial classification of all protein-coding genes. This allows for a genome-wide exploration of the expression profiles across human immune cell populations and all major human tissues and organs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bacterial Endotoxin Activates the Coagulation Cascade through Gasdermin D-Dependent Phosphatidylserine Exposure</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/31836429/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/31836429/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deletion of caspase-11 prevents disseminated intravascular coagulation (DIC) in sepsis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deletion of GSDMD prevents caspase-11- and TF-mediated DIC in endotoxemia&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GSDMD deficiency inhibits endotoxin-induced TF activation by reducing PS exposure&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Activation of GSDMD by caspase-11 triggers Ca2+-dependent PS exposure through TMEM16F&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Summary&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Excessive activation of the coagulation system leads to life-threatening disseminated intravascular coagulation (DIC). Here, we examined the mechanisms underlying the activation of coagulation by lipopolysaccharide (LPS), the major cell-wall component of Gram-negative bacteria. We found that caspase-11, a cytosolic LPS receptor, activated the coagulation cascade. Caspase-11 enhanced the activation of tissue factor (TF), an initiator of coagulation, through triggering the formation of gasdermin D (GSDMD) pores and subsequent phosphatidylserine exposure, in a manner independent of cell death. GSDMD pores mediated calcium influx, which induced phosphatidylserine exposure through transmembrane protein 16F, a calcium-dependent phospholipid scramblase. Deletion of &lt;em&gt;Casp11&lt;/em&gt;, ablation of &lt;em&gt;Gsdmd&lt;/em&gt;, or neutralization of phosphatidylserine or TF prevented LPS-induced DIC. In septic patients, plasma concentrations of interleukin (IL)-1α and IL-1β, biomarkers of GSDMD activation, correlated with phosphatidylserine exposure in peripheral leukocytes and DIC scores. Our findings mechanistically link immune recognition of LPS to coagulation, with implications for the treatment of DIC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
