<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blood | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/blood/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/blood/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Blood</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 29 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Blood</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/blood/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mesenchymal stem cell-derived extracellular vesicles attenuate tPA-induced blood-brain barrier disruption in murine ischemic stroke models</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36367475/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36367475/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Intracerebral hemorrhage following blood-brain barrier (BBB) disruption resulting from thrombolysis of ischemic stroke with tissue plasminogen activator (tPA) remains a critical clinical problem. Mesenchymal stem cell-derived extracellular vesicles (MSC-EVs) are promising nanotherapeutic agents that have the potential to repair the BBB after ischemic stroke; however, whether they can attenuate BBB disruption and hemorrhagic transformation after tPA thrombolysis is largely unknown. Here, we observed that MSC-EVs efficiently passed through the BBB and selectively accumulated in injured brain regions in ischemic stroke model mice in real time using aggregation-induced emission luminogens (AIEgens), which exhibit better tracking ability than the commercially available tracer DiR. Moreover, tPA administration promoted the homing of MSC-EVs to the ischemic brain and increased the uptake of MSC-EVs by astrocytes. Furthermore, the accumulated MSC-EVs attenuated the tPA-induced disruption of BBB integrity and alleviated hemorrhage by inhibiting astrocyte activation and inflammation. Mechanistically, miR-125b-5p delivered by MSC-EVs played an indispensable role in maintaining BBB integrity by targeting Toll-like receptor 4 (TLR4) and inhibiting nuclear transcription factor-kappaB (NF-κB) signaling in astrocytes. This study provides a noninvasive method for real-time tracking of MSC-EVs in the ischemic brain after tPA treatment and highlights the potential of MSC-EVs as thrombolytic adjuvants for ischemic stroke. STATEMENT OF SIGNIFICANCE: Although tPA thrombolysis is the most effective pharmaceutical strategy for acute ischemic stroke, its clinical application and therapeutic efficacy are challenged by tPA-induced BBB disruption and hemorrhagic transformation. Our study demonstrated that MSC-EVs can act as an attractive thrombolytic adjuvant to repair the BBB and improve thrombolysis in a mouse ischemic stroke model. Notably, by labeling MSC-EVs with AIEgens, we achieved accurate real-time imaging of MSC-EVs in the ischemic brain and therapeutic visualization. MSC-EVs inhibit astrocyte activation and associated inflammation through miR-125b-5p/TLR4/NF-κB pathway. Consequently, we revealed that MSC-EVs combined with tPA thrombolysis may be a promising approach for the treatment of ischemic stroke in clinical setting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Perivascular Macrophages Regulate Blood Flow Following Tissue Damage</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33878889/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33878889/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rationale:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ischemic injuries remain a leading cause of mortality and morbidity worldwide, and restoration of functional blood perfusion is vital to limit tissue damage and support healing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Objective:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To reveal a novel role of macrophages in reestablishment of functional tissue perfusion following ischemic injury that can be targeted to improve tissue restoration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Methods and Results:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using intravital microscopy of ischemic hindlimb muscle in mice, and confocal microscopy of human tissues from amputated legs, we found that macrophages accumulated perivascularly in ischemic muscles, where they expressed high levels of iNOS (inducible nitric oxide [NO] synthase). Genetic depletion of iNOS specifically in macrophages (Cx3cr1-CreERT2;Nos2&lt;sup&gt;fl/fl&lt;/sup&gt; or LysM-Cre;Nos2&lt;sup&gt;fl/fl&lt;/sup&gt;) did not affect vascular architecture but highly compromised blood flow regulation in ischemic but not healthy muscle, which resulted in aggravated ischemic damage. Thus, the ability to upregulate blood flow was shifted from eNOS (endothelial)-dependence in healthy muscles to completely rely on macrophage-derived iNOS during ischemia. Macrophages in ischemic muscles expressed high levels of CXCR4 (C-X-C chemokine receptor type 4) and CCR2 (C-C chemokine receptor type 2), and local overexpression by DNA plasmids encoding the corresponding chemokines CXCL12 (stromal-derived factor 1) or CCL2 (chemokine [C-C motif] ligand 2) increased macrophage numbers, while CXCL12 but not CCL2 induced their perivascular positioning. As a result, CXCL12-overexpression increased the number of perfused blood vessels in the ischemic muscles, improved functional muscle perfusion in a macrophage-iNOS-dependent manner, and ultimately restored limb function.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This study establishes a new function for macrophages during tissue repair, as they regulate blood flow through the release of iNOS-produced NO. Further, we demonstrate that macrophages can be therapeutically targeted to improve blood flow regulation and functional recovery of ischemic tissues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Heparin prevents caspase-11-dependent septic lethality independent of anticoagulant properties</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33561388/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33561388/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Heparin, a mammalian polysaccharide, is a widely used anticoagulant medicine to treat thrombotic disorders. It is also known to improve outcomes in sepsis, a leading cause of mortality resulted from infection-induced immune dysfunction. Whereas it is relatively clear how heparin exerts its anticoagulant effect, the immunomodulatory mechanisms enabled by heparin remain enigmatic. Here, we show that heparin prevented caspase-11-dependent immune responses and lethality in sepsis independent of its anticoagulant properties. Heparin or a chemically modified form of heparin without anticoagulant function inhibited the alarmin HMGB1-lipopolysaccharide (LPS) interaction and prevented the macrophage glycocalyx degradation by heparanase. These events blocked the cytosolic delivery of LPS in macrophages and the activation of caspase-11, a cytosolic LPS receptor that mediates lethality in sepsis. Survival was higher in septic patients treated with heparin than those without heparin treatment. The identification of this previously unrecognized heparin function establishes a link between innate immune responses and coagulation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>APOE4 leads to blood-brain barrier dysfunction predicting cognitive decline</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32376954/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32376954/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vascular contributions to dementia and Alzheimer&amp;rsquo;s disease are increasingly recognized. Recent studies have suggested that breakdown of the blood-brain barrier (BBB) is an early biomarker of human cognitive dysfunction, including the early clinical stages of Alzheimer&amp;rsquo;s disease. The E4 variant of apolipoprotein E (&lt;em&gt;APOE4&lt;/em&gt;), the main susceptibility gene for Alzheimer&amp;rsquo;s disease, leads to accelerated breakdown of the BBB and degeneration of brain capillary pericytes, which maintain BBB integrity. It is unclear, however, whether the cerebrovascular effects of &lt;em&gt;APOE4&lt;/em&gt; contribute to cognitive impairment. Here we show that individuals bearing &lt;em&gt;APOE4&lt;/em&gt; (with the ε3/ε4 or ε4/ε4 alleles) are distinguished from those without &lt;em&gt;APOE4&lt;/em&gt; (ε3/ε3) by breakdown of the BBB in the hippocampus and medial temporal lobe. This finding is apparent in cognitively unimpaired &lt;em&gt;APOE4&lt;/em&gt; carriers and more severe in those with cognitive impairment, but is not related to amyloid-β or tau pathology measured in cerebrospinal fluid or by positron emission tomography23. High baseline levels of the BBB pericyte injury biomarker soluble PDGFRβ7,8 in the cerebrospinal fluid predicted future cognitive decline in &lt;em&gt;APOE4&lt;/em&gt; carriers but not in non-carriers, even after controlling for amyloid-β and tau status, and were correlated with increased activity of the BBB-degrading cyclophilin A-matrix metalloproteinase-9 pathway19 in cerebrospinal fluid. Our findings suggest that breakdown of the BBB contributes to &lt;em&gt;APOE4&lt;/em&gt;-associated cognitive decline independently of Alzheimer&amp;rsquo;s disease pathology, and might be a therapeutic target in &lt;em&gt;APOE4&lt;/em&gt; carriers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The role of type 1 interferons in coagulation induced by gram-negative bacteria</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32016282/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32016282/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bacterial infection not only stimulates innate immune responses but also activates coagulation cascades. Overactivation of the coagulation system in bacterial sepsis leads to disseminated intravascular coagulation (DIC), a life-threatening condition. However, the mechanisms by which bacterial infection activates the coagulation cascade are not fully understood. Here we show that type 1 interferons (IFNs), a widely expressed family of cytokines that orchestrate innate antiviral and antibacterial immunity, mediate bacterial infection-induced DIC by amplifying the release of high-mobility group box 1 (HMGB1) into the bloodstream. Inhibition of the expression of type 1 IFNs and disruption of their receptor IFN-α/βR or downstream effector (eg, HMGB1) uniformly decreased gram-negative bacteria-induced DIC. Mechanistically, extracellular HMGB1 markedly increased the procoagulant activity of tissue factor by promoting the externalization of phosphatidylserine to the outer cell surface, where phosphatidylserine assembles a complex of cofactor-proteases of the coagulation cascades. These findings not only provide novel insights into the link between innate immune responses and coagulation, but they also open a new avenue for developing novel therapeutic strategies to prevent DIC in sepsis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A genome-wide transcriptomic analysis of protein-coding genes in human blood cells</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/31857451/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/31857451/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blood is the predominant source for molecular analyses in humans, both in clinical and research settings. It is the target for many therapeutic strategies, emphasizing the need for comprehensive molecular maps of the cells constituting human blood. In this study, we performed a genome-wide transcriptomic analysis of protein-coding genes in sorted blood immune cell populations to characterize the expression levels of each individual gene across the blood cell types. All data are presented in an interactive, open-access Blood Atlas as part of the Human Protein Atlas and are integrated with expression profiles across all major tissues to provide spatial classification of all protein-coding genes. This allows for a genome-wide exploration of the expression profiles across human immune cell populations and all major human tissues and organs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bacterial Endotoxin Activates the Coagulation Cascade through Gasdermin D-Dependent Phosphatidylserine Exposure</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/31836429/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/31836429/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deletion of caspase-11 prevents disseminated intravascular coagulation (DIC) in sepsis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deletion of GSDMD prevents caspase-11- and TF-mediated DIC in endotoxemia&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GSDMD deficiency inhibits endotoxin-induced TF activation by reducing PS exposure&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Activation of GSDMD by caspase-11 triggers Ca2+-dependent PS exposure through TMEM16F&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Summary&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Excessive activation of the coagulation system leads to life-threatening disseminated intravascular coagulation (DIC). Here, we examined the mechanisms underlying the activation of coagulation by lipopolysaccharide (LPS), the major cell-wall component of Gram-negative bacteria. We found that caspase-11, a cytosolic LPS receptor, activated the coagulation cascade. Caspase-11 enhanced the activation of tissue factor (TF), an initiator of coagulation, through triggering the formation of gasdermin D (GSDMD) pores and subsequent phosphatidylserine exposure, in a manner independent of cell death. GSDMD pores mediated calcium influx, which induced phosphatidylserine exposure through transmembrane protein 16F, a calcium-dependent phospholipid scramblase. Deletion of &lt;em&gt;Casp11&lt;/em&gt;, ablation of &lt;em&gt;Gsdmd&lt;/em&gt;, or neutralization of phosphatidylserine or TF prevented LPS-induced DIC. In septic patients, plasma concentrations of interleukin (IL)-1α and IL-1β, biomarkers of GSDMD activation, correlated with phosphatidylserine exposure in peripheral leukocytes and DIC scores. Our findings mechanistically link immune recognition of LPS to coagulation, with implications for the treatment of DIC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
