<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blood | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/blood/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/blood/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Blood</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Blood</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/blood/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fecal microbiota transplantation from young mice rejuvenates aged hematopoietic stem cells by suppressing inflammations</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36638348/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36638348/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hematopoietic stem cell (HSC) aging is accompanied by hematopoietic reconstitution dysfunction, including loss of regenerative and engraftment ability, myeloid differentiation bias and elevated risks of hematopoietic malignancies. Gut microbiota, a key regulator of host health and immunity, has been recently reported to impact hematopoiesis. However, there is currently limited empirical evidence elucidating the direct impact of gut microbiome on aging hematopoiesis. In this study, we performed fecal microbiota transplantation (FMT) from young mice to aged mice and observed significant increment in lymphoid differentiation and decrease in myeloid differentiation in aged recipient mice. Further, FMT from young mice rejuvenated aged HSCs with enhanced short-term and long-term hematopoietic repopulation capacity. Mechanistically, single-cell RNA sequencing deciphered that FMT from young mice mitigated inflammatory signals, upregulated FoxO signaling pathway and promoted lymphoid differentiation of HSCs during aging. Finally, integrated microbiome and metabolome analyses uncovered that FMT reshaped gut microbiota construction and metabolite landscape, and Lachnospiraceae and tryptophan-associated metabolites promoted the recovery of hematopoiesis and rejuvenated aged HSCs. Together, our study highlights the paramount importance of the gut microbiota in HSC aging and provides insights into therapeutic strategies for aging-related hematologic disorders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dietary ketone body-escalated histone acetylation in megakaryocytes alleviates chemotherapy-induced thrombocytopenia</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36449600/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36449600/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chemotherapy-induced thrombocytopenia (CIT) is a severe complication in patients with cancer that can lead to impaired therapeutic outcome and survival. Clinically, therapeutic options for CIT are limited by severe adverse effects and high economic burdens. Here, we demonstrate that ketogenic diets alleviate CIT in both animals and humans without causing thrombocytosis. Mechanistically, ketogenic diet-induced circulating β-hydroxybutyrate (β-OHB) increased histone H3 acetylation in bone marrow megakaryocytes. Gain- and loss-of-function experiments revealed a distinct role of 3-β-hydroxybutyrate dehydrogenase (BDH)-mediated ketone body metabolism in promoting histone acetylation, which promoted the transcription of platelet biogenesis genes and induced thrombocytopoiesis. Genetic depletion of the megakaryocyte-specific ketone body transporter monocarboxylate transporter 1 (MCT1) or pharmacological targeting of MCT1 blocked β-OHB-induced thrombocytopoiesis in mice. A ketogenesis-promoting diet alleviated CIT in mouse models. Moreover, a ketogenic diet modestly increased platelet counts without causing thrombocytosis in healthy volunteers, and a ketogenic lifestyle inversely correlated with CIT in patients with cancer. Together, we provide mechanistic insights into a ketone body-MCT1-BDH-histone acetylation-platelet biogenesis axis in megakaryocytes and propose a nontoxic, low-cost dietary intervention for combating CIT.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intestinal dysbiosis mediates cognitive impairment via the intestine and brain NLRP3 inflammasome activation in chronic sleep deprivation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36427810/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36427810/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Growing evidence suggests the involvement of the microbiota-gut-brain axis in cognitive impairment induced by sleep deprivation (SD), however how the microbiota-gut-brain axis work remains elusive. Here, we discovered that chronic SD induced intestinal dysbiosis, activated NLRP3 inflammasome in the colon and brain, destructed intestinal/blood-brain barrier, and impaired cognitive function in mice. Transplantation of &amp;ldquo;SD microbiota&amp;rdquo; could almost mimic the pathological and behavioral changes caused by chronic SD. Furthermore, all the behavioral and pathological abnormalities were practically reversed in chronic sleep-deprived NLRP3-/- mice. Regional knockdown NLRP3 expression in the gut and hippocampus, respectively. We observed that down-regulation of NLRP3 in the hippocampus inhibited neuroinflammation, and ameliorated synaptic dysfunction and cognitive impairment induced by chronic SD. More intriguingly, the down-regulation of NLRP3 in the gut protected the intestinal barrier, attenuated the levels of peripheral inflammatory factors, down-regulated the expression of NLRP3 in the brain, and improved cognitive function in chronic SD mice. Our results identified gut microbiota as a driver in chronic SD and highlighted the NLRP3 inflammasome as a key regulator within the microbiota-gut-brain axis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Xuebijing Administration Alleviates Pulmonary Endothelial Inflammation and Coagulation Dysregulation in the Early Phase of Sepsis in Rats</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36431172/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36431172/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ethnopharmacological relevance: Xuebijing injection is a Chinese herbal-derived drug composed of radix paeoniaerubra, rhizomachuanxiong, Salvia miltiorrhiza, floscarthami, and Angelica sinensis. This study aimed to investigate the effects of Xuebijing administration on pulmonary endothelial injury and coagulation dysfunction in a cecal ligation and puncture (CLP)-induced sepsis rat model. Materials and methods: A CLP-induced sepsis rat model was established. The CLP rats were treated with a vehicle or Xuebijing via intravenous infusion and sacrificed at 2, 4, 6, 8, or 12 h after CLP for lung tissue and blood sample collection. The mean arterial pressure (MAP) was monitored. Transmission microscopy examination and H&amp;amp;E staining were performed to observe pulmonary structural alterations. Enzyme linked immunosorbent assay (ELISA) was performed to measure the plasma levels of epithelial markers, proinflammatory cytokines, and coagulation-related proteins. Results: Compared with vehicle treatment, Xuebijing administration maintained the MAP in the normal range until 11 h after CLP. Transmission microscopy and H&amp;amp;E staining revealed that Xuebijing administration alleviated alveolar–capillary barrier impairments and lung inflammation in CLP rats. ELISA showed that Xuebijing administration effectively reversed CLP-induced elevations in the plasma levels of epithelial markers endothelin-1 and von Willebrand factor, starting 6 and 8 h after CLP, respectively. Xuebijing administration also significantly abolished CLP-induced rises in circulating proinflammatory cytokines interleukin 6 (IL-6) at 6 h after CLP, IL-1β at 2 and 12 h after CLP, and TNF-α at 2, 4, 6, 8, and 12 h after CLP. In addition, Xuebijing administration strongly reversed CLP-induced alterations in circulating active protein C and tissue-type plasminogen activator, starting 4 h and 2 h after CLP, respectively. Conclusions: Xuebijing ameliorates pulmonary endothelial injury, systemic inflammation, and coagulation dysfunction in early sepsis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mesenchymal stem cell-derived extracellular vesicles attenuate tPA-induced blood-brain barrier disruption in murine ischemic stroke models</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36367475/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36367475/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Intracerebral hemorrhage following blood-brain barrier (BBB) disruption resulting from thrombolysis of ischemic stroke with tissue plasminogen activator (tPA) remains a critical clinical problem. Mesenchymal stem cell-derived extracellular vesicles (MSC-EVs) are promising nanotherapeutic agents that have the potential to repair the BBB after ischemic stroke; however, whether they can attenuate BBB disruption and hemorrhagic transformation after tPA thrombolysis is largely unknown. Here, we observed that MSC-EVs efficiently passed through the BBB and selectively accumulated in injured brain regions in ischemic stroke model mice in real time using aggregation-induced emission luminogens (AIEgens), which exhibit better tracking ability than the commercially available tracer DiR. Moreover, tPA administration promoted the homing of MSC-EVs to the ischemic brain and increased the uptake of MSC-EVs by astrocytes. Furthermore, the accumulated MSC-EVs attenuated the tPA-induced disruption of BBB integrity and alleviated hemorrhage by inhibiting astrocyte activation and inflammation. Mechanistically, miR-125b-5p delivered by MSC-EVs played an indispensable role in maintaining BBB integrity by targeting Toll-like receptor 4 (TLR4) and inhibiting nuclear transcription factor-kappaB (NF-κB) signaling in astrocytes. This study provides a noninvasive method for real-time tracking of MSC-EVs in the ischemic brain after tPA treatment and highlights the potential of MSC-EVs as thrombolytic adjuvants for ischemic stroke. STATEMENT OF SIGNIFICANCE: Although tPA thrombolysis is the most effective pharmaceutical strategy for acute ischemic stroke, its clinical application and therapeutic efficacy are challenged by tPA-induced BBB disruption and hemorrhagic transformation. Our study demonstrated that MSC-EVs can act as an attractive thrombolytic adjuvant to repair the BBB and improve thrombolysis in a mouse ischemic stroke model. Notably, by labeling MSC-EVs with AIEgens, we achieved accurate real-time imaging of MSC-EVs in the ischemic brain and therapeutic visualization. MSC-EVs inhibit astrocyte activation and associated inflammation through miR-125b-5p/TLR4/NF-κB pathway. Consequently, we revealed that MSC-EVs combined with tPA thrombolysis may be a promising approach for the treatment of ischemic stroke in clinical setting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NETosis and thrombosis in vaccine-induced immune thrombotic thrombocytopenia</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36064843/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36064843/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vaccine-induced immune thrombotic thrombocytopenia (VITT) is a rare yet serious adverse effect of the adenoviral vector vaccines ChAdOx1 nCoV-19 (AstraZeneca) and Ad26.COV2.S (Janssen) against COVID-19. The mechanisms involved in clot formation and thrombocytopenia in VITT are yet to be fully determined. Here we show neutrophils undergoing NETosis and confirm expression markers of NETs in VITT patients. VITT antibodies directly stimulate neutrophils to release NETs and induce thrombus formation containing abundant platelets, neutrophils, fibrin, extracellular DNA and citrullinated histone H3 in a flow microfluidics system and in vivo. Inhibition of NETosis prevents VITT-induced thrombosis in mice but not thrombocytopenia. In contrast, in vivo blockage of FcγRIIa abrogates both thrombosis and thrombocytopenia suggesting these are distinct processes. Our findings indicate that anti-PF4 antibodies activate blood cells via FcγRIIa and are responsible for thrombosis and thrombocytopenia in VITT. Future development of NETosis and FcγRIIa inhibitors are needed to treat VITT and similar immune thrombotic thrombocytopenia conditions more effectively, leading to better patient outcomes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lung-Targeted Delivery of Cepharanthine by an Erythrocyte-Anchoring Strategy for the Treatment of Acute Lung Injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36145566/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36145566/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As one of the most frequent complications of critical illness, acute lung injury (ALI) carries a high risk of clinical morbidity and mortality. Cepharanthine (CPA) has significant anti-inflammatory activity, however, due to poor water solubility, low bioavailability, and short half-life, it fails to provide effective clinical management measures. Here, we explored the flexibility of an erythrocyte-anchoring strategy using CPA-encapsulated chitosan-coating nanoparticles (CPA-CNPs) anchored onto circulating erythrocytes for the treatment of ALI. CPA-CNPs adhered to erythrocytes successfully (E-CPA-CNPs) and exhibited high erythrocyte adhesion efficiency (&amp;gt;80%). Limited toxicity and favorable biocompatibility enabled further application of E-CPA-CNPs. Next, the reticuloendothelial system evasion features were analyzed in RAW264.7 macrophages and Sprague-Dawley rats. Compared with bare CPA-CNPs, erythrocyte-anchored CNPs significantly decreased cellular uptake in immune cells and prolonged circulation time in vivo. Notably, the erythrocyte-anchoring strategy enabled CNPs to be delivered and accumulated in the lungs (up to 6-fold). In the ALI mouse model, E-CPA-CNPs attenuated the progression of ALI by inhibiting inflammatory responses. Overall, our results demonstrate the outstanding advantages of erythrocyte-anchored CPA-CNPs in improving the pharmacokinetics and bioavailability of CPA, which offers great promise for a lung-targeted drug delivery system for the effective treatment of ALI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Platelets in the NETworks interweaving inflammation and thrombosis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/35979369/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/35979369/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Platelets are well characterized for their indispensable role in primary hemostasis to control hemorrhage. Research over the past years has provided a substantial body of evidence demonstrating that platelets also participate in host innate immunity. The surface expression of pattern recognition receptors, such as TLR2 and TLR4, provides platelets with the ability to sense bacterial products in their environment. Platelet α-granules contain microbicidal proteins, chemokines and growth factors, which upon release may directly engage pathogens and/or contribute to inflammatory signaling. Additionally, platelet interactions with neutrophils enhance neutrophil activation and are often crucial to induce a sufficient immune response. In particular, platelets can activate neutrophils to form neutrophil extracellular traps (NETs). This specific neutrophil effector function is characterized by neutrophils expelling chromatin fibres decorated with histones and antimicrobial proteins into the extracellular space where they serve to trap and kill pathogens. Until now, the mechanisms and signaling pathways between platelets and neutrophils inducing NET formation are still not fully characterized. NETs were also detected in thrombotic lesions in several disease backgrounds, pointing towards a role as an interface between neutrophils, platelets and thrombosis, also known as immunothrombosis. The negatively charged DNA within NETs provides a procoagulant surface, and in particular NET-derived proteins may directly activate platelets. In light of the current COVID-19 pandemic, the topic of immunothrombosis has become more relevant than ever, as a majority of COVID-19 patients display thrombi in the lung capillaries and other vascular beds. Furthermore, NETs can be found in the lung and other tissues and are associated with an increased mortality. Here, virus infiltration may lead to a cytokine storm that potently activates neutrophils and leads to massive neutrophil infiltration into the lung and NET formation. The resulting NETs presumably activate platelets and coagulation factors, further contributing to the subsequent emergence of microthrombi in pulmonary capillaries. In this review, we will discuss the interplay between platelets and NETs and the potential of this alliance to influence the course of inflammatory diseases. A better understanding of the underlying molecular mechanisms and the identification of treatment targets is of utmost importance to increase patients&amp;rsquo; survival and improve the clinical outcome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Platelet extracellular vesicles and the secretory interactome join forces in health and disease</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/35899405/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/35899405/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Extracellular vesicles (EVs) are small membrane-bound vesicles released by cells under various conditions. They are found in the extracellular milieu in all biological fluids. As the concentrations, contents, and origin of EVs can change during inflammation, the assessment of EVs can be used as a proxy of cellular activation. Here, we review the literature regarding EVs, more particularly those released by platelets and their mother cells, the megakaryocytes. Their cargo includes cytokines, growth factors, organelles (mitochondria and proteasomes), nucleic acids (messenger and non-coding RNA), transcription factors, and autoantigens. EVs may thus contribute to intercellular communication by facilitating exchange of material between cells. EVs also interact with other molecules secreted by cells. In autoimmune diseases, EVs are associated with antibodies secreted by B cells. By definition, EVs necessarily comprise a phospholipid moiety, which is thus the target of secreted phospholipases also abundantly expressed in the extracellular milieu. We discuss how platelet-derived EVs, which represent the majority of the circulating EVs, may contribute to immunity through the activity of their cargo or in combination with the secretory interactome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MASP-2 and MASP-3 inhibitors block complement activation, inflammation, and microvascular stasis in a murine model of vaso-occlusion in sickle cell disease</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35878790/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35878790/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Patients with sickle cell disease (SCD) have ongoing hemolysis that promotes endothelial injury, complement activation, inflammation, vaso-occlusion, ischemia-reperfusion pathophysiology, and pain. Complement activation markers are increased in SCD in steady-state and further increased during vaso-occlusive crisis (VOC). However, the mechanisms driving complement activation in SCD have not been completely elucidated. Ischemia-reperfusion and heme released from hemoglobin during hemolysis, events that characterize SCD pathophysiology, can activate the lectin pathway (LP) and alternative pathway (AP), respectively. Here we evaluated the role of LP and AP in Townes sickle (SS) mice using inhibitory monoclonal antibodies (mAb) to mannose binding lectin (MBL)-associated serine protease (MASP)-2 or MASP-3, respectively. Townes SS mice were pretreated with MASP-2 mAb, MASP-3 mAb, isotype control mAb, or PBS before they were challenged with hypoxia-reoxygenation or hemoglobin. Pretreatment of SS mice with MASP-2 or MASP-3 mAb, markedly reduced Bb fragments, C4d and C5a in plasma and complement deposition in the liver, kidneys, and lungs collected 4 hours after challenge compared to control mAb-treated mice. Consistent with complement inhibition, hepatic inflammation markers NF-ĸB phospho-p65, VCAM-1, ICAM-1, and E-selectin were significantly reduced in SS mice pretreated with MASP-2 or MASP-3 mAb. Importantly, MASP-2 or MASP-3 mAb pretreatment significantly inhibited microvascular stasis (vaso-occlusion) induced by hypoxia-reoxygenation or hemoglobin. These studies suggest that the LP and the AP are both playing a role in promoting inflammation and vaso-occlusion in SCD. Inhibiting complement activation via the LP or the AP might inhibit inflammation and prevent VOC in SCD patients.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extracellular Histones Trigger Disseminated Intravascular Coagulation by Lytic Cell Death</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35743244/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35743244/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Histones are cationic nuclear proteins that are essential for the structure and functions of eukaryotic chromatin. However, extracellular histones trigger inflammatory responses and contribute to death in sepsis by unknown mechanisms. We recently reported that inflammasome activation and pyroptosis trigger coagulation activation through a tissue-factor (TF)-dependent mechanism. We used a combination of various deficient mice to elucidate the molecular mechanism of histone-induced coagulation. We showed that histones trigger coagulation activation in vivo, as evidenced by coagulation parameters and fibrin deposition in tissues. However, histone-induced coagulopathy was neither dependent on intracellular inflammasome pathways involving caspase 1/11 and gasdermin D (GSDMD), nor on cell surface receptor TLR2- and TLR4-mediated host immune response, as the deficiency of these genes in mice did not protect against histone-induced coagulopathy. The incubation of histones with macrophages induced lytic cell death and phosphatidylserine (PS) exposure, which is required for TF activity, a key initiator of coagulation. The neutralization of TF diminished the histone-induced coagulation. Our findings revealed lytic cell death as a novel mechanism of histone-induced coagulation activation and thrombosis.
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Circulating tissue factor-positive extracellular vesicles and their association with thrombosis in different diseases</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/35708588/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/35708588/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tissue factor (TF) is a procoagulant protein released from activated host cells, such as monocytes, and tumor cells on extracellular vesicles (EVs). TF + EVs are observed in the circulation of patients with various types of diseases. In this review, we will summarize the association between TF + EVs and activation of coagulation and survival in different types of diseases, including cancer, sepsis, and infections with different viruses, such as human immunodeficiency virus (HIV), influenza A virus (IAV), and severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 (SARS-CoV-2). We will also discuss the source of TF + EVs in various diseases. EVTF activity is associated with thrombosis in pancreatic cancer patients and coronavirus disease 2019 patients (COVID-19) and with disseminated intravascular coagulation in cancer patients. EVTF activity is also associated with worse survival in patients with cancer and COVID-19. Monocytes are the major sources of TF + EVs in sepsis, and viral infections, such as HIV, Ebola virus, and SARS-CoV-2. In contrast, alveolar epithelial cells are the major source of TF + EVs in bronchoalveolar lavage fluid in COVID-19 and influenza A patients. These studies indicate that EVTF activity could be used as a biomarker to identify patients that have an increased risk of coagulopathy and mortality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spatiotemporal distribution of cellular injury and leukocytes during the progression of ventilator-induced lung injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35700201/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35700201/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Supportive mechanical ventilation is a necessary lifesaving treatment for acute respiratory distress syndrome (ARDS). This intervention often leads to injury exacerbation by ventilator-induced lung injury (VILI). Patterns of injury in ARDS and VILI are recognized to be heterogeneous; however, quantification of these injury distributions remains incomplete. Developing a more detailed understanding of injury heterogeneity, particularly how it varies in space and time, can help elucidate the mechanisms of VILI pathogenesis. Ultimately, this knowledge can be used to develop protective ventilation strategies that slow disease progression. To expand existing knowledge of VILI heterogeneity, we document the spatial evolution of cellular injury distribution and leukocyte infiltration, on the micro- and macroscales, during protective and injurious mechanical ventilation. We ventilated naïve mice using either high inspiratory pressure and zero positive end-expiratory pressure ventilation or low tidal volume with positive end-expiratory pressure. Distributions of cellular injury, identified with propidium iodide staining, were microscopically analyzed at three levels of injury severity. Cellular injury initiated in diffuse, quasi-random patterns, and progressed through expansion of high-density regions of injured cells termed &amp;ldquo;injury clusters.&amp;rdquo; The density profile of the expanding injury regions suggests that stress shielding occurs, protecting the already injured regions from further damage. Spatial distribution of leukocytes did not correlate with that of cellular injury or ventilation-induced changes in lung function. These results suggest that protective ventilation protocols should protect the interface between healthy and injured regions to stymie injury propagation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Caspase-4/11 exacerbates disease severity in SARS-CoV-2 infection by promoting inflammation and immunothrombosis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35588457/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35588457/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Significance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We report the discovery of fundamental roles for the noncanonical inflammasome molecule Caspase-4/11 in promoting pathological inflammatory and prothrombotic pathways in severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 (SARS–CoV-2) infections. Our work demonstrates that Caspase-11 has a broader role in immune responses beyond its previously appreciated effects in bacterial infections. Further, we show that Caspase-11–deficient mice infected with SARS–CoV-2 fare significantly better in terms of overall illness, lung inflammation, and thrombosis than wild-type (WT) mice, thus implicating Caspase-11 as a new therapeutic target for preventing or treating COVID-19.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 (SARS–CoV-2) is a worldwide health concern, and new treatment strategies are needed. Targeting inflammatory innate immunity pathways holds therapeutic promise, but effective molecular targets remain elusive. Here, we show that human caspase-4 (CASP4) and its mouse homolog, caspase-11 (CASP11), are up-regulated in SARS–CoV-2 infections and that CASP4 expression correlates with severity of SARS–CoV-2 infection in humans. SARS–CoV-2–infected &lt;em&gt;Casp11&lt;sup&gt;−/−&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; mice were protected from severe weight loss and lung pathology, including blood vessel damage, compared to wild-type (WT) mice and mice lacking the caspase downstream effector gasdermin-D (&lt;em&gt;Gsdmd&lt;sup&gt;−/−&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt;). Notably, viral titers were similar regardless of CASP11 knockout. Global transcriptomics of SARS–CoV-2–infected WT, &lt;em&gt;Casp11&lt;sup&gt;−/−&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Gsdmd&lt;sup&gt;−/−&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; lungs identified restrained expression of inflammatory molecules and altered neutrophil gene signatures in &lt;em&gt;Casp11&lt;sup&gt;−/−&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; mice. We confirmed that protein levels of inflammatory mediators interleukin (IL)-1β, IL-6, and CXCL1, as well as neutrophil functions, were reduced in &lt;em&gt;Casp11&lt;sup&gt;−/−&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; lungs. Additionally, &lt;em&gt;Casp11&lt;sup&gt;−/−&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; lungs accumulated less von Willebrand factor, a marker for endothelial damage, but expressed more Kruppel-Like Factor 2, a transcription factor that maintains vascular integrity. Overall, our results demonstrate that CASP4/11 promotes detrimental SARS–CoV-2–induced inflammation and coagulopathy, largely independently of GSDMD, identifying CASP4/11 as a promising drug target for treatment and prevention of severe COVID-19.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sepsis promotes splenic production of a protective platelet pool with high CD40 ligand expression</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35192546/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35192546/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Platelets have a wide range of functions including critical roles in hemostasis, thrombosis, and immunity. We hypothesized that during acute inflammation, such as in life-threatening sepsis, there are fundamental changes in the sites of platelet production and phenotypes of resultant platelets. Here, we showed during sepsis that the spleen was a major site of megakaryopoiesis and platelet production. Sepsis provoked an adrenergic-dependent mobilization of megakaryocyte-erythrocyte progenitors (MEPs) from the bone marrow to the spleen, where IL-3 induced their differentiation into megakaryocytes (MKs). In the spleen, immune-skewed MKs produced a CD40 ligandhi platelet population with potent immunomodulatory functions. Transfusions of post-sepsis platelets enriched from splenic production enhanced immune responses and reduced overall mortality in sepsis-challenged animals. These findings identify a spleen-derived protective platelet population that may be broadly immunomodulatory in acute inflammatory states such as sepsis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mesopore Controls the Responses of Blood Clot-Immune Complex via Modulating Fibrin Network</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34821070/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34821070/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Formation of blood clots, particularly the fibrin network and fibrin network-mediated early inflammatory responses, plays a critical role in determining the eventual tissue repair or regeneration following an injury. Owing to the potential role of fibrin network in mediating clot-immune responses, it is of great importance to determine whether clot-immune responses can be regulated via modulating the parameters of fibrin network. Since the diameter of D-terminal of a fibrinogen molecule is 9 nm, four different pore sizes (2, 8, 14, and 20 nm) are rationally selected to design mesoporous silica to control the fibrinogen adsorption and modulate the subsequent fibrin formation process. The fiber becomes thinner and the contact area with macrophages decreases when the pore diameters of mesoporous silica are greater than 9 nm. Importantly, these thinner fibers grown in pores with diameters larger than 9 nm inhibit the M1-polorazation of macrophages and reduce the productions of pro-inflammatory cytokines and chemokines by macrophages. These thinner fibers reduce inflammation of macrophages through a potential signaling pathway of cell adhesion-cytoskeleton assembly-inflammatory responses. Thus, the successful regulation of the clot-immune responses via tuning of the mesoporous pore sizes indicates the feasibility of developing advanced clot-immune regulatory materials.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extracellular vesicles from human iPSCs enhance reconstitution capacity of cord blood-derived hematopoietic stem and progenitor cells</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34140648/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34140648/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cord blood (CB) represents a source of hematopoietic stem and progenitor cells (CB-HSPCs) for bone marrow (BM) reconstitution, but clinical CB application is limited in adult patients due to the insufficient number of CB-HSCPCs and the lack of effective ex vivo approaches to increase CB-HSPC functionality. Since human-induced pluripotent stem cells (hiPSCs) have been indicated as donor cells for bioactive extracellular vesicles (EVs) modulating properties of other cells, we are the first to employ hiPSC-derived EVs (hiPSC-EVs) to enhance the hematopoietic potential of CB-derived CD45dimLin-CD34+ cell fraction enriched in CB-HSPCs. We demonstrated that hiPSC-EVs improved functional properties of CB-HSPCs critical for their hematopoietic capacity including metabolic, hematopoietic and clonogenic potential as well as survival, chemotactic response to stromal cell-derived factor 1 and adhesion to the model components of hematopoietic niche in vitro. Moreover, hiPSC-EVs enhanced homing and engraftment of CB-HSPCs in vivo. This phenomenon might be related to activation of signaling pathways in CB-HSPCs following hiPSC-EV treatment, as shown on both gene expression and the protein kinases activity levels. In conclusion, hiPSC-EVs might be used as ex vivo modulators of CB-HSPCs capacity to enhance their functional properties and augment future practical applications of CB-derived cells in BM reconstitution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Delivering Antisense Oligonucleotides across the Blood-Brain Barrier by Tumor Cell-Derived Small Apoptotic Bodies</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34258157/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34258157/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The blood-brain barrier (BBB) is the most restrictive and complicated barrier that keeps most biomolecules and drugs from the brain. An efficient brain delivery strategy is urgently needed for the treatment of brain diseases. Based on the studies of brain-targeting extracellular vesicles (EVs), the potential of using small apoptotic bodies (sABs) from brain metastatic cancer cells for brain-targeting drug delivery is explored. It is found that anti-TNF-α antisense oligonucleotide (ASO) combined with cationic konjac glucomannan (cKGM) can be successfully loaded into sABs via a transfection/apoptosis induction process and that the sABs generated by B16F10 cells have an extraordinarily high brain delivery efficiency. Further studies suggest that ASO-loaded sABs (sCABs) are transcytosed by b. End3 (brain microvascular endothelial cells, BMECs) to penetrate the BBB, which is mediated by CD44v6, and eventually taken up by microglial cells in the brain. In a Parkinson&amp;rsquo;s disease (PD) mouse model, sCABs dramatically ameliorate PD symptoms via the anti-inflammatory effect of ASO. This study suggests that sABs from brain metastatic cancer cells are excellent carriers for brain-targeted delivery, as they have not only an extraordinary delivery efficiency but also a much higher scale-up production potential than other EVs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Perivascular Macrophages Regulate Blood Flow Following Tissue Damage</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33878889/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33878889/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rationale:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ischemic injuries remain a leading cause of mortality and morbidity worldwide, and restoration of functional blood perfusion is vital to limit tissue damage and support healing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Objective:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To reveal a novel role of macrophages in reestablishment of functional tissue perfusion following ischemic injury that can be targeted to improve tissue restoration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Methods and Results:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using intravital microscopy of ischemic hindlimb muscle in mice, and confocal microscopy of human tissues from amputated legs, we found that macrophages accumulated perivascularly in ischemic muscles, where they expressed high levels of iNOS (inducible nitric oxide [NO] synthase). Genetic depletion of iNOS specifically in macrophages (Cx3cr1-CreERT2;Nos2&lt;sup&gt;fl/fl&lt;/sup&gt; or LysM-Cre;Nos2&lt;sup&gt;fl/fl&lt;/sup&gt;) did not affect vascular architecture but highly compromised blood flow regulation in ischemic but not healthy muscle, which resulted in aggravated ischemic damage. Thus, the ability to upregulate blood flow was shifted from eNOS (endothelial)-dependence in healthy muscles to completely rely on macrophage-derived iNOS during ischemia. Macrophages in ischemic muscles expressed high levels of CXCR4 (C-X-C chemokine receptor type 4) and CCR2 (C-C chemokine receptor type 2), and local overexpression by DNA plasmids encoding the corresponding chemokines CXCL12 (stromal-derived factor 1) or CCL2 (chemokine [C-C motif] ligand 2) increased macrophage numbers, while CXCL12 but not CCL2 induced their perivascular positioning. As a result, CXCL12-overexpression increased the number of perfused blood vessels in the ischemic muscles, improved functional muscle perfusion in a macrophage-iNOS-dependent manner, and ultimately restored limb function.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This study establishes a new function for macrophages during tissue repair, as they regulate blood flow through the release of iNOS-produced NO. Further, we demonstrate that macrophages can be therapeutically targeted to improve blood flow regulation and functional recovery of ischemic tissues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Heparin prevents caspase-11-dependent septic lethality independent of anticoagulant properties</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33561388/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33561388/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Heparin, a mammalian polysaccharide, is a widely used anticoagulant medicine to treat thrombotic disorders. It is also known to improve outcomes in sepsis, a leading cause of mortality resulted from infection-induced immune dysfunction. Whereas it is relatively clear how heparin exerts its anticoagulant effect, the immunomodulatory mechanisms enabled by heparin remain enigmatic. Here, we show that heparin prevented caspase-11-dependent immune responses and lethality in sepsis independent of its anticoagulant properties. Heparin or a chemically modified form of heparin without anticoagulant function inhibited the alarmin HMGB1-lipopolysaccharide (LPS) interaction and prevented the macrophage glycocalyx degradation by heparanase. These events blocked the cytosolic delivery of LPS in macrophages and the activation of caspase-11, a cytosolic LPS receptor that mediates lethality in sepsis. Survival was higher in septic patients treated with heparin than those without heparin treatment. The identification of this previously unrecognized heparin function establishes a link between innate immune responses and coagulation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>APOE4 leads to blood-brain barrier dysfunction predicting cognitive decline</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32376954/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32376954/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vascular contributions to dementia and Alzheimer&amp;rsquo;s disease are increasingly recognized. Recent studies have suggested that breakdown of the blood-brain barrier (BBB) is an early biomarker of human cognitive dysfunction, including the early clinical stages of Alzheimer&amp;rsquo;s disease. The E4 variant of apolipoprotein E (&lt;em&gt;APOE4&lt;/em&gt;), the main susceptibility gene for Alzheimer&amp;rsquo;s disease, leads to accelerated breakdown of the BBB and degeneration of brain capillary pericytes, which maintain BBB integrity. It is unclear, however, whether the cerebrovascular effects of &lt;em&gt;APOE4&lt;/em&gt; contribute to cognitive impairment. Here we show that individuals bearing &lt;em&gt;APOE4&lt;/em&gt; (with the ε3/ε4 or ε4/ε4 alleles) are distinguished from those without &lt;em&gt;APOE4&lt;/em&gt; (ε3/ε3) by breakdown of the BBB in the hippocampus and medial temporal lobe. This finding is apparent in cognitively unimpaired &lt;em&gt;APOE4&lt;/em&gt; carriers and more severe in those with cognitive impairment, but is not related to amyloid-β or tau pathology measured in cerebrospinal fluid or by positron emission tomography23. High baseline levels of the BBB pericyte injury biomarker soluble PDGFRβ7,8 in the cerebrospinal fluid predicted future cognitive decline in &lt;em&gt;APOE4&lt;/em&gt; carriers but not in non-carriers, even after controlling for amyloid-β and tau status, and were correlated with increased activity of the BBB-degrading cyclophilin A-matrix metalloproteinase-9 pathway19 in cerebrospinal fluid. Our findings suggest that breakdown of the BBB contributes to &lt;em&gt;APOE4&lt;/em&gt;-associated cognitive decline independently of Alzheimer&amp;rsquo;s disease pathology, and might be a therapeutic target in &lt;em&gt;APOE4&lt;/em&gt; carriers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The role of type 1 interferons in coagulation induced by gram-negative bacteria</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32016282/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32016282/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bacterial infection not only stimulates innate immune responses but also activates coagulation cascades. Overactivation of the coagulation system in bacterial sepsis leads to disseminated intravascular coagulation (DIC), a life-threatening condition. However, the mechanisms by which bacterial infection activates the coagulation cascade are not fully understood. Here we show that type 1 interferons (IFNs), a widely expressed family of cytokines that orchestrate innate antiviral and antibacterial immunity, mediate bacterial infection-induced DIC by amplifying the release of high-mobility group box 1 (HMGB1) into the bloodstream. Inhibition of the expression of type 1 IFNs and disruption of their receptor IFN-α/βR or downstream effector (eg, HMGB1) uniformly decreased gram-negative bacteria-induced DIC. Mechanistically, extracellular HMGB1 markedly increased the procoagulant activity of tissue factor by promoting the externalization of phosphatidylserine to the outer cell surface, where phosphatidylserine assembles a complex of cofactor-proteases of the coagulation cascades. These findings not only provide novel insights into the link between innate immune responses and coagulation, but they also open a new avenue for developing novel therapeutic strategies to prevent DIC in sepsis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A genome-wide transcriptomic analysis of protein-coding genes in human blood cells</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/31857451/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/31857451/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blood is the predominant source for molecular analyses in humans, both in clinical and research settings. It is the target for many therapeutic strategies, emphasizing the need for comprehensive molecular maps of the cells constituting human blood. In this study, we performed a genome-wide transcriptomic analysis of protein-coding genes in sorted blood immune cell populations to characterize the expression levels of each individual gene across the blood cell types. All data are presented in an interactive, open-access Blood Atlas as part of the Human Protein Atlas and are integrated with expression profiles across all major tissues to provide spatial classification of all protein-coding genes. This allows for a genome-wide exploration of the expression profiles across human immune cell populations and all major human tissues and organs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bacterial Endotoxin Activates the Coagulation Cascade through Gasdermin D-Dependent Phosphatidylserine Exposure</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/31836429/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/31836429/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deletion of caspase-11 prevents disseminated intravascular coagulation (DIC) in sepsis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deletion of GSDMD prevents caspase-11- and TF-mediated DIC in endotoxemia&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GSDMD deficiency inhibits endotoxin-induced TF activation by reducing PS exposure&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Activation of GSDMD by caspase-11 triggers Ca2+-dependent PS exposure through TMEM16F&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Summary&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Excessive activation of the coagulation system leads to life-threatening disseminated intravascular coagulation (DIC). Here, we examined the mechanisms underlying the activation of coagulation by lipopolysaccharide (LPS), the major cell-wall component of Gram-negative bacteria. We found that caspase-11, a cytosolic LPS receptor, activated the coagulation cascade. Caspase-11 enhanced the activation of tissue factor (TF), an initiator of coagulation, through triggering the formation of gasdermin D (GSDMD) pores and subsequent phosphatidylserine exposure, in a manner independent of cell death. GSDMD pores mediated calcium influx, which induced phosphatidylserine exposure through transmembrane protein 16F, a calcium-dependent phospholipid scramblase. Deletion of &lt;em&gt;Casp11&lt;/em&gt;, ablation of &lt;em&gt;Gsdmd&lt;/em&gt;, or neutralization of phosphatidylserine or TF prevented LPS-induced DIC. In septic patients, plasma concentrations of interleukin (IL)-1α and IL-1β, biomarkers of GSDMD activation, correlated with phosphatidylserine exposure in peripheral leukocytes and DIC scores. Our findings mechanistically link immune recognition of LPS to coagulation, with implications for the treatment of DIC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
