<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Lentivirus | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/lentivirus/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/lentivirus/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Lentivirus</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Lentivirus</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/lentivirus/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Engineered cell entry links receptor biology with single-cell genomics</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36516854/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36516854/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ENTER displays ligands, delivers payloads, and records receptor specificity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ENTER enables antigen-specific expansion or depletion of T or B cells&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ENTER-seq maps TCR specificity, clonality, and cell state in single cells&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ENTER-seq of patient sample decodes antiviral T cell memory&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cells communicate with each other via receptor-ligand interactions. Here, we describe lentiviral-mediated cell entry by engineered receptor-ligand interaction (ENTER) to display ligand proteins, deliver payloads, and record receptor specificity. We optimize ENTER to decode interactions between T cell receptor (TCR)-MHC peptides, antibody-antigen, and other receptor-ligand pairs. A viral presentation strategy allows ENTER to capture interactions between B cell receptor and any antigen. We engineer ENTER to deliver genetic payloads to antigen-specific T or B cells to selectively modulate cellular behavior in mixed populations. Single-cell readout of ENTER by RNA sequencing (ENTER-seq) enables multiplexed enumeration of antigen specificities, TCR clonality, cell type, and states of individual T cells. ENTER-seq of CMV-seropositive patient blood samples reveals the viral epitopes that drive effector memory T cell differentiation and inter-clonal vs. intra-clonal phenotypic diversity targeting the same epitope. ENTER technology enables systematic discovery of receptor specificity, linkage to cell fates, and antigen-specific cargo delivery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hypoxia-inducible lentiviral gene expression in engineered human macrophages</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35728871/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35728871/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Human immune cells, including monocyte-derived macrophages, can be engineered to deliver proinflammatory cytokines, bispecific antibodies, and chimeric antigen receptors to support immune responses in different disease settings. When gene expression is regulated by constitutively active promoters, lentiviral payload gene expression is unregulated, and can result in potentially toxic quantities of proteins. Regulated delivery of lentivirally encoded proteins may allow localized or conditional therapeutic protein expression to support safe delivery of adoptively transferred, genetically modified cells with reduced capacity for systemic toxicities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; In this study, we engineered human macrophages to express genes regulated by hypoxia responsive elements included in the lentiviral promoter region to drive conditional lentiviral gene expression only under hypoxic conditions. We tested transduced macrophages cultured in hypoxic conditions for the transient induced expression of reporter genes and the secreted cytokine, interleukin-12. Expression of hypoxia-regulated genes was investigated both transcriptionally and translationally, and in the presence of human tumor cells in a slice culture system. Finally, hypoxia-regulated gene expression was evaluated in a subcutaneous humanized-mouse cancer model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; Engineered macrophages were shown to conditionally and tranisently express lentivirally encoded gene protein products, including IL-12 in hypoxic conditions &lt;em&gt;in vitro&lt;/em&gt;. On return to normoxic conditions, lentiviral payload expression returned to basal levels. Reporter genes under the control of hypoxia response elements were upregulated under hypoxic conditions in the presence of human colorectal carcinoma cells and in the hypoxic xenograft model of glioblastoma, suggesting utility for systemic engineered cell delivery capable of localized gene delivery in cancer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; Macrophages engineered to express hypoxia-regulated payloads have the potential to be administered systemically and conditionally express proteins in tissues with hypoxic conditions. In contrast to immune cells that function or survive poorly in hypoxic conditions, macrophages maintain a proinflammatory phenotype that may support continued gene and protein expression when regulated by conditional hypoxia responsive elements and naturally traffic to hypoxic microenvironments, making them ideal vehicles for therapeutic payloads to hypoxic tissues, such as solid tumors. With the ability to fine-tune delivery of potent proteins in response to endogenous microenvironments, macrophage-based cellular therapies may therefore be designed for different disease settings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>B7-1 mediates podocyte injury and glomerulosclerosis through communication with Hsp90ab1-LRP5-β-catenin pathway</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35710882/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35710882/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Podocyte injury is a hallmark of glomerular diseases; however, the underlying mechanisms remain unclear. B7-1 is increased in injured podocytes, but its intrinsic role is controversial. The clinical data here revealed the intimate correlation of urinary B7-1 with severity of glomerular injury. Through transcriptomic and biological assays in B7-1 transgenic and adriamycin nephropathy models, we identified B7-1 is a key mediator in podocyte injury and glomerulosclerosis through a series of signal transmission to β-catenin. Using LC-MS/MS, Hsp90ab1, a conserved molecular chaperone, was distinguished to be an anchor for transmitting signals from B7-1 to β-catenin. Molecular docking and subsequent mutant analysis further identified the residue K69 in the N terminal domain of Hsp90ab1 was the key binding site for B7-1 to activate LRP5/β-catenin pathway. The interaction and biological functions of B7-1-Hsp90ab1-LRP5 complex were further demonstrated in vitro and in vivo. We also found B7-1 is a novel downstream target of β-catenin. Our results indicate an intercrossed network of B7-1, which collectively induces podocyte injury and glomerulosclerosis. Our study provides an important clue to improve the therapeutic strategies to target B7-1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mesenchymal Stem Cell-Derived Extracellular Vesicles with High PD-L1 Expression for Autoimmune Diseases Treatment</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34613627/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34613627/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Autoimmune diseases are the third most common disease influencing the quality of life of many patients. Here, a programmed cell death-ligand 1 + (PD-L1) mesenchymal stem cell (MSC) derived extracellular vesicles (MSC-sEVs-PD-L1) using lentivirus-mediated gene transfection technology is developed for reconfiguration of the local immune microenvironment of affected tissue in autoimmune diseases. MSC-sEVs-PD-L1 exhibits an impressive ability to regulate various activated immune cells to an immunosuppressed state in vitro. More importantly, in dextran sulfate sodium-induced ulcerative colitis (UC) and imiquimod-induced psoriasis mouse models, a significantly high accumulation of MSC-sEVs-PD-L1 is observed in the inflamed tissues compared to the PD-L1+ MSCs. Therapeutic efficiency in both UC and psoriasis mouse disease models is demonstrated using MSC-sEVs-PD-L1 to reshape the inflammatory ecosystem in the local immune context. A technology is developed using MSC-sEVs-PD-L1 as a natural delivery platform for autoimmune diseases treatment with high clinical potential.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Engineered MARCH8-Resistant Vesicular Stomatitis Virus Glycoprotein Enhances Lentiviral Vector Transduction</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33678011/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33678011/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lentiviral vectors are one of the most commonly used viral delivery systems for gene therapy. Vesicular stomatitis virus-G envelope glycoprotein (VSV G)-pseudotyped lentiviral vectors have been widely used in clinical studies for treatment of virus infections and genetic deficient diseases. However, the efficiency of lentiviral vector transduction has been long recognized as a limiting factor in clinical gene therapy application, especially in transducing hematopoietic stem cells. MARCH8 (membrane-associated RING-CH 8), an E3 ubiquitin ligase, has been reported to target and downregulate VSV G. Results in this study show that MARCH8 induces ubiquitination and lysosome degradation of VSV G, and knockout of MARCH8 in virus-producing cells increases lentiviral vector transduction by elevating the level of VSV G protein. We then engineered VSV G mutant that has the lysine residues in the cytoplasmic domain substituted for arginine, and showed that this G mutant resists degradation by MARCH8, and allows the enhancement of transduction efficiency of lentiviral vector particles than the parental VSV G protein. This engineered VSV G mutant thus further advances the lentiviral vector system as a powerful tool in gene therapy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
