<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Transcriptomics | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/transcriptomics/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/transcriptomics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Transcriptomics</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Transcriptomics</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/transcriptomics/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transcriptomic profiling reveals sex-specific molecular signatures of adipose endothelial cells under obesogenic conditions</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36624843/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36624843/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Female mice display greater adipose angiogenesis and maintain healthier adipose tissue than do males upon high-fat diet feeding. Through transcriptome analysis of endothelial cells (EC) from the white adipose tissue of male and female mice high-fat-fed for 7 weeks, we found that adipose EC exhibited pronouncedly sex-distinct transcriptomes. Genes upregulated in female adipose EC were associated with proliferation, oxidative phosphorylation, and chromatin remodeling contrasting the dominant enrichment for genes related to inflammation and a senescence-associated secretory of male EC. Similar sex-biased phenotypes of adipose EC were detectable in a dataset of aged EC. The highly proliferative phenotype of female EC was observed also in culture conditions. In turn, male EC displayed greater inflammatory potential than female EC in culture, based on basal and tumor necrosis factor alpha-stimulated patterns of gene expression. Our study provides insights into molecular programs that distinguish male and female EC responses to pathophysiological conditions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Time Series Transcriptomic Analysis of Bronchoalveolar Lavage Cells from Piglets Infected with Virulent or Low-Virulent Porcine Reproductive and Respiratory Syndrome Virus 1</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34851149/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34851149/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Porcine reproductive and respiratory syndrome virus (PRRSV) has evolved to escape the immune surveillance for a survival advantage leading to a strong modulation of host&amp;rsquo;s immune responses and favoring secondary bacterial infections. However, limited data are available on how the immunological and transcriptional responses elicited by virulent and low-virulent PRRSV-1 strains are comparable and how they are conserved during the infection. To explore the kinetic transcriptional signature associated with the modulation of host immune response at lung level, a time-series transcriptomic analysis was performed in bronchoalveolar lavage cells upon experimental in vivo infection with two PRRSV-1 strains of different virulence, virulent subtype 3 Lena strain or the low-virulent subtype 1 3249 strain. The time-series analysis revealed overlapping patterns of dysregulated genes enriched in T-cell signaling pathways among both virulent and low-virulent strains, highlighting an upregulation of co-stimulatory and co-inhibitory immune checkpoints that were disclosed as Hub genes. On the other hand, virulent Lena infection induced an early and more marked &amp;ldquo;negative regulation of immune system process&amp;rdquo; with an overexpression of co-inhibitory receptors genes related to T-cell and NK cell functions, in association with more severe lung lesion, lung viral load, and BAL cell kinetics. These results underline a complex network of molecular mechanisms governing PRRSV-1 immunopathogenesis at lung level, revealing a pivotal role of co-inhibitory and co-stimulatory immune checkpoints in the pulmonary disease, which may have an impact on T-cell activation and related pathways. These immune checkpoints, together with the regulation of cytokine-signaling pathways, modulated in a virulence-dependent fashion, orchestrate an interplay among pro- and anti-inflammatory responses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Importance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Porcine reproductive and respiratory syndrome virus (PRRSV) is one of the major threats to swine health and global production, causing substantial economic losses. We explore the mechanisms involved in the modulation of host immune response at lung level performing a time-series transcriptomic analysis upon experimental infection with two PRRSV-1 strains of different virulence. A complex network of molecular mechanisms was revealed to control the immunopathogenesis of PRRSV-1 infection, highlighting an interplay among pro- and anti-inflammatory responses as a potential mechanism to restrict inflammation-induced lung injury. Moreover, a pivotal role of co-inhibitory and co-stimulatory immune checkpoints was evidenced, which may lead to progressive dysfunction of T cells, impairing viral clearance and leading to persistent infection, favoring as well secondary bacterial infections or viral rebound. However, further studies should be conducted to evaluate the functional role of immune checkpoints in advanced stages of PRRSV infection and explore a possible T-cell exhaustion state.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
