<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Circadian Rhythm | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/circadian-rhythm/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/circadian-rhythm/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Circadian Rhythm</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Circadian Rhythm</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/circadian-rhythm/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nucleus-exported CLOCK acetylates PRPS to promote de novo nucleotide synthesis and liver tumour growth</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36646788/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36646788/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Impairment of the circadian clock is linked to cancer development. However, whether the circadian clock is modulated by oncogenic receptor tyrosine kinases remains unclear. Here we demonstrated that receptor tyrosine kinase activation promotes CK2-mediated CLOCK S106 phosphorylation and subsequent disassembly of the CLOCK–BMAL1 dimer and suppression of the downstream gene expression in hepatocellular carcinoma (HCC) cells. In addition, CLOCK S106 phosphorylation exposes its nuclear export signal to bind Exportin1 for nuclear exportation. Cytosolic CLOCK acetylates PRPS1/2 K29 and blocks HSC70-mediated and lysosome-dependent PRPS1/2 degradation. Stabilized PRPS1/2 promote de novo nucleotide synthesis and HCC cell proliferation and liver tumour growth. Furthermore, CLOCK S106 phosphorylation and PRPS1/2 K29 acetylation are positively correlated in human HCC specimens and with HCC poor prognosis. These findings delineate a critical mechanism by which oncogenic signalling inhibits canonical CLOCK transcriptional activity and simultaneously confers CLOCK with instrumental moonlighting functions to promote nucleotide synthesis and tumour growth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Circadian regulator BMAL1::CLOCK promotes cell proliferation in hepatocellular carcinoma by controlling apoptosis and cell cycle</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36595671/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36595671/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hepatocellular carcinoma (HCC) remains a global health challenge whose incidence is growing worldwide. Previous evidence strongly supported the notion that the circadian clock controls physiological homeostasis of the liver and plays a key role in hepatocarcinogenesis. Despite the progress, cellular and molecular mechanisms underpinning this HCC-clock crosstalk remain unknown. Addressing this knowledge gap, we show here that although the human HCC cells Hep3B, HepG2, and Huh7 displayed variations in circadian rhythm profiles, all cells relied on the master circadian clock transcription factors, BMAL1 and CLOCK, for sustained cell growth. Down-regulating &lt;em&gt;Bmal1&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;Clock&lt;/em&gt; in the HCC cells induced apoptosis and arrested cell cycle at the G&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;/M phase. Mechanistically, we found that inhibiting &lt;em&gt;Bmal1&lt;/em&gt;/&lt;em&gt;Clock&lt;/em&gt; induced dysregulation of the cell cycle regulators &lt;em&gt;Wee1&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;p21&lt;/em&gt; which cooperatively contribute to tumor cell death. &lt;em&gt;Bmal1&lt;/em&gt;/&lt;em&gt;Clock&lt;/em&gt; knockdown caused downregulation of &lt;em&gt;Wee1&lt;/em&gt; that led to apoptosis activation and upregulation of &lt;em&gt;p21&lt;/em&gt; which arrested the cell cycle at the G&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;/M phase. Collectively, our results suggest that the circadian clock regulators BMAL1 and CLOCK promote HCC cell proliferation by controlling &lt;em&gt;Wee1&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;p21&lt;/em&gt; levels, thereby preventing apoptosis and cell cycle arrest. Our findings shed light on cellular impact of the clock proteins for maintaining HCC oncogenesis and provide proof-of-principle for developing cancer therapy based on modulation of the circadian clock.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ventilator-induced Lung Injury Is Modulated by the Circadian Clock</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36480958/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36480958/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rationale:&lt;/em&gt; Mechanical ventilation is life-saving but may evoke ventilator-induced lung injury.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Objectives:&lt;/em&gt; To explore how the circadian clock modulates severity of murine ventilator-induced lung injury via the core clock component BMAL1 in myeloid cells.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; Myeloid cell BMAL1-deficient (&lt;em&gt;LysM&lt;sup&gt;Bmal1-/-&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt;) or wild type control (&lt;em&gt;LysM&lt;sup&gt;Bmal1+/+&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt;) mice were subjected to 4 hours mechanical ventilation (34 mL/kg bodyweight) to induce lung injury. Ventilation was initiated at dawn or dusk, or in complete darkness (circadian time 0 or 12) to determine diurnal and circadian effects. Lung injury was quantified by lung function, pulmonary permeability, blood gas analysis, neutrophil recruitment, inflammatory markers and histology. Neutrophil activation and oxidative burst were analyzed ex vivo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Measurements and main results:&lt;/em&gt; In diurnal experiments, mice ventilated at dawn exhibited higher permeability and neutrophil recruitment compared to dusk. Experiments at circadian time showed deterioration of pulmonary function, worsening of oxygenation and increased mortality at circadian time 0 compared to circadian time 12. Wild type neutrophils isolated at dawn showed higher activation and ROS production compared to dusk, while these day-night differences were dampened in &lt;em&gt;LysM&lt;sup&gt;Bmal1-/-&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; neutrophils. In &lt;em&gt;LysM&lt;sup&gt;Bmal1-/-&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; mice, circadian variations in VILI severity were dampened and VILI-induced mortality at circadian time 0 was reduced compared with &lt;em&gt;LysM&lt;sup&gt;Bmal1+/+&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; mice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/em&gt; Inflammatory response and lung barrier dysfunction upon mechanical ventilation exhibit diurnal variations, regulated by the circadian clock. &lt;em&gt;LysM&lt;sup&gt;Bmal1-/-&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; mice are less susceptible to ventilation-induced pathology and lack circadian variation of severity compared with &lt;em&gt;LysM&lt;sup&gt;Bmal1+/+&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; mice. Our data suggest that the internal clock in myeloid cells is an important modulator of ventilator-induced lung injury.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dendritic cells direct circadian anti-tumor immune responses</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36470303/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36470303/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The process of cancer immunosurveillance is a mechanism of tumor suppression that can protect the host from cancer development throughout its lifetime1,2. Yet, it is unknown whether its effectiveness fluctuates over a single day. Here, we demonstrate that the initial time-of-day of tumor engraftment dictates ensuing tumor size across murine cancer models. Using immunodeficient mice and animals lacking lineage-specific circadian functions, we show that dendritic cells (DCs) and CD8&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T cells exert circadian anti-tumor functions that control melanoma volume. Specifically, we find that rhythmic trafficking of DCs to the tumor draining lymph node (dLN) governs a circadian response of tumor antigen-specific CD8&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T cells, which is dependent on circadian expression of the co-stimulatory molecule CD80. Consequently, cancer immunotherapy is more effective when synchronized with DC functions, shows circadian outcomes in mice and suggests similar effects in humans. These data demonstrate that circadian rhythms of anti-tumor immune components are not only critical for the control of tumor size but can also be exploited therapeutically.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Circadian clock-based therapeutics in chronic pulmonary diseases</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/36302705/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/36302705/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The circadian clock is the biochemical oscillator that orchestrates the observable circadian rhythms in physiology and behavior. Disruption of the circadian clock in the lungs during chronic pulmonary diseases is considered one of the key etiological risk factors that drive pathobiology. Preclinical studies support that pharmacological manipulation of the circadian clock is a conceivable approach for the development of novel clock-based therapeutics. Despite recent advances, no effort has been undertaken to integrate novel findings for the treatment and management of chronic lung diseases. We, therefore, recognize the need to discuss the candidate clock genes that can be potentially targeted for therapeutic intervention. Here, we aim to create the first roadmap that will advance the development of circadian- clock-based therapeutics that may provide better outcomes in treating chronic pulmonary diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Knockout of the Circadian Clock Protein PER1 (Period1) Exacerbates Hypertension and Increases Kidney Injury in Dahl Salt-Sensitive Rats</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36093781/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36093781/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Circadian rhythms play an essential role in physiological function. The molecular clock that underlies circadian physiological function consists of a core group of transcription factors, including the protein PER1 (Period1). Studies in mice show that PER1 plays a role in the regulation of blood pressure and renal sodium handling; however, the results are dependent on the strain being studied. Using male Dahl salt-sensitive (SS) rats with global knockout of PER1 (&lt;em&gt;SS&lt;sup&gt;Per1-/-&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt;), we aim to test the hypothesis that PER1 plays a key role in the regulation of salt-sensitive blood pressure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; The model was generated using CRISPR/Cas9 and was characterized using radiotelemetry and measures of renal function and circadian rhythm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;SS&lt;sup&gt;Per1-/-&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; rats had similar mean arterial pressure when fed a normal 0.4% NaCl diet but developed augmented hypertension after three weeks on a high-salt (4% NaCl) diet. Despite being maintained on a normal 12:12 light:dark cycle, &lt;em&gt;SS&lt;sup&gt;Per1-/-&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; rats exhibited desynchrony mean arterial pressure rhythms on a high-salt diet, as evidenced by increased variability in the time of peak mean arterial pressure. &lt;em&gt;SS&lt;sup&gt;Per1-/-&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; rats excrete less sodium after three weeks on the high-salt diet. Furthermore, &lt;em&gt;SS&lt;sup&gt;Per1-/-&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; rats exhibited decreased creatinine clearance, a measurement of renal function, as well as increased signs of kidney tissue damage. &lt;em&gt;SS&lt;sup&gt;Per1-/-&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; rats also exhibited higher plasma aldosterone levels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; Altogether, our findings demonstrate that loss of PER1 in Dahl SS rats causes an array of deleterious effects, including exacerbation of the development of salt-sensitive hypertension and renal damage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Disruption of the circadian clock drives Apc loss of heterozygosity to accelerate colorectal cancer</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35947664/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35947664/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An alarming rise in young onset colorectal cancer (CRC) has been reported; however, the underlying molecular mechanism remains undefined. Suspected risk factors of young onset CRC include environmental aspects, such as lifestyle and dietary factors, which are known to affect the circadian clock. We find that both genetic disruption and environmental disruption of the circadian clock accelerate &lt;em&gt;Apc&lt;/em&gt;-driven CRC pathogenesis in vivo. Using an intestinal organoid model, we demonstrate that clock disruption promotes transformation by driving &lt;em&gt;Apc&lt;/em&gt; loss of heterozygosity, which hyperactivates Wnt signaling. This up-regulates &lt;em&gt;c-Myc&lt;/em&gt;, a known Wnt target, which drives heightened glycolytic metabolism. Using patient-derived organoids, we show that circadian rhythms are lost in human tumors. Last, we identify that variance between core clock and Wnt pathway genes significantly predicts the survival of patients with CRC. Overall, our findings demonstrate a previously unidentified mechanistic link between clock disruption and CRC, which has important implications for young onset cancer prevention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In Vivo Imaging of Circadian NET Formation During Lung Injury by Four-Dimensional Intravital Microscopy</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35610434/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35610434/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Neutrophil extracellular traps (NETs) are toxic extracellular structures deployed by neutrophils in response to pathogens and sterile danger signals. NETs are circadian in nature as mouse and human neutrophils preferentially deploy them at night or early morning. Traditionally, NETs have been quantified using a plethora of methods including immunofluorescence and ELISA-based assays; however few options are available to visualize them in vivo. Here we describe a method to directly visualize and quantify NET formation and release in the microvasculature of the lung using intravital imaging in a model of acute lung injury. The method allows four-dimensional capture and quantification of NET formation dynamics over time and should be a useful resource for those interested in visualizing neutrophil responses &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comparative transcriptomics reveals circadian and pluripotency networks as two pillars of longevity regulation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35580607/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35580607/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Neg-MLS genes are involved in energy metabolism and inflammation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pos-MLS genes are involved in DNA repair, microtubule organization, and RNA transport&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Neg-MLS genes are controlled by the circadian network&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pos-MLS genes are controlled by pluripotency genes and upregulated during reprogramming&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Summary&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mammals differ more than 100-fold in maximum lifespan. Here, we conducted comparative transcriptomics on 26 species with diverse lifespans. We identified thousands of genes with expression levels negatively or positively correlated with a species’ maximum lifespan (Neg- or Pos-MLS genes). Neg-MLS genes are primarily involved in energy metabolism and inflammation. Pos-MLS genes show enrichment in DNA repair, microtubule organization, and RNA transport. Expression of Neg- and Pos-MLS genes is modulated by interventions, including mTOR and PI3K inhibition. Regulatory networks analysis showed that Neg-MLS genes are under circadian regulation possibly to avoid persistent high expression, whereas Pos-MLS genes are targets of master pluripotency regulators OCT4 and NANOG and are upregulated during somatic cell reprogramming. Pos-MLS genes are highly expressed during embryogenesis but significantly downregulated after birth. This work provides targets for anti-aging interventions by defining pathways correlating with longevity across mammals and uncovering circadian and pluripotency networks as central regulators of longevity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Circadian molecular clock disruption in chronic pulmonary diseases</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/35508604/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/35508604/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The circadian clock is the biochemical oscillator with a near 24-h period that is responsible for generating the circadian rhythms in peripheral organs including the lung. Mounting evidence suggests that circadian clock disruption during chronic lung diseases plays an essential role in augmented oxidative stress, inflammatory response, metabolic imbalances, hypoxia/hyperoxia, mucus secretion, dysregulated autophagy, and alters pulmonary function. Here, we review circadian clock disruption and discuss candidate clock genes that are altered at the transcriptional or translational level in chronic pulmonary diseases. This review aims to provide the current knowledge and understanding of the circadian molecular clock disruption in chronic pulmonary diseases which will further advance the development of novel clock-based therapeutics in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Circadian clock, diurnal glucose metabolic rhythm, and dawn phenomenon</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/35466006/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/35466006/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Autophagy is an intracellular self-digestion mechanism, by which cellular components are sorted into double-membrane autophagosomes and delivered to lysosomes for degradation. Cells use autophagy to dispose of wastes and eliminate hazards, while recycling nutrients and tuning metabolism in the process. Through these functions, autophagy promotes cell fitness, genome integrity, tissue homeostasis, and cell survival and growth under stress. Both autophagy upregulation and downregulation have been found in human cancers, suggesting a complex role in tumor development. Accumulating results from autophagy-deficient mice and mouse models of human cancers have demonstrated that autophagy generally suppresses tumor initiation, but promotes tumor progression, in a manner that is dependent on timing and context and modified by specific tumorigenic events. Given the role of autophagy in facilitating tumor growth, autophagy inhibition has gained wide attention as a potential anticancer therapy. Here, we summarize relevant genetic, preclinical, and clinical studies and discuss the multifaceted role of autophagy in cancer, as well as the prospects of autophagy inhibition for cancer therapy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Circadian regulation of cancer cell and tumor microenvironment crosstalk</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/34272133/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/34272133/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Circadian rhythms regulate a remarkable variety of physiologic functions in living organisms. Circadian disruption is associated with tumorigenesis and tumor progression through effects on cancer cell biological properties, including proliferation, DNA repair, apoptosis, metabolism, and stemness. Emerging evidence indicates that circadian clocks also play an influential role in the tumor microenvironment (TME). This review outlines recent discoveries on how cancer cell clock components (including circadian clock and clock genes/proteins) regulate TME biology and, reciprocally, how TME clock components affect tumor growth, metastasis, and therapeutic response. An improved understanding of how clock components regulate the symbiosis between cancer cells and the TME will inform the development of novel clock-oriented therapeutic strategies, including immunotherapy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Circadian rhythms and obesity: Timekeeping governs lipid metabolism</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/32656907/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/32656907/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Almost all living organisms have evolved autoregulatory transcriptional-translational feedback loops that produce oscillations with a period of approximately 24-h. These endogenous time keeping mechanisms are called circadian clocks. The main function of these circadian clocks is to drive overt circadian rhythms in the physiology of the organisms to ensure that main physiological functions are in synchrony with the external environment. Disruption of circadian rhythms caused by genetic or environmental factors has long-term consequences for metabolic health. Of relevance, host circadian rhythmicity and lipid metabolism are increasingly recognized to cross-regulate and the circadian clock-lipid metabolism interplay may involve in the development of obesity. Multiple systemic and molecular mechanisms, such as hormones (ie, melatonin, leptin, and glucocorticoid), the gut microbiome, and energy metabolism, link the circadian clock and lipid metabolism, and predictably, the deregulation of circadian clock-lipid metabolism interplay can increase the risk of obesity, which in turn may exacerbate circadian disorganization. Feeding time and dietary nutrients are two of key environmental Zeitgebers affecting the circadian rhythm-lipid metabolism interplay, and the influencing mechanisms in obesity development are highlighted in this review. Together, the characterization of the clock machinery in lipid metabolism aimed at producing a healthy circadian lifestyle may improve obesity care.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paraventricular hypothalamus mediates diurnal rhythm of metabolism</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32732906/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32732906/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Defective rhythmic metabolism is associated with high-fat high-caloric diet (HFD) feeding, ageing and obesity; however, the neural basis underlying HFD effects on diurnal metabolism remains elusive. Here we show that deletion of BMAL1, a core clock gene, in paraventricular hypothalamic (PVH) neurons reduces diurnal rhythmicity in metabolism, causes obesity and diminishes PVH neuron activation in response to fast-refeeding. Animal models mimicking deficiency in PVH neuron responsiveness, achieved through clamping PVH neuron activity at high or low levels, both show obesity and reduced diurnal rhythmicity in metabolism. Interestingly, the PVH exhibits BMAL1-controlled rhythmic expression of GABA-A receptor γ2 subunit, and dampening rhythmicity of GABAergic input to the PVH reduces diurnal rhythmicity in metabolism and causes obesity. Finally, BMAL1 deletion blunts PVH neuron responses to external stressors, an effect mimicked by HFD feeding. Thus, BMAL1-driven PVH neuron responsiveness in dynamic activity changes involving rhythmic GABAergic neurotransmission mediates diurnal rhythmicity in metabolism and is implicated in diet-induced obesity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chronic circadian disruption modulates breast cancer stemness and immune microenvironment to drive metastasis in mice</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32581213/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32581213/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Breast cancer is the most common type of cancer worldwide and one of the major causes of cancer death in women. Epidemiological studies have established a link between night-shift work and increased cancer risk, suggesting that circadian disruption may play a role in carcinogenesis. Here, we aim to shed light on the effect of chronic jetlag (JL) on mammary tumour development. To do this, we use a mouse model of spontaneous mammary tumourigenesis and subject it to chronic circadian disruption. We observe that circadian disruption significantly increases cancer-cell dissemination and lung metastasis. It also enhances the stemness and tumour-initiating potential of tumour cells and creates an immunosuppressive shift in the tumour microenvironment. Finally, our results suggest that the use of a CXCR2 inhibitor could correct the effect of JL on cancer-cell dissemination and metastasis. Altogether, our data provide a conceptual framework to better understand and manage the effects of chronic circadian disruption on breast cancer progression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rhythms of life: circadian disruption and brain disorders across the lifespan</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/30459365/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/30459365/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many processes in the human body — including brain function — are regulated over the 24-hour cycle, and there are strong associations between disrupted circadian rhythms (for example, sleep–wake cycles) and disorders of the CNS. Brain disorders such as autism, depression and Parkinson disease typically develop at certain stages of life, and circadian rhythms are important during each stage of life for the regulation of processes that may influence the development of these disorders. Here, we describe circadian disruptions observed in various brain disorders throughout the human lifespan and highlight emerging evidence suggesting these disruptions affect the brain. Currently, much of the evidence linking brain disorders and circadian dysfunction is correlational, and so whether and what kind of causal relationships might exist are unclear. We therefore identify remaining questions that may direct future research towards a better understanding of the links between circadian disruption and CNS disorders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reciprocal Regulation between the Circadian Clock and Hypoxia Signaling at the Genome Level in Mammals</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/27773697/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/27773697/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Circadian regulation is critically important in maintaining metabolic and physiological homeostasis. However, little is known about the possible influence of the clock on physiological abnormalities occurring under pathological conditions. Here, we report the discovery that hypoxia, a condition that causes catastrophic bodily damage, is gated by the circadian clock in vivo. Hypoxia signals conversely regulate the clock by slowing the circadian cycle and dampening the amplitude of oscillations in a dose-dependent manner. ChIP-seq analyses of hypoxia-inducible factor HIF1A and the core clock component BMAL1 revealed crosstalk between hypoxia and the clock at the genome level. Further, severe consequences caused by acute hypoxia, such as those that occur with heart attacks, were correlated with defects in circadian rhythms. We propose that the clock plays functions in fine-tuning hypoxic responses under pathophysiological conditions. We argue that the clock can, and likely should, be exploited therapeutically to reduce the severity of fatal hypoxia-related diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Loss of ZBTB20 impairs circadian output and leads to unimodal behavioral rhythms</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/27657167/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/27657167/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many animals display morning and evening bimodal activities in the day/night cycle. However, little is known regarding the potential components involved in the regulation of bimodal behavioral rhythms in mammals. Here, we identified that the zinc finger protein gene &lt;em&gt;Zbtb20&lt;/em&gt; plays a crucial role in the regulation of bimodal activities in mice. Depletion of &lt;em&gt;Zbtb20&lt;/em&gt; in nerve system resulted in the loss of early evening activity, but the increase of morning activity. We found that &lt;em&gt;Zbtb20&lt;/em&gt;-deficient mice exhibited a pronounced decrease in the expression of &lt;em&gt;Prokr2&lt;/em&gt; and resembled phenotypes of &lt;em&gt;Prok2&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Prokr2&lt;/em&gt;-knockout mice. Injection of adeno-associated virus-double-floxed &lt;em&gt;Prokr2&lt;/em&gt; in suprachiasmatic nucleus could partly restore evening activity in &lt;em&gt;Nestin-Cre&lt;/em&gt;; &lt;em&gt;Zbtb20&lt;sup&gt;fl/fl&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; (NS-ZB20KO) mice. Furthermore, loss of &lt;em&gt;Zbtb20&lt;/em&gt; in &lt;em&gt;Foxg1&lt;/em&gt; loci, but intact in the suprachiasmatic nucleus, was not responsible for the unimodal activity of NS-ZB20KO mice. Our study provides evidence that ZBTB20-mediated PROKR2 signaling is critical for the evening behavioral rhythms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cell autonomous regulation of herpes and influenza virus infection by the circadian clock</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/27528682/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/27528682/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Viruses are intracellular pathogens that hijack host cell machinery and resources to replicate. Rather than being constant, host physiology is rhythmic, undergoing circadian (∼24 h) oscillations in many virus-relevant pathways, but whether daily rhythms impact on viral replication is unknown. We find that the time of day of host infection regulates virus progression in live mice and individual cells. Furthermore, we demonstrate that herpes and influenza A virus infections are enhanced when host circadian rhythms are abolished by disrupting the key clock gene transcription factor Bmal1. Intracellular trafficking, biosynthetic processes, protein synthesis, and chromatin assembly all contribute to circadian regulation of virus infection. Moreover, herpesviruses differentially target components of the molecular circadian clockwork. Our work demonstrates that viruses exploit the clockwork for their own gain and that the clock represents a novel target for modulating viral replication that extends beyond any single family of these ubiquitous pathogens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Long-Range Chromosome Interactions Mediated by Cohesin Shape Circadian Gene Expression</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/27135601/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/27135601/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mammalian circadian rhythm is established by the negative feedback loops consisting of a set of clock genes, which lead to the circadian expression of thousands of downstream genes in vivo. As genome-wide transcription is organized under the high-order chromosome structure, it is largely uncharted how circadian gene expression is influenced by chromosome architecture. We focus on the function of chromatin structure proteins cohesin as well as CTCF (CCCTC-binding factor) in circadian rhythm. Using circular chromosome conformation capture sequencing, we systematically examined the interacting loci of a Bmal1-bound super-enhancer upstream of a clock gene Nr1d1 in mouse liver. These interactions are largely stable in the circadian cycle and cohesin binding sites are enriched in the interactome. Global analysis showed that cohesin-CTCF co-binding sites tend to insulate the phases of circadian oscillating genes while cohesin-non-CTCF sites are associated with high circadian rhythmicity of transcription. A model integrating the effects of cohesin and CTCF markedly improved the mechanistic understanding of circadian gene expression. Further experiments in cohesin knockout cells demonstrated that cohesin is required at least in part for driving the circadian gene expression by facilitating the enhancer-promoter looping. This study provided a novel insight into the relationship between circadian transcriptome and the high-order chromosome structure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
