<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>PI3K/AKT | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/pi3k/akt/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/pi3k/akt/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>PI3K/AKT</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>PI3K/AKT</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/pi3k/akt/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>PI3K/AKT-mediated autophagy inhibition facilitates mast cell activation to enhance severe inflammatory lung injury in influenza A virus- and secondary Staphylococcus aureus-infected mice</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36549394/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36549394/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Influenza A virus infection causes considerable morbidity and mortality each year globally, and secondary bacterial infection further exacerbates the severity and fatality of the initial viral infection. Mast cells have substantial roles in protecting the respiratory tract mucosa, while their role in viral and bacterial co-infection remains unclear. The present study revealed that secondary Staphylococcus aureus infection significantly aggravated the activation of mast cells during the initial H1N1 infection both in vivo and in vitro, which was closely related to the increased inflammatory lung injury and mortality. Meanwhile, the secondary S. aureus infection suppressed autophagy and promoted inflammatory mediators released by mast cells through activating the PI3K/Akt signaling pathway. Blocking PI3K/Akt pathway by LY294002, an inhibitor of Akt phosphorylation, could rescue autophagy and inhibit the release of inflammatory mediators. Furthermore, based on the influenza A viral and secondary bacterial infected mice model, we showed that the combination of LY294002 and antiviral drug oseltamivir could effectively reduce the inflammatory damage and pro-inflammatory cytokines releasing in lungs, recovering body weight loss and improving the survival rate from the co-infections. In conclusion, secondary bacterial infection can inhibit autophagy and stimulate mast cell activation through the PI3K/Akt pathway, which might explain why secondary bacterial infection would cause severe and fatal consequences following an initial influenza A viral infection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JCAD promotes arterial thrombosis through PI3K/Akt modulation: a translational study</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36469488/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36469488/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Aims:&lt;/em&gt; Variants of the junctional cadherin 5 associated (JCAD) locus associate with acute coronary syndromes. JCAD promotes experimental atherosclerosis through the large tumor suppressor kinase 2 (LATS2)/Hippo pathway. This study investigates the role of JCAD in arterial thrombosis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods and results:&lt;/em&gt; JCAD knockout (&lt;em&gt;Jcad&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt;) mice underwent photochemically induced endothelial injury to trigger arterial thrombosis. Primary human aortic endothelial cells (HAECs) treated with JCAD small interfering RNA (&lt;em&gt;siJCAD&lt;/em&gt;), LATS2 small interfering RNA (&lt;em&gt;siLATS2&lt;/em&gt;) or control siRNA (siSCR) were employed for in vitro assays. Plasma JCAD was measured in patients with chronic coronary syndrome or ST-elevation myocardial infarction (STEMI). &lt;em&gt;Jcad&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; mice displayed reduced thrombogenicity as reflected by delayed time to carotid occlusion. Mechanisms include reduced activation of the coagulation cascade [reduced tissue factor (TF) expression and activity] and increased fibrinolysis [higher thrombus embolization episodes and D-dimer levels, reduced vascular plasminogen activator inhibitor (PAI)-1 expression]. In vitro, JCAD silencing inhibited TF and PAI-1 expression in HAECs. JCAD-silenced HAECs (&lt;em&gt;siJCAD&lt;/em&gt;) displayed increased levels of LATS2 kinase. Yet, double JCAD and LATS2 silencing did not restore the control phenotype. &lt;em&gt;si-JCAD&lt;/em&gt; HAECs showed increased levels of phosphoinositide 3-kinases (PI3K)/proteinkinase B (Akt) activation, known to downregulate procoagulant expression. The PI3K/Akt pathway inhibitor-wortmannin-prevented the effect of JCAD silencing on TF and PAI-1, indicating a causative role. Also, co-immunoprecipitation unveiled a direct interaction between JCAD and Akt. Confirming in vitro findings, PI3K/Akt and P-yes-associated protein levels were higher in &lt;em&gt;Jcad&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; animals. Lastly, as compared with chronic coronary syndrome, STEMI patients showed higher plasma JCAD, which notably correlated positively with both TF and PAI-1 levels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; JCAD promotes arterial thrombosis by modulating coagulation and fibrinolysis. Herein, reported translational data suggest JCAD as a potential therapeutic target for atherothrombosis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Attenuation of the Severity of Acute Respiratory Distress Syndrome by Pomiferin through Blocking Inflammation and Oxidative Stress in an AKT/Foxo1 Pathway-Dependent Manner</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36471865/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36471865/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acute respiratory distress syndrome (ARDS) gives rise to uncontrolled inflammatory response and oxidative stress, causing very high mortality globally. Pomiferin is a kind of prenylated isoflavonoid extracted from &lt;em&gt;Maclura pomifera&lt;/em&gt;, owning anti-inflammatory and antioxidant properties. However, the functions and possible mechanisms of pomiferin in lipopolysaccharide- (LPS-) induced ARDS remain unknown. C57BL/6 mice were injected with LPS (5 mg/kg) intratracheally to induce an in vivo ARDS model while RAW264.7 macrophages were stimulated with LPS (100 ng/ml) to induce an in vitro model. Our data demonstrated that pomiferin (20 mg/kg) significantly improved pulmonary function and lung pathological injury in mice with ARDS, apart from increasing survival rate. Meanwhile, pomiferin treatment also inhibited LPS-induced inflammation as well as oxidative stress in lung tissues. LPS stimulation significantly activated AKT/Foxo1 signal pathway in lung tissues, which could be reversed after pomiferin treatment. In vitro experiments further showed that 10, 20, and 50 μM of pomiferin could enhance cell viability of RAW264.7 macrophages stimulated with LPS. What is more, 3-deoxysappanchalcone (3-DE), one AKT agonist, was used to active AKT in RAW264.7 macrophages. The results further showed that 3-DE could abolish pomiferin-elicited protection in LPS-treated RAW264.7 macrophages, evidenced by activated inflammation and oxidative stress. Taken together, our study showed that pomiferin could exert an ARDS-protective effect by blocking the AKT/Foxo1 signal pathway to inhibit LPS-induced inflammatory response and oxidative injury, which may serve as a potential candidate for the treatment of ARDS in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1,2,3,4,6-O-Pentagalloylglucose Protects against Acute Lung Injury by Activating the AMPK/PI3K/Akt/Nrf2 Pathway</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36430900/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36430900/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An acute lung injury (ALI) is a serious lung disease with a high mortality rate, warranting the development of novel therapies. Previously, we reported that 1,2,3,4,6-O-pentagalloylglucose (PGG) could afford protection against ALI, however, the PGG-mediated protective effects remain elusive. Herein, PGG (60 and 30 mg/kg) markedly inhibited the lung wet/drug weight ratio and attenuated histological changes in the lungs (&lt;em&gt;p&lt;/em&gt; &amp;lt; 0.05). A pretreatment with PGG (60 and 30 mg/kg) reduced the number of total leukocytes and the production of pro-inflammatory cytokines IL-6 and IL-1β in bronchoalveolar lavage fluid (&lt;em&gt;p&lt;/em&gt; &amp;lt; 0.05). In addition, PGG (60 and 30 mg/kg) also attenuated oxidative stress by reducing the formation of formation and the depletion of superoxide dismutase to treat an ALI (&lt;em&gt;p&lt;/em&gt; &amp;lt; 0.05). To further explore the PGG-induced mechanism against an ALI, we screened the PGG pathway using immunohistochemical analysis, immunofluorescence assays, and Western blotting (WB). WB revealed that the expression levels of adenosine monophosphate-activated protein kinase phosphorylation (p-AMPK), phosphoinositide 3-kinase (PI3K), protein kinase B phosphorylation (P-Akt), and nuclear factor erythroid 2-related factor (Nrf2) were significantly higher in the PGG group (60 and 30 mg/kg) than in the lipopolysaccharide group (&lt;em&gt;p&lt;/em&gt; &amp;lt; 0.05); these findings were confirmed by the immunohistochemical and immunofluorescence results. Accordingly, PGG could be effective against an ALI by inhibiting inflammation and oxidative stress via AMPK/PI3K/Akt/Nrf2 signaling, allowing for the potential development of this as a natural drug against an ALI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fibroblast growth factor 10 protects against particulate matter-induced lung injury by inhibiting oxidative stress-mediated pyroptosis via the PI3K/Akt/Nrf2 signaling pathway</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36461597/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36461597/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Particulate matter (PM) is a major environmental contaminant that causes and worsens respiratory diseases. Fibroblast growth factor 10 (FGF10), a paracrine fibroblast growth factor that specifically stimulates repair and regeneration after injury, has been shown to protect against PM-induced lung injury. However, the underlying mechanisms are still unclear. In this study, the protective effects of FGF10 were investigated using a PM-induced lung injury mouse model in vivo and BEAS-2B cells in vitro. According to the findings, FGF10 treatment alleviated PM-induced oxidative damage and pyroptosis in vivo and in vitro. Mechanistically, FGF10 activated antioxidative Nrf2 signaling. Inhibition of PI3K signaling with LY294002 or Nrf2 signaling with ML385 revealed that FGF10-mediated lung protection was mediated by the PI3K/Akt/Nrf2 pathway. These results collectively indicate that FGF10 inhibits oxidative stress-mediated pyroptosis via the PI3K/Akt/Nrf2 pathway, suggesting a possible therapy for PM-induced lung injury.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mechanisms of Biochanin A Alleviating PM2.5 Organic Extracts-Induced EMT of A549 Cells through the PI3K/Akt Pathway</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/36181478/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/36181478/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Epithelial–mesenchymal transition (EMT) is an important step in tumor progression, which enables tumor cells to acquire migration and invasion characteristics. The aim of this study was to investigate the mechanism of biological biochanin A (BCA) in ameliorating fine particulate matter (PM&lt;sub&gt;2.5&lt;/sub&gt;) lung injury. The results showed that PM&lt;sub&gt;2.5&lt;/sub&gt; could induce spindle-like changes in cell morphology, causing the ability of migration and invasion. However, they were significantly inhibited by BCA treatment (10/20/30 μm). After BCA treatment, the release and transcription of chemokine CXCL12 and its receptor gene CXCR4 were inhibited, and the release of growth inducer TGF-β1 was significantly reduced. In addition, BCA promoted the transcription of E-cadherin and β-catenin, inhibiting the expression of N-cadherin, vimentin, and fibronectin, and down-regulated the expression of MMP-2/9. We found that BCA effectively interfered with the PI3K/Akt signaling pathway activated by PM&lt;sub&gt;2.5&lt;/sub&gt;. In conclusion, PM&lt;sub&gt;2.5&lt;/sub&gt; can induce EMT in lung cancer cells, and BCA may reverse this process by activating the PI3K/Akt signaling pathway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>D-tagatose protects against oleic acid-induced acute respiratory distress syndrome in rats by activating PTEN/PI3K/AKT pathway</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36189316/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36189316/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acute respiratory distress syndrome (ARDS) is characterized by disruption of the alveolar-capillary barrier, resulting in severe alveolar edema and inflammation. D-tagatose (TAG) is a low-calorie fructose isomer with diverse biological activities whose role in ARDS has never been explored. We found that TAG protects lung tissues from injury in the oleic acid-induced rat model of ARDS. Seventeen male Sprague-Dawley rats were randomly assigned to 3 groups: Sham (n = 5), ARDS (n = 6), and TAG + ARDS (n = 6). The treatment groups were injected with oleic acid to induce ARDS, and the TAG + ARDS group was given TAG 3 days before the induction. After the treatments, the effect of TAG was evaluated by blood gas analysis and observing the gross and histological structure of the lung. The results showed that TAG significantly improved the oxygenation function, reduced the respiratory acidosis and the inflammatory response. TAG also improved the vascular permeability in ARDS rats and promoted the differentiation of alveolar type II cells, maintaining the stability of the alveolar structure. This protective effect of TAG on the lung may be achieved by activating the PTEN/PI3K/AKT pathway. Thus, TAG protects against oleic acid-induced ARDS in rats, suggesting a new clinical strategy for treating the condition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The dipeptidyl peptidase-4 inhibitor linagliptin ameliorates LPS-induced acute lung injury by maintenance of pulmonary microvascular barrier via activating the Epac1/AKT pathway</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36115114/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36115114/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Linagliptin alleviates LPS-induced pulmonary injury and edema.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Linagliptin protects against PMVECs hyperpermeability via preventing the loss of adherens junctions and tight junctions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Linagliptin inhibits LPS-induced oxidative stress by regulating mitochondrial function.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Linagliptin attenuates PMVECs barrier dysfunction via activating the Epac1/AKT signaling axis.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pulmonary microvascular endothelial cells (PMVECs) barrier dysfunction is a main pathophysiological feature of sepsis-related acute lung injury (ALI). This study aimed to investigate whether the dipeptidyl peptidase (DPP)-4 inhibitor linagliptin could protect against LPS-induced PMVECs barrier disruption and its underlying molecular mechanisms. A classical ALI animal model and LPS-treated PMVECs were applied and all were treated with or without linagliptin. Cellular experiments demonstrated that linagliptin could mitigate LPS-induced PMVECs hyperpermeability and intercellular junction (VE-cadherin, β-catenin, and ZO-1) disruption in a dose-dependent manner. Correspondingly, it was observed that linagliptin pretreatment distinctly relieved LPS-induced lung injury, oxidative stress, and pulmonary edema in vivo. Furthermore, we found that the inhibition of oxidative stress by linagliptin may be achieved by reversing impaired mitochondrial function. Mechanistically, linagliptin administration promoted the activation of the Epac1 pathway and its downstream AKT pathway, while inhibition of the Epac1/Akt signaling pathway significantly alleviated the above-mentioned protective effect of linagliptin on the PMVECs barrier. Taken together, these data suggest that linagliptin can effectively reserve PMVECs barrier dysfunction and inhibit oxidative stress to protect against ALI via activating the Epac1/AKT signaling pathway, and thus may become a potential clinical therapeutic strategy for ALI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pretreatment with rosavin attenuates PM2.5-induced lung injury in rats through antiferroptosis via PI3K/Akt/Nrf2 signaling pathway</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36097321/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36097321/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inflammation and oxidative stress caused by fine particulate matter (PM2.5) increase the incidence and mortality rates of respiratory disorders. Rosavin is the main chemical component of Rhodiola plants, which exerts anti-oxidative and antiinflammatory effects. In this research, the potential therapeutic effect of rosavin was investigated by the PM2.5-induced lung injury rat model. Rats were instilled with PM2.5 (7.5 mg/kg) suspension intratracheally, while rosavin (50 mg/kg, 100 mg/kg) was delivered by intraperitoneal injection before the PM2.5 injection. It was observed that rosavin could prevent lung injury caused by PM2.5. PM2.5 showed obvious ferroptosis-related ultrastructural alterations, which were significantly corrected by rosavin. The pretreatment with rosavin downregulated the levels of tissue iron, malondialdehyde, and 4-hydroxynonenal, and increased the levels of glutathione. The expression of nuclear factor E2-related factor 2 (Nrf2) was upregulated by rosavin, together with other ferroptosis-related proteins. RSL3, a specific ferroptosis agonist, reversed the beneficial impact of rosavin. The network pharmacology approach predicted the activation of rosavin on the phosphatidylinositol 3-kinase (PI3K)/protein kinase B (Akt) signaling pathway. LY294002, a potent PI3K inhibitor, decreased the upregulation of Nrf2 induced by rosavin. In conclusion, rosavin prevented lung injury induced by PM2.5 stimulation and suppressed ferroptosis via upregulating PI3K/Akt/Nrf2 signaling pathway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Erythropoietin mediates re-programming of endotoxin-tolerant macrophages through PI3K/AKT signaling and protects mice against secondary infection</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36016936/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36016936/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Initial lipopolysaccharide (LPS) exposure leads to a hypo-responsive state by macrophages to a secondary stimulation of LPS, known as endotoxin tolerance. However, recent findings show that functions of endotoxin-tolerant macrophages are not completely suppressed, whereas they undergo a functional re-programming process with upregulation of a panel of molecules leading to enhanced protective functions including antimicrobial and tissue-remodeling activities. However, the underlying molecular mechanisms are still elusive. Erythropoietin (EPO), a glycoprotein regulated by hypoxia-inducible factor 1α (HIF-1α), exerts anti-inflammatory and tissue-protective activities. Nevertheless, the potential effects of EPO on functional re-programming of endotoxin-tolerant macrophages have not been investigated yet. Here, we found that initial LPS exposure led to upregulation of HIF-1α/EPO in macrophages and that EPO enhanced tolerance in tolerized macrophages and mice as demonstrated by suppressed proinflammatory genes such as &lt;em&gt;Il1b&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Il6&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Tnfa&lt;/em&gt; after secondary LPS stimulation. Moreover, we showed that EPO improved host protective genes in endotoxin-tolerant macrophages and mice, such as the anti-bacterial genes coding for cathelicidin-related antimicrobial peptide (&lt;em&gt;Cnlp&lt;/em&gt;) and macrophage receptor with collagenous structure (&lt;em&gt;Marco&lt;/em&gt;), and the tissue-repairing gene vascular endothelial growth factor C (&lt;em&gt;Vegfc&lt;/em&gt;). Therefore, our findings indicate that EPO mediates the functional re-programming of endotoxin-tolerant macrophages. Mechanistically, we found that PI3K/AKT signaling contributed to EPO-mediated re-programming through upregulation of &lt;em&gt;Irak3&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Wdr5&lt;/em&gt; expression. Specifically, IL-1 receptor-associated kinase 3 (IRAK3) was responsible for inhibiting proinflammatory genes &lt;em&gt;Il1b&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Il6&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Tnfa&lt;/em&gt; in tolerized macrophages after LPS rechallenge, whereas WDR5 contributed to the upregulation of host beneficial genes including &lt;em&gt;Cnlp&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Marco&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Vegfc&lt;/em&gt;. In a septic model of mice, EPO pretreatment significantly promoted endotoxin-tolerant re-programming, alleviated lung injury, enhanced bacterial clearance, and decreased mortality in LPS-tolerized mice after secondary infection of &lt;em&gt;Escherichia coli&lt;/em&gt;. Collectively, our results reveal a novel role for EPO in mediating functional re-programming of endotoxin-tolerant macrophages; thus, targeting EPO appears to be a new therapeutic option in sepsis and other inflammatory disorders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PD-L1 maintains neutrophil extracellular traps release by inhibiting neutrophil autophagy in endotoxin-induced lung injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36016930/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36016930/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Programmed death ligand 1 (PD-L1) is not only an important molecule in mediating tumor immune escape, but also regulates inflammation development. Here we showed that PD-L1 was upregulated on neutrophils in lipopolysaccharide (LPS)-induced acute respiratory distress syndrome (ARDS). Neutrophil specific knockout of PD-L1 reduced lung injury in ARDS model induced by intratracheal LPS injection. The level of NET release was reduced and autophagy is elevated by PD-L1 knockout in ARDS neutrophils both &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;in vitro&lt;/em&gt;. Inhibition of autophagy could reverse the inhibitory effect of PD-L1 knockout on NET release. PD-L1 interacted with p85 subunit of PI3K at the endoplasmic reticulum (ER) in neutrophils from ARDS patients, activating the PI3K/Akt/mTOR pathway. An extrinsic neutralizing antibody against PD-L1 showed a protective effect against ARDS. Together, PD-L1 maintains the release of NETs by regulating autophagy through the PI3K/Akt/mTOR pathway in ARDS. Anti-PD-L1 therapy may be a promising measure in treating ARDS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Methylene-bridge tryptophan fatty acylation regulates PI3K-AKT signaling and glucose uptake</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35294873/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35294873/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The methylene-bridge-containing polyunsaturated fatty acids EPA and DHA modify proteins&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tryptophan is a site of posttranslational modifications by polyunsaturated fatty acids&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;EPA and DHA activate AKT signaling by modifying PDK1 and AKT2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;EPA and DHA promote glucose uptake but induce insulin resistance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Summary&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Protein fatty acylation regulates numerous cell signaling pathways. Polyunsaturated fatty acids (PUFAs) exert a plethora of physiological effects, including cell signaling regulation, with underlying mechanisms to be fully understood. Herein, we report that docosahexaenoic acid (DHA) and eicosapentaenoic acid (EPA) regulate PI3K-AKT signaling by modifying PDK1 and AKT2. DHA-administered mice exhibit altered phosphorylation of proteins in signaling pathways. Methylene bridge-containing DHA/EPA acylate δ1 carbon of tryptophan 448/543 in PDK1 and tryptophan 414 in AKT2 via free radical pathway, recruit both the proteins to the cytoplasmic membrane, and activate PI3K signaling and glucose uptake in a tryptophan acylation-dependent but insulin-independent manner in cultured cells and in mice. DHA/EPA deplete cytosolic PDK1 and AKT2 and induce insulin resistance. Akt2 knockout in mice abrogates DHA/EPA-induced PI3K-AKT signaling. Our results identify PUFA’s methylene bridge tryptophan acylation, a protein fatty acylation that regulates cell signaling and may underlie multifaceted effects of methylene-bridge-containing PUFAs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hypoxia adipose stem cell-derived exosomes promote high-quality healing of diabetic wound involves activation of PI3K/Akt pathways</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34233694/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34233694/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Refractory diabetic wounds can cause persistent inflammation and delayed healing due to hypoxia. Currently, no optimal solution is available. Exosomes of adipose stem cells (ADSCs-exo) may promote skin wound healing, however, molecular mechanisms remains mysterious. We found significantly enhanced survival and proliferation of adipose stem cells after hypoxia induction compared to normoxia. Here, we aimed to investigate if hypoxic adipose stem cells exosomes (HypADSCs-exo) participate in hypoxia adaptability and accelerate diabetic wound healing. Based on high-throughput sequencing, 215 microRNAs (miRNAs) were upregulated and 369 miRNAs downregulated in HypADSCs-exo compared to ADSCs-exo. Up-regulated miR-21-3p, miR-126-5p, miR-31-5p whereas down-regulated gene miR-99b and miR-146-a correlated with wound healing. According to Gene Ontology (GO) and Kyoto Encyclopedia of Genes and Genomes (KEGG), miRNAs might regulate cell metabolism, differentiation and Transforming growth factor-β (TGF-β) function. Consistently, HpyADSCs-exo could promote diabetic wounds healing and inhibit inflammation through PI3K/AKT signaling pathway. Collectively, HpyADSCs-exo can promote diabetic wound healing as an alternative strategy to improve wound healing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Identification of poly(ADP-ribose) polymerase 9 (PARP9) as a noncanonical sensor for RNA virus in dendritic cells</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33976210/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33976210/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Innate immune cells are critical in protective immunity against viral infections, involved in sensing foreign viral nucleic acids. Here we report that the poly(ADP-ribose) polymerase 9 (PARP9), a member of PARP family, serves as a non-canonical sensor for RNA virus to initiate and amplify type I interferon (IFN) production. We find knockdown or deletion of PARP9 in human or mouse dendritic cells and macrophages inhibits type I IFN production in response to double strand RNA stimulation or RNA virus infection. Furthermore, mice deficient for PARP9 show enhanced susceptibility to infections with RNA viruses because of the impaired type I IFN production. Mechanistically, we show that PARP9 recognizes and binds viral RNA, with resultant recruitment and activation of the phosphoinositide 3-kinase (PI3K) and AKT3 pathway, independent of mitochondrial antiviral-signaling (MAVS). PI3K/AKT3 then activates the IRF3 and IRF7 by phosphorylating IRF3 at Ser385 and IRF7 at Ser437/438 mediating type I IFN production. Together, we reveal a critical role for PARP9 as a non-canonical RNA sensor that depends on the PI3K/AKT3 pathway to produce type I IFN. These findings may have important clinical implications in controlling viral infections and viral-induced diseases by targeting PARP9.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Novel Long Non-Coding RNA lnc030 Maintains Breast Cancer Stem Cell Stemness by Stabilizing SQLE mRNA and Increasing Cholesterol Synthesis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33511005/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33511005/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Erratum in:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/advs.202204046&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;A Novel Long Non-Coding RNA lnc030 Maintains Breast Cancer Stem Cell Stemness by Stabilizing SQLE mRNA and Increasing Cholesterol Synthesis&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cancer stem cells (CSCs) are considered the roots of cancer metastasis and recurrence (CSCs), due in part to their self-renewal and therapy resistance properties. However, the underlying mechanisms for the regulation of CSC stemness are poorly understood. Recently, increasing evidence shows that long non-coding RNAs (lncRNAs) are critical regulators for cancer cell function in various malignancies including breast cancer, but how lncRNAs regulate the function of breast cancer stem cells (BCSCs) remains to be determined. Herein, using lncRNA/mRNA microarray assays, a novel lncRNA (named lnc030) is identified, which is highly expressed in BCSCs in vitro and in vivo, as a pivotal regulator in maintaining BCSC stemness and promoting tumorigenesis. Mechanistically, lnc030 cooperates with poly(rC) binding protein 2(PCBP2) to stabilize squalene epoxidase (SQLE) mRNA, resulting in an increase of cholesterol synthesis. The increased cholesterol in turn actives PI3K/Akt signaling, which governs BCSC stemness. In summary, these findings demonstrate that a new, lnc030-based mechanism for regulating cholesterol synthesis and stemness properties of BCSCs. The lnc030-SQLE-cholesterol synthesis pathway may serve as an effective therapeutic target for BCSC elimination and breast cancer treatment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
