<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>PI3K/AKT | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/pi3k/akt/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/pi3k/akt/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>PI3K/AKT</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>PI3K/AKT</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/pi3k/akt/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>PI3K/AKT-mediated autophagy inhibition facilitates mast cell activation to enhance severe inflammatory lung injury in influenza A virus- and secondary Staphylococcus aureus-infected mice</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36549394/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36549394/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Influenza A virus infection causes considerable morbidity and mortality each year globally, and secondary bacterial infection further exacerbates the severity and fatality of the initial viral infection. Mast cells have substantial roles in protecting the respiratory tract mucosa, while their role in viral and bacterial co-infection remains unclear. The present study revealed that secondary Staphylococcus aureus infection significantly aggravated the activation of mast cells during the initial H1N1 infection both in vivo and in vitro, which was closely related to the increased inflammatory lung injury and mortality. Meanwhile, the secondary S. aureus infection suppressed autophagy and promoted inflammatory mediators released by mast cells through activating the PI3K/Akt signaling pathway. Blocking PI3K/Akt pathway by LY294002, an inhibitor of Akt phosphorylation, could rescue autophagy and inhibit the release of inflammatory mediators. Furthermore, based on the influenza A viral and secondary bacterial infected mice model, we showed that the combination of LY294002 and antiviral drug oseltamivir could effectively reduce the inflammatory damage and pro-inflammatory cytokines releasing in lungs, recovering body weight loss and improving the survival rate from the co-infections. In conclusion, secondary bacterial infection can inhibit autophagy and stimulate mast cell activation through the PI3K/Akt pathway, which might explain why secondary bacterial infection would cause severe and fatal consequences following an initial influenza A viral infection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JCAD promotes arterial thrombosis through PI3K/Akt modulation: a translational study</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36469488/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36469488/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Aims:&lt;/em&gt; Variants of the junctional cadherin 5 associated (JCAD) locus associate with acute coronary syndromes. JCAD promotes experimental atherosclerosis through the large tumor suppressor kinase 2 (LATS2)/Hippo pathway. This study investigates the role of JCAD in arterial thrombosis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods and results:&lt;/em&gt; JCAD knockout (&lt;em&gt;Jcad&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt;) mice underwent photochemically induced endothelial injury to trigger arterial thrombosis. Primary human aortic endothelial cells (HAECs) treated with JCAD small interfering RNA (&lt;em&gt;siJCAD&lt;/em&gt;), LATS2 small interfering RNA (&lt;em&gt;siLATS2&lt;/em&gt;) or control siRNA (siSCR) were employed for in vitro assays. Plasma JCAD was measured in patients with chronic coronary syndrome or ST-elevation myocardial infarction (STEMI). &lt;em&gt;Jcad&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; mice displayed reduced thrombogenicity as reflected by delayed time to carotid occlusion. Mechanisms include reduced activation of the coagulation cascade [reduced tissue factor (TF) expression and activity] and increased fibrinolysis [higher thrombus embolization episodes and D-dimer levels, reduced vascular plasminogen activator inhibitor (PAI)-1 expression]. In vitro, JCAD silencing inhibited TF and PAI-1 expression in HAECs. JCAD-silenced HAECs (&lt;em&gt;siJCAD&lt;/em&gt;) displayed increased levels of LATS2 kinase. Yet, double JCAD and LATS2 silencing did not restore the control phenotype. &lt;em&gt;si-JCAD&lt;/em&gt; HAECs showed increased levels of phosphoinositide 3-kinases (PI3K)/proteinkinase B (Akt) activation, known to downregulate procoagulant expression. The PI3K/Akt pathway inhibitor-wortmannin-prevented the effect of JCAD silencing on TF and PAI-1, indicating a causative role. Also, co-immunoprecipitation unveiled a direct interaction between JCAD and Akt. Confirming in vitro findings, PI3K/Akt and P-yes-associated protein levels were higher in &lt;em&gt;Jcad&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; animals. Lastly, as compared with chronic coronary syndrome, STEMI patients showed higher plasma JCAD, which notably correlated positively with both TF and PAI-1 levels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; JCAD promotes arterial thrombosis by modulating coagulation and fibrinolysis. Herein, reported translational data suggest JCAD as a potential therapeutic target for atherothrombosis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Attenuation of the Severity of Acute Respiratory Distress Syndrome by Pomiferin through Blocking Inflammation and Oxidative Stress in an AKT/Foxo1 Pathway-Dependent Manner</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36471865/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36471865/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acute respiratory distress syndrome (ARDS) gives rise to uncontrolled inflammatory response and oxidative stress, causing very high mortality globally. Pomiferin is a kind of prenylated isoflavonoid extracted from &lt;em&gt;Maclura pomifera&lt;/em&gt;, owning anti-inflammatory and antioxidant properties. However, the functions and possible mechanisms of pomiferin in lipopolysaccharide- (LPS-) induced ARDS remain unknown. C57BL/6 mice were injected with LPS (5 mg/kg) intratracheally to induce an in vivo ARDS model while RAW264.7 macrophages were stimulated with LPS (100 ng/ml) to induce an in vitro model. Our data demonstrated that pomiferin (20 mg/kg) significantly improved pulmonary function and lung pathological injury in mice with ARDS, apart from increasing survival rate. Meanwhile, pomiferin treatment also inhibited LPS-induced inflammation as well as oxidative stress in lung tissues. LPS stimulation significantly activated AKT/Foxo1 signal pathway in lung tissues, which could be reversed after pomiferin treatment. In vitro experiments further showed that 10, 20, and 50 μM of pomiferin could enhance cell viability of RAW264.7 macrophages stimulated with LPS. What is more, 3-deoxysappanchalcone (3-DE), one AKT agonist, was used to active AKT in RAW264.7 macrophages. The results further showed that 3-DE could abolish pomiferin-elicited protection in LPS-treated RAW264.7 macrophages, evidenced by activated inflammation and oxidative stress. Taken together, our study showed that pomiferin could exert an ARDS-protective effect by blocking the AKT/Foxo1 signal pathway to inhibit LPS-induced inflammatory response and oxidative injury, which may serve as a potential candidate for the treatment of ARDS in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Methylene-bridge tryptophan fatty acylation regulates PI3K-AKT signaling and glucose uptake</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35294873/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35294873/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The methylene-bridge-containing polyunsaturated fatty acids EPA and DHA modify proteins&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tryptophan is a site of posttranslational modifications by polyunsaturated fatty acids&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;EPA and DHA activate AKT signaling by modifying PDK1 and AKT2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;EPA and DHA promote glucose uptake but induce insulin resistance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Summary&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Protein fatty acylation regulates numerous cell signaling pathways. Polyunsaturated fatty acids (PUFAs) exert a plethora of physiological effects, including cell signaling regulation, with underlying mechanisms to be fully understood. Herein, we report that docosahexaenoic acid (DHA) and eicosapentaenoic acid (EPA) regulate PI3K-AKT signaling by modifying PDK1 and AKT2. DHA-administered mice exhibit altered phosphorylation of proteins in signaling pathways. Methylene bridge-containing DHA/EPA acylate δ1 carbon of tryptophan 448/543 in PDK1 and tryptophan 414 in AKT2 via free radical pathway, recruit both the proteins to the cytoplasmic membrane, and activate PI3K signaling and glucose uptake in a tryptophan acylation-dependent but insulin-independent manner in cultured cells and in mice. DHA/EPA deplete cytosolic PDK1 and AKT2 and induce insulin resistance. Akt2 knockout in mice abrogates DHA/EPA-induced PI3K-AKT signaling. Our results identify PUFA’s methylene bridge tryptophan acylation, a protein fatty acylation that regulates cell signaling and may underlie multifaceted effects of methylene-bridge-containing PUFAs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Identification of poly(ADP-ribose) polymerase 9 (PARP9) as a noncanonical sensor for RNA virus in dendritic cells</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33976210/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33976210/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Innate immune cells are critical in protective immunity against viral infections, involved in sensing foreign viral nucleic acids. Here we report that the poly(ADP-ribose) polymerase 9 (PARP9), a member of PARP family, serves as a non-canonical sensor for RNA virus to initiate and amplify type I interferon (IFN) production. We find knockdown or deletion of PARP9 in human or mouse dendritic cells and macrophages inhibits type I IFN production in response to double strand RNA stimulation or RNA virus infection. Furthermore, mice deficient for PARP9 show enhanced susceptibility to infections with RNA viruses because of the impaired type I IFN production. Mechanistically, we show that PARP9 recognizes and binds viral RNA, with resultant recruitment and activation of the phosphoinositide 3-kinase (PI3K) and AKT3 pathway, independent of mitochondrial antiviral-signaling (MAVS). PI3K/AKT3 then activates the IRF3 and IRF7 by phosphorylating IRF3 at Ser385 and IRF7 at Ser437/438 mediating type I IFN production. Together, we reveal a critical role for PARP9 as a non-canonical RNA sensor that depends on the PI3K/AKT3 pathway to produce type I IFN. These findings may have important clinical implications in controlling viral infections and viral-induced diseases by targeting PARP9.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
