<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Severe Fever with Thrombocytopenia Syndrome Virus | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/severe-fever-with-thrombocytopenia-syndrome-virus/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/severe-fever-with-thrombocytopenia-syndrome-virus/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Severe Fever with Thrombocytopenia Syndrome Virus</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Severe Fever with Thrombocytopenia Syndrome Virus</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/severe-fever-with-thrombocytopenia-syndrome-virus/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Single-cell landscape of peripheral immune responses to fatal SFTS</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34818556/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34818556/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Single-cell landscape of peripheral immune responses is reprogrammed in SFTS&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Exacerbated IFN-I response is related to hyper-inflammation and fatal outcome in SFTS&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Intermediate monocytes and IFN-I-inducible plasmablasts are major targets for SFTSV&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Severe fever with thrombocytopenia syndrome (SFTS) is an emerging infectious disease with high fatality. Poor prognosis of SFTS has been associated with dysregulated host immunity; however, the immune patterns associated with pathophysiology involving SFTS exacerbation remain unclear. Here, we show that the single-cell landscape of peripheral immune responses is reprogrammed in SFTS and characterized by monocyte shift to an intermediate type along with complement activation, perturbation of plasmablast composition, and highly exhausted T cells, all correlated with lethal consequences. We identify the overexpression of interferon (IFN)-stimulated genes across most immune cell types after SFTSV infection, which are simultaneously related to older age, high viremia, and a hyperinflammatory response. A retrospective clinical study reveals no efficiency of IFN-α in treating SFTS. These data collectively support the intermediate monocytes and IFN-I-inducible plasmablasts to be major targets for SFTS virus infection, and they indicate the pivotal role of the IFN-I response in exacerbating hyperinflammation and lethal SFTS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Infection of humanized mice with a novel phlebovirus presented pathogenic features of severe fever with thrombocytopenia syndrome</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33974679/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33974679/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Severe fever with thrombocytopenia syndrome virus (SFTSV) is a tick-borne emerging phlebovirus with high mortality rates of 6.0 to 30%. SFTSV infection is characterized by high fever, thrombocytopenia, leukopenia, hemorrhage and multiple organ failures. Currently, specific therapies and vaccines remain elusive. Suitable small animal models are urgently needed to elucidate the pathogenesis and evaluate the potential drug and vaccine for SFTSV infection. Previous models presented only mild or no pathogenesis of SFTS, limiting their applications in SFTSV infection. Therefore, it is an urgent need to develop a small animal model for the investigation of SFTSV pathogenesis and evaluation of therapeutics. In the current report, we developed a SFTSV infection model based on the HuPBL-NCG mice that recapitulates many pathological characteristics of SFTSV infection in humans. Virus-induced histopathological changes were identified in spleen, lung, kidney, and liver. SFTSV was colocalized with macrophages in the spleen and liver, suggesting that the macrophages in the spleen and liver could be the principle target cells of SFTSV. In addition, histological analysis showed that the vascular endothelium integrity was severely disrupted upon viral infection along with depletion of platelets. In vitro cellular assays further revealed that SFTSV infection increased the vascular permeability of endothelial cells by promoting tyrosine phosphorylation and internalization of the adhesion molecule vascular endothelial (VE)-cadherin, a critical component of endothelial integrity. In addition, we found that both virus infection and pathogen-induced exuberant cytokine release dramatically contributed to the vascular endothelial injury. We elucidated the pathogenic mechanisms of hemorrhage syndrome and developed a humanized mouse model for SFTSV infection, which should be helpful for anti-SFTSV therapy and pathogenesis study.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
