<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Nanomedicine | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/nanomedicine/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/nanomedicine/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Nanomedicine</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Nanomedicine</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/nanomedicine/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extracellular vesicle-encapsulated CC16 as novel nanotherapeutics for treatment of acute lung injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36635966/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36635966/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acute lung injury (ALI) is still associated with high mortality. Growing evidence suggests that Club Cell Protein 16 (CC16) plays a protective role against ALI. However, the doses of recombinant CC16 (rCC16) used in preclinical studies are supraphysiological for clinical applications. Extracellular vesicles (EVs) are nanovesicles endogenously generated by mammalian cells. Our study demonstrated that CC16 is released via small EVs and EV-encapsulated CC16 (sEV-CC16) has anti-inflammatory activities, which protect mice from lipopolysaccharide (LPS) or bacteria-induced ALI. Additionally, sEV-CC16 can activate the DNA damage repair signaling pathways. Consistent with this activity, we observed more severe DNA damage in lungs from Cc16 knockout (KO) than wild-type (WT) mice. Mechanistically, we elucidated that CC16 suppresses NF-κB signaling activation by binding to Heat Shock Protein 60 (HSP60). We concluded that sEV-CC16 could be a potential therapeutic agent for ALI by inhibiting the inflammatory and DNA damage responses by reducing NF-κB signaling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tea leaf-derived exosome-like nanotherapeutics retard breast tumor growth by pro-apoptosis and microbiota modulation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36600299/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36600299/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While several artificial nanodrugs have been approved for clinical treatment of breast tumor, their long-term applications are restricted by unsatisfactory therapeutic outcomes, side reactions and high costs. Conversely, edible plant-derived natural nanotherapeutics (NTs) are source-widespread and cost-effective, which have been shown remarkably effective in disease treatment. Herein, we extracted and purified exosome-like NTs from tea leaves (TLNTs), which had an average diameter of 166.9 nm and a negative-charged surface of - 28.8 mV. These TLNTs contained an adequate slew of functional components such as lipids, proteins and pharmacologically active molecules. In vitro studies indicated that TLNTs were effectively internalized by breast tumor cells (4T1 cells) and caused a 2.5-fold increase in the amount of intracellular reactive oxygen species (ROS) after incubation for 8 h. The high levels of ROS triggered mitochondrial damages and arrested cell cycles, resulting in the apoptosis of tumor cells. The mouse experiments revealed that TLNTs achieved good therapeutic effects against breast tumors regardless of intravenous injection and oral administration through direct pro-apoptosis and microbiota modulation. Strikingly, the intravenous injection of TLNTs, not oral administration, yielded obvious hepatorenal toxicity and immune activation. These findings collectively demonstrate that TLNTs can be developed as a promising oral therapeutic platform for the treatment of breast cancer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lung Organoids for Hazard Assessment of Nanomaterials</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/36555307/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/36555307/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lung epithelial organoids for the hazard assessment of inhaled nanomaterials offer a promising improvement to in vitro culture systems used so far. Organoids grow in three-dimensional (3D) spheres and can be derived from either induced pluripotent stem cells (iPSC) or primary lung tissue stem cells from either human or mouse. In this perspective we will highlight advantages and disadvantages of traditional culture systems frequently used for testing nanomaterials and compare them to lung epithelial organoids. We also discuss the differences between tissue and iPSC-derived organoids and give an outlook in which direction the whole field could possibly go with these versatile tools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blood-brain barrier Permeable nanoparticles for Alzheimer&#39;s disease treatment by selective mitophagy of microglia</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35965114/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35965114/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Current treatments for Alzheimer&amp;rsquo;s disease (AD) that focus on inhibition of Aβ aggregation failed to show effectiveness in people who already had Alzheimer&amp;rsquo;s symptoms. Strategies that synergistically exert neuroprotection and alleviation of oxidative stress could be a promising approach to correct the pathological brain microenvironment. Based on the key roles of microglia in modulation of AD microenvironment, we describe here the development of Prussian blue/polyamidoamine (PAMAM) dendrimer/Angiopep-2 (PPA) nanoparticles that can regulate the mitophagy of microglia as a potential AD treatment. PPA nanoparticles exhibit superior blood-brain barrier (BBB) permeability and exert synergistic effects of ROS scavenging and restoration of mitochondrial function of microglia. PPA nanoparticles effectively reduce neurotoxic Aβ aggregate and rescue the cognitive functions in APP/PS1 model mice. Together, our data suggest that these multifunctional dendrimer nanoparticles exhibit efficient neuroprotection and microglia modulation and can be exploited as a promising approach for the treatment of AD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NIR-driven polydopamine-based nanoenzymes as ROS scavengers to suppress osteoarthritis progression</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/mtnano.2022.100240/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/mtnano.2022.100240/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The excessive reactive oxygen species (ROS) is always associated with the degradation of cartilage matrix during osteoarthritis (OA). The development of novel nanoenzymes with excellent ROS scavenging ability and biosafety shows great potentials for improving OA treatment. Herein a novel functional polydopamine (P) loading with ultrasmall Pt and Cu nanoparticles (P@Pt@Cu) was developed to act as nanoenzymes to scavenge ROS for OA treatment, wherein the excellent catalytic activities of Pt and Cu were employed. Results showed that P@Pt@Cu simultaneously presented obvious enzyme-mimicking properties like superoxide dismutase, catalase, and glutathione peroxidase, leading to excellent antioxidant and anti-inflammatory activities in H2O2 stimulated chondrocytes and OA joints with low cytotoxicity, leading to significant alleviation of OA progression. Besides, near infrared stimulation strengthened the antioxidant and anti-inflammation ability of P@Pt@Cu, resulting in the most prominent therapeutic effects. The proposed polydopamine-based nanoenzymes inspired a novel therapeutic strategy for OA therapy in clinic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tumor-Activatable Nanoparticles Target Low-Density Lipoprotein Receptor to Enhance Drug Delivery and Antitumor Efficacy</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35748191/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35748191/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The binding of plasma proteins to nanomedicines is widely considered detrimental to their delivery to tumors. Here, the design of OxPt/SN38 nanoparticle containing a hydrophilic oxaliplatin (OxPt) prodrug in a coordination polymer core and a hydrophobic cholesterol-conjugated SN38 prodrug on the lipid shell for active tumor targeting is reported. OxPt/SN38 hitchhikes on low-density lipoprotein (LDL) particles, concentrates in tumors via LDL receptor-mediated endocytosis, and selectively releases SN38 and OxPt in acidic, esterase-rich, and reducing tumor microenvironments, leading to 6.0- and 4.9-times higher accumulations in tumors over free drugs. By simultaneously crosslinking DNA and inhibiting topoisomerase I, OxPt/SN38 achieved 92-98% tumor growth inhibition in five colorectal cancer tumor models and prolonged mouse survival by 58-80 days compared to free drug controls in three human colorectal cancer tumor models without causing serious side effects. The study has uncovered a novel nanomedicine strategy to co-deliver combination chemotherapies to tumors via active targeting of the LDL receptor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ROS-responsive polymer nanoparticles with enhanced loading of dexamethasone effectively modulate the lung injury microenvironment</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35724918/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35724918/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The acute lung injury (ALI) is an inflammatory disorder associated with cytokine storm, which activates various reactive oxygen species (ROS) signaling pathways and causes severe complications in patients as currently seen in coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19). There is an urgent need for medication of the inflammatory lung environment and effective delivery of drugs to lung to reduce the burden of high doses of medications and attenuate inflammatory cells and pathways. Herein, we prepared dexamethasone-loaded ROS-responsive polymer nanoparticles (PFTU@DEX NPs) by a modified emulsion approach, which achieved high loading content of DEX (11.61 %). DEX was released faster from the PFTU@DEX NPs in a ROS environment, which could scavenge excessive ROS efficiently both &lt;em&gt;in vitro&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt;. The PFTU NPs and PFTU@DEX NPs showed no hemolysis and cytotoxicity. Free DEX, PFTU NPs and PFTU@DEX NPs shifted M1 macrophages to M2 macrophages in RAW264.7 cells, and showed anti-inflammatory modulation to A549 cells &lt;em&gt;in vitro&lt;/em&gt;. The PFTU@DEX NPs treatment significantly reduced the increased total protein concentration in BALF of ALI mice. The delivery of PFTU@DEX NPs decreased the proportion of neutrophils significantly, mitigated the cell apoptosis remarkably compared to the other groups, reduced M1 macrophages and increased M2 macrophages &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt;. Moreover, the PFTU@DEX NPs had the strongest ability to suppress the expression of NLRP3, Caspase1, and IL-1β. Therefore, the PFTU@DEX NPs could efficiently suppress inflammatory cells, ROS signaling pathways, and cell apoptosis to ameliorate LPS-induced ALI. STATEMENT OF SIGNIFICANCE: The acute lung injury (ALI) is an inflammatory disorder associated with cytokine storm, which activates various reactive oxygen species (ROS) signaling pathways and causes severe complications in patients. There is an urgent need for medication of the inflammatory lung environment and effective delivery of drugs to modulate the inflammatory disorder and suppress the expression of ROS and inflammatory cytokines. The inhaled PFTU@DEX NPs prepared through a modified nanoemulsification method suppressed the activation of NLRP3, induced the polarization of macrophage phenotype from M1 to M2, and thereby reduced the neutrophil infiltration, inhibited the release of proteins and inflammatory mediators, and thus decreased the acute lung injury &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Uptake of Functional Ultrasmall Gold Nanoparticles in 3D Gut Cell Models</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35712760/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35712760/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ultrasmall gold nanoparticles (2 nm) easily penetrate the membranes of intestinal murine epithelial cells (MODE-K) and colorectal cancer cells (CT-26). They are also taken up by 3D spheroids (400 µm) of these cell types and primary gut organoids (500 µm). In contrast, dissolved dyes are not taken up by any of these cells or 3D structures. The distribution of fluorescent ultrasmall gold nanoparticles inside cells, spheroids, and gut organoids is examined by confocal laser scanning microscopy. Nanoparticles conjugated with the cytostatic drug doxorubicin and a fluorescent dye exhibit significantly greater cytotoxicity toward CT-26 tumor spheroids than equally concentrated dissolved doxorubicin, probably because they enter the interior of a spheroid much more easily than dissolved doxorubicin. Comprehensive analyses show that the cellular uptake of ultrasmall gold nanoparticles occurs by different endocytosis pathways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A novel inhalable quercetin-alginate nanogel as a promising therapy for acute lung injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35690763/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35690763/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Acute lung injury (ALI), a severe health-threatening disease, has a risk of causing chronic pulmonary fibrosis. Informative and powerful evidence suggests that inflammation and oxidative stress play a central role in the pathogenesis of ALI. Quercetin is well recognized for its excellent antioxidant and anti-inflammatory properties, which showed great potential for ALI treatment. However, the application of quercetin is often hindered by its low solubility and bioavailability. Therefore, to overcome these challenges, an inhalable quercetin-alginate nanogel (QU-Nanogel) was fabricated, and by this special &amp;ldquo;material-drug&amp;rdquo; structure, the solubility and bioavailability of quercetin were significantly enhanced, which could further increase the activity of quercetin and provide a promising therapy for ALI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; QU-Nanogel is a novel alginate and quercetin based &amp;ldquo;material-drug&amp;rdquo; structural inhalable nanogel, in which quercetin was stabilized by hydrogen bonding to obtain a &amp;ldquo;co-construct&amp;rdquo; water-soluble nanogel system, showing antioxidant and anti-inflammatory properties. QU-Nanogel has an even distribution in size of less than 100 nm and good biocompatibility, which shows a stronger protective and antioxidant effect in vitro. Tissue distribution results provided evidence that the QU-Nanogel by ultrasonic aerosol inhalation is a feasible approach to targeted pulmonary drug delivery. Moreover, QU-Nanogel was remarkably reversed ALI rats by relieving oxidative stress damage and acting the down-regulation effects of mRNA and protein expression of inflammation cytokines via ultrasonic aerosol inhalation administration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; In the ALI rat model, this novel nanogel showed an excellent therapeutic effect by ultrasonic aerosol inhalation administration by protecting and reducing pulmonary inflammation, thereby preventing subsequent pulmonary fibrosis. This work demonstrates that this inhalable QU-Nanogel may function as a promising drug delivery strategy in treating ALI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Novel Drug Delivery Technologies and Targets for Renal Disease</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/35652363/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/35652363/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The burden of acute and chronic kidney diseases to the health care system is exacerbated by the high mortality that this disease carries paired with the still limited availability of comprehensive therapies. A reason partially resides in the complexity of the kidney, with multiple potential target cell types and a complex structural environment that complicate strategies to protect and recover renal function after injury. Management of both acute and chronic renal disease, irrespective of the cause, are mainly focused on supportive treatments and renal replacement strategies when needed. Emerging preclinical evidence supports the feasibility of drug delivery technology for the kidney, and recent studies have contributed to building a robust catalog of peptides, proteins, nanoparticles, liposomes, extracellular vesicles, and other carriers that may be fused to therapeutic peptides, proteins, nucleic acids, or small molecule drugs. These fusions can display a precise renal uptake, an enhanced circulating time, and a directed intraorgan biodistribution while protecting their cargo to improve therapeutic efficacy. However, several hurdles that slow the transition towards clinical applications are still in the way, such as solubility, toxicity, and sub-optimal renal targeting. This review will discuss the feasibility and current limitations of drug delivery technologies for the treatment of renal disease, offering an update on their potential and the future directions of these promising strategies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Perspectives of using microRNA-loaded nanocarriers for epigenetic reprogramming of drug resistant colorectal cancers</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/35623562/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/35623562/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Epigenetic regulation by microRNAs (miRs) demonstrated a promising therapeutic potential of these molecules to regulate genetic activity in different cancers, including colorectal cancers (CRCs). The RNA-based therapy does not change genetic codes in tumor cells but can silence oncogenes and/or reactivate inhibited tumor suppressor genes. In many cancers, specific miRs were shown to promote or stop tumor progression. Among confirmed and powerful epigenetic regulators of colon carcinogenesis and development of resistance are onco-miRs, which include let-7, miR-21, miR-22, miR-23a, miR-27a, miR-34, miR-92, miR-96, miR-125b, miR-135b, miR-182, miR-200c, miR-203, miR-221, miR-421, miR-451, and others. Moreover, various tumor-suppressor miRs (miR-15b-5b, miR-18a, miR-20b, miR-22, miR-96, miR-139-5p, miR-145, miR-149, miR-197, miR-199b, miR-203, miR-214, miR-218, miR-320, miR-375-3p, miR-409-3p, miR-450b-5p, miR-494, miR-577, miR-874, and others) were found silenced in drug-resistant CRCs. Re-expression of tumor suppressor miR is complicated by the chemical nature of miRs that are not long-lasting compounds and require protection from the enzymatic degradation. Several recent studies explored application of miRs using nanocarrier complexes. This study critically describes the most successfully tested nanoparticle complexes used for intracellular delivery of nuclear acids and miRs, including micelles, liposomes, inorganic and polymeric NPs, dendrimers, and aptamers. Nanocarriers shield incorporated miRs and improve the agent stability in circulation. Attachment of antibodies and/or specific peptide or ligands facilitates cell-targeted miR delivery. Addressing in vivo challenges, a broad spectrum of non-toxic materials has been tested and indicated reliable advantages of lipid-based (lipoplexes) and polymer-based liposomes. Recent cutting-edge developments indicated that lipid-based complexes with multiple cargo, including several miRs, are the most effective approach to eradicate drug-resistant tumors. Focusing on CRC-specific miRs, this review provides a guidance and insights towards the most promising direction to achieve dramatic reduction in tumor growth and metastasis using miR-nanocarrier complexes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plasma-Enabled Smart Nanoexosome Platform as Emerging Immunopathogenesis for Clinical Viral Infection</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/35631640/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/35631640/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Smart nanoexosomes are nanosized structures enclosed in lipid bilayers that are structurally similar to the viruses released by a variety of cells, including the cells lining the respiratory system. Of particular importance, the interaction between smart nanoexosomes and viruses can be used to develop antiviral drugs and vaccines. It is possible that nanoexosomes will be utilized and antibodies will be acquired more successfully for the transmission of an immune response if reconvalescent plasma (CP) is used instead of reconvalescent plasma exosomes (CPExo) in this concept. Convalescent plasma contains billions of smart nanoexosomes capable of transporting a variety of molecules, including proteins, lipids, RNA and DNA among other viral infections. Smart nanoexosomes are released from virus-infected cells and play an important role in mediating communication between infected and uninfected cells. Infections use the formation, production and release of smart nanoexosomes to enhance the infection, transmission and intercellular diffusion of viruses. Cell-free smart nanoexosomes produced by mesenchymal stem cells (MSCs) could also be used as cell-free therapies in certain cases. Smart nanoexosomes produced by mesenchymal stem cells can also promote mitochondrial function and heal lung injury. They can reduce cytokine storms and restore the suppression of host antiviral defenses weakened by viral infections. This study examines the benefits of smart nanoexosomes and their roles in viral transmission, infection, treatment, drug delivery and clinical applications. We also explore some potential future applications for smart nanoexosomes in the treatment of viral infections.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sorafenib-loaded silica-containing redox nanoparticles for oral anti-liver fibrosis therapy</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35395328/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35395328/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Liver fibrosis is a chronic disease resulting from repetitive or prolonged liver injury with limited treatment options. Sorafenib has been reported to be a potential antifibrotic agent; however, its therapeutic effect is restricted because of its low bioavailability and severe adverse effects in the gastrointestinal (GI) tract. In this study, we developed sorafenib-loaded silica-containing redox nanoparticles (sora@siRNP) as an oral nanomedicine to treat liver fibrosis. The designed siRNP were prepared by self-assembly of amphiphilic block copolymers, which possess antioxidant nitroxide radicals as a side chain of the hydrophobic segment and porous silica particles in the nanoparticle core. The silica moieties in the core formed a crosslink between the self-assembling block copolymers to afford stable drug absorption, which could be useful in harsh GI conditions after oral drug administration. Based on in vitro evaluation, sora@siRNP exerted antiproliferative and antifibrotic effects against hepatic stellate cells (HSCs) and low toxicity against normal endothelial cells. A pharmacokinetic study showed that siRNP significantly improved the bioavailability and distribution of sorafenib in the liver. In an in vivo study using a mouse model of CCl&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;-induced liver fibrosis, oral administration of sora@siRNP significantly suppressed the fibrotic area in comparison to free sorafenib administration. In mice with CCl&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;-induced fibrosis, free sorafenib administration did not suppress the expression of α-smooth muscle actin; however, mice treated with sora@siRNP showed significantly suppressed expression of α-smooth muscle actin, indicating the inhibition of HSC activation, which was confirmed by in vitro experiments. Moreover, oral administration of free sorafenib induced severe intestinal damage and increased leakage into the gut, which can be attributed to the generation of reactive oxygen species (ROS). Our antioxidant nanocarriers, siRNP, reduced the adverse effects of local ROS scavenging in the GI tract. Our results suggest that sora@siRNP could serve as a promising oral nanomedicine for liver fibrosis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Red blood cell-hitchhiking mediated pulmonary delivery of ivermectin: Effects of nanoparticle properties</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35390488/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35390488/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ivermectin-loaded nanoparticles were delivered to lungs through adsorption on RBCs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RBC-hitchhiking strategy improved ivermectin pharmacokinetics and bioavailability.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nanoparticle properties affected the characteristics of RBC-nanoparticles &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recent studies have demonstrated that ivermectin (IVM) exhibits antiviral activity against severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 (SARS-CoV-2), the causative virus of coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19). However, the repurposing of IVM for the treatment of COVID-19 has presented challenges primarily due to the low IVM plasma concentration after oral administration, which was well below IC50. Here, a red blood cell (RBC)-hitchhiking strategy was used for the targeted delivery of IVM-loaded nanoparticles (NPs) to the lung. IVM-loaded poly (lactic-co-glycolic acid) (PLGA) NPs (IVM-PNPs) and chitosan-coating IVM-PNPs (IVM-CSPNPs) were prepared and adsorbed onto RBCs. Both RBC-hitchhiked IVM-PNPs and IVM-CSPNPs could significantly enhance IVM delivery to lungs, improve IVM accumulation in lung tissue, inhibit the inflammatory responses and finally significantly alleviate the progression of acute lung injury. Specifically, the redistribution and circulation effects were related to the properties of NPs. RBC-hitchhiked cationic IVM-CSPNPs showed a longer circulation time, slower accumulation and elimination rates, and higher anti-inflammatory activities than RBC-hitchhiked anionic IVM-PNPs. Therefore, RBC-hitchhiking provides an alternative strategy to improve IVM pharmacokinetics and bioavailability for repurposing of IVM to treat COVID-19. Furthermore, according to different redistribution effects of different NPs, RBC-hitchhiked NPs may achieve various accumulation rates and circulation times for different requirements of drug delivery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In vivo self-assembled drug nanocrystals for metastatic breast cancer all-stage targeted therapy</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35378211/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35378211/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chemotherapy is still the mainstay treatment for metastatic triple-negative breast cancers (TNBC) currently in clinical practice. The unmet needs of chemotherapy for metastatic TNBC are mainly from the insufficient drug delivery and unavailable targeting strategy that thwart the whole progression of metastatic TNBC. The in vivo ligands-mediated active targeting efficiency is usually affected by protein corona. While, the protein corona-bridged natural targeting, in turn, provides a new way for specific drug delivery. Herein, we develop a novel metastatic progression-oriented in vivo self-assembled Cabazitaxel nanocrystals (CNC) delivery system (PC/CNC) through the CNC automatically absorbing functional plasma proteins (transferrin, apolipoprotein A-IV and apolipoprotein E) in vivo, aiming to achieve the simultaneously targeted delivery to primary tumors, circulating tumor cells and metastatic lesions. With the unique advantages of superhigh drug-loading and protein corona empowered active targeting properties to tumor cells, HUVECs, active-platelets and blood-brain barrier/blood-tumor barrier, the PC/CNC exhibits a significantly improved therapeutic effect in metastatic TNBC therapy compared with free drug and CNC-loaded liposomes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mannan-decorated pathogen-like polymeric nanoparticles as nanovaccine carriers for eliciting superior anticancer immunity</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35364489/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35364489/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using nanotechnology for cancer vaccine design holds great promise because of the intrinsic feature of nanoparticles in being captured by antigen-presenting cells (APCs). However, there are still obstacles in current nanovaccine systems in achieving efficient tumor therapeutic effects, which could partially be attributed to the unsatisfactory vaccine carrier design. Herein, we report a mannan-decorated pathogen-like polymeric nanoparticle as a protein vaccine carrier for eliciting robust anticancer immunity. This nanovaccine was constructed as a core-shell structure with mannan as the shell, polylactic acid-polyethylenimine (PLA-PEI) assembled nanoparticle as the core, and protein antigens and Toll-like receptor 9 (TLR9) agonist CpG absorbed onto the PLA-PEI core via electrostatic interactions. Compared to other hydrophilic materials, mannan decoration could greatly enhance the lymph node draining ability of the nanovaccine and promote the capturing by the CD8&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; dendritic cells (DCs) in the lymph node, while PLA-PEI as the inner core could enhance antigen endosome escape thus promoting the antigen cross-presentation. In addition, mannan itself as a TLR4 agonist could synergize with CpG for maximally activating the DCs. Excitingly, we observed in several murine tumor models that using this nanovaccine alone could elicit robust immune response in vivo and result in superior anti-tumor effects with 50% of mice completely cured. This study strongly evidenced that mannan decoration and a rationally designed nanovaccine system could be quite robust in tumor vaccine therapy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nanotechnology-based therapeutics for targeting inflammatory lung diseases</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/35315290/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/35315290/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nanoformulation of a carbon monoxide releasing molecule protects against cyclosporin A-induced nephrotoxicity and renal fibrosis via the suppression of the NLRP3 inflammasome mediated TGF-β/Smad pathway</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35304324/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35304324/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cyclosporin A (CsA) induced nephrotoxicity i.e., renal fibrosis is a critical clinical problem in renal transplant patients, in which chronic inflammatory response is the major cause. Previously, we developed a nano-drug delivery system for carbon monoxide (CO), a multi-functional gaseous molecule with a potent anti-inflammatory effect, i.e., SMA/CORM2, which showed therapeutic potential in several inflammatory disease models. Accordingly, in this study, we explored the potential and usefulness of SMA/CORM2 on CsA induced renal fibrosis. When mice were exposed to CsA for 4 weeks, severe injuries in the kidney as revealed by decreased kidney function and histological examination, and activation of NLRP3 inflammasome, as well as renal fibrosis along with the upregulation of transforming growth factor β (TGFβ)/Smad signaling molecule were observed, whereas SMA/CORM2 (1 mg/kg) treatment remarkably ameliorated the inflammatory injury and fibrosis in the kidney. CO is the major effector molecule of SMA/CORM2 which significantly suppressed the activation of NLRP3 inflammasome, and induced the downregulation of TGFβ/Smad signaling. Inhibition of NLRP3 inflammasome by its inhibitor MCC950 also similarly decreased TGFβ/Smad expression and subsequently improved kidney injury and renal fibrosis, suggesting SMA/CORM2 induced suppression of TGFβ/Smad signaling and renal signaling via an NLRP3 inflammasome-dependent pathway. Compared to native CORM2, SMA/CORM2 exhibited better therapeutic/preventive effects owing to its superior water-solubility and bioavailability. These findings strongly indicated the applicability of SMA/CORM2 as an enhanced permeability and retention (EPR) effect-based nanomedicine for CsA induced renal fibrosis as well as other inflammatory diseases. STATEMENT OF SIGNIFICANCE: Carbon monoxide (CO) is an important gaseous signaling molecule that plays a crucial role in the maintenance of homeostasis. Because of its versatile functions, it exhibits the potential as the target molecule for many diseases, including inflammatory diseases and cancer. The development of stable and disease-targeted delivery systems of CO is thus of interest and importance. Previously we developed a nano micellar CO donor SMA/CORM2 which shows superior bioavailability and therapeutic potential in many inflammatory disease models. We reported here, SMA/CORM2, through controlled release of CO, greatly ameliorated CsA-induced renal fibrosis via suppressing the NLRP3 inflammasome mediated TGF-β/Smad pathway. These findings suggest a new anti-inflammatory mechanism of CO, which also provides a new approach for controlling CsA-induced nephrotoxicity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dexamethasone-loaded ROS-responsive poly(thioketal) nanoparticles suppress inflammation and oxidative stress of acute lung injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35415281/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35415281/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A therapeutic nanoplatform with ROS-responsiveness was developed for the regulation of inflammation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;NPs composed of low Mw of PPADT and high Mw of PTKU were loaded with dexamethasone to obtain a self-adaptive system.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Dex-loaded NPs significantly decreased lung inflammation, and reduced lung injury and mortality &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acute lung injury (ALI) is associated with excessive inflammatory response, leading to acute respiratory distress syndrome (ARDS) without timely treatment. A fewer effective drugs are available currently to treat the ALI/ARDS. Herein, a therapeutic nanoplatform with reactive oxygen species (ROS)-responsiveness was developed for the regulation of inflammation. Dexamethasone acetate (Dex) was encapsulated into poly(thioketal) polymers to form polymeric nanoparticles (NPs) (PTKNPs@Dex). The NPs were composed of poly(1,4-phenyleneacetonedimethylene thioketal) (PPADT) and polythioketal urethane (PTKU), in which the thioketal bonds could be cleaved by the high level of ROS at the ALI site. The PTKNPs@Dex could accumulate in the pulmonary inflammatory sites and release the encapsulated payloads rapidly, leading to the decreased ROS level, less generation of pro-inflammatory cytokines, and reduced lung injury and mortality of mice. RNA sequencing (RNA-seq) analysis showed that the therapeutic efficacy of the NPs was associated with the modulation of many immune and inflammation-linked pathways. These findings provide a newly developed nanoplatform for the efficient treatment of ALI/ARDS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nanotopography Sequentially Mediates Human Mesenchymal Stem Cell-Derived Small Extracellular Vesicles for Enhancing Osteogenesis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34935354/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34935354/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Engineered small extracellular vesicles (sEVs) are used as tools to enhance therapeutic efficacy. However, such application of sEVs is associated with several issues, including high costs and a high risk of tumorigenesis. Nanotopography has a greater influence on bone-related cell behaviors. However, whether nanotopography specifically mediate sEV content to perform particular biological functions remains unclear. Here, we demonstrate that selective nanotopography may be used to sequentially mediate human bone mesenchymal stem cell (hBMSC) sEVs to enhance the therapeutic efficacy of hBMSCs-EVs for osteogenesis. We subjected sEVs harvested from hBMSCs cultured on polished titanium plates (Ti) or nanotopographical titanium plates (Ti4) after 7, 14, and 21 d for RNA sequencing, and we found that there was no significant difference in sEV-miRNA expression after 7 d. Differentially expressed osteogenic-related microRNAs were founded after 14 days, and KEGG analysis indicated that the main microRNAs were associated with osteogenesis-related pathways, such as TGF-beta, AMPK, and FoxO. A significant difference was found in sEV-miRNAs expression after 21 d. We loaded sEV secreted from hBMSCs cultured on Ti4 after 21 d on 3D-printed porous PEEK scaffolds with poly dopamine (PDA) and found that such scaffolds showed superior osteogenic ability after 6- and 12-weeks. Here, we demonstrate the alkali- and heat-treated nanotopography with the ability of stimulating osteogenic differentiation of hBMSC can induce the secretion of pro-osteogenesis sEV, and we also found that sEVs meditate osteogenesis through miRNA. Thus, whether nanotopography has the ability to regulate other contents of sEVs such as proteins for enhancing osteogenesis needs further research. These findings may help us use nanotopography to extract sEVs for other biomedical applications, including cancer therapy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multifunctional Magnesium Organic Framework-Based Microneedle Patch for Accelerating Diabetic Wound Healing</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34761898/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34761898/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Diabetic wound healing is one of the major challenges in the biomedical fields. The conventional single drug treatments have unsatisfactory efficacy, and the drug delivery effectiveness is restricted by the penetration depth. Herein, we develop a magnesium organic framework-based microneedle patch (denoted as MN-MOF-GO-Ag) that can realize transdermal delivery and combination therapy for diabetic wound healing. Multifunctional magnesium organic frameworks (Mg-MOFs) are mixed with poly(γ-glutamic acid) (γ-PGA) hydrogel and loaded into the tips of MN-MOF-GO-Ag, which slowly releases Mg2+ and gallic acid in the deep layer of the dermis. The released Mg2+ induces cell migration and endothelial tubulogenesis, while gallic acid, a reactive oxygen species-scavenger, promotes antioxidation. Besides, the backing layer of MN-MOF-GO-Ag is made of γ-PGA hydrogel and graphene oxide-silver nanocomposites (GO-Ag) which further enables excellent antibacterial effects for accelerating wound healing. The therapeutic effects of MN-MOF-GO-Ag on wound healing are demonstrated with the full-thickness cutaneous wounds of a diabetic mouse model. The significant improvement of wound healing is achieved for mice treated with MN-MOF-GO-Ag.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A DNA Nanoraft-Based Cytokine Delivery Platform for Alleviation of Acute Kidney Injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34723467/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34723467/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Erratum in:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Correction to “&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubs.acs.org/doi/10.1021/acsnano.2c02862&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;A DNA Nanoraft-Based Cytokine Delivery Platform for Alleviation of Acute Kidney Injury&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cytokine immunotherapy represents an attractive strategy to stimulate robust immune responses for renal injury repair in ischemic acute kidney injury (AKI). However, its clinical application is hindered by its nonspecificity to kidney, short circulation half-life, and severe side effects. An ideal cytokine immunotherapy for AKI requires preferential delivery of cytokines with accurate dosage to the kidney and sustained-release of cytokines to stimulate the immune responses. Herein, we developed a DNA nanoraft cytokine by precisely arranging interleukin-33 (IL-33) nanoarray on rectangle DNA origami, through which IL-33 can be preferentially delivered to the kidney for alleviation of AKI. A nanoraft carrying precisely quantified IL-33 predominantly accumulated in the kidney for up to 48 h. Long-term sustained-release of IL-33 from nanoraft induced rapid expansion of type 2 innate lymphoid cells (ILC 2s) and regulatory T cells (Tregs) and achieved better treatment efficiency compared to free IL-33 treatment. Thus, our study demonstrates that a nanoraft can serve as a structurally well-defined delivery platform for cytokine immunotherapy in ischemic AKI and other renal diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multifaceted roles of a bioengineered nanoreactor in repressing radiation-induced lung injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34478930/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34478930/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Radiation-induced lung injury (RILI) is a potentially fatal and dose-limiting complication of thoracic cancer radiotherapy. However, effective therapeutic agents for this condition are limited. Here, we describe a novel strategy to exert additive effects of a non-erythropoietic EPO derivative (ARA290), along with a free radical scavenger, superoxide dismutase (SOD), using a bioengineered nanoreactor (SOD@ARA290-HBc). ARA290-chimeric nanoreactor makes SOD present in a confined reaction space by encapsulation into its interior to heighten stability against denaturing stimuli. In a RILI mouse model, intratracheal administration of SOD@ARA290-HBc was shown to significantly ameliorate acute radiation pneumonitis and pulmonary fibrosis. Our investigations revealed that SOD@ARA290-HBc performs its radioprotective effects by protecting against radiation induced alveolar epithelial cell apoptosis and ferroptosis, suppressing oxidative stress, inhibiting inflammation and by modulating the infiltrated macrophage phenotype, or through a combination of these mechanisms. In conclusion, SOD@ARA29-HBc is a potential therapeutic agent for RILI, and given its multifaceted roles, it may be further developed as a translational nanomedicine for other related disorders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
