<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Nanomedicine | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/nanomedicine/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/nanomedicine/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Nanomedicine</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Nanomedicine</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/nanomedicine/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extracellular vesicle-encapsulated CC16 as novel nanotherapeutics for treatment of acute lung injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36635966/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36635966/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acute lung injury (ALI) is still associated with high mortality. Growing evidence suggests that Club Cell Protein 16 (CC16) plays a protective role against ALI. However, the doses of recombinant CC16 (rCC16) used in preclinical studies are supraphysiological for clinical applications. Extracellular vesicles (EVs) are nanovesicles endogenously generated by mammalian cells. Our study demonstrated that CC16 is released via small EVs and EV-encapsulated CC16 (sEV-CC16) has anti-inflammatory activities, which protect mice from lipopolysaccharide (LPS) or bacteria-induced ALI. Additionally, sEV-CC16 can activate the DNA damage repair signaling pathways. Consistent with this activity, we observed more severe DNA damage in lungs from Cc16 knockout (KO) than wild-type (WT) mice. Mechanistically, we elucidated that CC16 suppresses NF-κB signaling activation by binding to Heat Shock Protein 60 (HSP60). We concluded that sEV-CC16 could be a potential therapeutic agent for ALI by inhibiting the inflammatory and DNA damage responses by reducing NF-κB signaling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tumor-Activatable Nanoparticles Target Low-Density Lipoprotein Receptor to Enhance Drug Delivery and Antitumor Efficacy</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35748191/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35748191/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The binding of plasma proteins to nanomedicines is widely considered detrimental to their delivery to tumors. Here, the design of OxPt/SN38 nanoparticle containing a hydrophilic oxaliplatin (OxPt) prodrug in a coordination polymer core and a hydrophobic cholesterol-conjugated SN38 prodrug on the lipid shell for active tumor targeting is reported. OxPt/SN38 hitchhikes on low-density lipoprotein (LDL) particles, concentrates in tumors via LDL receptor-mediated endocytosis, and selectively releases SN38 and OxPt in acidic, esterase-rich, and reducing tumor microenvironments, leading to 6.0- and 4.9-times higher accumulations in tumors over free drugs. By simultaneously crosslinking DNA and inhibiting topoisomerase I, OxPt/SN38 achieved 92-98% tumor growth inhibition in five colorectal cancer tumor models and prolonged mouse survival by 58-80 days compared to free drug controls in three human colorectal cancer tumor models without causing serious side effects. The study has uncovered a novel nanomedicine strategy to co-deliver combination chemotherapies to tumors via active targeting of the LDL receptor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
