<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Nanomedicine | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/nanomedicine/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/nanomedicine/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Nanomedicine</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Nanomedicine</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/nanomedicine/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Thrombin-Activated Peptide-Templated Nanozyme for Remedying Ischemic Stroke Via Thrombolytic and Neuroprotective Actions</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36730098/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36730098/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ischemic stroke (IS) is one of the most common causes of disability and death. Thrombolysis and neuroprotection are two current major therapeutic strategies to overcome the ischemic and reperfusion damages. Here, we have designed a novel peptide-templated MnO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; nanozyme (PNzyme/MnO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;) that integrates the thrombolytic activity of the functional peptides with the ROS scavenging ability of the nanozyme. Through the self-assembled polypeptides that contains multiple functional motifs, the novel peptide-templated nanozyme is able to bind fibrin in the thrombus, cross blood brain barrier, and finally accumulate in the ischemic neuronal tissues, where the thrombolytic motif is &amp;ldquo;switch-on&amp;rdquo; by the action of thrombin. In mice and rat IS models, the PNzyme/MnO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; prolonged blood circulation time and exhibited strong thrombolytic action, and reduced the ischemic damages in brain tissues. Moreover, this peptide-templated nanozyme also effectively inhibited the activation of astrocytes and the secretion of pro-inflammatory cytokines. These data indicated that rationally designed PNzyme/MnO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; nanozyme exerts both thrombolytic and neuroprotective actions. Giving its long half-life in the blood and ability to target brain thrombi, the biocompatible nanozyme may serve as a novel therapeutic agent to improve the efficacy and prevent secondary thrombosis during the treatment of IS. This article is protected by copyright. All rights reserved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rapidly Blocking the Calcium Overload/ROS Production Feedback Loop to Alleviate Acute Kidney Injury via Microenvironment-Responsive BAPTA-AM/BAC Co-Delivery Nanosystem</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36719986/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36719986/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Calcium overload and ROS overproduction, two major triggers of acute kidney injury (AKI), are self-amplifying and mutually reinforcing, forming a complicated cascading feedback loop that induces kidney cell &amp;ldquo;suicide&amp;rdquo; and ultimately renal failure. There are currently no clinically effective drugs for the treatment of AKI, excluding adjuvant therapy. In this study, a porous silicon-based nanocarrier rich in disulfide bond skeleton (&amp;lt;50 nm) is developed that enables efficient co-loading of the hydrophilic drug borane amino complex and the hydrophobic drug BAPTA-AM, with its outer layer sealed by the renal tubule-targeting peptide PEG-LTH. Once targeted to the kidney injured site, the nanocarrier structure collapses in the high glutathione environment of the early stage of AKI, releasing the drugs. Under the action of the slightly acidic inflammatory environment and intracellular esterase, the released drugs produce hydrogen and BAPTA, which can rapidly eliminate the excess ROS and overloaded Ca2+ , blocking endoplasmic reticulum/mitochondrial apoptosis pathway (ATF4-CHOP-Bax axis, Casp-12-Casp-3 axis, Cyt-C-Casp-3 axis) and inflammatory pathway (TNF-α-NF-κB axis) from the source, thus rescuing the renal cells in the &amp;ldquo;critical survival&amp;rdquo; state and further restoring the kidney function. Overall, this nanoparticle shows substantial clinical promise as a potential therapeutic strategy for I/R injury-related diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extracellular vesicle-encapsulated CC16 as novel nanotherapeutics for treatment of acute lung injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36635966/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36635966/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acute lung injury (ALI) is still associated with high mortality. Growing evidence suggests that Club Cell Protein 16 (CC16) plays a protective role against ALI. However, the doses of recombinant CC16 (rCC16) used in preclinical studies are supraphysiological for clinical applications. Extracellular vesicles (EVs) are nanovesicles endogenously generated by mammalian cells. Our study demonstrated that CC16 is released via small EVs and EV-encapsulated CC16 (sEV-CC16) has anti-inflammatory activities, which protect mice from lipopolysaccharide (LPS) or bacteria-induced ALI. Additionally, sEV-CC16 can activate the DNA damage repair signaling pathways. Consistent with this activity, we observed more severe DNA damage in lungs from Cc16 knockout (KO) than wild-type (WT) mice. Mechanistically, we elucidated that CC16 suppresses NF-κB signaling activation by binding to Heat Shock Protein 60 (HSP60). We concluded that sEV-CC16 could be a potential therapeutic agent for ALI by inhibiting the inflammatory and DNA damage responses by reducing NF-κB signaling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ZIF-8 Nanoparticles Evoke Pyroptosis for High-Efficiency Cancer Immunotherapy</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36629270/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36629270/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although zeolitic imidazolate framework-8 (ZIF-8) has been applied in various tumor therapies, the intrinsic immunogenicity remains unclear. Here, we initiatively discover that ZIF-8 nanoparticles (NPs) can intrinsically induce pyroptosis by a caspase-1/gasdermin D (GSDMD)-dependent pathway. The pyroptotic cell death is accompanied by necrosis and immunogenic cell death (ICD) simultaneously for efficient in situ immunity initiation. Meanwhile, carbonyl cyanide m-chlorophenyl hydrazone (CCCP), a mitochondrial depolarizing agent, is successfully loaded into ZIF-8 NPs and found to further enhance the pyroptosis process. Collectively, the obtained Pluronic F127-modified CCCP-incorporated ZIF-8 NPs (F127ZIF-8CCCP NPs) activate antitumor immunity and reprogram immunosuppressive tumor microenvironment (TME), realizing high-efficiency tumor growth inhibition. This work will facilitate biomedicine applications of ZIF-8 and provide good inspiration for pyroptosis-induced cancer therapy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tea leaf-derived exosome-like nanotherapeutics retard breast tumor growth by pro-apoptosis and microbiota modulation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36600299/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36600299/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While several artificial nanodrugs have been approved for clinical treatment of breast tumor, their long-term applications are restricted by unsatisfactory therapeutic outcomes, side reactions and high costs. Conversely, edible plant-derived natural nanotherapeutics (NTs) are source-widespread and cost-effective, which have been shown remarkably effective in disease treatment. Herein, we extracted and purified exosome-like NTs from tea leaves (TLNTs), which had an average diameter of 166.9 nm and a negative-charged surface of - 28.8 mV. These TLNTs contained an adequate slew of functional components such as lipids, proteins and pharmacologically active molecules. In vitro studies indicated that TLNTs were effectively internalized by breast tumor cells (4T1 cells) and caused a 2.5-fold increase in the amount of intracellular reactive oxygen species (ROS) after incubation for 8 h. The high levels of ROS triggered mitochondrial damages and arrested cell cycles, resulting in the apoptosis of tumor cells. The mouse experiments revealed that TLNTs achieved good therapeutic effects against breast tumors regardless of intravenous injection and oral administration through direct pro-apoptosis and microbiota modulation. Strikingly, the intravenous injection of TLNTs, not oral administration, yielded obvious hepatorenal toxicity and immune activation. These findings collectively demonstrate that TLNTs can be developed as a promising oral therapeutic platform for the treatment of breast cancer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Regulatory Fibroblast-Like Synoviocytes Cell Membrane Coated Nanoparticles: A Novel Targeted Therapy for Rheumatoid Arthritis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36509660/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36509660/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fibroblast-like synoviocytes (FLS) are the main cell component in the inflamed joints of patients with rheumatoid arthritis (RA). FLS intimately interact with infiltrating T cells. Fibroblasts have potent inhibitory effects on T cells, leading to the resolution of inflammation and immune tolerance. However, this &amp;ldquo;regulatory&amp;rdquo; phenotype is defect in RA, and FLS in RA instead act as &amp;ldquo;proinflammatory&amp;rdquo; phenotype mediating inflammation perpetuation. Signals that orchestrate fibroblast heterogeneity remain unclear. Here, it is demonstrated that different cytokines can induce distinct phenotypes of FLS. Interferon-gamma (IFN-γ) is pivotal in inducing the regulatory phenotype of FLS (which is termed FLSreg ) characterized by high expressions of several inhibitory molecules. Rapamycin enhances the effect of IFN-γ on FLS. Based on the characteristics of FLSreg , a novel biomimetic therapeutic strategy for RA is designed by coating cell membrane derived from FLSreg induced by IFN-γ and rapamycin on nanoparticles, which is called FIRN. FIRN show good efficacy, stability, and inflammatory joint targeting ability in an RA mouse model. The findings clarify how fibroblast phenotypes are modulated in the inflammatory microenvironment and provide insights into novel therapeutic designs for autoimmune diseases based on regulatory fibroblasts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lung Organoids for Hazard Assessment of Nanomaterials</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/36555307/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/36555307/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lung epithelial organoids for the hazard assessment of inhaled nanomaterials offer a promising improvement to in vitro culture systems used so far. Organoids grow in three-dimensional (3D) spheres and can be derived from either induced pluripotent stem cells (iPSC) or primary lung tissue stem cells from either human or mouse. In this perspective we will highlight advantages and disadvantages of traditional culture systems frequently used for testing nanomaterials and compare them to lung epithelial organoids. We also discuss the differences between tissue and iPSC-derived organoids and give an outlook in which direction the whole field could possibly go with these versatile tools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blood-brain barrier Permeable nanoparticles for Alzheimer&#39;s disease treatment by selective mitophagy of microglia</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35965114/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35965114/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Current treatments for Alzheimer&amp;rsquo;s disease (AD) that focus on inhibition of Aβ aggregation failed to show effectiveness in people who already had Alzheimer&amp;rsquo;s symptoms. Strategies that synergistically exert neuroprotection and alleviation of oxidative stress could be a promising approach to correct the pathological brain microenvironment. Based on the key roles of microglia in modulation of AD microenvironment, we describe here the development of Prussian blue/polyamidoamine (PAMAM) dendrimer/Angiopep-2 (PPA) nanoparticles that can regulate the mitophagy of microglia as a potential AD treatment. PPA nanoparticles exhibit superior blood-brain barrier (BBB) permeability and exert synergistic effects of ROS scavenging and restoration of mitochondrial function of microglia. PPA nanoparticles effectively reduce neurotoxic Aβ aggregate and rescue the cognitive functions in APP/PS1 model mice. Together, our data suggest that these multifunctional dendrimer nanoparticles exhibit efficient neuroprotection and microglia modulation and can be exploited as a promising approach for the treatment of AD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NIR-driven polydopamine-based nanoenzymes as ROS scavengers to suppress osteoarthritis progression</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/mtnano.2022.100240/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/mtnano.2022.100240/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The excessive reactive oxygen species (ROS) is always associated with the degradation of cartilage matrix during osteoarthritis (OA). The development of novel nanoenzymes with excellent ROS scavenging ability and biosafety shows great potentials for improving OA treatment. Herein a novel functional polydopamine (P) loading with ultrasmall Pt and Cu nanoparticles (P@Pt@Cu) was developed to act as nanoenzymes to scavenge ROS for OA treatment, wherein the excellent catalytic activities of Pt and Cu were employed. Results showed that P@Pt@Cu simultaneously presented obvious enzyme-mimicking properties like superoxide dismutase, catalase, and glutathione peroxidase, leading to excellent antioxidant and anti-inflammatory activities in H2O2 stimulated chondrocytes and OA joints with low cytotoxicity, leading to significant alleviation of OA progression. Besides, near infrared stimulation strengthened the antioxidant and anti-inflammation ability of P@Pt@Cu, resulting in the most prominent therapeutic effects. The proposed polydopamine-based nanoenzymes inspired a novel therapeutic strategy for OA therapy in clinic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tumor-Activatable Nanoparticles Target Low-Density Lipoprotein Receptor to Enhance Drug Delivery and Antitumor Efficacy</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35748191/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35748191/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The binding of plasma proteins to nanomedicines is widely considered detrimental to their delivery to tumors. Here, the design of OxPt/SN38 nanoparticle containing a hydrophilic oxaliplatin (OxPt) prodrug in a coordination polymer core and a hydrophobic cholesterol-conjugated SN38 prodrug on the lipid shell for active tumor targeting is reported. OxPt/SN38 hitchhikes on low-density lipoprotein (LDL) particles, concentrates in tumors via LDL receptor-mediated endocytosis, and selectively releases SN38 and OxPt in acidic, esterase-rich, and reducing tumor microenvironments, leading to 6.0- and 4.9-times higher accumulations in tumors over free drugs. By simultaneously crosslinking DNA and inhibiting topoisomerase I, OxPt/SN38 achieved 92-98% tumor growth inhibition in five colorectal cancer tumor models and prolonged mouse survival by 58-80 days compared to free drug controls in three human colorectal cancer tumor models without causing serious side effects. The study has uncovered a novel nanomedicine strategy to co-deliver combination chemotherapies to tumors via active targeting of the LDL receptor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ROS-responsive polymer nanoparticles with enhanced loading of dexamethasone effectively modulate the lung injury microenvironment</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35724918/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35724918/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The acute lung injury (ALI) is an inflammatory disorder associated with cytokine storm, which activates various reactive oxygen species (ROS) signaling pathways and causes severe complications in patients as currently seen in coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19). There is an urgent need for medication of the inflammatory lung environment and effective delivery of drugs to lung to reduce the burden of high doses of medications and attenuate inflammatory cells and pathways. Herein, we prepared dexamethasone-loaded ROS-responsive polymer nanoparticles (PFTU@DEX NPs) by a modified emulsion approach, which achieved high loading content of DEX (11.61 %). DEX was released faster from the PFTU@DEX NPs in a ROS environment, which could scavenge excessive ROS efficiently both &lt;em&gt;in vitro&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt;. The PFTU NPs and PFTU@DEX NPs showed no hemolysis and cytotoxicity. Free DEX, PFTU NPs and PFTU@DEX NPs shifted M1 macrophages to M2 macrophages in RAW264.7 cells, and showed anti-inflammatory modulation to A549 cells &lt;em&gt;in vitro&lt;/em&gt;. The PFTU@DEX NPs treatment significantly reduced the increased total protein concentration in BALF of ALI mice. The delivery of PFTU@DEX NPs decreased the proportion of neutrophils significantly, mitigated the cell apoptosis remarkably compared to the other groups, reduced M1 macrophages and increased M2 macrophages &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt;. Moreover, the PFTU@DEX NPs had the strongest ability to suppress the expression of NLRP3, Caspase1, and IL-1β. Therefore, the PFTU@DEX NPs could efficiently suppress inflammatory cells, ROS signaling pathways, and cell apoptosis to ameliorate LPS-induced ALI. STATEMENT OF SIGNIFICANCE: The acute lung injury (ALI) is an inflammatory disorder associated with cytokine storm, which activates various reactive oxygen species (ROS) signaling pathways and causes severe complications in patients. There is an urgent need for medication of the inflammatory lung environment and effective delivery of drugs to modulate the inflammatory disorder and suppress the expression of ROS and inflammatory cytokines. The inhaled PFTU@DEX NPs prepared through a modified nanoemulsification method suppressed the activation of NLRP3, induced the polarization of macrophage phenotype from M1 to M2, and thereby reduced the neutrophil infiltration, inhibited the release of proteins and inflammatory mediators, and thus decreased the acute lung injury &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Uptake of Functional Ultrasmall Gold Nanoparticles in 3D Gut Cell Models</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35712760/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35712760/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ultrasmall gold nanoparticles (2 nm) easily penetrate the membranes of intestinal murine epithelial cells (MODE-K) and colorectal cancer cells (CT-26). They are also taken up by 3D spheroids (400 µm) of these cell types and primary gut organoids (500 µm). In contrast, dissolved dyes are not taken up by any of these cells or 3D structures. The distribution of fluorescent ultrasmall gold nanoparticles inside cells, spheroids, and gut organoids is examined by confocal laser scanning microscopy. Nanoparticles conjugated with the cytostatic drug doxorubicin and a fluorescent dye exhibit significantly greater cytotoxicity toward CT-26 tumor spheroids than equally concentrated dissolved doxorubicin, probably because they enter the interior of a spheroid much more easily than dissolved doxorubicin. Comprehensive analyses show that the cellular uptake of ultrasmall gold nanoparticles occurs by different endocytosis pathways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A novel inhalable quercetin-alginate nanogel as a promising therapy for acute lung injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35690763/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35690763/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Acute lung injury (ALI), a severe health-threatening disease, has a risk of causing chronic pulmonary fibrosis. Informative and powerful evidence suggests that inflammation and oxidative stress play a central role in the pathogenesis of ALI. Quercetin is well recognized for its excellent antioxidant and anti-inflammatory properties, which showed great potential for ALI treatment. However, the application of quercetin is often hindered by its low solubility and bioavailability. Therefore, to overcome these challenges, an inhalable quercetin-alginate nanogel (QU-Nanogel) was fabricated, and by this special &amp;ldquo;material-drug&amp;rdquo; structure, the solubility and bioavailability of quercetin were significantly enhanced, which could further increase the activity of quercetin and provide a promising therapy for ALI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; QU-Nanogel is a novel alginate and quercetin based &amp;ldquo;material-drug&amp;rdquo; structural inhalable nanogel, in which quercetin was stabilized by hydrogen bonding to obtain a &amp;ldquo;co-construct&amp;rdquo; water-soluble nanogel system, showing antioxidant and anti-inflammatory properties. QU-Nanogel has an even distribution in size of less than 100 nm and good biocompatibility, which shows a stronger protective and antioxidant effect in vitro. Tissue distribution results provided evidence that the QU-Nanogel by ultrasonic aerosol inhalation is a feasible approach to targeted pulmonary drug delivery. Moreover, QU-Nanogel was remarkably reversed ALI rats by relieving oxidative stress damage and acting the down-regulation effects of mRNA and protein expression of inflammation cytokines via ultrasonic aerosol inhalation administration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; In the ALI rat model, this novel nanogel showed an excellent therapeutic effect by ultrasonic aerosol inhalation administration by protecting and reducing pulmonary inflammation, thereby preventing subsequent pulmonary fibrosis. This work demonstrates that this inhalable QU-Nanogel may function as a promising drug delivery strategy in treating ALI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Novel Drug Delivery Technologies and Targets for Renal Disease</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/35652363/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/35652363/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The burden of acute and chronic kidney diseases to the health care system is exacerbated by the high mortality that this disease carries paired with the still limited availability of comprehensive therapies. A reason partially resides in the complexity of the kidney, with multiple potential target cell types and a complex structural environment that complicate strategies to protect and recover renal function after injury. Management of both acute and chronic renal disease, irrespective of the cause, are mainly focused on supportive treatments and renal replacement strategies when needed. Emerging preclinical evidence supports the feasibility of drug delivery technology for the kidney, and recent studies have contributed to building a robust catalog of peptides, proteins, nanoparticles, liposomes, extracellular vesicles, and other carriers that may be fused to therapeutic peptides, proteins, nucleic acids, or small molecule drugs. These fusions can display a precise renal uptake, an enhanced circulating time, and a directed intraorgan biodistribution while protecting their cargo to improve therapeutic efficacy. However, several hurdles that slow the transition towards clinical applications are still in the way, such as solubility, toxicity, and sub-optimal renal targeting. This review will discuss the feasibility and current limitations of drug delivery technologies for the treatment of renal disease, offering an update on their potential and the future directions of these promising strategies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Perspectives of using microRNA-loaded nanocarriers for epigenetic reprogramming of drug resistant colorectal cancers</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/35623562/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/35623562/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Epigenetic regulation by microRNAs (miRs) demonstrated a promising therapeutic potential of these molecules to regulate genetic activity in different cancers, including colorectal cancers (CRCs). The RNA-based therapy does not change genetic codes in tumor cells but can silence oncogenes and/or reactivate inhibited tumor suppressor genes. In many cancers, specific miRs were shown to promote or stop tumor progression. Among confirmed and powerful epigenetic regulators of colon carcinogenesis and development of resistance are onco-miRs, which include let-7, miR-21, miR-22, miR-23a, miR-27a, miR-34, miR-92, miR-96, miR-125b, miR-135b, miR-182, miR-200c, miR-203, miR-221, miR-421, miR-451, and others. Moreover, various tumor-suppressor miRs (miR-15b-5b, miR-18a, miR-20b, miR-22, miR-96, miR-139-5p, miR-145, miR-149, miR-197, miR-199b, miR-203, miR-214, miR-218, miR-320, miR-375-3p, miR-409-3p, miR-450b-5p, miR-494, miR-577, miR-874, and others) were found silenced in drug-resistant CRCs. Re-expression of tumor suppressor miR is complicated by the chemical nature of miRs that are not long-lasting compounds and require protection from the enzymatic degradation. Several recent studies explored application of miRs using nanocarrier complexes. This study critically describes the most successfully tested nanoparticle complexes used for intracellular delivery of nuclear acids and miRs, including micelles, liposomes, inorganic and polymeric NPs, dendrimers, and aptamers. Nanocarriers shield incorporated miRs and improve the agent stability in circulation. Attachment of antibodies and/or specific peptide or ligands facilitates cell-targeted miR delivery. Addressing in vivo challenges, a broad spectrum of non-toxic materials has been tested and indicated reliable advantages of lipid-based (lipoplexes) and polymer-based liposomes. Recent cutting-edge developments indicated that lipid-based complexes with multiple cargo, including several miRs, are the most effective approach to eradicate drug-resistant tumors. Focusing on CRC-specific miRs, this review provides a guidance and insights towards the most promising direction to achieve dramatic reduction in tumor growth and metastasis using miR-nanocarrier complexes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plasma-Enabled Smart Nanoexosome Platform as Emerging Immunopathogenesis for Clinical Viral Infection</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/35631640/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/35631640/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Smart nanoexosomes are nanosized structures enclosed in lipid bilayers that are structurally similar to the viruses released by a variety of cells, including the cells lining the respiratory system. Of particular importance, the interaction between smart nanoexosomes and viruses can be used to develop antiviral drugs and vaccines. It is possible that nanoexosomes will be utilized and antibodies will be acquired more successfully for the transmission of an immune response if reconvalescent plasma (CP) is used instead of reconvalescent plasma exosomes (CPExo) in this concept. Convalescent plasma contains billions of smart nanoexosomes capable of transporting a variety of molecules, including proteins, lipids, RNA and DNA among other viral infections. Smart nanoexosomes are released from virus-infected cells and play an important role in mediating communication between infected and uninfected cells. Infections use the formation, production and release of smart nanoexosomes to enhance the infection, transmission and intercellular diffusion of viruses. Cell-free smart nanoexosomes produced by mesenchymal stem cells (MSCs) could also be used as cell-free therapies in certain cases. Smart nanoexosomes produced by mesenchymal stem cells can also promote mitochondrial function and heal lung injury. They can reduce cytokine storms and restore the suppression of host antiviral defenses weakened by viral infections. This study examines the benefits of smart nanoexosomes and their roles in viral transmission, infection, treatment, drug delivery and clinical applications. We also explore some potential future applications for smart nanoexosomes in the treatment of viral infections.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sorafenib-loaded silica-containing redox nanoparticles for oral anti-liver fibrosis therapy</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35395328/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35395328/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Liver fibrosis is a chronic disease resulting from repetitive or prolonged liver injury with limited treatment options. Sorafenib has been reported to be a potential antifibrotic agent; however, its therapeutic effect is restricted because of its low bioavailability and severe adverse effects in the gastrointestinal (GI) tract. In this study, we developed sorafenib-loaded silica-containing redox nanoparticles (sora@siRNP) as an oral nanomedicine to treat liver fibrosis. The designed siRNP were prepared by self-assembly of amphiphilic block copolymers, which possess antioxidant nitroxide radicals as a side chain of the hydrophobic segment and porous silica particles in the nanoparticle core. The silica moieties in the core formed a crosslink between the self-assembling block copolymers to afford stable drug absorption, which could be useful in harsh GI conditions after oral drug administration. Based on in vitro evaluation, sora@siRNP exerted antiproliferative and antifibrotic effects against hepatic stellate cells (HSCs) and low toxicity against normal endothelial cells. A pharmacokinetic study showed that siRNP significantly improved the bioavailability and distribution of sorafenib in the liver. In an in vivo study using a mouse model of CCl&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;-induced liver fibrosis, oral administration of sora@siRNP significantly suppressed the fibrotic area in comparison to free sorafenib administration. In mice with CCl&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;-induced fibrosis, free sorafenib administration did not suppress the expression of α-smooth muscle actin; however, mice treated with sora@siRNP showed significantly suppressed expression of α-smooth muscle actin, indicating the inhibition of HSC activation, which was confirmed by in vitro experiments. Moreover, oral administration of free sorafenib induced severe intestinal damage and increased leakage into the gut, which can be attributed to the generation of reactive oxygen species (ROS). Our antioxidant nanocarriers, siRNP, reduced the adverse effects of local ROS scavenging in the GI tract. Our results suggest that sora@siRNP could serve as a promising oral nanomedicine for liver fibrosis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Red blood cell-hitchhiking mediated pulmonary delivery of ivermectin: Effects of nanoparticle properties</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35390488/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35390488/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ivermectin-loaded nanoparticles were delivered to lungs through adsorption on RBCs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RBC-hitchhiking strategy improved ivermectin pharmacokinetics and bioavailability.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nanoparticle properties affected the characteristics of RBC-nanoparticles &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recent studies have demonstrated that ivermectin (IVM) exhibits antiviral activity against severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 (SARS-CoV-2), the causative virus of coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19). However, the repurposing of IVM for the treatment of COVID-19 has presented challenges primarily due to the low IVM plasma concentration after oral administration, which was well below IC50. Here, a red blood cell (RBC)-hitchhiking strategy was used for the targeted delivery of IVM-loaded nanoparticles (NPs) to the lung. IVM-loaded poly (lactic-co-glycolic acid) (PLGA) NPs (IVM-PNPs) and chitosan-coating IVM-PNPs (IVM-CSPNPs) were prepared and adsorbed onto RBCs. Both RBC-hitchhiked IVM-PNPs and IVM-CSPNPs could significantly enhance IVM delivery to lungs, improve IVM accumulation in lung tissue, inhibit the inflammatory responses and finally significantly alleviate the progression of acute lung injury. Specifically, the redistribution and circulation effects were related to the properties of NPs. RBC-hitchhiked cationic IVM-CSPNPs showed a longer circulation time, slower accumulation and elimination rates, and higher anti-inflammatory activities than RBC-hitchhiked anionic IVM-PNPs. Therefore, RBC-hitchhiking provides an alternative strategy to improve IVM pharmacokinetics and bioavailability for repurposing of IVM to treat COVID-19. Furthermore, according to different redistribution effects of different NPs, RBC-hitchhiked NPs may achieve various accumulation rates and circulation times for different requirements of drug delivery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In vivo self-assembled drug nanocrystals for metastatic breast cancer all-stage targeted therapy</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35378211/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35378211/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chemotherapy is still the mainstay treatment for metastatic triple-negative breast cancers (TNBC) currently in clinical practice. The unmet needs of chemotherapy for metastatic TNBC are mainly from the insufficient drug delivery and unavailable targeting strategy that thwart the whole progression of metastatic TNBC. The in vivo ligands-mediated active targeting efficiency is usually affected by protein corona. While, the protein corona-bridged natural targeting, in turn, provides a new way for specific drug delivery. Herein, we develop a novel metastatic progression-oriented in vivo self-assembled Cabazitaxel nanocrystals (CNC) delivery system (PC/CNC) through the CNC automatically absorbing functional plasma proteins (transferrin, apolipoprotein A-IV and apolipoprotein E) in vivo, aiming to achieve the simultaneously targeted delivery to primary tumors, circulating tumor cells and metastatic lesions. With the unique advantages of superhigh drug-loading and protein corona empowered active targeting properties to tumor cells, HUVECs, active-platelets and blood-brain barrier/blood-tumor barrier, the PC/CNC exhibits a significantly improved therapeutic effect in metastatic TNBC therapy compared with free drug and CNC-loaded liposomes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mannan-decorated pathogen-like polymeric nanoparticles as nanovaccine carriers for eliciting superior anticancer immunity</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35364489/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35364489/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using nanotechnology for cancer vaccine design holds great promise because of the intrinsic feature of nanoparticles in being captured by antigen-presenting cells (APCs). However, there are still obstacles in current nanovaccine systems in achieving efficient tumor therapeutic effects, which could partially be attributed to the unsatisfactory vaccine carrier design. Herein, we report a mannan-decorated pathogen-like polymeric nanoparticle as a protein vaccine carrier for eliciting robust anticancer immunity. This nanovaccine was constructed as a core-shell structure with mannan as the shell, polylactic acid-polyethylenimine (PLA-PEI) assembled nanoparticle as the core, and protein antigens and Toll-like receptor 9 (TLR9) agonist CpG absorbed onto the PLA-PEI core via electrostatic interactions. Compared to other hydrophilic materials, mannan decoration could greatly enhance the lymph node draining ability of the nanovaccine and promote the capturing by the CD8&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; dendritic cells (DCs) in the lymph node, while PLA-PEI as the inner core could enhance antigen endosome escape thus promoting the antigen cross-presentation. In addition, mannan itself as a TLR4 agonist could synergize with CpG for maximally activating the DCs. Excitingly, we observed in several murine tumor models that using this nanovaccine alone could elicit robust immune response in vivo and result in superior anti-tumor effects with 50% of mice completely cured. This study strongly evidenced that mannan decoration and a rationally designed nanovaccine system could be quite robust in tumor vaccine therapy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nanotechnology-based therapeutics for targeting inflammatory lung diseases</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/35315290/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/35315290/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nanoformulation of a carbon monoxide releasing molecule protects against cyclosporin A-induced nephrotoxicity and renal fibrosis via the suppression of the NLRP3 inflammasome mediated TGF-β/Smad pathway</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35304324/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35304324/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cyclosporin A (CsA) induced nephrotoxicity i.e., renal fibrosis is a critical clinical problem in renal transplant patients, in which chronic inflammatory response is the major cause. Previously, we developed a nano-drug delivery system for carbon monoxide (CO), a multi-functional gaseous molecule with a potent anti-inflammatory effect, i.e., SMA/CORM2, which showed therapeutic potential in several inflammatory disease models. Accordingly, in this study, we explored the potential and usefulness of SMA/CORM2 on CsA induced renal fibrosis. When mice were exposed to CsA for 4 weeks, severe injuries in the kidney as revealed by decreased kidney function and histological examination, and activation of NLRP3 inflammasome, as well as renal fibrosis along with the upregulation of transforming growth factor β (TGFβ)/Smad signaling molecule were observed, whereas SMA/CORM2 (1 mg/kg) treatment remarkably ameliorated the inflammatory injury and fibrosis in the kidney. CO is the major effector molecule of SMA/CORM2 which significantly suppressed the activation of NLRP3 inflammasome, and induced the downregulation of TGFβ/Smad signaling. Inhibition of NLRP3 inflammasome by its inhibitor MCC950 also similarly decreased TGFβ/Smad expression and subsequently improved kidney injury and renal fibrosis, suggesting SMA/CORM2 induced suppression of TGFβ/Smad signaling and renal signaling via an NLRP3 inflammasome-dependent pathway. Compared to native CORM2, SMA/CORM2 exhibited better therapeutic/preventive effects owing to its superior water-solubility and bioavailability. These findings strongly indicated the applicability of SMA/CORM2 as an enhanced permeability and retention (EPR) effect-based nanomedicine for CsA induced renal fibrosis as well as other inflammatory diseases. STATEMENT OF SIGNIFICANCE: Carbon monoxide (CO) is an important gaseous signaling molecule that plays a crucial role in the maintenance of homeostasis. Because of its versatile functions, it exhibits the potential as the target molecule for many diseases, including inflammatory diseases and cancer. The development of stable and disease-targeted delivery systems of CO is thus of interest and importance. Previously we developed a nano micellar CO donor SMA/CORM2 which shows superior bioavailability and therapeutic potential in many inflammatory disease models. We reported here, SMA/CORM2, through controlled release of CO, greatly ameliorated CsA-induced renal fibrosis via suppressing the NLRP3 inflammasome mediated TGF-β/Smad pathway. These findings suggest a new anti-inflammatory mechanism of CO, which also provides a new approach for controlling CsA-induced nephrotoxicity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A silica-based antioxidant nanoparticle for oral delivery of Camptothecin which reduces intestinal side effects while improving drug efficacy for colon cancer treatment</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35235866/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35235866/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Camptothecin (CPT) is a potent anticancer agent for the treatment of colorectal cancer; however, it exhibits some limitations, including poor solubility, low stability, and low bioavailability via oral administration, which restrict its usability in clinical treatments. In addition, overproduction of reactive oxygen species (ROS) during chemotherapy induces drug resistance and severe intestinal side effects. In this study, silica-installed ROS scavenging nanoparticles (siRNP) with 50-60 nm in diameter were employed to overcome the aforementioned drawbacks of CPT. The solubility of CPT was significantly improved by incorporating it into the core of the nanoparticle, forming CPT-loaded siRNP (CPT@siRNP). The anticancer activity of CPT@siRNP against colorectal cancer cells (C-26) in vitro was significantly improved as compared to free CPT through higher efficiency of intracellular internalization and induction of apoptosis. Owing to its antioxidant properties, CPT@siRNP reduced cytotoxicity to normal endothelial cells, which was in sharp contrast to the high toxicity of free CPT. Oral administration of CPT and CPT@siRNP to the C-26 tumor-bearing mice exhibited antitumor activity, accompanied by effective suppression of tumor growth. Although CPT treatment suppressed tumor progression, it caused severe side effects, including intestinal damage and significant bodyweight loss. Interestingly, such noticeable side effects were not observed in the mice treated with CPT@siRNP, and the effect of tumor growth inhibition tended to be similar to or higher than that of CPT treatment. The results obtained in this study indicate that CPT@siRNP is a potential therapeutic nanomedicine for the treatment of colon cancer. STATEMENT OF SIGNIFICANCE: Here we employed silica-containing antioxidant nanoparticle (siRNP) as promising oral delivery nanocarrier of campothecin (CPT) to treat colon cancer. The design of siRNP via covalent conjugation of antioxidant nitroxide radicals and the silanol groups in the polymer backbone contributes to a significant increase in the absorption of hydrophobic drug molecules inside the core and enhances the stability of nanoparticles in the gastrointestinal environment for oral drug delivery. CPT-loaded siRNP (CPT@siRNP) significantly improved solubility of CPT. As compared to free CTP, the CPT@siRNP treatment showed a significantly higher toxicity to colon cancer cell, inhibition of cancer cell migration, and induction of apopotosis. With the antioxidant feature, siRNP also significantly suppressed the intestinal side effects caused by CPT treatment in tumor-bearing mouse model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An mTOR siRNA-Loaded Spermidine/DNA Tetrahedron Nanoplatform with a Synergistic Anti-Inflammatory Effect on Acute Lung Injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35167728/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35167728/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acute lung injury (ALI) is characterized by severe inflammation and damage to the lung air-blood barrier, resulting in respiratory function damage and life-threatening outcomes. Macrophage polarization plays an essential role in the occurrence, development, and outcome of ALI. As drug carriers, self-assembled DNA nanostructures can potentially overcome the drawbacks and limitations of traditional anti-inflammatory agents owing to their nontoxicity, programmability, and excellent structural control at the nanoscale. A small interfering RNA (siRNA) and drug dual therapy nanoplatform are proposed and constructed here to combat ALI. The nanoplatform consists of a spermidine-assembled DNA tetrahedron and four mammalian target of rapamycin siRNAs. Spermidine serves as a mediator of drug delivery vehicle synthesis and a drug that alters macrophage polarization. Both spermidine and siRNA exert anti-inflammatory effects in vitro and in vivo by regulating the macrophage phenotype. More importantly, these factors exhibit a synergistic anti-inflammatory effect by promoting macrophage autophagy. For the first time, an anti-inflammatory dual therapy strategy that uses self-assembled DNA nanostructures as nontoxic, programmable delivery vehicles is proposed and demonstrated through this work. Future work on utilizing DNA nanostructures for the treatment of noncancerous diseases such as ALI is highly promising and desirable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Affimer Tagged Cubosomes: Targeting of Carcinoembryonic Antigen Expressing Colorectal Cancer Cells Using In Vitro and In Vivo Models</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35196008/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35196008/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nanomedicines, while having been approved for cancer therapy, present many challenges such as low stability, rapid clearance, and nonspecificity leading to off-target toxicity. Cubosomes are porous lyotropic liquid crystalline nanoparticles that have shown great premise as drug delivery vehicles; however, their behavior &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt; is largely underexplored, hindering clinical translation. Here, we have engineered cubosomes based on the space group &lt;em&gt;Im3m&lt;/em&gt; that are loaded with copper acetylacetonate as a model drug, and their surfaces are functionalized for the first time with Affimer proteins via copper-free click chemistry to actively target overexpressed carcinoembryonic antigens on LS174T colorectal cancer cells. Unlike nontargeted cubosomes, Affimer tagged cubosomes showed preferential accumulation in cancer cells compared to normal cells not only &lt;em&gt;in vitro&lt;/em&gt; (2D monolayer cell culture and 3D spheroid models) but also &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt; in colorectal cancer mouse xenografts, while exhibiting low nonspecific absorption and toxicity in other vital organs. Cancerous spheroids had maximum cell death compared to noncancerous cells upon targeted delivery. Xenografts subjected to targeted drug-loaded cubosomes showed a 5-7-fold higher drug accumulation in the tumor tissue compared to the liver, kidneys, and other vital organs, a significant decrease in tumor growth, and an increased survival rate compared to the nontargeted group. This work encompasses the first thorough preclinical investigation of Affimer targeted cubosomes as a cancer therapeutic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dexamethasone-loaded ROS-responsive poly(thioketal) nanoparticles suppress inflammation and oxidative stress of acute lung injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35415281/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35415281/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A therapeutic nanoplatform with ROS-responsiveness was developed for the regulation of inflammation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;NPs composed of low Mw of PPADT and high Mw of PTKU were loaded with dexamethasone to obtain a self-adaptive system.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Dex-loaded NPs significantly decreased lung inflammation, and reduced lung injury and mortality &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acute lung injury (ALI) is associated with excessive inflammatory response, leading to acute respiratory distress syndrome (ARDS) without timely treatment. A fewer effective drugs are available currently to treat the ALI/ARDS. Herein, a therapeutic nanoplatform with reactive oxygen species (ROS)-responsiveness was developed for the regulation of inflammation. Dexamethasone acetate (Dex) was encapsulated into poly(thioketal) polymers to form polymeric nanoparticles (NPs) (PTKNPs@Dex). The NPs were composed of poly(1,4-phenyleneacetonedimethylene thioketal) (PPADT) and polythioketal urethane (PTKU), in which the thioketal bonds could be cleaved by the high level of ROS at the ALI site. The PTKNPs@Dex could accumulate in the pulmonary inflammatory sites and release the encapsulated payloads rapidly, leading to the decreased ROS level, less generation of pro-inflammatory cytokines, and reduced lung injury and mortality of mice. RNA sequencing (RNA-seq) analysis showed that the therapeutic efficacy of the NPs was associated with the modulation of many immune and inflammation-linked pathways. These findings provide a newly developed nanoplatform for the efficient treatment of ALI/ARDS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nanocurcumin Potently Inhibits SARS-CoV-2 Spike Protein-Induced Cytokine Storm by Deactivation of MAPK/NF-κB Signaling in Epithelial Cells</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35112841/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35112841/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interleukin-mediated deep cytokine storm, an aggressive inflammatory response to SARS-CoV-2 virus infection in COVID-19 patients, is correlated directly with lung injury, multi-organ failure, and poor prognosis of severe COVID-19 patients. Curcumin (CUR), a phenolic antioxidant compound obtained from turmeric (&lt;em&gt;Curcuma longa L.&lt;/em&gt;), is well-known for its strong anti-inflammatory activity. However, its &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt; efficacy is constrained due to poor bioavailability. Herein, we report that CUR-encapsulated polysaccharide nanoparticles (CUR-PS-NPs) potently inhibit the release of cytokines, chemokines, and growth factors associated with damage of SARS-CoV-2 spike protein (CoV2-SP)-stimulated liver Huh7.5 and lung A549 epithelial cells. Treatment with CUR-PS-NPs effectively attenuated the interaction of ACE2 and CoV2-SP. The effects of CUR-PS-NPs were linked to reduced NF-κB/MAPK signaling which in turn decreased CoV2-SP-mediated phosphorylation of p38 MAPK, p42/44 MAPK, and p65/NF-κB as well as nuclear p65/NF-κB expression. The findings of the study strongly indicate that organic NPs of CUR can be used to control hyper-inflammatory responses and prevent lung and liver injuries associated with CoV2-SP-mediated cytokine storm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transforming the Chemical Structure and Bio-Nano Activity of Doxorubicin by Ultrasound for Selective Killing of Cancer Cells</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35100658/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35100658/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reconfiguring the structure and selectivity of existing chemotherapeutics represents an opportunity for developing novel tumor-selective drugs. Here, as a proof-of-concept, the use of high-frequency sound waves is demonstrated to transform the nonselective anthracycline doxorubicin into a tumor selective drug molecule. The transformed drug self-aggregates in water to form ≈200 nm nanodrugs without requiring organic solvents, chemical agents, or surfactants. The nanodrugs preferentially interact with lipid rafts in the mitochondria of cancer cells. The mitochondrial localization of the nanodrugs plays a key role in inducing reactive oxygen species mediated selective death of breast cancer, colorectal carcinoma, ovarian carcinoma, and drug-resistant cell lines. Only marginal cytotoxicity (80-100% cell viability) toward fibroblasts and cardiomyocytes is observed, even after administration of high doses of the nanodrug (25-40 µg mL&lt;sup&gt;-1&lt;/sup&gt;). Penetration, cytotoxicity, and selectivity of the nanodrugs in tumor-mimicking tissues are validated by using a 3D coculture of cancer and healthy cells and 3D cell-collagen constructs in a perfusion bioreactor. The nanodrugs exhibit tropism for lung and limited accumulation in the liver and spleen, as suggested by in vivo biodistribution studies. The results highlight the potential of this approach to transform the structure and bioactivity of anticancer drugs and antibiotics bearing sono-active moieties.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Renal Nano-drug delivery for acute kidney Injury: Current status and future perspectives</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/35085695/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/35085695/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acute kidney injury (AKI) causes considerable morbidity and mortality, particularly in the case of post-cardiac infarction or kidney transplantation; however, the site-specific accumulation of small molecule reno-protective agents for AKI has often proved ineffective due to dynamic fluid and solute excretion and non-selectivity, which impedes therapeutic efficacy. This article reviews the current status and future trajectories of renal nanomedicine research for AKI management from pharmacological and clinical perspectives, with a particular focus on appraising nanosized drug carrier (NDC) use for the delivery of reno-protective agents of different pharmacological classes and the effectiveness of NDCs in improving renal tissue targeting selectivity and efficacy of said agents. This review reveals the critical shift in the role of the small molecule reno-protective agents in AKI pharmacotherapy - from prophylaxis to treatment - when using NDCs for delivery to the kidney. We also highlight the need to identify the accumulation sites of NDCs carrying reno-protective agents in renal tissues during in vivo assessments and detail the less-explored pharmacological classes of reno-protective agents whose efficacies may be improved via NDC-based delivery. We conclude the paper by outlining the challenges and future perspectives of NDC-based reno-protective agent delivery for better clinical management of AKI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>N6-Methyladenosine Reader YTHDF1 Promotes ARHGEF2 Translation and RhoA Signaling in Colorectal Cancer</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34968454/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34968454/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background &amp;amp; aims:&lt;/em&gt; N6-methyladenosine (m&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;A) governs the fate of RNAs through m&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;A readers. Colorectal cancer (CRC) exhibits aberrant m&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;A modifications and expression of m&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;A regulators. However, how m&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;A readers interpret oncogenic m&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;A methylome to promote malignant transformation remains to be illustrated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; YTH N6-methyladenosine RNA binding protein 1 (Ythdf1) knockout mouse was generated to determine the effect of Ythdf1 in CRC tumorigenesis in vivo. Multiomic analysis of RNA-sequencing, m&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;AA methylated RNA immunoprecipitation sequencing, YTHDF1 RNA immunoprecipitation sequencing, and proteomics were performed to unravel targets of YTHDF1 in CRC. The therapeutic potential of targeting YTHDF1-m&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;A-Rho/Rac guanine nucleotide exchange factor 2 (ARHGEF2) was evaluated using small interfering RNA (siRNA) encapsulated by lipid nanoparticles (LNP).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; DNA copy number gain of YTHDF1 is a frequent event in CRC and contributes to its overexpression. High expression of YTHDF1 is significantly associated with metastatic gene signature in patient tumors. Ythdf1 knockout in mice dampened tumor growth in an inflammatory CRC model. YTHDF1 promotes cell growth in CRC cell lines and primary organoids and lung and liver metastasis in vivo. Integrative multiomics analysis identified RhoA activator ARHGEF2 as a key downstream target of YTHDF1. YTHDF1 binds to m&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;A sites of ARHGEF2 messenger RNA, resulting in enhanced translation of ARHGEF2. Ectopic expression of ARHGEF2 restored impaired RhoA signaling, cell growth, and metastatic ability both in vitro and in vivo caused by YTHDF1 loss, verifying that ARHGEF2 is a key target of YTHDF1. Finally, ARHGEF2 siRNA delivered by LNP significantly suppressed tumor growth and metastasis in vivo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; We identify a novel oncogenic epitranscriptome axis of YTHDF1-m&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;A-ARHGEF2, which regulates CRC tumorigenesis and metastasis. siRNA-delivering LNP drug validated the therapeutic potential of targeting this axis in CRC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Silymarin/curcumin loaded albumin nanoparticles coated by chitosan as muco-inhalable delivery system observing anti-inflammatory and anti COVID-19 characterizations in oleic acid triggered lung injury and in vitro COVID-19 experiment</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34968533/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34968533/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Respiratory infected by COVID-19 represents a major global health problem at moment even after recovery from virus corona. Since, the lung lesions for infected patients are still sufferings from acute respiratory distress syndrome including alveolar septal edema, pneumonia, hyperplasia, and hyaline membranes Therefore, there is an urgent need to identify additional candidates having ability to overcome inflammatory process and can enhance efficacy in the treatment of COVID-19. The polypenolic extracts were integrated into moeties of bovine serum albumin (BSA) and then were coated by chitosan as a mucoadhesion polymer. The results of interleukin-6, and c-reactive protein showed significant reduction in group treated by Encap. SIL + CUR (64 ± 0.8 Pg/μL &amp;amp; 6 ± 0.5 μg/μL) compared to group treated by Cham. + CUR (102 ± 0.8 Pg/μL &amp;amp; 7 ± 0.5 μg/μL) respectively and free capsules (with no any drug inside) (148 ± 0.6 Pg/μL &amp;amp; 10 ± 0.6 μg/μL) respectively. Histopathology profile was improved completely. Additionally, encapsulating silymarin showed anti-viral activity in vitro COVID-19 experiment. It can be summarized that muco-inhalable delivery system (MIDS) loaded by silymarin can be used to overcome inflammation induced by oleic acid and to overcome COVID-19.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nanotopography Sequentially Mediates Human Mesenchymal Stem Cell-Derived Small Extracellular Vesicles for Enhancing Osteogenesis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34935354/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34935354/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Engineered small extracellular vesicles (sEVs) are used as tools to enhance therapeutic efficacy. However, such application of sEVs is associated with several issues, including high costs and a high risk of tumorigenesis. Nanotopography has a greater influence on bone-related cell behaviors. However, whether nanotopography specifically mediate sEV content to perform particular biological functions remains unclear. Here, we demonstrate that selective nanotopography may be used to sequentially mediate human bone mesenchymal stem cell (hBMSC) sEVs to enhance the therapeutic efficacy of hBMSCs-EVs for osteogenesis. We subjected sEVs harvested from hBMSCs cultured on polished titanium plates (Ti) or nanotopographical titanium plates (Ti4) after 7, 14, and 21 d for RNA sequencing, and we found that there was no significant difference in sEV-miRNA expression after 7 d. Differentially expressed osteogenic-related microRNAs were founded after 14 days, and KEGG analysis indicated that the main microRNAs were associated with osteogenesis-related pathways, such as TGF-beta, AMPK, and FoxO. A significant difference was found in sEV-miRNAs expression after 21 d. We loaded sEV secreted from hBMSCs cultured on Ti4 after 21 d on 3D-printed porous PEEK scaffolds with poly dopamine (PDA) and found that such scaffolds showed superior osteogenic ability after 6- and 12-weeks. Here, we demonstrate the alkali- and heat-treated nanotopography with the ability of stimulating osteogenic differentiation of hBMSC can induce the secretion of pro-osteogenesis sEV, and we also found that sEVs meditate osteogenesis through miRNA. Thus, whether nanotopography has the ability to regulate other contents of sEVs such as proteins for enhancing osteogenesis needs further research. These findings may help us use nanotopography to extract sEVs for other biomedical applications, including cancer therapy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advances in Biosensor Technologies for Acute Kidney Injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/34928578/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/34928578/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acute kidney injury (AKI) is one of the most prevalent and complex clinical syndromes with high morbidity and mortality. The traditional diagnosis parameters are insufficient regarding specificity and sensitivity, and therefore, novel biomarkers and their facile and rapid applications are being sought to improve the diagnostic procedures. The biosensors, which are employed on the basis of electrochemistry, plasmonics, molecular probes, and nanoparticles, are the prominent ways of developing point-of-care devices, along with the mutual integration of efficient surface chemistry strategies. In this manner, biosensing platforms hold pivotal significance in detecting and quantifying novel AKI biomarkers to improve diagnostic interventions, potentially accelerating clinical management to control the injury in a timely manner. In this review, novel diagnostic platforms and their manufacturing processes are presented comprehensively. Furthermore, strategies to boost their effectiveness are also indicated with several applications. To maximize these efforts, we also review various biosensing approaches with a number of biorecognition elements (e.g., antibodies, aptamers, and molecular imprinting molecules), as well as benchmark their features such as robustness, stability, and specificity of these platforms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RBC-hitchhiking chitosan nanoparticles loading methylprednisolone for lung-targeting delivery</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34933051/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34933051/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hyper-inflammation associated with cytokine storm syndrome causes high mortality in patients with COVID-19. Glucocorticoids, such as methylprednisolone sodium succinate (MPSS), effectively inhibit this inflammatory response. However, frequent and chronic administration of glucocorticoids at high doses leads to hormone dependence and serious side effects. The aim of the present study was to combine nanoparticles with erythrocytes for the targeted delivery of MPSS to the lungs. Chitosan nanoparticles loading MPSS (MPSS-CSNPs) were prepared and adsorbed on the surface of red blood cells (RBC-MPSS-CSNPs) by non-covalent interaction. In vivo pharmacokinetic study indicated that RBC-hitchhiking could significantly reduce the plasma concentration of the drug and prolong the circulation time. The mean residence time (MRT) and area under the curve (AUC) of the RBC-MPSS-CSNPs group were significantly higher than those of the MPSS-CSNPs group and the MPSS injection group. Moreover, in vivo imaging and tissue distribution indicated that RBC-hitchhiking facilitated the accumulation of nanoparticles loading fluorescein in the lung, preventing uptake of these nanoparticles by the liver. Furthermore, compared with the MPSS-CSNPs and MPSS treatment groups, treatment with RBC-MPSS-CSNPs considerably inhibited the production of inflammatory cytokines such as TNF-α and IL-6, and consequently attenuated lung injury induced by lipopolysaccharide in rats. Therefore, RBC-hitchhiking is a potentially effective strategy for the delivery of nanoparticles to the lungs for the treatment of acute lung injury and acute respiratory distress syndrome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nano-enabled Tumor Systematic Energy Exhaustion via Zinc (II) Interference Mediated Glycolysis Inhibition and Specific GLUT1 Depletion</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34913610/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34913610/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite the promise of tumor starvation therapies, they are often associated with nonspecific and incomplete energy blockade. Here, a novel paradigm of starvation therapy is proposed to synergize the &amp;ldquo;Zn&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt; interference&amp;rdquo;-mediated glycolysis inhibition and Zn&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt;-activating GLUT1 (Glucose transporter 1) tumor specific depletion for systematic energy exhaustion. It is discovered that ZIF-8 (zinc imidazolate metal-organic frameworks ) can induce abrupt intracellular Zn&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt; elevation preferentially in melanoma cells, and then achieve effective glycolysis blockade through &amp;ldquo;Zn&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt; interference&amp;rdquo;-triggered decrease of NAD+ and inactivation of GAPDH, making it a powerful tumor energy nanoinhibitor. Meanwhile, Zn&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt;-activating DNAzymes for specifically cleaving GLUT1 mRNA is designed. This DNAzyme can only be activated under intracellular Zn&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt; overloading, and then directionally cut off glucose supply, which further restrains the adaptive up-regulation of glycolytic flux after glycolysis inhibition in tumors. Afterward, DNAzymes are loaded in ZIF-8 concurrently tethered by hyaluronic acid (HA), constructing a &amp;ldquo;nanoenabled energy interrupter &amp;ldquo;. Such a rational design presents a preferential accumulation tendency to tumor sites due to the active CD44-targeting mechanisms, specifically achieves remarkable systematic energy exhaustion in melanoma cells, and affords 80.8% in tumor growth suppression without systemic toxicity in vivo. This work verifies a fascinating therapeutic platform enabling ion interference-inductive starvation strategy for effective tumor therapy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Combating Complement&#39;s Deleterious Effects on Nanomedicine by Conjugating Complement Regulatory Proteins to Nanoparticles</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34910334/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34910334/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Complement opsonization is among the biggest challenges facing nanomedicine. Nearly instantly after injection into blood, nanoparticles are opsonized by the complement protein C3, leading to clearance by phagocytes, fouling of targeting moieties, and release of anaphylatoxins. While surface polymers such as poly(ethylene glycol) (PEG) partially decrease complement opsonization, most nanoparticles still suffer from extensive complement opsonization, especially when linked to targeting moieties. To ameliorate the deleterious effects of complement, two of mammals&amp;rsquo; natural regulators of complement activation (RCAs), Factors H and I, are here conjugated to the surface of nanoparticles. In vitro, Factor H or I conjugation to PEG-coated nanoparticles decrease their C3 opsonization, and markedly reduce nanoparticle uptake by phagocytes. In an in vivo mouse model of sepsis-induced lung injury, Factor I conjugation abrogates nanoparticle uptake by intravascular phagocytes in the lungs, allowing the blood concentration of the nanoparticle to remain elevated much longer. For nanoparticles targeted to the lung&amp;rsquo;s endothelium by conjugation to anti-ICAM antibodies, Factor I conjugation shifts the cell-type distribution away from phagocytes and toward endothelial cells. Finally, Factor I conjugation abrogates the severe anaphylactoid responses common to many nanoparticles, preventing systemic capillary leak and preserving blood flow to visceral organs and the brain. Thus, conjugation of RCAs, like Factor I, to nanoparticles is likely to help in nanomedicine&amp;rsquo;s long battle against complement, improving several key parameters critical for clinical success.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rescuing ischemic stroke by biomimetic nanovesicles through accelerated thrombolysis and sequential ischemia-reperfusion protection</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34902617/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34902617/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rational design of nanomedicine to accelerate thrombolysis and sequentially avoid thrombolysis-mediated reperfusion injury is still a challenge. Here, we develop a biomimetic nanovesicle (tPA/MNP@PM, tMP) by simple encapsulating melanin nanoparticles (MNP) and tPA with a platelet membrane vesicle (PM), which integrates the thrombus targeting property of PM, the photothermal conversion performance and free radical scavenging property of natural melanin for cascaded ischemic stroke treatment. Benefiting from natural thrombus-targeted adhesion capability of PM, nanovesicles could efficiently target thrombus site. Then near-infrared (NIR) mediated photothermal of MNP could lead to rupture of nanovesicles, thus achieving precise release of tPA in thrombus. Interestingly, local hyperthermia also increases the activity of tPA for accelerating thrombolysis. Afterwards, site specific released MNP (4.5 nm) accompanied by hemoperfusion can cross the BBB and accumulate in cerebral ischemia site, scavenging various free radicals and suppressing inflammation- and immune response-induced injury to achieve neuroprotection after thrombolysis. In addition, the biomimetic nanovesicle could block tPA-induced brain hemorrhage after stroke to improve thrombolytic therapy. The evaluation in ischemic stroke mice confirmed that the simple-prepared nanomedicine with cascaded thrombus targeting, precise thrombolysis and ischemia-reperfusion protection properties can significantly enhance the treatment effect of ischemic stroke. STATEMENT OF SIGNIFICANCE: Ischemic stroke is recognized as a leading cause of death and disability in the world. Rational design of nanomedicine to accelerate thrombolysis and sequentially avoid thrombolysis-mediated reperfusion injury is still a challenge. Herein, a biomimetic nanovesicle (tMP) was developed for sequential ischemic stroke treatment. It could overcome the drawbacks of free tPA for safe thrombolysis: i) platelet membrane biomimetic coating significantly increases thrombus targeting; ii) NIR-mediated photothermal of natural melanin precise controlled release of tPA in thrombus in situ, and local hyperthermia also increases the thrombolytic activity of tPA. Notably, released melanin nanoparticles (4.5 nm) accompanied by hemoperfusion can across BBB and avoid ischemia-reperfusion injury through free radical scavenging and inflammation/immune response suppression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fe-Curcumin Nanozyme-Mediated Reactive Oxygen Species Scavenging and Anti-Inflammation for Acute Lung Injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35106369/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35106369/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pneumonia, such as acute lung injury (ALI), has been a type of lethal disease that is generally caused by uncontrolled inflammatory response and excessive generation of reactive oxygen species (ROS). Herein, we report Fe-curcumin-based nanoparticles (Fe-Cur NPs) with nanozyme functionalities in guiding the intracellular ROS scavenging and meanwhile exhibiting anti-inflammation efficacy for curing ALI. The nanoparticles are noncytotoxic when directing these biological activities. Mechanism studies for the anti-inflammation aspects of Fe-Cur NPs were systematically carried out, in which the infected cells and tissues were alleviated through downregulating levels of several important inflammatory cytokines (such as TNF-α, IL-1β, and IL-6), decreasing the intracellular Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt; release, inhibiting NLRP3 inflammasomes, and suppressing NF-κB signaling pathways. In addition, we performed both the intratracheal and intravenous injection of Fe-Cur NPs in mice experiencing ALI and, importantly, found that the accumulation of such nanozymes was enhanced in lung tissue (better than free curcumin drugs), demonstrating its promising therapeutic efficiency in two different administration methods. We showed that the inflammation reduction of Fe-Cur NPs was effective in animal experiments and that ROS scavenging was also effectively achieved in lung tissue. Finally, we revealed that Fe-Cur NPs can decrease the level of macrophage cells (CD11b&lt;sup&gt;lo&lt;/sup&gt;F4/80&lt;sup&gt;hi&lt;/sup&gt;) and CD3&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt;CD45&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T cells in mice, which could help suppress the inflammation cytokine storm caused by ALI. Overall, this work has developed the strategy of using Fe-Cur NPs as nanozymes to scavenge intracellular ROS and as an anti-inflammation nanodrugs to synergistically cure ALI, which may serve as a promising therapeutic agent in the clinical treatment of this deadly disease. Fe-Cur NP nanozymes were designed to attenuate ALI by clearing intracellular ROS and alleviating inflammation synergistically. Relevant cytokines, inflammasomes, and signaling pathways were studied.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nano-Enabled Reposition of Proton Pump Inhibitors for TLR Inhibition: Toward A New Targeted Nanotherapy for Acute Lung Injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34816630/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34816630/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Toll-like receptor (TLR) activation in macrophages plays a critical role in the pathogenesis of acute lung injury (ALI). While TLR inhibition is a promising strategy to control the overwhelming inflammation in ALI, there still lacks effective TLR inhibitors for clinical uses to date. A unique class of peptide-coated gold nanoparticles (GNPs) is previously discovered, which effectively inhibited TLR signaling and protected mice from lipopolysaccharide (LPS)-induced ALI. To fast translate such a discovery into potential clinical applicable nanotherapeutics, herein an elegant strategy of &amp;ldquo;nano-enabled drug repurposing&amp;rdquo; with &amp;ldquo;nano-targeting&amp;rdquo; is introduced to empower the existing drugs for new uses. Combining transcriptome sequencing with Connectivity Map analysis, it is identified that the proton pump inhibitors (PPIs) share similar mechanisms of action to the discovered GNP-based TLR inhibitor. It is confirmed that PPIs (including omeprazole) do inhibit endosomal TLR signaling and inflammatory responses in macrophages and human peripheral blood mononuclear cells, and exhibits anti-inflammatory activity in an LPS-induced ALI mouse model. The omeprazole is then formulated into a nanoform with liposomes to enhance its macrophage targeting ability and the therapeutic efficacy in vivo. This research provides a new translational strategy of nano-enabled drug repurposing to translate bioactive nanoparticles into clinically used drugs and targeted nano-therapeutics for ALI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Preferential siRNA delivery to injured kidneys for combination treatment of acute kidney injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34826532/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34826532/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acute kidney injury (AKI) is characterized by a sudden loss of renal function and is associated with high morbidity and mortality. Tumor suppressor p53 and chemokine receptor CXCR4 were both implicated in the AKI pathology. Here, we report on the development and evaluation of polymeric CXCR4 antagonist (PCX) siRNA carrier for selective delivery to injured kidneys in AKI. Our results show that PCX/siRNA nanoparticles (polyplexes) provide protection against cisplatin injury to tubule cells in vitro when both CXCR4 and p53 are inhibited. The polyplexes selectively accumulate and are retained in the injured kidneys in cisplatin and bilateral ischemia reperfusion injury models of AKI. Treating AKI with the combined CXCR4 inhibition and p53 gene silencing with the PCX/sip53 polyplexes improves kidney function and decreases renal damage. Overall, our results suggest that the PCX/sip53 polyplexes have a significant potential to enhance renal accumulation in AKI and deliver therapeutic siRNA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multifunctional Magnesium Organic Framework-Based Microneedle Patch for Accelerating Diabetic Wound Healing</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34761898/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34761898/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Diabetic wound healing is one of the major challenges in the biomedical fields. The conventional single drug treatments have unsatisfactory efficacy, and the drug delivery effectiveness is restricted by the penetration depth. Herein, we develop a magnesium organic framework-based microneedle patch (denoted as MN-MOF-GO-Ag) that can realize transdermal delivery and combination therapy for diabetic wound healing. Multifunctional magnesium organic frameworks (Mg-MOFs) are mixed with poly(γ-glutamic acid) (γ-PGA) hydrogel and loaded into the tips of MN-MOF-GO-Ag, which slowly releases Mg2+ and gallic acid in the deep layer of the dermis. The released Mg2+ induces cell migration and endothelial tubulogenesis, while gallic acid, a reactive oxygen species-scavenger, promotes antioxidation. Besides, the backing layer of MN-MOF-GO-Ag is made of γ-PGA hydrogel and graphene oxide-silver nanocomposites (GO-Ag) which further enables excellent antibacterial effects for accelerating wound healing. The therapeutic effects of MN-MOF-GO-Ag on wound healing are demonstrated with the full-thickness cutaneous wounds of a diabetic mouse model. The significant improvement of wound healing is achieved for mice treated with MN-MOF-GO-Ag.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Melanin-like Nanoenzyme for Acute Lung Injury Therapy via Suppressing Oxidative and Endoplasmic Reticulum Stress Response</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34834263/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34834263/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nanoenzyme-mediated catalytic activity is emerging as a novel strategy for reactive oxygen species (ROS) scavenging in acute lung injury (ALI) treatment. However, one of the main hurdles for these metal-containing nanoenzymes is their potential toxicity and single therapeutic mechanism. Herein, we uncovered a melanin-like nanoparticles derived from the self-polymerization of 1,8-dihydroxynaphthalene (PDH nanoparticles), showing a significant anti-inflammation therapeutic effect on ALI mice. The prepared PDH nanoparticles rich in phenol groups could not only act as radical scavengers to alleviate oxidative stress but could also chelate calcium overload to suppress the endoplasmic reticulum stress response. As revealed by the therapeutic effect in vivo, PDH nanoparticles significantly prohibited neutrophil infiltration and the secretion of proinflammatory cytokines (TNF-α and IL-6), thus improving the inflammatory cascade in the ALI model. Above all, our work provides an effective anti-inflammatory nanoplatform by using the inherent capability of melanin-like nanoenzymes, proposing the potential application prospects of these melanin-like nanoparticles for acute inflammation-induced injury treatment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A DNA Nanoraft-Based Cytokine Delivery Platform for Alleviation of Acute Kidney Injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34723467/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34723467/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Erratum in:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Correction to “&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubs.acs.org/doi/10.1021/acsnano.2c02862&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;A DNA Nanoraft-Based Cytokine Delivery Platform for Alleviation of Acute Kidney Injury&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cytokine immunotherapy represents an attractive strategy to stimulate robust immune responses for renal injury repair in ischemic acute kidney injury (AKI). However, its clinical application is hindered by its nonspecificity to kidney, short circulation half-life, and severe side effects. An ideal cytokine immunotherapy for AKI requires preferential delivery of cytokines with accurate dosage to the kidney and sustained-release of cytokines to stimulate the immune responses. Herein, we developed a DNA nanoraft cytokine by precisely arranging interleukin-33 (IL-33) nanoarray on rectangle DNA origami, through which IL-33 can be preferentially delivered to the kidney for alleviation of AKI. A nanoraft carrying precisely quantified IL-33 predominantly accumulated in the kidney for up to 48 h. Long-term sustained-release of IL-33 from nanoraft induced rapid expansion of type 2 innate lymphoid cells (ILC 2s) and regulatory T cells (Tregs) and achieved better treatment efficiency compared to free IL-33 treatment. Thus, our study demonstrates that a nanoraft can serve as a structurally well-defined delivery platform for cytokine immunotherapy in ischemic AKI and other renal diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multifaceted roles of a bioengineered nanoreactor in repressing radiation-induced lung injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34478930/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34478930/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Radiation-induced lung injury (RILI) is a potentially fatal and dose-limiting complication of thoracic cancer radiotherapy. However, effective therapeutic agents for this condition are limited. Here, we describe a novel strategy to exert additive effects of a non-erythropoietic EPO derivative (ARA290), along with a free radical scavenger, superoxide dismutase (SOD), using a bioengineered nanoreactor (SOD@ARA290-HBc). ARA290-chimeric nanoreactor makes SOD present in a confined reaction space by encapsulation into its interior to heighten stability against denaturing stimuli. In a RILI mouse model, intratracheal administration of SOD@ARA290-HBc was shown to significantly ameliorate acute radiation pneumonitis and pulmonary fibrosis. Our investigations revealed that SOD@ARA290-HBc performs its radioprotective effects by protecting against radiation induced alveolar epithelial cell apoptosis and ferroptosis, suppressing oxidative stress, inhibiting inflammation and by modulating the infiltrated macrophage phenotype, or through a combination of these mechanisms. In conclusion, SOD@ARA29-HBc is a potential therapeutic agent for RILI, and given its multifaceted roles, it may be further developed as a translational nanomedicine for other related disorders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lung-Targeted Transgene Expression of Nanocomplexed Ad5 Enhances Immune Response in the Presence of Preexisting Immunity</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36714358/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36714358/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recombinant adenovirus serotype 5 (Ad5) vector has been widely applied in vaccine development targeting infectious diseases, such as Ebola virus disease and coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19). However, the high prevalence of preexisting anti-vector immunity compromises the immunogenicity of Ad5-based vaccines. Thus, there is a substantial unmet need to minimize preexisting immunity while improving the insert-induced immunity of Ad5 vectors. Herein, we address this need by utilizing biocompatible nanoparticles to modulate Ad5-host interactions. We show that positively charged human serum albumin nanoparticles ((+)HSAnp), which are capable of forming a complex with Ad5, significantly increase the transgene expression of Ad5 in both coxsackievirus-adenovirus receptor-positive and -negative cells. Furthermore, in charge- and dose-dependent manners, Ad5/(+)HSAnp complexes achieve robust (up to 227-fold higher) and long-term (up to 60 days) transgene expression in the lungs of mice following intranasal instillation. Importantly, in the presence of preexisting anti-Ad5 immunity, complexed Ad5-based Ebola and COVID-19 vaccines significantly enhance antigen-specific humoral response and mucosal immunity. These findings suggest that viral aggregation and charge modification could be leveraged to engineer enhanced viral vectors for vaccines and gene therapies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
