<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Spinal Cord | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/spinal-cord/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/spinal-cord/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Spinal Cord</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Spinal Cord</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/spinal-cord/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spinal VGLUT3 lineage neurons drive visceral mechanical allodynia but not sensitized visceromotor reflexes</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36584681/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36584681/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Focal colorectal distention (fCRD) can drive both visceromotor reflexes and aversion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spinal CCK neurons drive acute visceromotor reflexes and aversion by noxious fCRD&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spinal VGLUT3 lineage neurons drive fCRD-evoked allodynia in mice with colitis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spinal VGLUT3-negative neurons sufficiently drive sensitized visceromotor reflexes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Summary&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Visceral pain is among the most prevalent and bothersome forms of chronic pain, but their transmission in the spinal cord is still poorly understood. Here, we conducted focal colorectal distention (fCRD) to drive both visceromotor responses (VMRs) and aversion. We first found that spinal CCK neurons were necessary for noxious fCRD to drive both VMRs and aversion under naive conditions. We next showed that spinal VGLUT3 neurons mediate visceral allodynia, whose ablation caused loss of aversion evoked by low-intensity fCRD in mice with gastrointestinal (GI) inflammation or spinal circuit disinhibition. Importantly, these neurons were dispensable for driving sensitized VMRs under both inflammatory and central disinhibition conditions. Anatomically, a subset of VGLUT3 neurons projected to parabrachial nuclei, whose photoactivation sufficiently generated aversion in mice with GI inflammation, without influencing VMRs. Our studies suggest the presence of different spinal substrates that transmit nociceptive versus affective dimensions of visceral sensory information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Proper wiring of newborn neurons to control bladder function after complete spinal cord injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36455486/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36455486/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Activation of endogenous neurogenesis by bioactive materials enables restoration of sensory/motor function after complete spinal cord injury (SCI) via formation of new relay neural circuits. The underlying wiring logic of newborn neurons in adult central nervous system (CNS) is unknown. Here, we report neurotrophin3-loaded chitosan biomaterial substantially recovered bladder function after SCI. Multiple neuro-circuitry tracing technologies using pseudorabies virus (PRV), rabies virus (RV), and anterograde adeno-associated virus (AAV), demonstrated that newborn neurons were integrated into the micturition neural circuits and reconnected higher brain centers and lower spinal cord centers to control voiding, and participated in the restoration of the lower urinary tract function, even in the absence of long-distance axonal regeneration. Opto- and chemo-genetic studies further supported the notion that the supraspinal control of the lower urinary tract function was partially recovered. Our data demonstrated that regenerated relay neurons could be properly integrated into disrupted long-range neural circuits to restore function of adult CNS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generation of neural organoids for spinal-cord regeneration via the direct reprogramming of human astrocytes</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36424465/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36424465/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Organoids with region-specific architecture could facilitate the repair of injuries of the central nervous system. Here we show that human astrocytes can be directly reprogrammed into early neuroectodermal cells via the overexpression of &lt;em&gt;OCT4&lt;/em&gt;, the suppression of &lt;em&gt;p53&lt;/em&gt; and the provision of the small molecules CHIR99021, SB431542, RepSox and Y27632. We also report that the activation of signalling mediated by fibroblast growth factor, sonic hedgehog and bone morphogenetic protein 4 in the reprogrammed cells induces them to form spinal-cord organoids with functional neurons specific to the dorsal and ventral domains. In mice with complete spinal-cord injury, organoids transplanted into the lesion differentiated into spinal-cord neurons, which migrated and formed synapses with host neurons. The direct reprogramming of human astrocytes into neurons may pave the way for in vivo neural organogenesis from endogenous astrocytes for the repair of injuries to the central nervous system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Puerarin: A protective drug against ischemia-reperfusion injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/36091830/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/36091830/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ischemia-reperfusion (I/R) is a pathological process that occurs in numerous organs throughout the human body and is frequently associated with severe cellular damage and death. Puerarin is an isoflavone compound extracted from the root of Pueraria lobata and has pharmacological effects such as dilating cerebral vessels and anti-free radical generation in cerebral ischemic tissues. With the deepening of experimental research and clinical research on puerarin, it has been found that puerarin has a protective effect on ischemia-reperfusion injury (IRI) of the heart, brain, spinal cord, lung, intestine and other organs. In summary, puerarin has a vast range of pharmacological effects and significant protective effects, and it also has obvious advantages in the clinical protection of patients with organ IRI. With the deepening of experimental pharmacological research and clinical research, it is expected to be an effective drug for IRI treatment. In this review, we summarize the current knowledge of the protective effect of puerarin on I/R organ injury and its possible underlying molecular mechanisms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LncRNA RMRP Contributes to the Development and Progression of Spinal Cord Injury by Regulating miR-766-5p/FAM83A Axis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35902548/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35902548/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spinal cord injury (SCI) is known as a central nervous system disorder. Previous studies suggested that long-non-coding RNA RMRP (LncRNA RMRP) was abnormally expressed in SCI, but the potential underlying mechanism remains to be further explored. To explore the regulatory roles of LncRNA RMRP/miR-766-5p/FAM83A axis in SCI. Spinal T9 hemisection was performed on healthy adult male Sprague Dawley (SD) rats to establish the SCI rat models. The expressions of LncRNA RMRP in spinal cord of rats in different groups were examined by RT-qPCR. Moreover, AGE1.HN and PC12 cells were treated with hypoxic condition, and expression of LncRNA RMRP was examined by RT-qPCR methods. Furthermore, hypoxic PC12 cells were transfected with LncRNA RMRP OE, and the cell viability, proliferation, and apoptosis were examined. Next, the direct targeting relationship between LncRNA RMRP and miR-766-5p, as well as miR-766-5p and FAM83A, was confirmed by dual-luciferase reporter and RNA pull-down assays. Finally, the effects of LncRNA RMRP/miR-766-5p/FAM83A axis on cell viability, proliferation, and apoptosis were examined. LncRNA RMRP was downregulated in SCI rats and over-expression of LncRNA RMRP alleviated the SCI condition. LncRNA RMRP over-expression increased the viability and proliferation, and inhibited the apoptosis of hypoxic PC12 cells in vitro. miR-766-5p was confirmed as a target of LncRNA RMRP, and FAM83A was confirmed as a target of miR-766-5p. LncRNA RMRP could regulate the proliferation and apoptosis of hypoxic PC12 cells via regulating miR-766-5p/FAM83A axis in vitro. LncRNA RMRP may contribute to the pathogenesis of SCI via regulating miR-766-5p/FAM83A axis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Influence of respiratory loading on left-ventricular function in cervical spinal cord injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35751465/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35751465/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cervical spinal cord injury (C-SCI) negatively impacts cardiac and respiratory function. As the heart and lungs are linked via the pulmonary circuit these systems are interdependent. Here, we utilized inspiratory and expiratory loading to assess whether augmenting the respiratory pump improves left-ventricular (LV) filling and output in individuals with motor-complete C-SCI. We hypothesized LV end-diastolic volume (LVEDV) would increase and decrease with inspiratory and expiratory loading, respectively. Participants (C-SCI: 7M/1F, 35 ± 7 years; able-bodied: 7M/1F, 32 ± 6 years) were assessed under five conditions during 45° head-up tilt; unloaded, inspiratory loading with -10 and -20 cm H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O oesophageal pressure (&lt;em&gt;P&lt;sub&gt;oes&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/em&gt;) on inspiration, and expiratory loading with +10 and +20 cm H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O &lt;em&gt;P&lt;sub&gt;oes&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/em&gt; on expiration. An oesophageal balloon catheter monitored &lt;em&gt;P&lt;sub&gt;oes&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/em&gt; , and LV structure and function were assessed by echocardiography. In C-SCI only, (1) +20 cm H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O reduced LVEDV vs. unloaded (81 ± 15 vs. 88 ± 11 ml, &lt;em&gt;P&lt;/em&gt; = 0.006); (2) heart rate was higher during +20 cm H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O compared to unloaded (&lt;em&gt;P&lt;/em&gt; = 0.001) and +10 cm H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O (&lt;em&gt;P&lt;/em&gt; = 0.002); (3) cardiac output was higher during +20 cm H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O than unloaded (&lt;em&gt;P&lt;/em&gt; = 0.002); and (4) end-expiratory lung volume was higher during +20 cm H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O vs. unloaded (63 ± 10 vs. 55 ± 13% total lung capacity, &lt;em&gt;P&lt;/em&gt; = 0.003) but was unaffected by inspiratory loading. In both groups, -10 and -20 cm H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O had no significant effect on LVEDV. These findings suggest greater expiratory positive pressure acutely impairs LV filling in C-SCI, potentially via impaired venous return, mediastinal constraint and/or direct ventricular interaction subsequent to dynamic hyperinflation. Inspiratory loading did not significantly improve LV function in C-SCI and neither inspiratory nor expiratory loading affected cardiac function or lung volumes in able-bodied participants. KEY POINTS: Cervical spinal cord injury (C-SCI) alters both the cardiac and the respiratory system, but little is known about how these systems interact following injury. Here, we manipulated inspiratory or expiratory intrathoracic pressure (ITP) to mechanistically test the role of the respiratory pump in circulatory function in highly trained individuals with C-SCI and an able-bodied reference group. In individuals with C-SCI, greater ITP during expiratory loading caused dynamic hyperinflation that was associated with impaired left-ventricular filling. More negative ITP during inspiratory loading did not significantly alter left-ventricular volumes in either group. Interventions that prevent dynamic hyperinflation and/or enhance the ability to generate expiratory pressures may help preserve left-ventricular filling in individuals with C-SCI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
