<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Spinal Cord | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/spinal-cord/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/spinal-cord/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Spinal Cord</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Spinal Cord</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/spinal-cord/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Mouse Model of Spinal Cord Hypoperfusion with Immediate Paralysis Caused by Endovascular Repair of Thoracic Aortic Aneurysm</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36716430/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36716430/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; A clinically relevant mouse model of thoracic endovascular aortic repair-induced ischemic spinal cord injury has been lacking since the procedure was first employed in 1991. We hypothesized that ligation of mouse intercostal arteries would simulate thoracic endovascular aortic repair-induced ischemic spinal cord injury and behavioral deficit. We aimed to create a mouse model of thoracic endovascular aortic repair-induced spinal cord hypoperfusion by ligating five pairs of mouse intercostal vessels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; Mice were divided into sham (n=53) and ligation (n=60) groups. We double ligated three pairs and single ligated two pairs of thoracic intercostal arteries in adult C57BL/6 mice. A laser doppler probe was used in vivo on the spinal cords and intercostal arteries to document the extent of arterial ligation and spinal cord hypoperfusion. The Basso Mouse Scale for Locomotion, histological studies, and electron microscopy demonstrated post-ligation locomotive and histopathological changes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; Ligation induced a significant and instantaneous drop in blood flow in the intercostal arteries (% change) (mean=-63.81, 95%CI: -72.28 to -55.34) and the thoracic spinal cord (% change) (mean=-68.55, 95%CI: -80.23 to -56.87).Paralysis onset was immediate and of varying degree, with behavioral deficit stratified into three groups: 9.4% exhibited severe paralysis, 37.5% moderate paralysis, and 53.1% mild paralysis at day 1 (n=32; &lt;em&gt;p&lt;/em&gt;&amp;lt;0.001). Mild and moderate paralysis was transient, gradually improving over time. Severe paralysis showed no improvement and exhibited a higher mortality rate (83%; n=15/18) compared to moderately (33%; n=6/18) and mildly (24%; n=6/25) paralyzed mice (&lt;em&gt;p&lt;/em&gt;&amp;lt;0.001). The overall ligation group survival rate (84%; n=46/55) was significantly lower than the sham group (100%; n=48/48) with &lt;em&gt;p&lt;/em&gt;=0.003.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/em&gt; Our mouse model generates reproducible spinal cord hypoperfusion and accompanying histopathological ischemic spinal cord damage. The resulting anatomical changes and variable behavioral deficits mimic the variability in radiological and clinical findings in human patients.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Schwann cell-derived exosomes containing MFG-E8 modify macrophage/microglial polarization for attenuating inflammation via the SOCS3/STAT3 pathway after spinal cord injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36717543/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36717543/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Macrophage/microglia polarization acts as an important part in regulating inflammatory responses in spinal cord injury (SCI). However, the regulation of inflammation of Schwann cell-derived exosomes (SCDEs) for SCI repair is still unclear. Therefore, we intend to find out the effect of SCDEs on regulating the inflammation related to macrophage polarization during the recovery of SCI. Firstly, the thesis demonstrated that SCDEs could attenuate the LPS- inflammation in BMDMs by suppressing M1 polarization and stimulating M2 polarization. Similarly, SCDEs improved functional recovery of female Wistar rats of the SCI contusion model according to BBB (Basso, Beattie, and Bresnahan) score, electrophysiological assay, and the gait analysis system of CatWalk XT. Moreover, MFG-E8 was verified as the main component of SCDEs to improve the inflammatory response by proteomic sequencing and lentiviral transfection. Improvement of the inflammatory microenvironment also inhibited neuronal apoptosis. The knockout of MFG-E8 in SCs can reverse the anti-inflammatory effects of SCDEs treatment. The SOCS3/STAT3 signaling pathway was identified to participate in upregulating M2 polarization induced by MFG-E8. In conclusion, our findings will enrich the mechanism of SCDEs in repairing SCI and provide potential applications and new insights for the clinical translation of SCDEs treatment for SCI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spinal VGLUT3 lineage neurons drive visceral mechanical allodynia but not sensitized visceromotor reflexes</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36584681/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36584681/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Focal colorectal distention (fCRD) can drive both visceromotor reflexes and aversion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spinal CCK neurons drive acute visceromotor reflexes and aversion by noxious fCRD&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spinal VGLUT3 lineage neurons drive fCRD-evoked allodynia in mice with colitis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spinal VGLUT3-negative neurons sufficiently drive sensitized visceromotor reflexes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Summary&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Visceral pain is among the most prevalent and bothersome forms of chronic pain, but their transmission in the spinal cord is still poorly understood. Here, we conducted focal colorectal distention (fCRD) to drive both visceromotor responses (VMRs) and aversion. We first found that spinal CCK neurons were necessary for noxious fCRD to drive both VMRs and aversion under naive conditions. We next showed that spinal VGLUT3 neurons mediate visceral allodynia, whose ablation caused loss of aversion evoked by low-intensity fCRD in mice with gastrointestinal (GI) inflammation or spinal circuit disinhibition. Importantly, these neurons were dispensable for driving sensitized VMRs under both inflammatory and central disinhibition conditions. Anatomically, a subset of VGLUT3 neurons projected to parabrachial nuclei, whose photoactivation sufficiently generated aversion in mice with GI inflammation, without influencing VMRs. Our studies suggest the presence of different spinal substrates that transmit nociceptive versus affective dimensions of visceral sensory information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Proper wiring of newborn neurons to control bladder function after complete spinal cord injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36455486/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36455486/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Activation of endogenous neurogenesis by bioactive materials enables restoration of sensory/motor function after complete spinal cord injury (SCI) via formation of new relay neural circuits. The underlying wiring logic of newborn neurons in adult central nervous system (CNS) is unknown. Here, we report neurotrophin3-loaded chitosan biomaterial substantially recovered bladder function after SCI. Multiple neuro-circuitry tracing technologies using pseudorabies virus (PRV), rabies virus (RV), and anterograde adeno-associated virus (AAV), demonstrated that newborn neurons were integrated into the micturition neural circuits and reconnected higher brain centers and lower spinal cord centers to control voiding, and participated in the restoration of the lower urinary tract function, even in the absence of long-distance axonal regeneration. Opto- and chemo-genetic studies further supported the notion that the supraspinal control of the lower urinary tract function was partially recovered. Our data demonstrated that regenerated relay neurons could be properly integrated into disrupted long-range neural circuits to restore function of adult CNS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generation of neural organoids for spinal-cord regeneration via the direct reprogramming of human astrocytes</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36424465/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36424465/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Organoids with region-specific architecture could facilitate the repair of injuries of the central nervous system. Here we show that human astrocytes can be directly reprogrammed into early neuroectodermal cells via the overexpression of &lt;em&gt;OCT4&lt;/em&gt;, the suppression of &lt;em&gt;p53&lt;/em&gt; and the provision of the small molecules CHIR99021, SB431542, RepSox and Y27632. We also report that the activation of signalling mediated by fibroblast growth factor, sonic hedgehog and bone morphogenetic protein 4 in the reprogrammed cells induces them to form spinal-cord organoids with functional neurons specific to the dorsal and ventral domains. In mice with complete spinal-cord injury, organoids transplanted into the lesion differentiated into spinal-cord neurons, which migrated and formed synapses with host neurons. The direct reprogramming of human astrocytes into neurons may pave the way for in vivo neural organogenesis from endogenous astrocytes for the repair of injuries to the central nervous system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Puerarin: A protective drug against ischemia-reperfusion injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/36091830/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/36091830/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ischemia-reperfusion (I/R) is a pathological process that occurs in numerous organs throughout the human body and is frequently associated with severe cellular damage and death. Puerarin is an isoflavone compound extracted from the root of Pueraria lobata and has pharmacological effects such as dilating cerebral vessels and anti-free radical generation in cerebral ischemic tissues. With the deepening of experimental research and clinical research on puerarin, it has been found that puerarin has a protective effect on ischemia-reperfusion injury (IRI) of the heart, brain, spinal cord, lung, intestine and other organs. In summary, puerarin has a vast range of pharmacological effects and significant protective effects, and it also has obvious advantages in the clinical protection of patients with organ IRI. With the deepening of experimental pharmacological research and clinical research, it is expected to be an effective drug for IRI treatment. In this review, we summarize the current knowledge of the protective effect of puerarin on I/R organ injury and its possible underlying molecular mechanisms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LncRNA RMRP Contributes to the Development and Progression of Spinal Cord Injury by Regulating miR-766-5p/FAM83A Axis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35902548/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35902548/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spinal cord injury (SCI) is known as a central nervous system disorder. Previous studies suggested that long-non-coding RNA RMRP (LncRNA RMRP) was abnormally expressed in SCI, but the potential underlying mechanism remains to be further explored. To explore the regulatory roles of LncRNA RMRP/miR-766-5p/FAM83A axis in SCI. Spinal T9 hemisection was performed on healthy adult male Sprague Dawley (SD) rats to establish the SCI rat models. The expressions of LncRNA RMRP in spinal cord of rats in different groups were examined by RT-qPCR. Moreover, AGE1.HN and PC12 cells were treated with hypoxic condition, and expression of LncRNA RMRP was examined by RT-qPCR methods. Furthermore, hypoxic PC12 cells were transfected with LncRNA RMRP OE, and the cell viability, proliferation, and apoptosis were examined. Next, the direct targeting relationship between LncRNA RMRP and miR-766-5p, as well as miR-766-5p and FAM83A, was confirmed by dual-luciferase reporter and RNA pull-down assays. Finally, the effects of LncRNA RMRP/miR-766-5p/FAM83A axis on cell viability, proliferation, and apoptosis were examined. LncRNA RMRP was downregulated in SCI rats and over-expression of LncRNA RMRP alleviated the SCI condition. LncRNA RMRP over-expression increased the viability and proliferation, and inhibited the apoptosis of hypoxic PC12 cells in vitro. miR-766-5p was confirmed as a target of LncRNA RMRP, and FAM83A was confirmed as a target of miR-766-5p. LncRNA RMRP could regulate the proliferation and apoptosis of hypoxic PC12 cells via regulating miR-766-5p/FAM83A axis in vitro. LncRNA RMRP may contribute to the pathogenesis of SCI via regulating miR-766-5p/FAM83A axis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spinal Cord Injury Impairs Lung Immunity in Mice</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35697382/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35697382/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pulmonary infection is a leading cause of morbidity and mortality after spinal cord injury (SCI). Although SCI causes atrophy and dysfunction in primary and secondary lymphoid tissues with a corresponding decrease in the number and function of circulating leukocytes, it is unknown whether this SCI-dependent systemic immune suppression also affects the unique tissue-specific antimicrobial defense mechanisms that protect the lung. In this study, we tested the hypothesis that SCI directly impairs pulmonary immunity and subsequently increases the risk for developing pneumonia. Using mouse models of severe high-level SCI, we find that recruitment of circulating leukocytes and transcriptional control of immune signaling in the lung is impaired after SCI, creating an environment that is permissive for infection. Specifically, we saw a sustained loss of pulmonary leukocytes, a loss of alveolar macrophages at chronic time points postinjury, and a decrease in immune modulatory genes, especially cytokines, needed to eliminate pulmonary infections. Importantly, this injury-dependent impairment of pulmonary antimicrobial defense is only partially overcome by boosting the recruitment of immune cells to the lung with the drug AMD3100, a Food and Drug Administration-approved drug that mobilizes leukocytes and hematopoietic stem cells from bone marrow. Collectively, these data indicate that the immune-suppressive effects of SCI extend to the lung, a unique site of mucosal immunity. Furthermore, preventing lung infection after SCI will likely require novel strategies, beyond the use of orthodox antibiotics, to reverse or block tissue-specific cellular and molecular determinants of pulmonary immune surveillance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Influence of respiratory loading on left-ventricular function in cervical spinal cord injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35751465/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35751465/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cervical spinal cord injury (C-SCI) negatively impacts cardiac and respiratory function. As the heart and lungs are linked via the pulmonary circuit these systems are interdependent. Here, we utilized inspiratory and expiratory loading to assess whether augmenting the respiratory pump improves left-ventricular (LV) filling and output in individuals with motor-complete C-SCI. We hypothesized LV end-diastolic volume (LVEDV) would increase and decrease with inspiratory and expiratory loading, respectively. Participants (C-SCI: 7M/1F, 35 ± 7 years; able-bodied: 7M/1F, 32 ± 6 years) were assessed under five conditions during 45° head-up tilt; unloaded, inspiratory loading with -10 and -20 cm H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O oesophageal pressure (&lt;em&gt;P&lt;sub&gt;oes&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/em&gt;) on inspiration, and expiratory loading with +10 and +20 cm H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O &lt;em&gt;P&lt;sub&gt;oes&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/em&gt; on expiration. An oesophageal balloon catheter monitored &lt;em&gt;P&lt;sub&gt;oes&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/em&gt; , and LV structure and function were assessed by echocardiography. In C-SCI only, (1) +20 cm H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O reduced LVEDV vs. unloaded (81 ± 15 vs. 88 ± 11 ml, &lt;em&gt;P&lt;/em&gt; = 0.006); (2) heart rate was higher during +20 cm H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O compared to unloaded (&lt;em&gt;P&lt;/em&gt; = 0.001) and +10 cm H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O (&lt;em&gt;P&lt;/em&gt; = 0.002); (3) cardiac output was higher during +20 cm H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O than unloaded (&lt;em&gt;P&lt;/em&gt; = 0.002); and (4) end-expiratory lung volume was higher during +20 cm H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O vs. unloaded (63 ± 10 vs. 55 ± 13% total lung capacity, &lt;em&gt;P&lt;/em&gt; = 0.003) but was unaffected by inspiratory loading. In both groups, -10 and -20 cm H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O had no significant effect on LVEDV. These findings suggest greater expiratory positive pressure acutely impairs LV filling in C-SCI, potentially via impaired venous return, mediastinal constraint and/or direct ventricular interaction subsequent to dynamic hyperinflation. Inspiratory loading did not significantly improve LV function in C-SCI and neither inspiratory nor expiratory loading affected cardiac function or lung volumes in able-bodied participants. KEY POINTS: Cervical spinal cord injury (C-SCI) alters both the cardiac and the respiratory system, but little is known about how these systems interact following injury. Here, we manipulated inspiratory or expiratory intrathoracic pressure (ITP) to mechanistically test the role of the respiratory pump in circulatory function in highly trained individuals with C-SCI and an able-bodied reference group. In individuals with C-SCI, greater ITP during expiratory loading caused dynamic hyperinflation that was associated with impaired left-ventricular filling. More negative ITP during inspiratory loading did not significantly alter left-ventricular volumes in either group. Interventions that prevent dynamic hyperinflation and/or enhance the ability to generate expiratory pressures may help preserve left-ventricular filling in individuals with C-SCI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>lncRNA MEG3 restrained the M1 polarization of microglia in acute spinal cord injury through the HuR/A20/NF-κB axis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35338543/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35338543/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The M1 polarization of microglia and neuroinflammation restrict the treatment of acute spinal cord injury (ASCI), and long non-coding ribonucleic acid (lncRNA) maternally expressed gene 3 (MEG3) expression is lessened in ASCI. However, the function and mechanism of lncRNA MEG3 in the M1 polarization of microglia and neuroinflammation in ASCI are unclear. The expressions of lncRNA MEG3 in ASCI mouse spinal cord tissues and lipopolysaccharide (LPS)-treated primary microglia and BV2 cells were quantified through a quantitative real-time polymerase chain reaction. In-vitro assays were conducted to explore the function of lncRNA MEG3 in the M1 polarization of microglia and neuroinflammation in ASCI. RNA degradation, RNA immunoprecipitation, RNA pull-down, cycloheximide-chase, and ubiquitination analyses were carried out to probe into the mechanism of lncRNA MEG3 in the M1 polarization of microglia and neuroinflammation in ASCI. The lncRNA MEG3 expression was lessened in the ASCI mouse spinal cord tissues and LPS-treated primary microglia and BV2 cells, and the overexpression of lncRNA MEG3 restrained the M1 polarization of microglia and the neuroinflammation by regulating the NF-κB signaling pathway. For the investigation of the potential mechanism of such, the overexpression of lncRNA MEG3 restrained the M1 polarization of microglia through the HuR/A20/NF-κB axis and boosted the motor function recovery and neuroinflammation relief in the mice with SCI. The overexpression of lncRNA MEG3 restrained the M1 polarization of microglia through the HuR/A20/NF-κB axis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Epigenetic modifications in spinal ligament aging</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/35218968/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/35218968/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spinal ligament aging is a complex process involving genetic, epigenetic, and environmental factors.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;DNA methylation, histone modifications and ncRNAs exert vital functions in spinal ligament aging.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Epigenetic alterations provide promising diagnostic and therapeutic targets for spinal ligament aging.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spinal stenosis is a common degenerative spine disorder in the aged population and the spinal ligament aging is a main contributor to this chronic disease. However, the underlying mechanisms of spinal ligament aging remain unclear. Epigenetics is the study of heritable and reversible changes in the function of a gene or genome that occur without any alteration in the primary DNA sequence. Epigenetic alterations have been demonstrated to play crucial roles in age-related diseases and conditions, and they are recently studied as biomarkers and therapeutic targets in the field of cancer research. The main epigenetic modifications, including DNA methylation alteration, histone modifications as well as dysregulated noncoding RNA modulation, have all been implicated in spinal ligament aging diseases. DNA methylation modulates the expression of critical genes including WNT5A, GDNF, ACSM5, miR-497 and miR-195 during spinal ligament degeneration. Histone modifications widely affect gene expression and obvious histone modification abnormalities have been found in spinal ligament aging. MicroRNAs (miRNAs), long noncoding RNAs (lncRNAs) and circular RNAs (circRNAs) exert crucial regulating effects on spinal ligament aging conditions via targeting various osteogenic or fibrogenic differentiation related genes. To our knowledge, there is no systematic review yet to summarize the involvement of epigenetic mechanisms of spinal ligament aging in degenerative spinal diseases. In this study, we systematically discussed the different epigenetic modifications and their potential functions in spinal ligament aging process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ruxolitinib attenuates secondary injury after traumatic spinal cord injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35142693/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35142693/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Excessive inflammation post-traumatic spinal cord injury (SCI) induces microglial activation, which leads to prolonged neurological dysfunction. However, the mechanism underlying microglial activation-induced neuroinflammation remains poorly understood. Ruxolitinib (RUX), a selective inhibitor of JAK1/2, was recently reported to inhibit inflammatory storms caused by SARS-CoV-2 in the lung. However, its role in disrupting inflammation post-SCI has not been confirmed. In this study, microglia were treated with RUX for 24 hours and then activated with interferon-γ for 6 hours. The results showed that interferon-γ-induced phosphorylation of JAK and STAT in microglia was inhibited, and the mRNA expression levels of pro-inflammatory cytokines tumor necrosis factor-α, interleukin-1β, interleukin-6, and cell proliferation marker Ki67 were reduced. In further in vivo experiments, a mouse model of spinal cord injury was treated intragastrically with RUX for 3 successive days, and the findings suggest that RUX can inhibit microglial proliferation by inhibiting the interferon-γ/JAK/STAT pathway. Moreover, microglia treated with RUX centripetally migrated toward injured foci, remaining limited and compacted within the glial scar, which resulted in axon preservation and less demyelination. Moreover, the protein expression levels of tumor necrosis factor-α, interleukin-1β, and interleukin-6 were reduced. The neuromotor function of SCI mice also recovered. These findings suggest that RUX can inhibit neuroinflammation through inhibiting the interferon-γ/JAK/STAT pathway, thereby reducing secondary injury after SCI and producing neuroprotective effects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coding and long non-coding gene expression changes in the CNS traumatic injuries</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/35129669/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/35129669/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Traumatic brain injury (TBI) and spinal cord injury (SCI) are two main central nervous system (CNS) traumas, caused by external physical insults. Both injuries have devastating effects on the quality of life, and there is no effective therapy at present. Notably, gene expression profiling using bulk RNA sequencing (RNA-Seq) and single-cell RNA-Seq (scRNA-Seq) have revealed significant changes in many coding and non-coding genes, as well as important pathways in SCI and TBI. Particularly, recent studies have revealed that long non-coding RNAs (lncRNAs) with lengths greater than 200 nucleotides and without protein-coding potential have tissue- and cell type-specific expression pattern and play critical roles in CNS injury by gain- and loss-of-function approaches. LncRNAs have been shown to regulate protein-coding genes or microRNAs (miRNAs) directly or indirectly, participating in processes including inflammation, glial activation, cell apoptosis, and vasculature events. Therefore, lncRNAs could serve as potential targets for the diagnosis, treatment, and prognosis of SCI and TBI. In this review, we highlight the recent progress in transcriptome studies of SCI and TBI and insights into molecular mechanisms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
