<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Anoikis | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/anoikis/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/anoikis/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Anoikis</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Anoikis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/anoikis/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Identification of a novel anoikis-related gene signature to predict prognosis and tumor microenvironment in lung adenocarcinoma</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36507553/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36507553/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Lung adenocarcinoma (LUAD) is the most prevalent histotype of non-small cell lung cancer. Anoikis, an alternative form of programmed cell death, plays a pivotal role in cancer invasion and metastasis, preventing the detached cancer cells from readhering to other substrates for abnormal proliferation. The aim of this study was to conduct a comprehensive analyses of the prognostic implications of anoikis-related genes (ARGs) in LUAD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; ARGs were selected from The Cancer Genome Atlas (TCGA) database and Genecards dataset using differential expression analysis. The signature incorporating ARGs was identified using univariate Cox regression analysis and LASSO regression analysis. Furthermore, a nomogram containing the signature and clinical information was developed through univariate and multivariate Cox regression analysis. Kaplan-Meier survival analysis and receiver operating characteristic (ROC) curves were applied to evaluate the predictive validity of these risk models. Finally, functional analysis of the selected ARGs in signature and analysis of immune landscape were also conducted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; A 16-gene signature was integrated to stratify LUAD patients into different survival risk groups. The prognostic risk score generated from the signature and TNM stage were identified as independent prognostic factors and utilized to develop a nomogram. Both the signature and the nomogram showed satisfactory prediction performance in predicting overall survival (OS) of LUAD patients. The ARGs were enriched in several biological functions and signaling pathways. Finally, differences of immune landscape were investigated among the high- and low-risk groups stratified by the signature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; This study revealed potential relationships between ARGs and prognosis of LUAD. The prognostic predictors identified in present study could be utilized as potential biomarkers for clinical applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anoikis-Associated Lung Cancer Metastasis: Mechanisms and Therapies</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/36230714/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/36230714/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tumor metastasis occurs in lung cancer, resulting in tumor progression and therapy failure. Anoikis is a mechanism of apoptosis that combats tumor metastasis; it inhibits the escape of tumor cells from the native extracellular matrix to other organs. Deciphering the regulators and mechanisms of anoikis in cancer metastasis is urgently needed to treat lung cancer. Several natural and synthetic products exhibit the pro-anoikis potential in lung cancer cells and in vivo models. These products include artonin E, imperatorin, oroxylin A, lupalbigenin, sulforaphane, renieramycin M, avicequinone B, and carbenoxolone. This review summarizes the current understanding of the molecular mechanisms of anoikis regulation and relevant regulators involved in lung cancer metastasis and discusses the therapeutic potential of targeting anoikis in the treatment of lung cancer metastasis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Identification and validation of an anoikis-associated gene signature to predict clinical character, stemness, IDH mutation, and immune filtration in glioblastoma</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36091049/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36091049/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Glioblastoma (GBM) is the most prominent and aggressive primary brain tumor in adults. Anoikis is a specific form of programmed cell death that plays a key role in tumor invasion and metastasis. The presence of anti-anoikis factors is associated with tumor aggressiveness and drug resistance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; The non-negative matrix factorization algorithm was used for effective dimension reduction for integrated datasets. Differences in the tumor microenvironment (TME), stemness indices, and clinical characteristics between the two clusters were analyzed. Difference analysis, weighted gene coexpression network analysis (WGCNA), univariate Cox regression, and least absolute shrinkage and selection operator regression were leveraged to screen prognosis-related genes and construct a risk score model. Immunohistochemistry was performed to evaluate the expression of representative genes in clinical specimens. The relationship between the risk score and the TME, stemness, clinical traits, and immunotherapy response was assessed in GBM and pancancer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; Two definite clusters were identified on the basis of anoikis-related gene expression. Patients with GBM assigned to C1 were characterized by shortened overall survival, higher suppressive immune infiltration levels, and lower stemness indices. We further constructed a risk scoring model to quantify the regulatory patterns of anoikis-related genes. The higher risk score group was characterized by a poor prognosis, the infiltration of suppressive immune cells and a differentiated phenotype, whereas the lower risk score group exhibited the opposite effects. In addition, patients in the lower risk score group exhibited a higher frequency of isocitrate dehydrogenase (IDH) mutations and a more sensitive response to immunotherapy. Drug sensitivity analysis was performed, revealing that the higher risk group may benefit more from drugs targeting the PI3K/mTOR signaling pathway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/em&gt; We revealed potential relationships between anoikis-related genes and clinical features, TME, stemness, IDH mutation, and immunotherapy and elucidated their therapeutic value.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CircCEMIP promotes anoikis-resistance by enhancing protective autophagy in prostate cancer cells</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35655258/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35655258/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Circular RNAs (circRNAs) are essential participants in the development and progression of various malignant tumors. Previous studies have shown that cell migration-inducing protein (CEMIP) accelerates prostate cancer (PCa) anoikis resistance (AR) by activating autophagy. This study focused on the effect of circCEMIP on PCa metastasis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; This study gradually revealed the role of circ_0004585 in PCa anoikis resistance via quantitative real-time PCR (qRT-PCR) analysis, western blotting, pull-down assays, and dual fluorescence reporter assays.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; Functionally, circ_0004585 promoted PCa cells invasion and metastasis both in vitro and in vivo. Mechanistically, circ_0004585 directly interacted with miR-1248 to upregulate target gene expression. Furthermore, target prediction and dual-luciferase reporter assays identified transmembrane 9 superfamily member 4 (TM9SF4) as a potential miR-1248 target. Pathway analysis revealed that TM9SF4 activated autophagy to promote PCa cells anoikis resistance via mTOR phosphorylation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; These results demonstrated that circ_0004585 played an oncogenic role during PCa invasion and metastasis by targeting the miR-1248/TM9SF4 axis while providing new insight into therapeutic strategy development for metastatic PCa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Histone H3K27me3 Demethylases KDM6A/B Resist Anoikis and Transcriptionally Regulate Stemness-Related Genes</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35186918/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35186918/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Epithelial cancer cells that lose attachment from the extracellular matrix (ECM) to seed in a distant organ often undergo anoikis&amp;rsquo;s specialized form of apoptosis. Recently, KDM3A (H3K9 demethylase) has been identified as a critical effector of anoikis in cancer cells. However, whether other histone demethylases are involved in promoting or resisting anoikis remains elusive. We screened the major histone demethylases and found that both H3K27 histone demethylases, namely, KDM6A/B were highly expressed during ECM detachment. Inhibition of the KDM6A/B activity by using a specific inhibitor results in reduced sphere formation capacity and increased apoptosis. Knockout of KDM6B leads to the loss of stem cell properties in solitary cells. Furthermore, we found that KDM6B maintains stemness by transcriptionally regulating the expression of stemness genes &lt;em&gt;SOX2&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;SOX9&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;CD44&lt;/em&gt; in detached cells. KDM6B occupies the promoter region of both &lt;em&gt;SOX2&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;CD44&lt;/em&gt; to regulate their expression epigenetically. We also noticed an increased occupancy of the HIF1α promoter by KDM6B, suggesting its regulatory role in maintaining hypoxia in detached cancer cells. This observation was further strengthened as we found a significant positive association in the expression of both KDM6B and HIF1α in various cancer types. Overall, our results reveal a novel transcriptional program that regulates resistance against anoikis and maintains stemness-like properties.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anoikis: an emerging hallmark in health and diseases</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/21953325/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/21953325/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anoikis is a programmed cell death occurring upon cell detachment from the correct extracellular matrix, thus disrupting integrin ligation. It is a critical mechanism in preventing dysplastic cell growth or attachment to an inappropriate matrix. Anoikis prevents detached epithelial cells from colonizing elsewhere and is thus essential for tissue homeostasis and development. As anchorage-independent growth and epithelial-mesenchymal transition, two features associated with anoikis resistance, are crucial steps during tumour progression and metastatic spreading of cancer cells, anoikis deregulation has now evoked particular attention from the scientific community. The aim of this review is to analyse the molecular mechanisms governing both anoikis and anoikis resistance, focusing on their regulation in physiological processes, as well as in several diseases, including metastatic cancers, cardiovascular diseases and diabetes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
