<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mitophagy | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/mitophagy/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/mitophagy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Mitophagy</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Mitophagy</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/mitophagy/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>The nucleoprotein of influenza A virus inhibits the innate immune response by inducing mitophagy</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36588386/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36588386/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mitophagy is a form of autophagy that plays a key role in maintaining the homeostasis of functional mitochondria in the cell. Viruses have evolved various strategies to manipulate mitophagy to escape host immune responses and promote virus replication. In this study, the nucleoprotein (NP) of H1N1 virus (PR8 strain) was identified as a regulator of mitophagy. We revealed that NP-mediated mitophagy leads to the degradation of the mitochondria-anchored protein MAVS, thereby blocking MAVS-mediated antiviral signaling and promoting virus replication. The NP-mediated mitophagy is dependent on the interaction of NP with MAVS and the cargo receptor TOLLIP. Moreover, Y313 of NP is a key residue for the MAVS-NP interaction and NP-mediated mitophagy. The NPY313F mutation significantly attenuates the virus-induced mitophagy and the virus replication in vitro and in vivo. Taken together, our findings uncover a novel mechanism by which the NP of influenza virus induces mitophagy to attenuate innate immunity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lycopene Attenuates Di(2-ethylhexyl) Phthalate-Induced Mitochondrial Damage and Inflammation in Kidney via cGAS-STING Signaling</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36583613/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36583613/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Di(2-ethylhexyl) phthalate (DEHP) is a highly harmful and persistent environmental pollutant. Due to its unique chemical composition, it frequently dissolves and enters the environment to endanger human and animal health. Lycopene is a natural bioactive component that can potentially reduce the risk of environmental factor-induced chronic diseases. The present study sought to explore the role and underlying mechanism of lycopene (LYC) on DEHP-induced renal inflammatory response and apoptosis. In this study, mice were orally treated with LYC (5 mg/kg BW/day) and/or DEHP (500 or 1000 mg/kg BW/day) for 28 days. Our results indicated that LYC prevented DEHP-induced histopathological alterations and ultrastructural injuries, including decreased mitochondrial membrane potential (ΔΨm), PINK1/Parkin pathway-mediated mitophagy, and mitochondrial energetic deficit. When damaged mitochondria release mitochondrial DNA (mtDNA) into cytosol, LYC can alleviate inflammation and apoptosis caused by DEHP exposure by activating the cyclic GMP-AMP synthase-stimulator of interferon gene (cGAS-STING) signal pathway. Collectively, our data demonstrate that LYC can reduce mitophagy caused by DEHP exposure by activating the PINK1/Parkin pathway and then reduce renal inflammation and apoptosis through the cGAS-STING pathway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>STAT3/mitophagy axis coordinates macrophage NLRP3 inflammasome activation and inflammatory bone loss</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36502520/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36502520/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Signal transducer and activator of transcription 3 (STAT3), a cytokine-responsive transcription factor, is known to play a role in immunity and bone remodeling. However, whether and how STAT3 impacts macrophage NLR family pyrin domain containing 3 (NLRP3) inflammasome activation associated with inflammatory bone loss remains unknown. Here, STAT3 signaling is hyperactivated in macrophages in the context of both non-sterile and sterile inflammatory osteolysis, and this was highly correlated with the cleaved interleukin-1β (IL-1β) expression pattern. Strikingly, pharmacological inhibition of STAT3 markedly blocks macrophage NLRP3 inflammasome activation in vitro, thereby relieving inflammatory macrophage-amplified osteoclast formation and bone resorptive activity. Mechanistically, STAT3 inhibition in macrophages triggers PTEN-induced kinase 1 (PINK1)-dependent mitophagy that eliminates dysfunctional mitochondria, reverses mitochondrial membrane potential collapse, and inhibits mitochondrial reactive oxygen species release, thus inactivating the NLRP3 inflammasome. In vivo, STAT3 inhibition effectively protects mice from both infection-induced periapical lesions and aseptic titanium particle-mediated calvarial bone erosion with potent induction of PINK1 and downregulation of inflammasome activation, macrophage infiltration, and osteoclast formation. This study reveals the regulatory role of the STAT3/mitophagy axis at the osteo-immune interface and highlights a potential therapeutic intervention to prevent inflammatory bone loss.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Antioxidant mitoquinone ameliorates EtOH-LPS induced lung injury by inhibiting mitophagy and NLRP3 inflammasome activation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36059543/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36059543/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chronic ethanol abuse is a systemic disorder and a risk factor for acute respiratory distress syndrome (ARDS) and chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD). However, the mechanisms involved are unknown. One explanation is that ethanol produces damaging reactive oxygen species (ROS) and disturbs the balance of mitochondria within the lungs to promote a pro-injury environment. We hypothesized that targeting an antioxidant to the mitochondria would prevent oxidative damage and attenuate EtOH-LPS-induced lung injury. To test this, we investigated the effects of mitochondria-targeted ubiquinone, Mitoquinone (MitoQ) on ethanol-sensitized lung injury induced by LPS. Lung inflammation, ROS, mitochondria function, and mitophagy were assessed. We demonstrated that chronic ethanol feeding sensitized the lung to LPS-induced lung injury with significantly increased reactive oxygen species ROS level and mitochondrial injury as well as lung cellular NLRP3 inflammasome activation. These deleterious effects were attenuated by MitoQ administration in mice. The protective effects of MitoQ are associated with decreased cellular mitophagy and NLRP3 inflammasome activation &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;in vitro&lt;/em&gt;. Taken together, our results demonstrated that ethanol aggravated LPS-induced lung injury, and antioxidant MitoQ protects from EtOH-LPS-induced lung injury, probably through reducing mitophagy and protecting mitochondria, followed by NLRP3 inflammasome activation. These results will provide the prevention and treatment of ethanol intake effects with new ideas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UBXD8 mediates mitochondria-associated degradation to restrain apoptosis and mitophagy</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35979733/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35979733/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The hexameric AAA-ATPase valosin-containing protein (VCP) is essential for mitochondrial protein quality control. How VCP is recruited to mammalian mitochondria remains obscure. Here we report that UBXD8, an ER- and lipid droplet-localized VCP adaptor, also localizes to mitochondria and locally recruits VCP. UBXD8 associates with mitochondrial and ER ubiquitin E3 ligases and targets their substrates for degradation. Remarkably, both mitochondria- and ER-localized UBXD8 can degrade mitochondrial and ER substrates in cis and in trans. UBXD8 also associates with the TOM complex but is dispensable for translocation-associated degradation. UBXD8 knockout impairs the degradation of the pro-survival protein Mcl1 but surprisingly sensitizes cells to apoptosis and mitochondrial stresses. UBXD8 knockout also hyperactivates mitophagy. We identify pro-apoptotic BH3-only proteins Noxa, Bik, and Bnip3 as novel UBXD8 substrates and determine that UBXD8 inhibits apoptosis via degrading Noxa and restrains mitophagy via degrading Bnip3. Collectively, our characterizations reveal UBXD8 as the major mitochondrial adaptor of VCP and unveil its role in apoptosis and mitophagy regulation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dynamic O-GlcNAcylation coordinates ferritinophagy and mitophagy to activate ferroptosis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35504898/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35504898/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ferroptosis is a regulated iron-dependent cell death characterized by the accumulation of lipid peroxidation. A myriad of facets linking amino acid, lipid, redox, and iron metabolisms were found to drive or to suppress the execution of ferroptosis. However, how the cells decipher the diverse pro-ferroptotic stress to activate ferroptosis remains elusive. Here, we report that protein O-GlcNAcylation, the primary nutrient sensor of glucose flux, orchestrates both ferritinophagy and mitophagy for ferroptosis. Following the treatment of ferroptosis stimuli such as RSL3, a commonly used ferroptosis inducer, there exists a biphasic change of protein O-GlcNAcylation to modulate ferroptosis. Pharmacological or genetic inhibition of O-GlcNAcylation promoted ferritinophagy, resulting in the accumulation of labile iron towards mitochondria. Inhibition of O-GlcNAcylation resulted in mitochondria fragmentation and enhanced mitophagy, providing an additional source of labile iron and rendering the cell more sensitive to ferroptosis. Mechanistically, we found that de-O-GlcNAcylation of the ferritin heavy chain at S179 promoted its interaction with NCOA4, the ferritinophagy receptor, thereby accumulating labile iron for ferroptosis. Our findings reveal a previously uncharacterized link of dynamic O-GlcNAcylation with iron metabolism and decision-making for ferroptosis, thus offering potential therapeutic intervention for fighting disease.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paradoxical Mitophagy Regulation by PINK1 and TUFm</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33113344/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33113344/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sepsis is the major cause of acute kidney injury (AKI) associated with high mortality rates. Mitochondrial dysfunction contributes to the pathophysiology of septic AKI. Mitophagy is an important mitochondrial quality control mechanism that selectively eliminates damaged mitochondria, but its role and regulation in septic AKI remain largely unknown. Here, we demonstrate the induction of mitophagy in mouse models of septic AKI induced by lipopolysaccharide (LPS) treatment or by cecal ligation and puncture. Mitophagy was also induced in cultured proximal tubular epithelial cells exposed to LPS. Induction of mitophagy under these experimental setting was suppressed by pink1 or park2 knockout, indicating the role of the PINK1/PARK2 pathway of mitophagy in septic AKI. In addition, sepsis induced more severe kidney injury and cell apoptosis in pink1 or park2 knockout mice than in wild-type mice, suggesting a beneficial role of mitophagy in septic AKI. Furthermore, in cultured renal tubular cells treated with LPS, knockdown of pink1 or park2 inhibited mitochondrial accumulation of the autophagy adaptor optineurin (OPTN) and silencing Optn inhibited LPS-induced mitophagy. Taken together, these findings suggest that the PINK1/PARK2 pathway of mitophagy plays an important role in mitochondrial quality control, tubular cell survival, and renal function in septic AKI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The PINK1/PARK2/optineurin pathway of mitophagy is activated for protection in septic acute kidney injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33137712/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33137712/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sepsis is the major cause of acute kidney injury (AKI) associated with high mortality rates. Mitochondrial dysfunction contributes to the pathophysiology of septic AKI. Mitophagy is an important mitochondrial quality control mechanism that selectively eliminates damaged mitochondria, but its role and regulation in septic AKI remain largely unknown. Here, we demonstrate the induction of mitophagy in mouse models of septic AKI induced by lipopolysaccharide (LPS) treatment or by cecal ligation and puncture. Mitophagy was also induced in cultured proximal tubular epithelial cells exposed to LPS. Induction of mitophagy under these experimental setting was suppressed by pink1 or park2 knockout, indicating the role of the PINK1/PARK2 pathway of mitophagy in septic AKI. In addition, sepsis induced more severe kidney injury and cell apoptosis in pink1 or park2 knockout mice than in wild-type mice, suggesting a beneficial role of mitophagy in septic AKI. Furthermore, in cultured renal tubular cells treated with LPS, knockdown of pink1 or park2 inhibited mitochondrial accumulation of the autophagy adaptor optineurin (OPTN) and silencing Optn inhibited LPS-induced mitophagy. Taken together, these findings suggest that the PINK1/PARK2 pathway of mitophagy plays an important role in mitochondrial quality control, tubular cell survival, and renal function in septic AKI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visualizing and Modulating Mitophagy for Therapeutic Studies of Neurodegeneration</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32437660/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32437660/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dysfunctional mitochondria accumulate in many human diseases. Accordingly, mitophagy, which removes these mitochondria through lysosomal degradation, is attracting broad attention. Due to uncertainties in the operational principles of conventional mitophagy probes, however, the specificity and quantitativeness of their readouts are disputable. Thorough investigation of the behaviors and fates of fluorescent proteins inside and outside lysosomes enabled us to develop an indicator for mitophagy, mito-SRAI. Through strict control of its mitochondrial targeting, we were able to monitor mitophagy in fixed biological samples more reproducibly than before. Large-scale image-based high-throughput screening led to the discovery of a hit compound that induces selective mitophagy of damaged mitochondria. In a mouse model of Parkinsons disease, we found that dopaminergic neurons selectively failed to execute mitophagy that promoted their survival within lesions. These results show that mito-SRAI is an essential tool for quantitative studies of mitochondrial quality control.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crosstalk between mitophagy and innate immunity in viral infection</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/36590405/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/36590405/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mitochondria are important organelles involved in cell metabolism and programmed cell death in eukaryotic cells and are closely related to the innate immunity of host cells against viruses. Mitophagy is a process in which phagosomes selectively phagocytize damaged or dysfunctional mitochondria to form autophagosomes and is degraded by lysosomes, which control mitochondrial mass and maintain mitochondrial dynamics and cellular homeostasis. Innate immunity is an important part of the immune system and plays a vital role in eliminating viruses. Viral infection causes many physiological and pathological alterations in host cells, including mitophagy and innate immune pathways. Accumulating evidence suggests that some virus promote self-replication through regulating mitophagy-mediated innate immunity. Clarifying the regulatory relationships among mitochondria, mitophagy, innate immunity, and viral infection will shed new insight for pathogenic mechanisms and antiviral strategies. This review systemically summarizes the activation pathways of mitophagy and the relationship between mitochondria and innate immune signaling pathways, and then discusses the mechanisms of viruses on mitophagy and innate immunity and how viruses promote self-replication by regulating mitophagy-mediated innate immunity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
