<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Breast | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/breast/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/breast/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Breast</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Breast</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/breast/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Niche stiffness sustains cancer stemness via TAZ and NANOG phase separation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36646707/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36646707/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Emerging evidence shows that the biomechanical environment is required to support cancer stem cells (CSCs), which play a crucial role in drug resistance. However, how mechanotransduction signals regulate CSCs and its clinical significance has remained unclear. Using clinical-practice ultrasound elastography for patients&amp;rsquo; lesions and atomic force microscopy for surgical samples, we reveal that increased matrix stiffness is associated with poor responses to neoadjuvant chemotherapy, worse prognosis, and CSC enrichment in patients with breast cancer. Mechanically, TAZ activated by biomechanics enhances CSC properties via phase separation with NANOG. TAZ-NANOG phase separation, which is dependent on acidic residues in the N-terminal activation domain of NANOG, promotes the transcription of SOX2 and OCT4. Therapeutically, targeting NANOG or TAZ reduces CSCs and enhances the chemosensitivity in vivo. Collectively, this study demonstrated that the phase separation of a pluripotency transcription factor links mechanical cues in the niche to the fate of CSCs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>T cell-derived interleukin-22 drives the expression of CD155 by cancer cells to suppress NK cell function and promote metastasis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36630913/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36630913/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IL-22 from Th cells acts on IL-22RA1&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; tumor cells to promote lung metastases&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mechanistically, IL-22 induces overexpression of CD155 on tumor cells&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Excessive CD155 promotes internalization of CD226 in NK cells, rendering them inert&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IL-22-CD155 signature governs early-stage lung and breast cancer patients’ survival&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although T cells can exert potent anti-tumor immunity, a subset of T helper (Th) cells producing interleukin-22 (IL-22) in breast and lung tumors is linked to dismal patient outcome. Here, we examined the mechanisms whereby these T cells contribute to disease. In murine models of lung and breast cancer, constitutional and T cell-specific deletion of &lt;em&gt;Il22&lt;/em&gt; reduced metastases without affecting primary tumor growth. Deletion of the IL-22 receptor on cancer cells decreases metastasis to a degree similar to that seen in &lt;em&gt;IL-22&lt;/em&gt;-deficient mice. IL-22 induced high expression of CD155, which bound to the activating receptor CD226 on NK cells. Excessive activation led to decreased amounts of CD226 and functionally impaired NK cells, which elevated the metastatic burden. IL-22 signaling was also associated with CD155 expression in human datasets and with poor patient outcomes. Taken together, our findings reveal an immunosuppressive circuit activated by T cell-derived IL-22 that promotes lung metastasis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tea leaf-derived exosome-like nanotherapeutics retard breast tumor growth by pro-apoptosis and microbiota modulation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36600299/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36600299/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While several artificial nanodrugs have been approved for clinical treatment of breast tumor, their long-term applications are restricted by unsatisfactory therapeutic outcomes, side reactions and high costs. Conversely, edible plant-derived natural nanotherapeutics (NTs) are source-widespread and cost-effective, which have been shown remarkably effective in disease treatment. Herein, we extracted and purified exosome-like NTs from tea leaves (TLNTs), which had an average diameter of 166.9 nm and a negative-charged surface of - 28.8 mV. These TLNTs contained an adequate slew of functional components such as lipids, proteins and pharmacologically active molecules. In vitro studies indicated that TLNTs were effectively internalized by breast tumor cells (4T1 cells) and caused a 2.5-fold increase in the amount of intracellular reactive oxygen species (ROS) after incubation for 8 h. The high levels of ROS triggered mitochondrial damages and arrested cell cycles, resulting in the apoptosis of tumor cells. The mouse experiments revealed that TLNTs achieved good therapeutic effects against breast tumors regardless of intravenous injection and oral administration through direct pro-apoptosis and microbiota modulation. Strikingly, the intravenous injection of TLNTs, not oral administration, yielded obvious hepatorenal toxicity and immune activation. These findings collectively demonstrate that TLNTs can be developed as a promising oral therapeutic platform for the treatment of breast cancer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Targeting SOST using a small-molecule compound retards breast cancer bone metastasis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36581888/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36581888/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Breast cancer metastasis to the bone can be exacerbated by osteoporosis, is associated with poor long-term survival, and has limited therapeutic options. Sclerostin (SOST) is an endogenous inhibitor of bone formation, and an attractive target for treatment of osteoporosis. However, it is unclear whether SOST can be used as a therapeutic target for bone metastases of breast cancer, and whether small molecule compounds that target SOST in breast cancer cells can inhibit breast cancer bone metastasis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; SOST expression in 442 breast cancer tissues was characterized by immunohistochemistry and statistically analyzed for the association with breast cancer bone metastases. Bone metastatic breast cancer SCP2 cells were induced for SOST silencing or overexpression and their bone metastatic behaviors were tested in vitro and in vivo. To identify potential therapeutics, we screened inhibitors of the interaction of SOST with STAT3 from a small chemical molecule library and tested the inhibitory effects of one inhibitor on breast cancer growth and bone metastasis in vitro and in vivo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; We found that up-regulated SOST expression was associated with breast cancer bone metastases and worse survival of breast cancer patients. SOST silencing significantly reduced the bone metastatic capacity of SCP2 cells. SOST interacted with STAT3 to enhance the TGF-β/KRAS signaling, increasing both tumor growth and bone metastasis. Treatment with one lead candidate, S6, significantly inhibited the growth of breast-cancer organoids and bone metastasis in mice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; Our findings highlight a new class of potential therapeutics for treatment of bone metastasis in breast cancer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ΔNp63/p73 drive metastatic colonization by controlling a regenerative epithelial stem cell program in quasi-mesenchymal cancer stem cells</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36538894/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36538894/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ΔNp63 and p73 maintain residence in the quasi-mesenchymal breast CSC state&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ΔNp63 and p73 are required for the post-extravasation proliferation of CSCs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ΔNp63 controls distinct transcriptional programs in CSCs and normal basal SCs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Quasi-mesenchymal CSCs use autocrine EGFR signaling to enable metastatic colonization&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cancer stem cells (CSCs) may serve as the cellular seeds of tumor recurrence and metastasis, and they can be generated via epithelial-mesenchymal transitions (EMTs). Isolating pure populations of CSCs is difficult because EMT programs generate multiple alternative cell states, and phenotypic plasticity permits frequent interconversions between these states. Here, we used cell-surface expression of integrin β4 (ITGB4) to isolate highly enriched populations of human breast CSCs, and we identified the gene regulatory network operating in ITGB4+ CSCs. Specifically, we identified ΔNp63 and p73, the latter of which transactivates ΔNp63, as centrally important transcriptional regulators of quasi-mesenchymal CSCs that reside in an intermediate EMT state. We found that the transcriptional program controlled by ΔNp63 in CSCs is largely distinct from the one that it orchestrates in normal basal mammary stem cells and, instead, it more closely resembles a regenerative epithelial stem cell response to wounding. Moreover, quasi-mesenchymal CSCs repurpose this program to drive metastatic colonization via autocrine EGFR signaling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two isoleucyl tRNAs that decode synonymous codons divergently regulate breast cancer metastatic growth by controlling translation of proliferation-regulating genes</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36510010/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36510010/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The human genome contains 61 codons encoding 20 amino acids. Synonymous codons representing a given amino acid are decoded by a set of transfer RNAs (tRNAs) called isoacceptors. We report the surprising observation that two isoacceptor tRNAs that decode synonymous codons become modulated in opposing directions during breast cancer progression. Specifically, tRNA&lt;sup&gt;Ile&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;sub&gt;UAU&lt;/sub&gt; became upregulated, whereas tRNA&lt;sup&gt;Ile&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;sub&gt;UAU&lt;/sub&gt; became repressed as breast cancer cells attained enhanced metastatic capacity. Functionally, tRNA&lt;sup&gt;Ile&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;sub&gt;UAU&lt;/sub&gt; promoted and tRNA&lt;sup&gt;Ile&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;sub&gt;UAU&lt;/sub&gt; suppressed metastatic colonization in mouse xenograft models. These tRNAs mediated opposing effects on codon-dependent translation of growth-promoting genes, consistent with genomic enrichment or depletion of their cognate codons in mitotic genes. Our findings uncover a specific isoacceptor tRNA pair that act in opposition, divergently impacting growth-regulating genes and a disease phenotype. Degeneracy of the genetic code can thus be biologically exploited by human cancer cells via tRNA isoacceptor shifts that causally facilitate the transition toward a growth-promoting state.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lipid-laden lung mesenchymal cells foster breast cancer metastasis via metabolic reprogramming of tumor cells and natural killer cells</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36476935/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36476935/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lung mesenchymal cells (MCs) store neutral lipids during breast cancer progression&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IL-1β elicits neutral lipid accumulation in lung MCs to foster metastasis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lipid-laden MCs metabolically reprogram both tumor cells and NK cells&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Targeting lipid-laden MCs improves the efficacy of NK cell-based immunotherapy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Summary&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the distant organ environment is known to support metastasis of primary tumors, its metabolic roles in this process remain underdetermined. Here, in breast cancer models, we found lung-resident mesenchymal cells (MCs) accumulating neutral lipids at the pre-metastatic stage. This was partially mediated by interleukin-1β (IL-1β)-induced hypoxia-inducible lipid droplet-associated (HILPDA) that subsequently represses adipose triglyceride lipase (ATGL) activity in lung MCs. MC-specific ablation of the ATGL or HILPDA genes in mice reinforced and reduced lung metastasis of breast cancer respectively, suggesting a metastasis-promoting effect of lipid-laden MCs. Mechanistically, lipid-laden MCs transported their lipids to tumor cells and natural killer (NK) cells via exosome-like vesicles, leading to heightened tumor cell survival and proliferation and NK cell dysfunction. Blockage of IL-1β, which was effective singly, improved the efficacy of adoptive NK cell immunotherapy in mitigating lung metastasis. Collectively, lung MCs metabolically regulate tumor cells and anti-tumor immunity to facilitate breast cancer lung metastasis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gut dysbiosis induces the development of mastitis through a reduction in host anti-inflammatory enzyme activity by endotoxemia</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36451232/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36451232/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Mounting experimental evidence has shown that the gut microbiota plays a significant role in the pathogenesis of mastitis, and clinical investigations have found that the occurrence of mastitis is correlated with ruminal dysbiosis. However, the underlying mechanism by which the ruminal microbiota participates in the development of mastitis remains unknown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; In the present study, we found that cows with clinical mastitis had marked systemic inflammation, which was associated with significant ruminal dysbiosis, especially enriched Proteobacteria in the rumen. Ruminal microbiota transplantation from mastitis cows (M-RMT) to mice induced mastitis symptoms in recipient mice along with increased mammary proinflammatory signature activation of the TLR4-cGAS-STING-NF-κB/NLRP3 pathways. M-RMT also induced mucosal inflammation and impaired intestinal barrier integrity, leading to increased endotoxemia and systemic inflammation. Moreover, we showed that M-RMT mirrored ruminal microbiota disruption in the gut of recipient mice, as evidenced by enriched Proteobacteria and similar bacterial functions, which were correlated with most proinflammatory parameters and serum lipopolysaccharide (LPS) levels in mice. Recurrent low-grade LPS treatment mirrored gut dysbiosis-induced endotoxemia and caused severe mastitis in mice. Furthermore, we found that gut dysbiosis-derived LPS reduced host alkaline phosphatase activity by activating neuraminidase (Neu), which facilitates low-grade LPS exposure and E. coli-induced mastitis in mice. Conversely, treatment with calf intestinal alkaline phosphatase or the Neu inhibitor zanamivir alleviated low-grade LPS exposure and E. coli-induced mastitis in mice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; Our results suggest that ruminal dysbiosis-derived low-grade endotoxemia can cause mastitis and aggravate pathogen-induced mastitis by impairing host anti-inflammatory enzymes, which implies that regulating the ruminal or gut microbiota to prevent low-grade systemic inflammation is a potential strategy for mastitis intervention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Immunosuppressive lncRNA LINC00624 promotes tumor progression and therapy resistance through ADAR1 stabilization</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36252997/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36252997/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Despite the success of HER2-targeted therapy in achieving prolonged survival in approximately 50% of treated individuals, treatment resistance is still an important challenge for HER2+ breast cancer (BC) patients. The influence of both adaptive and innate immune responses on the therapeutic outcomes of HER2+BC patients has been extensively demonstrated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; Long non-coding RNAs expressed in non-pathological complete response (pCR) HER2 positive BC were screened and validated by RNA-seq. Survival analysis were made by Kaplan-Meier method. Cell death assay and proliferation assay were performed to confirm the phenotype of LINC00624. RT-qPCR and western blot were used to assay the IFN response. Xenograft mouse model were used for in vivo confirmation of anti-neu treatment resistance. RNA pull-down and immunoblot were used to confirm the interaction of ADAR1 and LINC00624. ADAR1 recombinant protein were purified from baculovirus expression system. B16-OVA cells were used to study antigen presentation both in vitro and in vivo. Flow cytometry was used to determine the tumor infiltrated immune cells of xenograft model. Antisense oligonucleotides (ASOs) were used for in vivo treatment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; In this study, we found that LINC00624 blocked the antitumor effect of HER2- targeted therapy both in vitro and in vivo by inhibiting type I interferon (IFN) pathway activation. The double-stranded RNA-like structure of LINC00624 can bind and be edited by the adenosine (A) to inosine (I) RNA-editing enzyme adenosine deaminase RNA specific 1 (ADAR1), and this editing has been shown to release the growth inhibition and attenuate the innate immune response caused by the IFN response. Notably, LINC00624 promoted the stabilization of ADAR1 by inhibiting its ubiquitination-induced degradation triggered by β-TrCP. In contrast, LINC00624 inhibited major histocompatibility complex (MHC) class I antigen presentation and limited CD8+T cell infiltration in the cancer microenvironment, resulting in immune checkpoint blockade inhibition and anti-HER2 treatment resistance mediated through ADAR1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; In summary, these results suggest that LINC00624 is a cancer immunosuppressive lncRNA and targeting LINC00624 through ASOs in tumors expressing high levels of LINC00624 has great therapeutic potential in future clinical applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CircSEMA4B inhibits the progression of breast cancer by encoding a novel protein SEMA4B-211aa and regulating AKT phosphorylation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36115854/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36115854/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PI3K/AKT signaling pathway plays an important role in regulating the tumorigenesis, recurrence, and metastasis of breast cancer (BC). In this study, we discovered a circRNA with protein-coding potential, which we named circSEMA4B. CircSEMA4B could encode a novel protein, SEMA4B-211aa. Both circSEMA4B and SEMA4B-211aa were remarkably downregulated in BC tissues and cell lines. Low expression of circSEMA4B was positively associated with TNM stage, tumor size, lymph node metastasis, and distant metastasis of BC patients. The functional investigation showed that circSEMA4B and SEMA4B-211aa could significantly inhibit the proliferation and migration of BC in vivo and in vitro. Of note, SEMA4B-211aa inhibited the generation of PIP3 by binding to p85, thereby inhibiting the phosphorylation of AKT (Thr308). CircSEMA4B inhibited the phosphorylation of AKT (Ser473) through miR-330-3p/PDCD4 axis. Taken together, circSEMA4B is a novel negative regulator of PI3K/AKT signaling pathway, providing novel mechanistic insights into the underlying mechanisms of BC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TRIM27 cooperates with STK38L to inhibit ULK1-mediated autophagy and promote tumorigenesis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35670107/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35670107/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Autophagy represents a fundamental mechanism for maintaining cell survival and tissue homeostasis in response to physiological and pathological stress. Autophagy initiation converges on the FIP200-ATG13-ULK1 complex wherein the serine/threonine kinase ULK1 plays a central role. Here, we reveal that the E3 ubiquitin ligase TRIM27 functions as a negative regulatory component of the FIP200-ATG13-ULK1 complex. TRIM27 directly polyubiquitinates ULK1 at K568 and K571 sites with K48-linked ubiquitin chains, with proteasomal turnover maintaining control over basal ULK1 levels. However, during starvation-induced autophagy, TRIM27 catalyzes non-degradative K6- and K11-linked ubiquitination of the serine/threonine kinase 38-like (STK38L) kinase. In turn, STK38L ubiquitination promotes its activation and phosphorylation of ULK1 at Ser495, rendering ULK1 in a permissive state for TRIM27-mediated hyper-ubiquitination of ULK1. This cooperative mechanism serves to restrain the amplitude and duration of autophagy. Further evidence from mouse models shows that basal autophagy levels are increased in Trim27 knockout mice and that Trim27 differentially regulates tumorigenesis and metastasis. Our study identifies a key role of STK38L-TRIM27-ULK1 signaling axis in negatively controlling autophagy with relevance established in human breast cancer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The natural antisense transcript HAS2-AS1 regulates breast cancer cells aggressiveness independently from hyaluronan metabolism</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35395387/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35395387/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The survival probability of patients with estrogen receptor (ER) negative breast cancer is higher when the expression of HAS2-AS1 is elevated.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;HAS2-AS1 overexpression reduces cell aggressiveness only of ER negative and not of ER positive cell lines.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;HAS2-AS1 regulates neither hyaluronan accumulation nor hyaluronan synthases expression in ER negative breast cancer cells.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Microarray gene expression profiling reveals that HAS2-AS1 has a pivotal role to regulate the expression of several genes involved in tumorigenesis.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Overexpression of the Long isoform of HAS2-AS1 exon 2 induces mesenchymal to epithelial transition in ER negative breast cancer cells.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hyaluronan (HA) is a ubiquitous extracellular matrix component playing a crucial role in the regulation of cell behaviors, including cancer. Aggressive breast cancer cells tend to proliferate, migrate and metastatize. Notably, triple-negative breast cancer cells lacking the expression of estrogen receptor (ER) as well as progesterone receptor and HER2 are more aggressive than ER-positive ones. As currently no targeted therapy is available for triple-negative breast cancer, the identification of novel therapeutic targets has a high clinical priority. In ER-negative cells, tumoral behavior can be reduced by inhibiting HA synthesis or silencing the enzymes involved in its metabolism, such as HA synthase 2 (HAS2). HAS2-AS1 is a long non-coding RNA belonging to the natural antisense transcript family which is known to favor HAS2 gene expression and HA synthesis, thus bolstering malignant progression in brain, ovary, and lung tumors. As the role of HAS2-AS1 has not yet been investigated in breast cancer, in this work we report that ER-positive breast cancers had lower HAS2-AS1 expression compared to ER-negative tumors. Moreover, the survival of patients with ER-negative tumors was higher when the expression of HAS2-AS1 was elevated. Experiments with ER-negative cell lines as MDA-MB-231 and Hs 578T revealed that the overexpression of either the full-length HAS2-AS1 or its exon 2 long or short isoforms alone, strongly reduced cell viability, migration, and invasion, whereas HAS2-AS1 silencing increased cell aggressiveness. Unexpectedly, in these ER-negative cell lines, HAS2-AS1 is involved neither in the regulation of HAS2 nor in HA deposition. Finally, transcriptome analysis revealed that HAS2-AS1 modulation affected several pathways, including apoptosis, proliferation, motility, adhesion, epithelial to mesenchymal transition, and signaling, describing this long non-coding RNA as an important regulator of breast cancer cells aggressiveness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In vivo self-assembled drug nanocrystals for metastatic breast cancer all-stage targeted therapy</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35378211/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35378211/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chemotherapy is still the mainstay treatment for metastatic triple-negative breast cancers (TNBC) currently in clinical practice. The unmet needs of chemotherapy for metastatic TNBC are mainly from the insufficient drug delivery and unavailable targeting strategy that thwart the whole progression of metastatic TNBC. The in vivo ligands-mediated active targeting efficiency is usually affected by protein corona. While, the protein corona-bridged natural targeting, in turn, provides a new way for specific drug delivery. Herein, we develop a novel metastatic progression-oriented in vivo self-assembled Cabazitaxel nanocrystals (CNC) delivery system (PC/CNC) through the CNC automatically absorbing functional plasma proteins (transferrin, apolipoprotein A-IV and apolipoprotein E) in vivo, aiming to achieve the simultaneously targeted delivery to primary tumors, circulating tumor cells and metastatic lesions. With the unique advantages of superhigh drug-loading and protein corona empowered active targeting properties to tumor cells, HUVECs, active-platelets and blood-brain barrier/blood-tumor barrier, the PC/CNC exhibits a significantly improved therapeutic effect in metastatic TNBC therapy compared with free drug and CNC-loaded liposomes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hypoxia-induced circWSB1 promotes breast cancer progression through destabilizing p53 by interacting with USP10</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35351136/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35351136/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Hypoxia has long been considered as a hallmark of solid tumors and is closely associated with tumor progression. Circular RNAs (circRNAs) have been identified as a critical modulator in various cancers. However, the connections between hypoxia and circRNAs are largely unknown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; Here, we investigated the expression profile of circRNAs in breast cancer (BC) MCF-7 cells under hypoxia and normoxia using microarray. We identified a novel hypoxia-responsive circRNA named circWSB1, whose expression pattern, potential diagnostic value and prognostic significance were assessed by qRT-PCR and in situ hybridization. Loss- and gain-of-function investigations in vivo and in vitro were performed to determine the biological functions of circWSB1. Mechanistically, chromatin immunoprecipitation and dual luciferase reporter assays were carried out to analyze the biogenesis of circWSB1. Furthermore, biotin-labeled RNA pull-down, mass spectrometry, RNA immunoprecipitation, fluorescent in situ hybridization, RNA electrophoretic mobility shift, deletion-mapping, co-immunoprecipitation assays and rescue experiments were applied to investigate the interaction between circWSB1 and Ubiquitin-specific peptidase 10 (USP10) as well as the relationship between USP10 and p53.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; We found that the expression of circWSB1 was significantly upregulated in BC tissues and correlated with poor clinical outcomes, which might serve as an independent prognostic factor for BC patients. Ectopic expression of circWSB1 promoted the proliferation of BC cell in vitro and in vivo. Mechanistically, circWSB1 was transcriptionally upregulated by HIF1α in response to hypoxia and could competitively bind to deubiquitinase USP10 to prevent the access of p53 to USP10 in BC cells, leading to degradation of p53 and tumor progression of BC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; Taken together, our findings disclose a novel mechanism that hypoxia-inducible circWSB1 could interact with USP10 to attenuate USP10 mediated p53 stabilization and promote the progression of BC, providing an alternative prognostic biomarker and therapeutic target for BC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Counterintuitive production of tumor-suppressive secretomes from Oct4- and c-Myc-overexpressing tumor cells and MSCs</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35547745/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35547745/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Advanced breast cancer frequently metastasizes to bone, but inhibiting tumor progression in chemotherapy may occasionally enhance tumorigenesis. Here, we employed a counterintuitive approach of overexpressing Yamanaka factors (Oct4, c-Myc, Sox2, and Klf4) and examined a conditioned medium (CM)-based treatment option with induced tumor-suppressing cells (iTSCs).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;In vitro&lt;/em&gt; proliferation and migration assays were conducted using tumor cell lines derived from breast cancer, as well as prostate and pancreatic cancers, and osteosarcoma. The tumor-suppressing capability of iTSC-derived CM was evaluated using freshly isolated breast cancer tissues and a mouse model of mammary tumors and tumor-induced osteolysis. The regulatory mechanism was evaluated using Western blotting, immunoprecipitation, pull-down, gene overexpression, and RNA interference based on mass spectrometry-based proteomics data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; The overexpression of Oct4 and c-Myc in tumor cells and MSCs, but not Sox2 or Klf4, generated anti-tumor CM, which suppressed the progression of mammary tumors and tumor-induced bone loss. Notably, CM downregulated histone demethylase, and PDL-1, a blocker of T-cell-based immune responses. Whole-genome proteomics predicted enolase 1 (Eno1), Hsp90ab1, Eef2, and vinculin as extracellular tumor suppressors. Specifically, CD44 was co-immunoprecipitated with Eno1 and the silencing of CD44 suppressed Eno1&amp;rsquo;s anti-tumor action. The overexpression of Oct4 and c-Myc also generated secretomes that inhibited the development of bone-resorbing osteoclasts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; In analogous to cell competition in which Myc-overexpressing cells in Drosophila and mouse embryos remove neighboring cells with a lower level of Myc, this study presented the possibility of eliminating tumor cells by the secretory proteomes derived from Myc/Oc4-overexpressing iTSCs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The DNMT1-PAS1-PH20 axis drives breast cancer growth and metastasis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35307730/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35307730/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Early diagnosis of breast cancer lung metastasis by nanoprobe-based luminescence imaging of the pre-metastatic niche</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35292019/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35292019/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Early detection of breast cancer lung metastasis remains highly challenging, due to few metastatic cancer cells at an early stage. Herein we propose a new strategy for early diagnosis of lung metastasis of breast cancer by luminescence imaging of pulmonary neutrophil infiltration via self-illuminating nanoprobes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; Luminescent nanoparticles (LAD NPs) were engineered using a biocompatible, neutrophil-responsive self-illuminating cyclodextrin material and an aggregation-induced emission agent. The chemiluminescence resonance energy transfer (CRET) effect and luminescence properties of LAD NPs were fully characterized. Using mouse peritoneal neutrophils, in vitro luminescence properties of LAD NPs were thoroughly examined. In vivo luminescence imaging and correlation analyses were performed in mice inoculated with 4T1 cancer cells. Moreover, an active targeting nanoprobe was developed by surface decoration of LAD NPs with a neutrophil-targeting peptide, which was also systemically evaluated by in vitro and in vivo studies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; LAD NPs can generate long-wavelength and persistent luminescence due to the CRET effect. In a mouse model of 4T1 breast cancer lung metastasis, we found desirable correlation between neutrophils and tumor cells in the lungs, demonstrating the effectiveness of early imaging of the pre-metastatic niche by the newly developed LAD NPs. The active targeting nanoprobe showed further enhanced luminescence imaging capability for early detection of pulmonary metastasis. Notably, the targeting nanoprobe-based luminescence imaging strategy remarkably outperformed PET/CT imaging modalities in the examined mouse model. Also, preliminary tests demonstrated good safety of LAD NPs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; The neutrophil-targeting imaging strategy based on newly developed luminescence nanoparticles can serve as a promising modality for early diagnosis of lung metastasis of breast cancers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Low Glucose-Induced Overexpression of HOXC-AS3 Promotes Metabolic Reprogramming of Breast Cancer</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35031573/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35031573/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Breast cancer is the most common malignancy in women worldwide. However, the mechanisms underlying breast cancer energy metabolism and progression remain obscure. Cancer cells rapidly adapt to microenvironments with fluctuating nutrient levels. Here, we characterized a long noncoding RNA (lncRNA), HOXC-AS3, which is activated upon glucose deprivation to trigger a nutrient-stress response and a switch in glucose metabolism. Upregulation of HOXC-AS3 in breast cancer was identified by in published microarray and RNA-sequencing datasets, and then confirmed by qRT-PCR in fresh breast cancer tissues. Glucose deprivation induced HOXC-AS3 overexpression in a dose- and time-dependent manner in breast cancer cells. Gain- and loss-of-function experiments in vitro and in vivo showed that HOXC-AS3 triggers energy metabolism reprogramming. ChIRP-mass spectrometry and unique molecular identifier RNA immunoprecipitation and high-throughput sequencing (UMI RIP-seq) identified binding motifs of HOXC-AS3 with SIRT6. HOXC-AS3 selectively antagonized SIRT6-mediated H3K9ac deacetylation of glycolysis-related genes. Moreover, HOXC-AS3 binding to SIRT6 prevented contact inhibition of HIF1α, leading to reprogramming of metabolic pathways. In addition, HOXC-AS3, SP1, and miR-1224-5p formed a positive feedback loop to maintain cancer-promoting signals. Furthermore, administration of anti-HOXC-AS3-motif-RNAs effectively blocked the function of HOXC-AS3, ultimately suppressing breast cancer progression. These results reveal a critical role for HOXC-AS3 in regulating the metabolic reprogramming of breast cancer cells under metabolic stress. Use of an anti-HOXC-AS3-motif RNA mixture may be a promising strategy to suppress breast cancer progression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Significance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;HOXC-AS3 is a low glucose-activated long noncoding RNA that triggers metabolic reprogramming in breast cancer cells to adapt to nutrient stress, identifying HOXC-AS3 as a potential therapeutic target for breast cancer treatment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Metformin induces Ferroptosis by inhibiting UFMylation of SLC7A11 in breast cancer</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34162423/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34162423/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ferroptosis is a newly defined form of regulated cell death characterized by the iron-dependent accumulation of lipid peroxidation and is involved in various pathophysiological conditions, including cancer. Targeting ferroptosis is considered to be a novel anti-cancer strategy. The identification of FDA-approved drugs as ferroptosis inducers is proposed to be a new promising approach for cancer treatment. Despite a growing body of evidence indicating the potential efficacy of the anti-diabetic metformin as an anti-cancer agent, the exact mechanism underlying this efficacy has not yet been fully elucidated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The UFMylation of SLC7A11 is detected by immunoprecipitation and the expression of UFM1 and SLC7A11 in tumor tissues was detected by immunohistochemical staining. The level of ferroptosis is determined by the level of free iron, total/lipid Ros and GSH in the cells and the morphological changes of mitochondria are observed by transmission electron microscope. The mechanism in vivo was verified by in situ implantation tumor model in nude mice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Metformin induces ferroptosis in an AMPK-independent manner to suppress tumor growth. Mechanistically, we demonstrate that metformin increases the intracellular Fe2+ and lipid ROS levels. Specifically, metformin reduces the protein stability of SLC7A11, which is a critical ferroptosis regulator, by inhibiting its UFMylation process. Furthermore, metformin combined with sulfasalazine, the system xc− inhibitor, can work in a synergistic manner to induce ferroptosis and inhibit the proliferation of breast cancer cells.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This study is the first to demonstrate that the ability of metformin to induce ferroptosis may be a novel mechanism underlying its anti-cancer effect. In addition, we identified SLC7A11 as a new UFMylation substrate and found that targeting the UFM1/SLC7A11 pathway could be a promising cancer treatment strategy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FUT8-mediated aberrant N-glycosylation of B7H3 suppresses the immune response in triple-negative breast cancer</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33976130/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33976130/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most patients with triple negative breast cancer (TNBC) do not respond to anti-PD1/PDL1 immunotherapy, indicating the necessity to explore immune checkpoint targets. B7H3 is a highly glycosylated protein. However, the mechanisms of B7H3 glycosylation regulation and whether the sugar moiety contributes to immunosuppression are unclear. Here, we identify aberrant B7H3 glycosylation and show that N-glycosylation of B7H3 at NXT motif sites is responsible for its protein stability and immunosuppression in TNBC tumors. The fucosyltransferase FUT8 catalyzes B7H3 core fucosylation at N-glycans to maintain its high expression. Knockdown of FUT8 rescues glycosylated B7H3-mediated immunosuppressive function in TNBC cells. Abnormal B7H3 glycosylation mediated by FUT8 overexpression can be physiologically important and clinically relevant in patients with TNBC. Notably, the combination of core fucosylation inhibitor 2F-Fuc and anti-PDL1 results in enhanced therapeutic efficacy in B7H3-positive TNBC tumors. These findings suggest that targeting the FUT8-B7H3 axis might be a promising strategy for improving anti-tumor immune responses in patients with TNBC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Novel Long Non-Coding RNA lnc030 Maintains Breast Cancer Stem Cell Stemness by Stabilizing SQLE mRNA and Increasing Cholesterol Synthesis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33511005/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33511005/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Erratum in:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/advs.202204046&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;A Novel Long Non-Coding RNA lnc030 Maintains Breast Cancer Stem Cell Stemness by Stabilizing SQLE mRNA and Increasing Cholesterol Synthesis&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cancer stem cells (CSCs) are considered the roots of cancer metastasis and recurrence (CSCs), due in part to their self-renewal and therapy resistance properties. However, the underlying mechanisms for the regulation of CSC stemness are poorly understood. Recently, increasing evidence shows that long non-coding RNAs (lncRNAs) are critical regulators for cancer cell function in various malignancies including breast cancer, but how lncRNAs regulate the function of breast cancer stem cells (BCSCs) remains to be determined. Herein, using lncRNA/mRNA microarray assays, a novel lncRNA (named lnc030) is identified, which is highly expressed in BCSCs in vitro and in vivo, as a pivotal regulator in maintaining BCSC stemness and promoting tumorigenesis. Mechanistically, lnc030 cooperates with poly(rC) binding protein 2(PCBP2) to stabilize squalene epoxidase (SQLE) mRNA, resulting in an increase of cholesterol synthesis. The increased cholesterol in turn actives PI3K/Akt signaling, which governs BCSC stemness. In summary, these findings demonstrate that a new, lnc030-based mechanism for regulating cholesterol synthesis and stemness properties of BCSCs. The lnc030-SQLE-cholesterol synthesis pathway may serve as an effective therapeutic target for BCSC elimination and breast cancer treatment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chronic circadian disruption modulates breast cancer stemness and immune microenvironment to drive metastasis in mice</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32581213/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32581213/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Breast cancer is the most common type of cancer worldwide and one of the major causes of cancer death in women. Epidemiological studies have established a link between night-shift work and increased cancer risk, suggesting that circadian disruption may play a role in carcinogenesis. Here, we aim to shed light on the effect of chronic jetlag (JL) on mammary tumour development. To do this, we use a mouse model of spontaneous mammary tumourigenesis and subject it to chronic circadian disruption. We observe that circadian disruption significantly increases cancer-cell dissemination and lung metastasis. It also enhances the stemness and tumour-initiating potential of tumour cells and creates an immunosuppressive shift in the tumour microenvironment. Finally, our results suggest that the use of a CXCR2 inhibitor could correct the effect of JL on cancer-cell dissemination and metastasis. Altogether, our data provide a conceptual framework to better understand and manage the effects of chronic circadian disruption on breast cancer progression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
