<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Endoplasmic Reticulum | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/endoplasmic-reticulum/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/endoplasmic-reticulum/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Endoplasmic Reticulum</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Endoplasmic Reticulum</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/endoplasmic-reticulum/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>The UFM1 system regulates ER-phagy through the ufmylation of CYB5R3</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36543799/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36543799/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Protein modification by ubiquitin-like proteins (UBLs) amplifies limited genome information and regulates diverse cellular processes, including translation, autophagy and antiviral pathways. Ubiquitin-fold modifier 1 (UFM1) is a UBL covalently conjugated with intracellular proteins through ufmylation, a reaction analogous to ubiquitylation. Ufmylation is involved in processes such as endoplasmic reticulum (ER)-associated protein degradation, ribosome-associated protein quality control at the ER and ER-phagy. However, it remains unclear how ufmylation regulates such distinct ER-related functions. Here we identify a UFM1 substrate, NADH-cytochrome b5 reductase 3 (CYB5R3), that localizes on the ER membrane. Ufmylation of CYB5R3 depends on the E3 components UFL1 and UFBP1 on the ER, and converts CYB5R3 into its inactive form. Ufmylated CYB5R3 is recognized by UFBP1 through the UFM1-interacting motif, which plays an important role in the further uyfmylation of CYB5R3. Ufmylated CYB5R3 is degraded in lysosomes, which depends on the autophagy-related protein Atg7- and the autophagy-adaptor protein CDK5RAP3. Mutations of CYB5R3 and genes involved in the UFM1 system cause hereditary developmental disorders, and ufmylation-defective Cyb5r3 knock-in mice exhibit microcephaly. Our results indicate that CYB5R3 ufmylation induces ER-phagy, which is indispensable for brain development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Endosomal lipid signaling reshapes the endoplasmic reticulum to control mitochondrial function</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36520888/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36520888/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;INTRODUCTION&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cells need to react appropriately to nutritional cues. Defects in the rewiring of metabolism in response to alterations in nutrient supply have been linked to human diseases ranging from diabetes to muscle atrophy. Starvation represses anabolic pathways and facilitates catabolic ones, such as the degradation of macromolecules by autophagy and endolysosomes. Starvation also promotes the β-oxidation of fatty acids in mitochondria to produce adenosine triphosphate (ATP). Within cells, organelles including lysosomes and mitochondria undergo changes in shape and dynamics. These processes are often regulated by phosphoinositide lipids. Phosphoinositides are also involved in the formation of membrane contacts between organelles and in the response of cells and tissues to growth and nutrient signals. How the adaptive changes that protect mammalian cells and tissues from starvation-induced damage are coordinated on a cell-wide scale is unknown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;RATIONALE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Endolysosomal membrane dynamics and function are controlled by phosphoinositide signaling lipids, most notably by the synthesis and turnover of phosphatidylinositol 3-phosphate [PI(3)P]. Patients carrying mutations in the gene encoding the lipid phosphatase MTM1, an enzyme that mediates endosomal PI(3)P turnover, suffer from X-linked centronuclear myopathy (XLCNM), a severe neuromuscular disease characterized by muscle atrophy, disorganization of mitochondria, and defects in the organization of the muscle endoplasmic reticulum (ER). Given that PI(3)P is a hallmark of endosomes, we hypothesized that the control of early endosomal PI(3)P by MTM1 might serve to orchestrate adaptive changes in the dynamics of the ER and mitochondria in response to altering nutrient supply.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;RESULTS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Working with XLCNM patient–derived myoblasts and engineered cell lines, we found that nutrient starvation (for example, lack of amino acids) induced the hydrolysis of PI(3)P by endosomal recruitment of MTM1. Concomitantly, tubular ER membranes were observed to be converted into ER sheets by live super-resolution light microscopy. Mechanistically, loss of early endosomal PI(3)P upon starvation was found to reduce membrane contacts between peripheral ER tubules and early endosomes. These contacts function as physical tethers that may transmit pulling forces from highly motile peripheral endosomes to the tubular ER. Using proximity labeling proteomic and functional cell biological experiments we demonstrated that the ER–endosome contacts were mediated by binding of the related ER membrane proteins RRBP1 and kinectin 1 to PI(3)P on endosomes. To study the role of starvation-induced reshaping of tubular ER membranes into sheets on mitochondrial form and function, we combined live imaging with three-dimensional focused ion beam milling scanning electron microscopy (FIB-SEM) and proteomic analysis. We found that starvation-induced ER reshaping by MTM1 reduced the rate of mitochondrial fission and promoted the formation of a hyperfused mitochondrial network. Genetic manipulations that resulted in ER sheet expansion caused the formation of an enlarged mitochondrial network even in fed cells. Conversely, impaired ER reshaping and reduced mitochondrial network formation were observed in starved myoblasts from XLCNM patients. Mitochondrial network formation appeared to be critical for the delivery of fatty acids from lipid droplets to mitochondria and for oxidative ATP production to sustain energy supply in nutrient-deprived cells.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CONCLUSION&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our data unravel a crucial role for early endosomal lipid signaling in controlling ER morphology and, thereby, mitochondrial form and function to orchestrate the adaptive response of cells to alterations in nutrient (e.g., amino acid) supply. This mechanism operates independent of autophagy, a cellular self-eating process typically induced by prolonged starvation. Rather, it resembles an organellar conveyor belt, in which the tubular ER serves as a membrane conduit that transmits nutrient-triggered changes in endosomal PI(3)P levels to metabolic organelles to enable metabolic rewiring. How early endosomal PI(3)P levels and MTM1 function are controlled by cellular nutrient status is currently unknown. Defects in ER shape, mitochondrial morphogenesis, and cellular ATP depletion caused by loss of MTM1 function can explain the observed myofiber hypotrophy and defective ER organization in animal models of XLCNM and in human patients who often appear undernourished. We therefore hypothesize that dysregulated organelle remodeling may underlie XLCNM caused by MTM1 mutations in humans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exosome modification to better alleviates endoplasmic reticulum stress induced chondrocyte apoptosis and osteoarthritis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36370754/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36370754/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Osteoarthritis (OA) is characterized by cartilage matrix degeneration and chondrocyte apoptosis. Prolonged endoplasmic reticulum (ER) stress participates in chondrocyte apoptosis and cartilage degeneration in OA progression. miR-486-5p could suppress the apoptosis of nucleus pulposus cells and cardiomyocyte, yet whether miR-486-5p modified exosomes could modulate ER stress and apoptosis of chondrocytes remain unknown. We validated the increased inflammation and ER stress in OA synovium and cartilage, and the inhibition of ER stress could attenuate the IL-1β induced chondrocyte apoptosis. Administration of exogenous miR-486-5p could inhibit the ER stress, alleviate chondrocytes apoptosis and promote matrix regeneration. In comparison with direct administration of miR-486-5p and miR-486-5p overexpressing ADSCs, miR-486-5p modified exosomes indicated a better effect in modulating chondrocyte homeostasis. MiR-486-5p containing exosomes could also regulate macrophage polarization. Our IVIS imaging data validated that intraarticular injection of miR-486-5p containing exosomes could sustain for at least 7 days. MiR-486-5p containing exosomes showed a better effect on alleviating rats OA compared with direct administration of miR-486-5p and miR-486-5p overexpressing ADSCs. Our data demonstrated that miR-486-5p modified exosomes have a better effect on alleviating chondrocyte apoptosis and osteoarthritis. This study provides evidence of this efficient strategy of exosomal miRNA delivery and the miRNA-based therapy for OA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Calcium transients on the ER surface trigger liquid-liquid phase separation of FIP200 to specify autophagosome initiation sites</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36198318/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36198318/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The mechanism that initiates autophagosome formation on the ER in multicellular organisms is elusive. Here, we showed that autophagy stimuli trigger Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt; transients on the outer surface of the ER membrane, whose amplitude, frequency, and duration are controlled by the metazoan-specific ER transmembrane autophagy protein EPG-4/EI24. Persistent Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt; transients/oscillations on the cytosolic ER surface in EI24-depleted cells cause accumulation of FIP200 autophagosome initiation complexes on the ER. This defect is suppressed by attenuating ER Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt; transients. Multi-modal SIM analysis revealed that Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt; transients on the ER trigger the formation of dynamic and fusion-prone liquid-like FIP200 puncta. Starvation-induced Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt; transients on lysosomes also induce FIP200 puncta that further move to the ER. Multiple FIP200 puncta on the ER, whose association depends on the ER proteins VAPA/B and ATL2/3, assemble into autophagosome formation sites. Thus, Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt; transients are crucial for triggering phase separation of FIP200 to specify autophagosome initiation sites in metazoans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ER proteins decipher the tubulin code to regulate organelle distribution</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34912111/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34912111/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Erratum in:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Publisher Correction: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-022-04656-7&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;ER proteins decipher the tubulin code to regulate organelle distribution&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Organelles move along differentially modified microtubules to establish and maintain their proper distributions and functions. However, how cells interpret these post-translational microtubule modification codes to selectively regulate organelle positioning remains largely unknown. The endoplasmic reticulum (ER) is an interconnected network of diverse morphologies that extends promiscuously throughout the cytoplasm, forming abundant contacts with other organelles. Dysregulation of endoplasmic reticulum morphology is tightly linked to neurologic disorders and cancer. Here we demonstrate that three membrane-bound endoplasmic reticulum proteins preferentially interact with different microtubule populations, with CLIMP63 binding centrosome microtubules, kinectin (KTN1) binding perinuclear polyglutamylated microtubules, and p180 binding glutamylated microtubules. Knockout of these proteins or manipulation of microtubule populations and glutamylation status results in marked changes in endoplasmic reticulum positioning, leading to similar redistributions of other organelles. During nutrient starvation, cells modulate CLIMP63 protein levels and p180-microtubule binding to bidirectionally move endoplasmic reticulum and lysosomes for proper autophagic responses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TMEM41B acts as an ER scramblase required for lipoprotein biogenesis and lipid homeostasis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34015269/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34015269/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How amphipathic phospholipids are shuttled between the membrane bilayer remains an essential but elusive process, particularly at the endoplasmic reticulum (ER). One prominent phospholipid shuttling process concerns the biogenesis of APOB-containing lipoproteins within the ER lumen, which may require bulk trans-bilayer movement of phospholipids from the cytoplasmic leaflet of the ER bilayer. Here, we show that TMEM41B, present in the lipoprotein export machinery, encodes a previously conceptualized ER lipid scramblase mediating trans-bilayer shuttling of bulk phospholipids. Loss of hepatic TMEM41B eliminates plasma lipids, due to complete absence of mature lipoproteins within the ER, but paradoxically also activates lipid production. Mechanistically, scramblase deficiency triggers unique ER morphological changes and unsuppressed activation of SREBPs, which potently promotes lipid synthesis despite stalled secretion. Together, this response induces full-blown nonalcoholic hepatosteatosis in the TMEM41B-deficient mice within weeks. Collectively, our data uncovered a fundamental mechanism safe-guarding ER function and integrity, dysfunction of which disrupts lipid homeostasis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Atlastin 2/3 regulate ER targeting of the ULK1 complex to initiate autophagy</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33988678/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33988678/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dynamic targeting of the ULK1 complex to the ER is crucial for initiating autophagosome formation and for subsequent formation of ER-isolation membrane (IM; autophagosomal precursor) contact during IM expansion. Little is known about how the ULK1 complex, which comprises FIP200, ULK1, ATG13, and ATG101 and does not exist as a constitutively coassembled complex, is recruited and stabilized on the ER. Here, we demonstrate that the ER-localized transmembrane proteins Atlastin 2 and 3 (ATL2/3) contribute to recruitment and stabilization of ULK1 and ATG101 at the FIP200-ATG13-specified autophagosome formation sites on the ER. In ATL2/3 KO cells, formation of FIP200 and ATG13 puncta is unaffected, while targeting of ULK1 and ATG101 is severely impaired. Consequently, IM initiation is compromised and slowed. ATL2/3 directly interact with ULK1 and ATG13 and facilitate the ATG13-mediated recruitment/stabilization of ULK1 and ATG101. ATL2/3 also participate in forming ER-IM tethering complexes. Our study provides insights into the dynamic assembly of the ULK1 complex on the ER for autophagosome formation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Regulation of Wnt/PCP signaling through p97/VCP-KBTBD7-mediated Vangl ubiquitination and endoplasmic reticulum-associated degradation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33990333/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33990333/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The four-pass transmembrane proteins Vangl1 and Vangl2 are dedicated core components of Wnt/planar cell polarity (Wnt/PCP) signaling that critically regulate polarized cell behaviors in many morphological and physiological processes. Here, we found that the abundance of Vangl proteins is tightly controlled by the ubiquitin-proteasome system through endoplasmic reticulum-associated degradation (ERAD). The key ERAD component p97/VCP directly binds to Vangl at a highly conserved VCP-interacting motif and recruits the E3 ligase KBTBD7 via its UBA-UBX adaptors to promote Vangl ubiquitination and ERAD. We found that Wnt5a/CK1 prevents Vangl ubiquitination and ERAD by inducing Vangl phosphorylation, which facilitates Vangl export from the ER to the plasma membrane. We also provide in vivo evidence that KBTBD7 regulates convergent extension during zebrafish gastrulation and functions as a tumor suppressor in breast cancer by promoting Vangl degradation. Our findings reveal a previously unknown regulatory mechanism of Wnt/PCP signaling through the p97/VCP-KBTBD7-mediated ERAD pathway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Proteomics reveals distinct mechanisms regulating the release of cytokines and alarmins during pyroptosis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33691121/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33691121/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A major pathway for proinflammatory protein release by macrophages is inflammasome-mediated pyroptotic cell death. As conventional secretion, unconventional secretion, and cell death are executed simultaneously, however, the cellular mechanisms regulating this complex paracrine program remain incompletely understood. Here, we devise a quantitative proteomics strategy to define the cellular exit route for each protein by pharmacological and genetic dissection of cellular checkpoints regulating protein release. We report the release of hundreds of proteins during pyroptosis, predominantly due to cell lysis. They comprise constitutively expressed and transcriptionally induced proteins derived from the cytoplasm and specific intracellular organelles. Many low-molecular-weight proteins including the cytokine interleukin-1β, alarmins, and lysosomal-cargo proteins exit cells in the absence of cell lysis. Cytokines and alarmins are released in an endoplasmic reticulum (ER)-Golgi-dependent manner as free proteins rather than by extracellular vesicles. Our work provides an experimental framework for the dissection of cellular exit pathways and a resource for pyroptotic protein release.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Autophagy regulates fatty acid availability for oxidative phosphorylation through mitochondria-endoplasmic reticulum contact sites</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32792483/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32792483/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Autophagy has been associated with oncogenesis with one of its emerging key functions being its contribution to the metabolism of tumors. Therefore, deciphering the mechanisms of how autophagy supports tumor cell metabolism is essential. Here, we demonstrate that the inhibition of autophagy induces an accumulation of lipid droplets (LD) due to a decrease in fatty acid β-oxidation, that leads to a reduction of oxidative phosphorylation (OxPHOS) in acute myeloid leukemia (AML), but not in normal cells. Thus, the autophagic process participates in lipid catabolism that supports OxPHOS in AML cells. Interestingly, the inhibition of OxPHOS leads to LD accumulation with the concomitant inhibition of autophagy. Mechanistically, we show that the disruption of mitochondria-endoplasmic reticulum (ER) contact sites (MERCs) phenocopies OxPHOS inhibition. Altogether, our data establish that mitochondria, through the regulation of MERCs, controls autophagy that, in turn finely tunes lipid degradation to fuel OxPHOS supporting proliferation and growth in leukemia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Genome-wide ER-phagy Screen Highlights Key Roles of Mitochondrial Metabolism and ER-Resident UFMylation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32160526/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32160526/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Selective autophagy of organelles is critical for cellular differentiation, homeostasis, and organismal health. Autophagy of the ER (ER-phagy) is implicated in human neuropathy but is poorly understood beyond a few autophagosomal receptors and remodelers. By using an ER-phagy reporter and genome-wide CRISPRi screening, we identified 200 high-confidence human ER-phagy factors. Two pathways were unexpectedly required for ER-phagy. First, reduced mitochondrial metabolism represses ER-phagy, which is opposite of general autophagy and is independent of AMPK. Second, ER-localized UFMylation is required for ER-phagy to repress the unfolded protein response via IRE1α. The UFL1 ligase is brought to the ER surface by DDRGK1 to UFMylate RPN1 and RPL26 and preferentially targets ER sheets for degradation, analogous to PINK1-Parkin regulation during mitophagy. Our data provide insight into the cellular logic of ER-phagy, reveal parallels between organelle autophagies, and provide an entry point to the relatively unexplored process of degrading the ER network.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ER-Phagy: Quality Control and Turnover of Endoplasmic Reticulum</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/32302550/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/32302550/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The endoplasmic reticulum (ER) is the largest organelle in cells and has fundamental functions, such as folding, processing, and trafficking of proteins, cellular metabolism, and ion storage. To maintain its function, it is turned over constitutively, and even more actively under certain stress conditions. Quality control of the ER is mediated primarily by two pathways: the ubiquitin-proteasome system and autophagy (termed &amp;lsquo;ER-phagy&amp;rsquo;). The identification of ER-phagy adaptor molecules has shed light on the mechanisms and physiological significance of ER-phagy. Here, we describe recent findings on various types of ER-phagy and present unanswered questions related to their mechanism and regulation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The ER-Localized Transmembrane Protein TMEM39A/SUSR2 Regulates Autophagy by Controlling the Trafficking of the PtdIns(4)P Phosphatase SAC1</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/31806350/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/31806350/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TMEM39A, encoding an ER-localized transmembrane protein, is a susceptibility locus for multiple autoimmune diseases. The molecular function of TMEM39A remains completely unknown. Here we demonstrated that TMEM39A, also called SUSR2, modulates autophagy activity by regulating the spatial distribution and levels of PtdIns(4)P. Depletion of SUSR2 elevates late endosomal/lysosomal PtdIns(4)P levels, facilitating recruitment of the HOPS complex to promote assembly of the SNARE complex for autophagosome maturation. SUSR2 knockdown also increases the degradative capability of lysosomes. Mechanistically, SUSR2 interacts with the ER-localized PtdIns(4)P phosphatase SAC1 and also the COPII SEC23/SEC24 subunits to promote the ER-to-Golgi transport of SAC1. Retention of SAC1 on the ER in SUSR2 knockdown cells increases the level of PtdIns(3)P produced by the VPS34 complex, promoting autophagosome formation. Our study reveals that TMEM39A/SUSR2 acts as an adaptor protein for efficient export of SAC1 from the ER and provides insights into the pathogenesis of diseases associated with TMEM39A mutations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UFMylation of RPL26 links translocation-associated quality control to endoplasmic reticulum protein homeostasis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/31595041/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/31595041/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Protein biogenesis at the endoplasmic reticulum (ER) in eukaryotic cells is monitored by a protein quality control system named ER-associated protein degradation (ERAD). While there has been substantial progress in understanding how ERAD eliminates defective polypeptides generated from erroneous folding, how cells remove nascent chains stalled in the translocon during co-translational protein insertion into the ER is unclear. Here we show that ribosome stalling during protein translocation induces the attachment of UFM1, a ubiquitin-like modifier, to two conserved lysine residues near the COOH-terminus of the 60S ribosomal subunit RPL26 (uL24) at the ER. Strikingly, RPL26 UFMylation enables the degradation of stalled nascent chains, but unlike ERAD or previously established cytosolic ribosome-associated quality control (RQC), which uses proteasome to degrade their client proteins, ribosome UFMylation promotes the targeting of a translocation-arrested ER protein to lysosomes for degradation. RPL26 UFMylation is upregulated during erythroid differentiation to cope with increased secretory flow, and compromising UFMylation impairs protein secretion, and ultimately hemoglobin production. We propose that in metazoan, co-translational protein translocation into the ER is safeguarded by a UFMylation-dependent protein quality control mechanism, which when impaired causes anemia in mice and abnormal neuronal development in humans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ufbp1 promotes plasma cell development and ER expansion by modulating distinct branches of UPR</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/30842412/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/30842412/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The IRE1α/XBP1 branch of unfolded protein response (UPR) pathway has a critical function in endoplasmic reticulum (ER) expansion in plasma cells via unknown mechanisms; interestingly, another UPR branch, PERK, is suppressed during plasma cell development. Here we show that Ufbp1, a target and cofactor of the ufmylation pathway, promotes plasma cell development by suppressing the activation of PERK. By contrast, the IRE1α/XBP1 axis upregulates the expression of Ufbp1 and ufmylation pathway genes in plasma cells, while Ufbp1 deficiency impairs ER expansion in plasma cells and retards immunoglobulin production. Structure and function analysis suggests that lysine 267 of Ufbp1, the main lysine in Ufbp1 that undergoes ufmylation, is dispensable for the development of plasmablasts, but is required for immunoglobulin production and stimulation of ER expansion in IRE1α-deficient plasmablasts. Thus, Ufbp1 distinctly regulates different branches of UPR pathway to promote plasma cell development and function.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ribosomal protein RPL26 is the principal target of UFMylation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/30626644/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/30626644/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ubiquitin fold modifier 1 (UFM1) is a small, metazoan-specific, ubiquitin-like protein modifier that is essential for embryonic development. Although loss-of-function mutations in UFM1 conjugation are linked to endoplasmic reticulum (ER) stress, neither the biological function nor the relevant cellular targets of this protein modifier are known. Here, we show that a largely uncharacterized ribosomal protein, RPL26, is the principal target of UFM1 conjugation. RPL26 UFMylation and de-UFMylation is catalyzed by enzyme complexes tethered to the cytoplasmic surface of the ER and UFMylated RPL26 is highly enriched on ER membrane-bound ribosomes and polysomes. Biochemical analysis and structural modeling establish that UFMylated RPL26 and the UFMylation machinery are in close proximity to the SEC61 translocon, suggesting that this modification plays a direct role in cotranslational protein translocation into the ER. These data suggest that UFMylation is a ribosomal modification specialized to facilitate metazoan-specific protein biogenesis at the ER.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GRAMD1/ASTER-mediated cholesterol transport promotes Smoothened cholesterylation at the endoplasmic reticulum</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36524353/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jun 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36524353/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hedgehog (Hh) signaling pathway plays a pivotal role in embryonic development. Hh binding to Patched1 (PTCH1) derepresses Smoothened (SMO), thereby activating the downstream signal transduction. Covalent SMO modification by cholesterol in its cysteine-rich domain (CRD) is essential for SMO function. SMO cholesterylation is a calcium-accelerated autoprocessing reaction, and STIM1-ORAI1-mediated store-operated calcium entry promotes cholesterylation and activation of endosome-localized SMO. However, it is unknown whether the Hh-PTCH1 interplay regulates the activity of the endoplasmic reticulum (ER)-localized SMO. Here, we found that PTCH1 inhibited the COPII-dependent export of SMO from the ER, whereas Hh promoted this process. The RRxWxR amino acid motif in the cytosolic tail of SMO was essential for COPII recognition, ciliary localization, and signal transduction activity. Hh and PTCH1 regulated cholesterol modification of the ER-localized SMO, and SMO cholesterylation accelerated its exit from ER. The GRAMD1/ASTER sterol transport proteins facilitated cholesterol transfer to ER from PM, resulting in increased SMO cholesterylation and enhanced Hh signaling. Collectively, we reveal a regulatory role of GRAMD-mediated cholesterol transport in ER-resident SMO maturation and Hh signaling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
