<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Telomere/Telomerase | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/telomere/telomerase/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/telomere/telomerase/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Telomere/Telomerase</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Telomere/Telomerase</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/telomere/telomerase/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Identification of mechanism of cancer-cell-specific reactivation of hTERT offers therapeutic opportunities for blocking telomerase specifically in human colorectal cancer</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35697349/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35697349/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Transcriptional reactivation of hTERT is the limiting step in tumorigenesis. While mutations in hTERT promoter present in 19% of cancers are recognized as key drivers of hTERT reactivation, mechanisms by which wildtype hTERT (WT-hTERT) promoter is reactivated, in majority of human cancers, remain unknown. Using primary colorectal cancers (CRC) we identified Tert INTeracting region 2 (T-INT2), the critical chromatin region essential for reactivating WT-hTERT promoter in CRCs. Elevated β-catenin and JunD level in CRC facilitates chromatin interaction between hTERT promoter and T-INT2 that is necessary to turn on hTERTexpression. Pharmacological screens uncovered salinomycin, which inhibits JunD mediated hTERT-T-INT2 interaction that is required for the formation of a stable transcription complex on the hTERT promoter. Our results showed for the first time how known CRC alterations, such as APC, lead to WT-hTERT promoter reactivation during stepwise-tumorigenesis and provide a new perspective for developing cancer-specific drugs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Genome-Protective Topoisomerase 2a-Dependent G2 Arrest Requires p53 in hTERT-Positive Cancer Cells</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35247890/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35247890/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Topoisomerase 2a (Topo2a)-dependent G2 arrest engenders faithful segregation of sister chromatids, yet in certain tumor cell lines where this arrest is dysfunctional, a PKCε-dependent failsafe pathway can be triggered. Here we elaborate on recent advances in understanding the underlying mechanisms associated with this G2 arrest by determining that p53-p21 signaling is essential for efficient arrest in cell lines, in patient-derived cells, and in colorectal cancer organoids. Regulation of this p53 axis required the SMC5/6 complex, which is distinct from the p53 pathways observed in the DNA damage response. Topo2a inhibition specifically during S phase did not trigger G2 arrest despite affecting completion of DNA replication. Moreover, in cancer cells reliant upon the alternative lengthening of telomeres (ALT) mechanism, a distinct form of Topo2a-dependent, p53-independent G2 arrest was found to be mediated by BLM and Chk1. Importantly, the previously described PKCε-dependent mitotic failsafe was engaged in hTERT-positive cells when Topo2a-dependent G2 arrest was dysfunctional and where p53 was absent, but not in cells dependent on the ALT mechanism. In PKCε knockout mice, p53 deletion elicited tumors were less aggressive than in PKCε-replete animals and exhibited a distinct pattern of chromosomal rearrangements. This evidence suggests the potential of exploiting synthetic lethality in arrest-defective hTERT-positive tumors through PKCε-directed therapeutic intervention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Telomere shortening impairs alveolar regeneration</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35274784/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35274784/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Objectives:&lt;/em&gt; Short telomeres in alveolar type 2 (AT2) cells have been associated with many lung diseases. The study aimed to investigate the regeneration capacity of AT2 cells with short telomeres by knocking out Tert in mice (G4 &lt;em&gt;Tert&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt;) from the whole to the cellular level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Materials and methods:&lt;/em&gt; The lung injury model of mice was established by left pneumonectomy (PNX). The proliferation and differentiation of AT2 cells were observed by immunofluorescence staining in vivo and in vitro. The difference of the gene expression between control and G4 &lt;em&gt;Tert&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; group during the regeneration of AT2 cells was compared by RNA sequencing. The expression of tubulin polymerization promoting protein 3 (TPPP3) was reduced by adeno-associated virus delivery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; The alveolar regeneration in G4 &lt;em&gt;Tert&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; mice was impaired after PNX-induced lung injury. The regulation of cytoskeleton remodelling was defective in G4 &lt;em&gt;Tert&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; AT2 cells. The expression of TPPP3 was gradually increased during AT2 cell differentiation. The expression level of TPPP3 was reduced in G4 &lt;em&gt;Tert&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; AT2 cells. Reducing TPPP3 expression in AT2 cells limits the microtubule remodelling and differentiation of AT2 cells.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/em&gt; Short telomeres in AT2 cells result in the reduced expression level of TPPP3, leading to impaired regeneration capacity of AT2 cells.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Genome-wide screens identify specific drivers of mutant hTERT promoters</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35027447/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35027447/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Significance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mutations in &lt;em&gt;hTERT&lt;/em&gt; promoter are seen in over 19% of human cancers, irrespective of the cancer type. Understanding the molecular players that regulate Mut-&lt;em&gt;hTERT&lt;/em&gt; promoters may help the design of effective targeting strategies to inhibit telomerase reactivation specifically in cancer cells. Our work uses genome-wide functional screens to identify 30 specific regulators of Mut-&lt;em&gt;hTERT&lt;/em&gt; promoters. These candidates identified from the screening serve as an excellent resource to understand how telomerase is reactivated and as targets for making inhibitors to telomerase, a key driver of cancer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cancer-specific &lt;em&gt;hTERT&lt;/em&gt; promoter mutations reported in 19% of cancers result in enhanced telomerase activity. Understanding the distinctions between transcriptional regulation of wild-type (WT) and mutant (Mut) &lt;em&gt;hTERT&lt;/em&gt; promoters may open up avenues for development of inhibitors which specially block &lt;em&gt;hTERT&lt;/em&gt; expression in cancer cells. To comprehensively identify physiological regulators of WT- or Mut-&lt;em&gt;hTERT&lt;/em&gt; promoters, we generated several isogenic reporter cells driven by endogenous &lt;em&gt;hTERT&lt;/em&gt; loci. Genome-wide CRISPR-Cas9 and small interfering RNA screens using these isogenic reporter lines identified specific regulators of Mut-&lt;em&gt;hTERT&lt;/em&gt; promoters. We validate and characterize one of these hits, namely, MED12, a kinase subunit of mediator complex. We demonstrate that MED12 specifically drives expression of &lt;em&gt;hTERT&lt;/em&gt; from the Mut-&lt;em&gt;hTERT&lt;/em&gt; promoter by mediating long-range chromatin interaction between the proximal Mut-&lt;em&gt;hTERT&lt;/em&gt; promoter and &lt;em&gt;T-INT1&lt;/em&gt; distal regulatory region 260 kb upstream. Several hits identified in our screens could serve as potential therapeutic targets, inhibition of which may specifically block Mut-&lt;em&gt;hTERT&lt;/em&gt; promoter driven telomerase reactivation in cancers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
