<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Deep/Machine Learning | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/deep/machine-learning/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/deep/machine-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Deep/Machine Learning</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Deep/Machine Learning</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/deep/machine-learning/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Antiviral Approaches against Influenza Virus</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/36645300/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/36645300/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Preventing and controlling influenza virus infection remains a global public health challenge, as it causes seasonal epidemics to unexpected pandemics. These infections are responsible for high morbidity, mortality, and substantial economic impact. Vaccines are the prophylaxis mainstay in the fight against influenza. However, vaccination fails to confer complete protection due to inadequate vaccination coverages, vaccine shortages, and mismatches with circulating strains. Antivirals represent an important prophylactic and therapeutic measure to reduce influenza-associated morbidity and mortality, particularly in high-risk populations. Here, we review current FDA-approved influenza antivirals with their mechanisms of action, and different viral- and host-directed influenza antiviral approaches, including immunomodulatory interventions in clinical development. Furthermore, we also illustrate the potential utility of machine learning in developing next-generation antivirals against influenza.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hybrid reconstruction of the physical model with the deep learning that improves structured illumination microscopy</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/apn.2.1.016012/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/apn.2.1.016012/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Structured illumination microscopy (SIM) has been widely used in live-cell superresolution (SR) imaging. However, conventional physical model-based SIM SR reconstruction algorithms are prone to artifacts in handling raw images with low signal-to-noise ratios (SNRs). Deep-learning (DL)-based methods can address this challenge but may lead to degradation and hallucinations. By combining the physical inversion model with a total deep variation (TDV) regularization, we propose a hybrid restoration method (TDV-SIM) that outperforms conventional or DL methods in suppressing artifacts and hallucinations while maintaining resolutions. We demonstrate the performance superiority of TDV-SIM in restoring actin filaments, endoplasmic reticulum, and mitochondrial cristae from extremely low SNR raw images. Thus TDV-SIM represents the ideal method for prolonged live-cell SR imaging with minimal exposure and photodamage. Overall, TDV-SIM proves the power of integrating model-based reconstruction methods with DL ones, possibly leading to the rapid exploration of similar strategies in high-fidelity reconstructions of other microscopy methods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Identification of potent antimicrobial peptides via a machine-learning pipeline that mines the entire space of peptide sequences</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36635418/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36635418/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Systematically identifying functional peptides is difficult owing to the vast combinatorial space of peptide sequences. Here we report a machine-learning pipeline that mines the hundreds of billions of sequences in the entire virtual library of peptides made of 6-9 amino acids to identify potent antimicrobial peptides. The pipeline consists of trainable machine-learning modules (for performing empirical selection, classification, ranking and regression tasks) assembled sequentially following a coarse-to-fine design principle to gradually narrow down the search space. The leading three antimicrobial hexapeptides identified by the pipeline showed strong activities against a wide range of clinical isolates of multidrug-resistant pathogens. In mice with bacterial pneumonia, aerosolized formulations of the identified peptides showed therapeutic efficacy comparable to penicillin, negligible toxicity and a low propensity to induce drug resistance. The machine-learning pipeline may accelerate the discovery of new functional peptides.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multistain deep learning for prediction of prognosis and therapy response in colorectal cancer</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36624314/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36624314/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although it has long been known that the immune cell composition has a strong prognostic and predictive value in colorectal cancer (CRC), scoring systems such as the immunoscore (IS) or quantification of intraepithelial lymphocytes are only slowly being adopted into clinical routine use and have their limitations. To address this we established and evaluated a multistain deep learning model (MSDLM) utilizing artificial intelligence (AI) to determine the AImmunoscore (AIS) in more than 1,000 patients with CRC. Our model had high prognostic capabilities and outperformed other clinical, molecular and immune cell-based parameters. It could also be used to predict the response to neoadjuvant therapy in patients with rectal cancer. Using an explainable AI approach, we confirmed that the MSDLM&amp;rsquo;s decisions were based on established cellular patterns of anti-tumor immunity. Hence, the AIS could provide clinicians with a valuable decision-making tool based on the tumor immune microenvironment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SPICEMIX enables integrative single-cell spatial modeling of cell identity</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36624346/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36624346/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spatial transcriptomics can reveal spatially resolved gene expression of diverse cells in complex tissues. However, the development of computational methods that can use the unique properties of spatial transcriptome data to unveil cell identities remains a challenge. Here we introduce SPICEMIX, an interpretable method based on probabilistic, latent variable modeling for joint analysis of spatial information and gene expression from spatial transcriptome data. Both simulation and real data evaluations demonstrate that SPICEMIX markedly improves on the inference of cell types and their spatial patterns compared with existing approaches. By applying to spatial transcriptome data of brain regions in human and mouse acquired by seqFISH+, STARmap and Visium, we show that SPICEMIX can enhance the inference of complex cell identities, reveal interpretable spatial metagenes and uncover differentiation trajectories. SPICEMIX is a generalizable analysis framework for spatial transcriptome data to investigate cell-type composition and spatial organization of cells in complex tissues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Development of a 32-gene signature using machine learning for accurate prediction of inflammatory bowel disease</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36600111/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36600111/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inflammatory bowel disease (IBD) is a chronic inflammatory condition caused by multiple genetic and environmental factors. Numerous genes are implicated in the etiology of IBD, but the diagnosis of IBD is challenging. Here, XGBoost, a machine learning prediction model, has been used to distinguish IBD from healthy cases following elaborative feature selection. Using combined unsupervised clustering analysis and the XGBoost feature selection method, we successfully identified a 32-gene signature that can predict IBD occurrence in new cohorts with 0.8651 accuracy. The signature shows enrichment in neutrophil extracellular trap formation and cytokine signaling in the immune system. The probability threshold of the XGBoost-based classification model can be adjusted to fit personalized lifestyle and health status. Therefore, this study reveals potential IBD-related biomarkers that facilitate an effective personalized diagnosis of IBD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Co-evolution-based prediction of metal-binding sites in proteomes by machine learning</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36593274/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36593274/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Metal ions have various important biological roles in proteins, including structural maintenance, molecular recognition and catalysis. Previous methods of predicting metal-binding sites in proteomes were based on either sequence or structural motifs. Here we developed a co-evolution-based pipeline named &amp;lsquo;MetalNet&amp;rsquo; to systematically predict metal-binding sites in proteomes. We applied MetalNet to proteomes of four representative prokaryotic species and predicted 4,849 potential metalloproteins, which substantially expands the currently annotated metalloproteomes. We biochemically and structurally validated previously unannotated metal-binding sites in several proteins, including apo-citrate lyase phosphoribosyl-dephospho-CoA transferase citX, an Escherichia coli enzyme lacking structural or sequence homology to any known metalloprotein (Protein Data Bank (PDB) codes: 7DCM and 7DCN ). MetalNet also successfully recapitulated all known zinc-binding sites from the human spliceosome complex. The pipeline of MetalNet provides a unique and enabling tool for interrogating the hidden metalloproteome and studying metal biology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Circ-LocNet: A Computational Framework for Circular RNA Sub-Cellular Localization Prediction</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35897818/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35897818/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Circular ribonucleic acids (circRNAs) are novel non-coding RNAs that emanate from alternative splicing of precursor mRNA in reversed order across exons. Despite the abundant presence of circRNAs in human genes and their involvement in diverse physiological processes, the functionality of most circRNAs remains a mystery. Like other non-coding RNAs, sub-cellular localization knowledge of circRNAs has the aptitude to demystify the influence of circRNAs on protein synthesis, degradation, destination, their association with different diseases, and potential for drug development. To date, wet experimental approaches are being used to detect sub-cellular locations of circular RNAs. These approaches help to elucidate the role of circRNAs as protein scaffolds, RNA-binding protein (RBP) sponges, micro-RNA (miRNA) sponges, parental gene expression modifiers, alternative splicing regulators, and transcription regulators. To complement wet-lab experiments, considering the progress made by machine learning approaches for the determination of sub-cellular localization of other non-coding RNAs, the paper in hand develops a computational framework, Circ-LocNet, to precisely detect circRNA sub-cellular localization. Circ-LocNet performs comprehensive extrinsic evaluation of 7 residue frequency-based, residue order and frequency-based, and physio-chemical property-based sequence descriptors using the five most widely used machine learning classifiers. Further, it explores the performance impact of K-order sequence descriptor fusion where it ensembles similar as well dissimilar genres of statistical representation learning approaches to reap the combined benefits. Considering the diversity of statistical representation learning schemes, it assesses the performance of second-order, third-order, and going all the way up to seventh-order sequence descriptor fusion. A comprehensive empirical evaluation of Circ-LocNet over a newly developed benchmark dataset using different settings reveals that standalone residue frequency-based sequence descriptors and tree-based classifiers are more suitable to predict sub-cellular localization of circular RNAs. Further, K-order heterogeneous sequence descriptors fusion in combination with tree-based classifiers most accurately predict sub-cellular localization of circular RNAs. We anticipate this study will act as a rich baseline and push the development of robust computational methodologies for the accurate sub-cellular localization determination of novel circRNAs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ScoMorphoFISH: A deep learning enabled toolbox for single-cell single-mRNA quantification and correlative (ultra-)morphometry</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35593050/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35593050/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Increasing the information depth of single kidney biopsies can improve diagnostic precision, personalized medicine and accelerate basic kidney research. Until now, information on mRNA abundance and morphologic analysis has been obtained from different samples, missing out on the spatial context and single-cell correlation of findings. Herein, we present scoMorphoFISH, a modular toolbox to obtain spatial single-cell single-mRNA expression data from routinely generated kidney biopsies. Deep learning was used to virtually dissect tissue sections in tissue compartments and cell types to which single-cell expression data were assigned. Furthermore, we show correlative and spatial single-cell expression quantification with super-resolved podocyte foot process morphometry. In contrast to bulk analysis methods, this approach will help to identify local transcription changes even in less frequent kidney cell types on a spatial single-cell level with single-mRNA resolution. Using this method, we demonstrate that ACE2 can be locally upregulated in podocytes upon injury. In a patient suffering from COVID-19-associated collapsing FSGS, ACE2 expression levels were correlated with intracellular SARS-CoV-2 abundance. As this method performs well with standard formalin-fixed paraffin-embedded samples and we provide pretrained deep learning networks embedded in a comprehensive image analysis workflow, this method can be applied immediately in a variety of settings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A novel binary k-mer approach for classification of coding and non-coding RNAs across diverse species</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35476940/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35476940/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Classification among coding sequences (CDS) and non-coding RNA (ncRNA) sequences is a challenge and several machine learning models have been developed for the same. Since the frequency of curated CDS is many-folds as compared to that of the ncRNAs, we devised a novel approach to work with the complete datasets from fifteen diverse species. In our proposed binary approach, we replaced all the &amp;lsquo;A&amp;rsquo;s and &amp;lsquo;T&amp;rsquo;s with &amp;lsquo;0&amp;rsquo;s and &amp;lsquo;G&amp;rsquo;s and &amp;lsquo;C&amp;rsquo;s with &amp;lsquo;1&amp;rsquo;s to obtain a binary form of CDS and ncRNAs. The k-mer analysis of these binary sequences revealed that the frequency of binary patterns among the CDS and ncRNAs can be used as features to distinguish among them. Using insights from these distinguishing frequencies, we used k-nearest neighbor classifier to classify among them. Our strategy is not only time-efficient but leads to significantly increased performance metrics in terms of Matthews Correlation Coefficient (MCC), Accuracy, F1 score, Precision, Recall and AUC-ROC, for species like &lt;em&gt;P. paniscus&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;M. mulatta&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;M. lucifugus&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;G. gallus&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;C. japonica&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;C. abingdonii&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;A. carolinensis&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;D. melanogaster&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;C. elegans&lt;/em&gt; when compared with the conventional ATGC approach. Additionally, we also show that the performance obtained for diverse species tested on the model based on H. sapiens, correlated with the geological evolutionary timeline, thereby further strengthening our approach. Therefore, we propose that CDS and ncRNAs can be efficiently classified using &amp;ldquo;2-character&amp;rdquo; binary frequency as compared to &amp;ldquo;4-character&amp;rdquo; frequency of ATGC approach. Thus, our highly efficient binary approach can replace the more complex ATGC approach successfully.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Methodology to Detect Biological Particles Using a Biosensing Surface Integrated in Resistive Pulse Sensing</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35446533/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35446533/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Resistive pulse sensing (RPS) is an analytical method that can be used to individually count particles from a small sample. RPS simply monitors the physical characteristics of particles, such as size, shape, and charge density, and the integration of RPS with biosensing is an attractive theme to detect biological particles such as virus and bacteria. In this report, a methodology of biosensing on RPS was investigated. Polydopamine (PD), an adhesive component of mussels, was used as the base material to create a sensing surface. PD adheres to most materials, such as noble metals, metal oxides, semiconductors, and polymers; as a result, PD is a versatile intermediate layer for the fabrication of a biosensing surface. As an example of a biological particle, human influenza A virus (H1N1 subtype) was used to monitor translocation of particles through the pore membrane. When virus-specific ligands (6&amp;rsquo;-sialyllactose) were immobilized on the pore surface, the translocation time of the virus particles was considerably extended. The detailed translocation data suggest that the viral particles were trapped on the sensing surface by specific interactions. In addition, virus translocation processes on different pore surfaces were distinguished using machine learning. The result shows that the simple and versatile PD-based biosensor surface design was effective. This advanced RPS measurement system could be a promising analytical technique.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>High throughput data-based, toxicity pathway-oriented development of a quantitative adverse outcome pathway network linking AHR activation to lung damages</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34906874/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34906874/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An AOP network model was constructed concerning AHR-initiated lung damages.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gene expression signatures of toxicity pathways represented the molecular events.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;AOP was validated using high throughput data combined with machine learning models.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;AOP quantitative evaluation was proposed using RNA-seq technique and bioassays.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The quantitative adverse outcome pathway (qAOP) is proposed to inform dose-responses at multiple biological levels for the purpose of toxicity prediction. So far, qAOP models concerning human health are scarce. Previously, we proposed 5 key molecular pathways that led aryl hydrogen receptor (AHR) activation to lung damages. The present study assembled an AOP network based on the gene expression signatures of these toxicity pathways, and validated the network using publicly available high throughput data combined with machine learning models. In addition, the AOP network was quantitatively evaluated with omics approaches and bioassays, using 16HBE-CYP1A1 cells exposed to benzo(a)pyrene (BaP), a prototypical AHR activator. Benchmark dose (BMD) analysis of transcriptomics revealed that AHR gene held the lowest BMD value, whereas AHR pathway held the lowest point of departure (PoD) compared to the other 4 pathways. Targeted bioassays were further performed to quantitatively understand the cellular responses, including ROS generation, DNA damage, interleukin-6 production, and extracellular matrix increase marked by collagen expression. Eventually, response-response relationships were plotted using nonlinear model fitting. The present study developed a highly reliable AOP model concerning human health, and validated as well as quantitatively evaluated it, and such a method is likely to be adoptable for risk assessment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
