<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Phosphorylation | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/phosphorylation/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/phosphorylation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Phosphorylation</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Phosphorylation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/phosphorylation/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fructose-1,6-bisphosphatase 1 dephosphorylates IκBα and suppresses colorectal tumorigenesis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36646759/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36646759/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Emerging evidence demonstrates that some metabolic enzymes that phosphorylate soluble metabolites can also phosphorylate a variety of protein substrates as protein kinases to regulate cell cycle, apoptosis and many other fundamental cellular processes. However, whether a metabolic enzyme dephosphorylates protein as a protein phosphatase remains unknown. Here we reveal the gluconeogenic enzyme fructose 1,6-biphosphatase 1 (FBP1) that catalyzes the hydrolysis of fructose 1,6-bisphosphate (F-1,6-BP) to fructose 6-phosphate (F-6-P) as a protein phosphatase by performing a high-throughput screening of metabolic phosphatases with molecular docking followed by molecular dynamics (MD) simulations. Moreover, we identify IκBα as the substrate of FBP1-mediated dephosphorylation by performing phosphoproteomic analysis. Mechanistically, FBP1 directly interacts with and dephosphorylates the serine (S) 32/36 of IκBα upon TNFα stimulation, thereby inhibiting NF-κB activation. MD simulations indicate that the catalytic mechanism of FBP1-mediated IκBα dephosphorylation is similar to F-1,6-BP dephosphorylation, except for higher energetic barriers for IκBα dephosphorylation. Functionally, FBP1-dependent NF-κB inactivation suppresses colorectal tumorigenesis by sensitizing tumor cells to inflammatory stresses and preventing the mobilization of myeloid-derived suppressor cells. Our finding reveals a previously unrecognized role of FBP1 as a protein phosphatase and establishes the critical role of FBP1-mediated IκBα dephosphorylation in colorectal tumorigenesis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Metabolic enzyme UAP1 mediates IRF3 pyrophosphorylation to facilitate innate immune response</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36603579/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36603579/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;UAP1 is a positive regulator of type I interferon signaling&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;UAP1 catalyzes IRF3 pyrophosphorylation at serine 386&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;UAP1 pyrophosphorylates IRF3 at S386 to promote antiviral responses&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Summary&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Post-translational modifications (PTMs) of proteins are crucial to guarantee the proper biological functions in immune responses. Although protein phosphorylation has been extensively studied, our current knowledge of protein pyrophosphorylation, which occurs based on phosphorylation, is very limited. Protein pyrophosphorylation is originally considered to be a non-enzymatic process, and its function in immune signaling is unknown. Here, we identify a metabolic enzyme, UDP-N-acetylglucosamine pyrophosphorylase 1 (UAP1), as a pyrophosphorylase for protein serine pyrophosphorylation, by catalyzing the pyrophosphorylation of interferon regulatory factor 3 (IRF3) at serine (Ser) 386 to promote robust type I interferon (IFN) responses. Uap1 deficiency significantly impairs the activation of both DNA- and RNA-viruse-induced type I IFN pathways, and the Uap1-deficient mice are highly susceptible to lethal viral infection. Our findings demonstrate the function of protein pyrophosphorylation in the regulation of antiviral responses and provide insights into the crosstalk between metabolism and innate immunity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PLD2 deletion alleviates disruption of tight junctions in sepsis-induced ALI by regulating PA/STAT3 phosphorylation pathway</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36700766/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36700766/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PLD2 inhibition attenuated PA-induced STAT3 phosphorylation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;STAT3 signaling pathway negatively regulated the expression levels of claudin5, occludin and ZO-1.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;blocking PLD2 can improve ARDS, and PLD2 may be a therapeutic target in ARDS.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Increased inflammatory exudation caused by endothelium and endothelial junction damage is a typical pathological feature of acute respiratory distress syndrome/acute lung injury (ARDS/ALI). Previous studies have shown that phospholipase D2 (PLD2) can increase the inflammatory response and has a close relationship with the severity of sepsis-induced ALI and the mortality of sepsis, but its mechanism is unknown. This study explored the effect and mechanism of PLD2 deletion on the structure and function of endothelial tight junction (TJ) in lipopolysaccharide (LPS)-induced ALI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; We used C57BL/6 mice (wild-type and PLD2 knockout (PLD2-/-)) and human umbilical vein endothelial cell (HUVEC) models of sepsis-ALI. The pathological changes were evaluated by hematoxylin-eosin staining. Pulmonary vascular permeability was detected using wet-dry ratio, fluorescein isothiocyanate (FITC)-dextran, FITC-albumin, and immunoglobulin M concentration of bronchoalveolar lavage fluid. FITC-dextran and &lt;em&gt;trans&lt;/em&gt;-endothelial electrical resistance assay were used to evaluate endothelial permeability on LPS-stimulated HUVECs. The mRNA expressions of TJ proteins were detected by real-time quantitative polymerase chain reaction. Then, protein levels were detected through Western blot analysis and immunofluorescence. The content of phosphatidic acid (PA), a downstream product of PLD2, was detected using an enzyme-linked immunosorbent assay kit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; PLD2 deficiency not only alleviated lung histopathological changes and improved pulmonary vascular permeability but also increased the survival rate of ALI mice. Knockout of PLD2 or treatment with the PLD2 inhibitor can reduce the damage of endothelial TJ proteins, namely, claudin5, occludin and zonula occludens protein-1, in sepsis-ALI mice and LPS-stimulated HUVECs. The level of the PLD2 catalytic product PA increased in LPS-stimulated HUVECs, and exogenous PA can reduce the TJ protein expression and increase signal transducer and activator of transcription 3 (STAT3) phosphorylation in vitro. Inhibition of STAT3 phosphorylation attenuated PA-induced degradation of endothelial TJs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/em&gt; PLD2 knockout or inhibition may protect against LPS-induced lung injury by regulating the PA/STAT3 phosphorylation/endothelial TJ axis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SESAME-catalyzed H3T11 phosphorylation inhibits Dot1-catalyzed H3K79me3 to regulate autophagy and telomere silencing</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36473858/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36473858/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The glycolytic enzyme, pyruvate kinase Pyk1 maintains telomere heterochromatin by phosphorylating histone H3T11 (H3pT11), which promotes SIR (silent information regulator) complex binding at telomeres and prevents autophagy-mediated Sir2 degradation. However, the exact mechanism of action for H3pT11 is poorly understood. Here, we report that H3pT11 directly inhibits Dot1-catalyzed H3K79 tri-methylation (H3K79me3) and uncover how this histone crosstalk regulates autophagy and telomere silencing. Mechanistically, Pyk1-catalyzed H3pT11 directly reduces the binding of Dot1 to chromatin and inhibits Dot1-catalyzed H3K79me3, which leads to transcriptional repression of autophagy genes and reduced autophagy. Despite the antagonism between H3pT11 and H3K79me3, they work together to promote the binding of SIR complex at telomeres to maintain telomere silencing. Furthermore, we identify Reb1 as a telomere-associated factor that recruits Pyk1-containing SESAME (Serine-responsive SAM-containing Metabolic Enzyme) complex to telomere regions to phosphorylate H3T11 and prevent the invasion of H3K79me3 from euchromatin into heterochromatin to maintain telomere silencing. Together, these results uncover a histone crosstalk and provide insights into dynamic regulation of silent heterochromatin and autophagy in response to cell metabolism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AMPK directly phosphorylates TBK1 to integrate glucose sensing into innate immunity</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36384137/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36384137/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Viral infection induces acute blood glucose decline in rodents that activates AMPK&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;AMPK directly phosphorylates TBK1 at S511 to prime antiviral sensing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;AMPK-TBK1 couples glucose deficiency sensing and innate immune surveillance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Targeting the AMPK-TBK1 axis compromises innate antiviral immunity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nutrient sensing and damage sensing are two fundamental processes in living organisms. While hyperglycemia is frequently linked to diabetes-related vulnerability to microbial infection, how body glucose levels affect innate immune responses to microbial invasion is not fully understood. Here, we surprisingly found that viral infection led to a rapid and dramatic decrease in blood glucose levels in rodents, leading to robust AMPK activation. AMPK, once activated, directly phosphorylates TBK1 at S511, which triggers IRF3 recruitment and the assembly of MAVS or STING signalosomes. Consistently, ablation or inhibition of AMPK, knockin of TBK1-S511A, or increased glucose levels compromised nucleic acid sensing, while boosting AMPK-TBK1 cascade by AICAR or TBK1-S511E knockin improves antiviral immunity substantially in various animal models. Thus, we identify TBK1 as an AMPK substrate, reveal the molecular mechanism coupling a dual sensing of glucose and nuclei acids, and report its physiological necessity in antiviral defense.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blocking MG53S255 Phosphorylation Protects Diabetic Heart From Ischemic Injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36337049/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36337049/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; As an integral component of cell membrane repair machinery, MG53 (mitsugumin 53) is important for cardioprotection induced by ischemia preconditioning and postconditioning. However, it also impairs insulin signaling via its E3 ligase activity-mediated ubiquitination-dependent degradation of IR (insulin receptor) and IRS1 (insulin receptor substrate 1) and its myokine function-induced allosteric blockage of IR. Here, we sought to develop MG53 into a cardioprotection therapy by separating its detrimental metabolic effects from beneficial actions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; Using immunoprecipitation-mass spectrometry, site-specific mutation, in vitro kinase assay, and in vivo animal studies, we investigated the role of MG53 phosphorylation at serine 255 (S255). In particular, utilizing recombinant proteins and gene knock-in approaches, we evaluated the potential therapeutic effect of MG53-S255A mutant in treating cardiac ischemia/reperfusion injury in diabetic mice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; We identified S255 phosphorylation as a prerequisite for MG53 E3 ligase activity. Furthermore, MG53S255 phosphorylation was mediated by GSK3β (glycogen synthase kinase 3 beta) and markedly elevated in the animal models with metabolic disorders. Thus, IR-IRS1-GSK3β-MG53 formed a vicious cycle in the pathogenesis of metabolic disorders where aberrant insulin signaling led to hyper-activation of GSK3β, which in turn, phosphorylated MG53 and enhanced its E3 ligase activity, and further impaired insulin sensitivity. Importantly, S255A mutant eliminated the E3 ligase activity while retained cell protective function of MG53. Consequently, the S255A mutant, but not the wild type MG53, protected the heart against ischemia/reperfusion injury in db/db mice with advanced diabetes, although both elicited cardioprotection in normal mice. Moreover, in S255A knock-in mice, S255A mutant also mitigated ischemia/reperfusion-induced myocardial damage in the diabetic setting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; S255 phosphorylation is a biased regulation of MG53 E3 ligase activity. The MG53-S255A mutant provides a promising approach for the treatment of acute myocardial injury, especially in patients with metabolic disorders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PTP4A2 promotes lysophagy by dephosphorylation of VCP/p97 at Tyr805</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36300783/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36300783/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overexpression of PTP4A phosphatases are associated with advanced cancers, but their biological functions are far from fully understood due to limited knowledge about their physiological substrates. VCP is implicated in lysophagy via collaboration with specific cofactors in the ELDR complex. However, how the ELDR complex assembly is regulated has not been determined. Moreover, the functional significance of the penultimate and conserved Tyr805 phosphorylation in VCP has not been established. Here, we use an unbiased substrate trapping and mass spectrometry approach and identify VCP/p97 as a &lt;em&gt;bona fide&lt;/em&gt; substrate of PTP4A2. Biochemical studies show that PTP4A2 dephosphorylates VCP at Tyr805, enabling the association of VCP with its C-terminal cofactors UBXN6/UBXD1 and PLAA, which are components of the ELDR complex responsible for lysophagy, the autophagic clearance of damaged lysosomes. Functionally, PTP4A2 is required for cellular homeostasis by promoting lysophagy through facilitating ELDR-mediated K48-linked ubiquitin conjugate removal and autophagosome formation on the damaged lysosomes. Deletion of &lt;em&gt;Ptp4a2 in vivo&lt;/em&gt; compromises the recovery of glycerol-injection induced acute kidney injury due to impaired lysophagy and sustained lysosomal damage. Taken together, our data establish PTP4A2 as a critical regulator of VCP and uncover an important role for PTP4A2 in maintaining lysosomal homeostasis through dephosphorylation of VCP at Tyr805. Our study suggests that PTP4A2 targeting could be a potential therapeutic approach to treat cancers and other degenerative diseases by modulating lysosomal homeostasis and macroautophagy/autophagy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Protein phosphatase 1 regulates phosphorylation of gasdermin D and pyroptosis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36205355/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36205355/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We report that phosphorylation of gasdermin D (GSDMD)-NT, cleaved by inflammatory caspases, could inhibit pyroptosis. Phosphatase 1 (PP1) is responsible for the regulation of GSDMD phosphorylation and the capacity of GSDMD to induce cell death. Our findings reveal a critical regulatory mechanism as it provides insight into pyroptosis processes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Proteomic and phosphorylated proteomic landscape of injured lung in juvenile septic rats with therapeutic application of umbilical cord mesenchymal stem cells</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36341346/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36341346/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acute lung injury (ALI) is the most common complication of sepsis. Intravenous injection of HUMSCs can regulate the level of circulating endothelial cytokines and alleviate lung injury in juvenile septic rats. In this study, we performed proteomic and phosphorylated proteomic analysis of lung tissue of juvenile septic rats after Human Umbilical Cord Mesenchymal Stem Cells (HUMSCs) intervention for the first time, and screened the potential proteins and pathways of HUMSCs for therapeutic effect. The 4D proteome quantitative technique was used to quantitatively analyze the lung tissues of septic rats 24 hours (3 biological samples) and 24 hours after HUMSCs intervention (3 biological samples). A total of 213 proteins were identified as differentially expressed proteins, and 971 phosphorylation sites changed significantly. Based on the public database, we analyzed the functional enrichment of these proteins and phosphorylated proteins. In addition, Tenascin-C may be the key differential protein and ECM receptor interaction pathway may be the main signal pathway by using various algorithms to analyze the protein-protein interaction network. Phosphorylation analysis showed that tight junction pathway was closely related to immune inflammatory reaction, and EGFR interacted most, which may be the key differential phosphorylated protein. Finally, 123 conserved motifs of serine phosphorylation site (pS) and 17 conserved motifs of threonine (pT) phosphorylation sites were identified by motif analysis of phosphorylation sites. Results from proteomics and phosphorylated proteomics, the potential new therapeutic targets of HUMSCs in alleviating lung injury in juvenile septic rats were revealed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clathrin-associated AP-1 controls termination of STING signalling</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36261523/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36261523/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stimulator of interferon genes (STING) functions downstream of cyclic GMP-AMP synthase in DNA sensing or as a direct receptor for bacterial cyclic dinucleotides and small molecules to activate immunity during infection, cancer and immunotherapy. Precise regulation of STING is essential to ensure balanced immune responses and prevent detrimental autoinflammation. After activation, STING, a transmembrane protein, traffics from the endoplasmic reticulum to the Golgi, where its phosphorylation by the protein kinase TBK1 enables signal transduction. The mechanism that ends STING signalling at the Golgi remains unknown. Here we show that adaptor protein complex 1 (AP-1) controls the termination of STING-dependent immune activation. We find that AP-1 sorts phosphorylated STING into clathrin-coated transport vesicles for delivery to the endolysosomal system, where STING is degraded. We identify a highly conserved dileucine motif in the cytosolic C-terminal tail (CTT) of STING that, together with TBK1-dependent CTT phosphorylation, dictates the AP-1 engagement of STING. A cryo-electron microscopy structure of AP-1 in complex with phosphorylated STING explains the enhanced recognition of TBK1-activated STING. We show that suppression of AP-1 exacerbates STING-induced immune responses. Our results reveal a structural mechanism of negative regulation of STING and establish that the initiation of signalling is inextricably associated with its termination to enable transient activation of immunity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CircSEMA4B inhibits the progression of breast cancer by encoding a novel protein SEMA4B-211aa and regulating AKT phosphorylation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36115854/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36115854/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PI3K/AKT signaling pathway plays an important role in regulating the tumorigenesis, recurrence, and metastasis of breast cancer (BC). In this study, we discovered a circRNA with protein-coding potential, which we named circSEMA4B. CircSEMA4B could encode a novel protein, SEMA4B-211aa. Both circSEMA4B and SEMA4B-211aa were remarkably downregulated in BC tissues and cell lines. Low expression of circSEMA4B was positively associated with TNM stage, tumor size, lymph node metastasis, and distant metastasis of BC patients. The functional investigation showed that circSEMA4B and SEMA4B-211aa could significantly inhibit the proliferation and migration of BC in vivo and in vitro. Of note, SEMA4B-211aa inhibited the generation of PIP3 by binding to p85, thereby inhibiting the phosphorylation of AKT (Thr308). CircSEMA4B inhibited the phosphorylation of AKT (Ser473) through miR-330-3p/PDCD4 axis. Taken together, circSEMA4B is a novel negative regulator of PI3K/AKT signaling pathway, providing novel mechanistic insights into the underlying mechanisms of BC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The EGFR/ErbB inhibitor neratinib modifies the neutrophil phosphoproteome and promotes apoptosis and clearance by airway macrophages</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35967296/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35967296/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dysregulated neutrophilic inflammation can be highly destructive in chronic inflammatory diseases due to prolonged neutrophil lifespan and continual release of histotoxic mediators in inflamed tissues. Therapeutic induction of neutrophil apoptosis, an immunologically silent form of cell death, may be beneficial in these diseases, provided that the apoptotic neutrophils are efficiently cleared from the tissue. Previous research in our group identified ErbB inhibitors as able to induce neutrophil apoptosis and reduce neutrophilic inflammation both &lt;em&gt;in vitro&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt;. Here, we extend that work using a clinical ErbB inhibitor, neratinib, which has the potential to be repurposed in inflammatory diseases. We show that neratinib reduces neutrophilic migration o an inflammatory site in zebrafish larvae. Neratinib upregulates efferocytosis and reduces the number of persisting neutrophil corpses in mouse models of acute, but not chronic, lung injury, suggesting that the drug may have therapeutic benefits in acute inflammatory settings. Phosphoproteomic analysis of human neutrophils shows that neratinib modifies the phosphorylation of proteins regulating apoptosis, migration, and efferocytosis. This work identifies a potential mechanism for neratinib in treating acute lung inflammation by upregulating the clearance of dead neutrophils and, through examination of the neutrophil phosphoproteome, provides important insights into the mechanisms by which this may be occurring.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Novel role of COX6c in the regulation of oxidative phosphorylation and diseases</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/35879322/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/35879322/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Facts&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;COX6c is one of the most important subunits of the terminal enzyme of the respiratory chain in mitochondria.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;COX6c is closely related to a variety of diseases and can be used as a potential biomarker for diagnosis and treatment.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;COX6c plays a pivotal role in the regulation of the OXPHOS pathway. Mitochondrial biogenesis can be stimulated in response to low temperature and is reflected in increases in the expression and activity of COX6c.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Open questions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What extent are the activity and expression of COX6c altered in various diseases?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is the change in COX6c a secondary event associated with other pathways that might be the primary drivers of the functional outcomes or is it specific to the disease?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What are the specific mechanisms and processes that COX6c participates in during the development of disease?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cytochrome c oxidase subunit VIc (COX6c) is one of the most important subunits of the terminal enzyme of the respiratory chain in mitochondria. Numerous studies have demonstrated that COX6c plays a critical role in the regulation of oxidative phosphorylation (OXPHOS) and energy production. The release of COX6c from the mitochondria may be a hallmark of the intrinsic apoptosis pathway. Moreover, The changes in COX6c expression are widespread in a variety of diseases and can be chosen as a potential biomarker for diagnosis and treatment. In light of its exclusive effects, we present the elaborate roles that COX6c plays in various diseases. In this review, we first introduced basic knowledge regarding COX6c and its functions in the OXPHOS and apoptosis pathways. Subsequently, we described the regulation of COX6c expression and activity in both positive and negative ways. Furthermore, we summarized the elaborate roles that COX6c plays in various diseases, including cardiovascular disease, kidney disease, brain injury, skeletal muscle injury, and tumors. This review highlights recent advances and provides a comprehensive summary of COX6c in the regulation of OXPHOS in multiple diseases and may be helpful for drug design and the prediction, diagnosis, treatment, and prognosis of diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plk2-mediated phosphorylation and translocalization of Nrf2 activates anti-inflammation through p53/Plk2/p21cip1 signaling in acute kidney injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35842499/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35842499/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Plk2 is a cellular stress-responsive factor that is induced in response to oxidative stress. However, the roles of Plk2 in acute kidney injury (AKI) have not been clarified. We previously found that Plk2 is an interacting factor of Nrf2 in response to cellular stress, since Plk2 is upregulated in the Nrf2-dependent network. Here, we show that the levels of p53, Plk2, p21&lt;sup&gt;cip1&lt;/sup&gt;, and chromatin-bound Nrf2 were all upregulated in kidney tissues of mice or NRK52E cells treated with either cisplatin or methotrexate. Upregulation of Plk2 by p53 led to an increase of Nrf2 in both soluble and chromatin fractions in cisplatin-treated NRK52E cells. Consistently, depletion of Plk2 suppressed the levels of Nrf2. Of note, Plk2 directly phosphorylated Nrf2 at Ser40, which facilitated its interaction with p21&lt;sup&gt;cip1&lt;/sup&gt; and translocation into the nuclei for the activation of anti-oxidative and anti-inflammatory factors in response to AKI. Together, these findings suggest that Plk2 may serve as an anti-oxidative and anti-inflammatory regulator through the phosphorylation and activation of Nrf2 to protect kidney cells from kidney toxicants and that Plk2 and Nrf2 therefore work cooperatively for the protection and survival of kidney cells from harmful stresses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Energy homeostasis mediated by the LcSnRK1α-LcbZIP1/3 signaling pathway modulates litchi fruit senescence</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35634876/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35634876/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cellular energy status is a key factor deciding the switch-on of the senescence of horticultural crops. Despite the established significance of the conserved energy master regulator sucrose non-fermenting 1 (SNF1)-related protein kinase 1 (SnRK1) in plant development, its working mechanism and related signaling pathway in the regulation of fruit senescence remain enigmatic. Here, we demonstrate that energy deficit accelerates fruit senescence, whereas exogenous ATP treatment delays it. The transient suppression of &lt;em&gt;LcSnRK1α&lt;/em&gt; in litchi (&lt;em&gt;Litchi chinensis&lt;/em&gt; Sonn.) fruit inhibited the expression of energy metabolism-related genes, while its ectopic expression in tomato (&lt;em&gt;Solanum lycopersicum&lt;/em&gt;) promoted ripening and a high energy level. Biochemical analyses revealed that LcSnRK1α interacted with and phosphorylated the transcription factors LcbZIP1 and LcbZIP3, which directly bound to the promoters to activate the expression of &lt;em&gt;DARK-INDUCIBLE 10&lt;/em&gt; (&lt;em&gt;LcDIN10&lt;/em&gt;), &lt;em&gt;ASPARAGINE SYNTHASE 1&lt;/em&gt; (&lt;em&gt;LcASN1&lt;/em&gt;), and &lt;em&gt;ANTHOCYANIN SYNTHASE&lt;/em&gt; (&lt;em&gt;LcANS&lt;/em&gt;), thereby fine-tuning the metabolic reprogramming to ensure energy and redox homeostasis. Altogether, these observations reveal a post-translational modification mechanism by which &lt;em&gt;LcSnRK1α&lt;/em&gt;-mediated phosphorylation of LcbZIP1 and LcbZIP3 regulates the expression of metabolic reprogramming-related genes, consequently modulating litchi fruit senescence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FL118, acting as a &#39;molecular glue degrader&#39;, binds to dephosphorylates and degrades the oncoprotein DDX5 (p68) to control c-Myc, survivin and mutant Kras against colorectal and pancreatic cancer with high efficacy</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35604033/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35604033/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Pancreatic ductal adenocarcinoma (PDAC), a difficult-to-treat cancer, is expected to become the second-largest cause of cancer-related deaths by 2030, while colorectal cancer (CRC) is the third most common cancer and the third leading cause of cancer deaths. Currently, there is no effective treatment for PDAC patients. The development of novel agents to effectively treat these cancers remains an unmet clinical need. FL118, a novel anticancer small molecule, exhibits high efficacy against cancers; however, the direct biochemical target of FL118 is unknown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; FL118 affinity purification, mass spectrometry, Nanosep centrifugal device and isothermal titration calorimetry were used for identifying and confirming FL118 binding to DDX5/p68 and its binding affinity. Immunoprecipitation (IP), western blots, real-time reverse transcription PCR, gene silencing, overexpression (OE) and knockout (KO) were used for analysing gene/protein function and expression. Chromatin IP was used for analysing protein-DNA interactions. The 3-[4,5-dimethylthiazol-2-yl]-2,5-diphenyltetrazolium bromid assay and human PDAC/CRC cell/tumour models were used for determining PDAC/CRC cell/tumour in vitro and in vivo growth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; We discovered that FL118 strongly binds to dephosphorylates and degrades the DDX5 oncoprotein via the proteasome degradation pathway without decreasing DDX5 mRNA. Silencing and OE of DDX5 indicated that DDX5 is a master regulator for controlling the expression of multiple oncogenic proteins, including survivin, Mcl-1, XIAP, cIAP2, c-Myc and mutant Kras. Genetic manipulation of DDX5 in PDAC cells affects tumour growth. PDAC cells with DDX5 KO are resistant to FL118 treatment. Our human tumour animal model studies further indicated that FL118 exhibits high efficacy to eliminate human PDAC and CRC tumours that have a high expression of DDX5, while FL118 exhibits less effectiveness in PDAC and CRC tumours with low DDX5 expression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/em&gt; DDX5 is a bona fide FL118 direct target and can act as a biomarker for predicting PDAC and CRC tumour sensitivity to FL118. This would greatly impact FL118 precision medicine for patients with advanced PDAC or advanced CRC in the clinic. FL118 may act as a &amp;lsquo;molecular glue degrader&amp;rsquo; to directly glue DDX5 and ubiquitination regulators together to degrade DDX5.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LATS1 is a central signal transmitter for achieving full type-I interferon activity</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35394840/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35394840/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interferons (IFNs) have broad-spectrum antiviral activity to resist virus epidemic. However, IFN antiviral efficacy needs to be greatly improved. Here, we reveal that LATS1 is a vital signal transmitter governing full type-I IFN (IFN-I) signaling activity. LATS1 constitutively binds with the IFN-I receptor IFNAR2 and is rapidly tyro-phosphorylated by Tyk2 upon IFN-I engagement. Tyro-phosphorylation of LATS1 promotes LATS1 activation and YAP degradation, thereby promoting IFN-mediated antiproliferation activity. Moreover, activated LATS1 translocates into the nucleus and induces CDK8-Ser62 phosphorylation, which in turn phosphorylates STAT1 at Ser&lt;sup&gt;727&lt;/sup&gt; and induces full IFN-I antiviral activity. LATS1 deficiency restricts in vivo IFN-I signaling and attenuates host antiviral immune response. Our study identifies IFN-I as a previously unidentified extracellular diffusible ligand signal for activation of the Hippo core LATS1 pathway and reveals Tyk2-LATS1-CDK8 as a complete signaling cascade controlling full IFN-I activity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ZWC complex-mediated SPT5 phosphorylation suppresses divergent antisense RNA transcription at active gene promoters</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35325203/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35325203/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The human genome encodes large numbers of non-coding RNAs, including divergent antisense transcripts at transcription start sites (TSSs). However, molecular mechanisms by which divergent antisense transcription is regulated have not been detailed. Here, we report a novel ZWC complex composed of ZC3H4, WDR82 and CK2 that suppresses divergent antisense transcription. The ZWC complex preferentially localizes at TSSs of active genes through direct interactions of ZC3H4 and WDR82 subunits with the S5p RNAPII C-terminal domain. ZC3H4 depletion leads to increased divergent antisense transcription, especially at genes that naturally produce divergent antisense transcripts. We further demonstrate that the ZWC complex phosphorylates the previously uncharacterized N-terminal acidic domain of SPT5, a subunit of the transcription-elongation factor DSIF, and that this phosphorylation is responsible for suppressing divergent antisense transcription. Our study provides evidence that the newly identified ZWC-DSIF axis regulates the direction of transcription during the transition from early to productive elongation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NLRC4 Deficiency Leads to Enhanced Phosphorylation of MLKL and Necroptosis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35301258/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35301258/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hosts rely on the innate immune system to clear pathogens in response to infection. Pathogen-associated molecular patterns bind to innate immune receptors and engage activation of downstream signaling to initiate a host immune response to fight infection. A key component of this innate response is programmed cell death. Recent work has highlighted significant cross-talk and functional redundancy between cell death pathways, leading to the discovery of PANoptosis, an inflammatory programmed cell death pathway dependent on PANoptosomes, which are innate immune danger-sensing complexes that activate inflammatory cell death and contain caspases with or without inflammasome components and receptor interacting protein homotypic interaction motif-containing proteins. Although PANoptosis has been characterized in response to a growing number of pathogens, inflammatory diseases, and cancer, its role and the functional consequences of PANoptotic component modulation during NLR family CARD domain-containing protein 4 (NLRC4) activation by &lt;em&gt;Pseudomonas aeruginosa&lt;/em&gt; infection remain unknown. In this study, we show that P. aeruginosa can induce PANoptosis in mouse bone marrow-derived macrophages (BMDMs). Only the combined deletion of caspase-1, -11, -8, and RIPK3 protected mouse BMDMs from cell death. Moreover, we showed that PANoptotic components act in a compensatory manner; in the absence of NAIP5 and NLRC4 during P. aeruginosa challenge, activation of caspase-1, -3, -7, and -8 was reduced, whereas alternative cell death molecules such as RIPK1 and MLKL were activated in mouse BMDMs. Taken together, these data highlight the extensive cross-talk between cell death signaling molecules and showcase the plasticity of the system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DNA-PKcs interacts with and phosphorylates Fis1 to induce mitochondrial fragmentation in tubular cells during acute kidney injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35290083/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35290083/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The catalytic subunit of DNA-dependent protein kinase (DNA-PKcs) regulates cell death. We sought to determine whether DNA-PKcs played a role in the tubular damage that occurs during acute kidney injury (AKI) induced by LPS injection (to mimic sepsis), cisplatin administration, or renal ischemia/reperfusion injury. Although DNA-PKcs normally localizes to the nucleus, we detected cytoplasmic DNA-PKcs in mouse kidney tissues and urinary sediments of human patients with septic AKI. Increased cytoplasmic amounts of DNA-PKcs correlated with renal dysfunction. Tubule cell-specific &lt;em&gt;DNA-PKcs&lt;/em&gt; deletion attenuated AKI-mediated tubular cell death and changes in the abundance of various proteins with mitochondrial functions or roles in apoptotic pathways. DNA-PKcs interacted with Fis1 and phosphorylated it at Thr&lt;sup&gt;34&lt;/sup&gt; in its TQ motif, which increased the affinity of Fis1 for Drp1 and induced mitochondrial fragmentation. Knockin mice expressing a nonphosphorylatable T34A mutant exhibited improved renal function and histological features and reduced mitochondrial fragmentation upon induction of AKI. Phosphorylation of Thr&lt;sup&gt;34&lt;/sup&gt; in Fis1 was detectable in urinary sediments of human patients with septic AKI and correlated with renal dysfunction. Our findings provide insight into the role of cytoplasmic DNA-PKcs and phosphorylated Fis1 in AKI development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Phosphorylated NFS1 weakens oxaliplatin-based chemosensitivity of colorectal cancer by preventing PANoptosis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35221331/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35221331/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Metabolic enzymes have an indispensable role in metabolic reprogramming, and their aberrant expression or activity has been associated with chemosensitivity. Hence, targeting metabolic enzymes remains an attractive approach for treating tumors. However, the influence and regulation of cysteine desulfurase (NFS1), a rate-limiting enzyme in iron-sulfur (Fe-S) cluster biogenesis, in colorectal cancer (CRC) remain elusive. Here, using an in vivo metabolic enzyme gene-based clustered regularly interspaced short palindromic repeats (CRISPR)-Cas9 library screen, we revealed that loss of NFS1 significantly enhanced the sensitivity of CRC cells to oxaliplatin. In vitro and in vivo results showed that NFS1 deficiency synergizing with oxaliplatin triggered PANoptosis (apoptosis, necroptosis, pyroptosis, and ferroptosis) by increasing the intracellular levels of reactive oxygen species (ROS). Furthermore, oxaliplatin-based oxidative stress enhanced the phosphorylation level of serine residues of NFS1, which prevented PANoptosis in an S293 phosphorylation-dependent manner during oxaliplatin treatment. In addition, high expression of NFS1, transcriptionally regulated by MYC, was found in tumor tissues and was associated with poor survival and hyposensitivity to chemotherapy in patients with CRC. Overall, the findings of this study provided insights into the underlying mechanisms of NFS1 in oxaliplatin sensitivity and identified NFS1 inhibition as a promising strategy for improving the outcome of platinum-based chemotherapy in the treatment of CRC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TBK1-METTL3 axis facilitates antiviral immunity</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35172162/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35172162/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;TBK1 directly phosphorylates METTL3 at serine 67 upon VSV infection&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;TBK1 promotes catalytic activity of METTL3&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;S67 phosphorylation enhances METTL3 function in promoting translation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;mRNA m&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;A modification is heavily involved in modulation of immune responses. However, its function in antiviral immunity is controversial, and how immune responses regulate m&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;A modification remains elusive. We here find TBK1, a key kinase of antiviral pathways, phosphorylates the core m&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;A methyltransferase METTL3 at serine 67. The phosphorylated METTL3 interacts with the translational complex, which is required for enhancing protein translation, thus facilitating antiviral responses. TBK1 also promotes METTL3 activation and m&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;A modification to stabilize IRF3 mRNA. Type I interferon (IFN) induction is severely impaired in METTL3-deficient cells. &lt;em&gt;Mettl3&lt;sup&gt;fl/fl&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt;-lyz2-Cre mice are more susceptible to influenza A virus (IAV)-induced lethality than control mice. Consistently, &lt;em&gt;Ythdf1&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; mice show higher mortality than wild-type mice due to decreased IRF3 expression and subsequently attenuated IFN production. Together, we demonstrate that innate signals activate METTL3 via TBK1, and METTL3-mediated m&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;A modification secures antiviral immunity by promoting mRNA stability and protein translation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SENP7 senses oxidative stress to sustain metabolic fitness and antitumor functions of CD8&#43; T cells</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35143421/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35143421/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The functional integrity of CD8&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T cells is tightly coupled to metabolic reprogramming, but how oxidative stress directs CD8&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T cell metabolic fitness in the tumor microenvironment (TME) remains elusive. Here, we report that SUMO-specific protease 7 (SENP7) senses oxidative stress to maintain the CD8&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T cell metabolic state and antitumor functions. SENP7-deficient CD8&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T cells exhibited decreased glycolysis and oxidative phosphorylation, resulting in attenuated proliferation in vitro and dampened antitumor functions in vivo. Mechanistically, CD8&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T cell-derived ROS triggered cytosolic SENP7-mediated PTEN deSUMOylation, thereby promoting PTEN degradation and preventing PTEN-dependent metabolic defects. Importantly, lowering T cell-intrinsic ROS restricted SENP7 cytosolic translocation and repressed CD8&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T cell metabolic and functional activity in human colorectal cancer samples. Our findings reveal that SENP7, as an oxidative stress sensor, sustains CD8&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T cell metabolic fitness and effector functions and unveil an oxidative stress-sensing machinery in tumor-infiltrating CD8&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T cells.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DDR1 contributes to kidney inflammation and fibrosis by promoting the phosphorylation of BCR and STAT3</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34941574/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34941574/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Discoidin domain receptor 1 (DDR1), a receptor tyrosine kinase activated by collagen, contributes to chronic kidney disease. However, its role in acute kidney injury and subsequent development of kidney fibrosis is not clear. Thus, we performed a model of severe ischemia/reperfusion-induced acute kidney injury that progressed to kidney fibrosis in WT and Ddr1-null mice. We showed that Ddr1-null mice had reduced acute tubular injury, inflammation, and tubulointerstitial fibrosis with overall decreased renal monocyte chemoattractant protein (MCP-1) levels and STAT3 activation. We identified breakpoint cluster region (BCR) protein as a phosphorylated target of DDR1 that controls MCP-1 production in renal proximal tubule epithelial cells. DDR1-induced BCR phosphorylation or BCR downregulation increased MCP-1 secretion, suggesting that BCR negatively regulates the levels of MCP-1. Mechanistically, phosphorylation or downregulation of BCR increased β-catenin activity and in turn MCP-1 production. Finally, we showed that DDR1-mediated STAT3 activation was required to stimulate the secretion of TGF-β. Thus, DDR1 contributes to acute and chronic kidney injury by regulating BCR and STAT3 phosphorylation and in turn the production of MCP-1 and TGF-β. These findings identify DDR1 an attractive therapeutic target for ameliorating both proinflammatory and profibrotic signaling in kidney disease.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dimethyl fumarate attenuates LPS induced septic acute kidney injury by suppression of NFκB p65 phosphorylation and macrophage activation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34915410/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34915410/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Septic acute kidney injury (AKI) always accounts for high mortality of septic patients in ICU. Due to its not well understood mechanism for infection and immune-regulation in kidney dysfunction, there is a lack of effective therapy without side effects. Dimethyl fumarate (DMF) as an immunomodulatory molecule has been approved for treatment to multiple sclerosis. However, the therapeutic effect and immunomodulatory role underlying DMF action in septic AKI is unclear. This study aimed to elucidate the role of DMF in lipopolysaccharide (LPS)-induced septic AKI involving macrophage regulation. In current study, we administered DMF by oral gavage to mice with LPS-induced AKI, then harvested serum and kidney at three different time points. We further isolated Bone marrow-derived macrophages (BMDMs) from mice and stimulated them with LPS followed by DMF treatment. To explore immunomodulatory role of DMF in macrophages, we depleted macrophages in mice using liposomal clodronate after DMF treatment upon LPS-induced septic AKI. Then we observed that DMF attenuated renal dysfunction and murine pathological kidney injury after LPS injection. DMF could inhibit translocation of phosphorylated NF-κB p65 and suppress macrophage activation in LPS-induced AKI. DMF reduced the secretion of TNF-α and IL-6 whereas increased the secretion of IL-10 and Arg-1 in BMDMs after LPS stimulation. DMF also inhibited NF-κB p65 phosphorylation in BMDMs after LPS stimulation. Importantly, the effect of DMF against LPS-induced AKI, macrophage activation, and translocation of phosphorylated NF-κB p65 was impaired upon macrophage depletion. Thus, DMF could attenuate LPS-induced septic AKI by suppression of NF-κB p65 phosphorylation and macrophage activation. This work suggested the potential therapeutic role of DMF for patients in ICU threatened by septic AKI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HIPK2 phosphorylates HDAC3 for NF-κB acetylation to ameliorate colitis-associated colorectal carcinoma and sepsis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34244427/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34244427/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although inflammation is critical for the clearance of pathogens, uncontrolled inflammation also contributes to the development of multiple diseases such as cancer and sepsis. Since NF-κB-mediated transactivation in the nucleus is pivotal downstream of various stimuli to induce inflammation, searching the nuclear-localized targets specifically regulating NF-κB activation will provide important therapeutic application. Here, we have identified that homeodomain-interacting protein kinase 2 (HIPK2), a nuclear serine/threonine kinase, increases its expression in inflammatory macrophages. Importantly, HIPK2 deficiency or overexpression could enhance or inhibit inflammatory responses in LPS-stimulated macrophages, respectively. HIPK2-deficient mice were more susceptible to LPS-induced endotoxemia and CLP-induced sepsis. Adoptive transfer of &lt;em&gt;Hipk2&lt;sup&gt;+/-&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; bone marrow cells (BMs) also aggravated AOM/DSS-induced colorectal cancer. Mechanistically, HIPK2 bound and phosphorylated histone deacetylase 3 (HDAC3) at serine 374 to inhibit its enzymatic activity, thus reducing the deacetylation of p65 at lysine 218 to suppress NF-κB activation. Notably, the HDAC3 inhibitors protected wild-type or &lt;em&gt;Hipk2&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; BMs-reconstituted mice from LPS-induced endotoxemia. Our findings suggest that the HIPK2-HDAC3-p65 module in macrophages restrains excessive inflammation, which may represent a new layer of therapeutic mechanism for colitis-associated colorectal cancer and sepsis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IL-6 regulates autophagy and chemotherapy resistance by promoting BECN1 phosphorylation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34131122/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34131122/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Extracellular cytokines are enriched in the tumor microenvironment and regulate various important properties of cancers, including autophagy. However, the precise molecular mechanisms underlying the link between autophagy and extracellular cytokines remain to be elucidated. In the present study, we demonstrate that IL-6 activates autophagy through the IL-6/JAK2/BECN1 pathway and promotes chemotherapy resistance in colorectal cancer (CRC). Mechanistically, IL-6 triggers the interaction between JAK2 and BECN1, where JAK2 phosphorylates BECN1 at Y333. We demonstrate that BECN1 Y333 phosphorylation is crucial for BECN1 activation and IL-6-induced autophagy by regulating PI3KC3 complex formation. Furthermore, we investigate BECN1 Y333 phosphorylation as a predictive marker for poor CRC prognosis and chemotherapy resistance. Combination treatment with autophagy inhibitors or pharmacological agents targeting the IL-6/JAK2/BECN1 signaling pathway may represent a potential strategy for CRC cancer therapy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Atg1 kinase in fission yeast is activated by Atg11-mediated dimerization and cis-autophosphorylation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32909946/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32909946/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Autophagy is a proteolytic pathway that is conserved from yeasts to mammals. Atg1 kinase is essential for autophagy, but how its activity is controlled remains insufficiently understood. Here, we show that, in the fission yeast &lt;em&gt;Schizosaccharomyces pombe&lt;/em&gt;, Atg1 kinase activity requires Atg11, the ortholog of mammalian FIP200/RB1CC1, but does not require Atg13, Atg17, or Atg101. Remarkably, a 62 amino acid region of Atg11 is sufficient for the autophagy function of Atg11 and for supporting the Atg1 kinase activity. This region harbors an Atg1-binding domain and a homodimerization domain. Dimerizing Atg1 is the main role of Atg11, as it can be bypassed by artificially dimerizing Atg1. In an Atg1 dimer, only one Atg1 molecule needs to be catalytically active, suggesting that Atg1 activation can be achieved through cis-autophosphorylation. We propose that mediating Atg1 oligomerization and activation may be a conserved function of Atg11/FIP200 family proteins and cis-autophosphorylation may be a general mechanism of Atg1 activation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Autophagy regulates fatty acid availability for oxidative phosphorylation through mitochondria-endoplasmic reticulum contact sites</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32792483/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32792483/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Autophagy has been associated with oncogenesis with one of its emerging key functions being its contribution to the metabolism of tumors. Therefore, deciphering the mechanisms of how autophagy supports tumor cell metabolism is essential. Here, we demonstrate that the inhibition of autophagy induces an accumulation of lipid droplets (LD) due to a decrease in fatty acid β-oxidation, that leads to a reduction of oxidative phosphorylation (OxPHOS) in acute myeloid leukemia (AML), but not in normal cells. Thus, the autophagic process participates in lipid catabolism that supports OxPHOS in AML cells. Interestingly, the inhibition of OxPHOS leads to LD accumulation with the concomitant inhibition of autophagy. Mechanistically, we show that the disruption of mitochondria-endoplasmic reticulum (ER) contact sites (MERCs) phenocopies OxPHOS inhibition. Altogether, our data establish that mitochondria, through the regulation of MERCs, controls autophagy that, in turn finely tunes lipid degradation to fuel OxPHOS supporting proliferation and growth in leukemia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prediction of kinase-specific phosphorylation sites in proteins</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tool/2020-04-12-pkspsp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/tool/2020-04-12-pkspsp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In eukaryotes, protein phosphorylation is specifically catalyzed by numerous protein kinases (PKs), faithfully orchestrates various biological processes, and reversibly determines cellular dynamics and plasticity. Here we report an updated algorithm of &lt;a href=&#34;%28http://gps.biocuckoo.cn/%29&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Group-based Prediction System (PGS)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 5.0 to improve the performance for predicting kinase-specific phosphorylation sites (p-sites). Two novel methods, position weight determination (PWD) and scoring matrix optimization (SMO), were developed. Compared with other existing tools, &lt;a href=&#34;http://gps.biocuckoo.cn/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GPS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 5.0 exhibits a highly competitive accuracy. Besides serine/threonine or tyrosine kinases, &lt;a href=&#34;http://gps.biocuckoo.cn/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GPS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 5.0 also supports the prediction of dual-specificity kinase-specific p-sites. In the classical module of &lt;a href=&#34;http://gps.biocuckoo.cn/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GPS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 5.0, 617 individual predictors were constructed for predicting p-sites of 479 human PKs. To extend the application of &lt;a href=&#34;http://gps.biocuckoo.cn/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GPS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 5.0, a species-specific module was implemented to predict kinase-specific p-sites for 44,795 PKs in 161 eukaryotes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.phosphonet.ca/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PhosphoNET&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is an open-access, online resource developed by Kinexus Bioinformatics Corporation to foster the study of cell signalling systems to advance biomedical research in academia and industry. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.phosphonet.ca/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PhosphoNET&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is the worlds largest repository of known and predicted information on human phosphorylation sites, their evolutionary conservation, the identities of protein kinases that may target these sites and related phosphosites. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.phosphonet.ca/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PhosphoNET&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; presently holds data on over 950,000 known and putative phosphorylation sites (P-sites) in over 20,000 human proteins that have been collected from the scientific literature and other reputable websites. Over 19% of these phosphosites have been experimentally validated. The rest have been predicted with a novel P-Site Predictor algorithm developed at Kinexus with academic partners at the University of British Columbia and Simon Fraser University.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;With the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.phosphonet.ca/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PhosphoNET&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Evolution module, this website also provides information about cognate proteins in over 20 other species that may share these human phosphosites. This helps to define the most functionally important phosphosites as these are expected to be highly conserved in nature.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;With the Kinase Predictor module, listings are provided for the top 50 human protein kinases that are likely to phosphorylate each of these phosphosites using another proprietary kinase substrate prediction algorithm developed at Kinexus.  Our kinase substrate predictions are based on deduced consensus phosphorylation site amino acid frequency scoring matrices that we have determined for each of ~500 different human protein kinases. The specificity matrices are generated directly from the primary amino acid sequences of the catalytic domains of these kinases, and when available, have proven to correlate strongly with substrate prediction matrices based on alignment of known substrates of these kinases. The higher the score, the better the prospect that a kinase will phosphorylate a given site. Over 30 million kinase-substrate phosphosite pairs are quantified in &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.phosphonet.ca/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PhosphoNET&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Kinexus Bioinformatics Corporation has the capability to test most of these putative interactions in vitro for our clients.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;With the Phosphosite Match module, we have identified those phosphosites that show the greatest amino acid identity to a selected target human phosphosite. This tool is useful to identify related phosphosites that might be targeted the same protein kinases, phosphatases and/or adapter proteins. This type of query might also help identify potential off-targets for cross-reactive proteins that are detected with phosphosite-specific antibodies that were generated to recognize target phosphosites.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/tag/databases/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Databases&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/tool/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Tools &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Phosphorylation-Mediated IFN-γR2 Membrane Translocation Is Required to Activate Macrophage Innate Response</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/30318148/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/30318148/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Erratum in:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674%2820%2930214-2&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Phosphorylation-Mediated IFN-γR2 Membrane Translocation Is Required to Activate Macrophage Innate Response&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a critical step during innate response, the cytoplasmic β subunit (IFN-γR2) of interferon-γ receptor (IFN-γR) is induced and translocates to plasma membrane to join α subunit to form functional IFN-γR to mediate IFN-γ signaling. However, the mechanism driving membrane translocation and its significance remain largely unknown. We found, unexpectedly, that mice deficient in E-selectin, an endothelial cell-specific adhesion molecule, displayed impaired innate activation of macrophages upon Listeria monocytogenes infection yet had increased circulating IFN-γ. Inflammatory macrophages from E-selectin-deficient mice had less surface IFN-γR2 and impaired IFN-γ signaling. BTK elicited by extrinsic E-selectin engagement phosphorylates cytoplasmic IFN-γR2, facilitating EFhd2 binding and promoting IFN-γR2 trafficking from Golgi to cell membrane. Our findings demonstrate that membrane translocation of cytoplasmic IFN-γR2 is required to activate macrophage innate response against intracellular bacterial infection, identifying the assembly of functional cytokine receptors on cell membrane as an important layer in innate activation and cytokine signaling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tuning microtubule dynamics to enhance cancer therapy by modulating FER-mediated CRMP2 phosphorylation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/29396402/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/29396402/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Erratum in:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author Correction: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-022-31011-1&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tuning microtubule dynamics to enhance cancer therapy by modulating FER-mediated CRMP2 phosphorylation&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Though used widely in cancer therapy, paclitaxel only elicits a response in a fraction of patients. A strong determinant of paclitaxel tumor response is the state of microtubule dynamic instability. However, whether the manipulation of this physiological process can be controlled to enhance paclitaxel response has not been tested. Here, we show a previously unrecognized role of the microtubule-associated protein CRMP2 in inducing microtubule bundling through its carboxy terminus. This activity is significantly decreased when the FER tyrosine kinase phosphorylates CRMP2 at Y479 and Y499. The crystal structures of wild-type CRMP2 and CRMP2-Y479E reveal how mimicking phosphorylation prevents tetramerization of CRMP2. Depletion of FER or reducing its catalytic activity using sub-therapeutic doses of inhibitors increases paclitaxel-induced microtubule stability and cytotoxicity in ovarian cancer cells and in vivo. This work provides a rationale for inhibiting FER-mediated CRMP2 phosphorylation to enhance paclitaxel on-target activity for cancer therapy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
