<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Phosphorylation | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/phosphorylation/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/phosphorylation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Phosphorylation</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Phosphorylation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/phosphorylation/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blocking MG53S255 Phosphorylation Protects Diabetic Heart From Ischemic Injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36337049/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36337049/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; As an integral component of cell membrane repair machinery, MG53 (mitsugumin 53) is important for cardioprotection induced by ischemia preconditioning and postconditioning. However, it also impairs insulin signaling via its E3 ligase activity-mediated ubiquitination-dependent degradation of IR (insulin receptor) and IRS1 (insulin receptor substrate 1) and its myokine function-induced allosteric blockage of IR. Here, we sought to develop MG53 into a cardioprotection therapy by separating its detrimental metabolic effects from beneficial actions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; Using immunoprecipitation-mass spectrometry, site-specific mutation, in vitro kinase assay, and in vivo animal studies, we investigated the role of MG53 phosphorylation at serine 255 (S255). In particular, utilizing recombinant proteins and gene knock-in approaches, we evaluated the potential therapeutic effect of MG53-S255A mutant in treating cardiac ischemia/reperfusion injury in diabetic mice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; We identified S255 phosphorylation as a prerequisite for MG53 E3 ligase activity. Furthermore, MG53S255 phosphorylation was mediated by GSK3β (glycogen synthase kinase 3 beta) and markedly elevated in the animal models with metabolic disorders. Thus, IR-IRS1-GSK3β-MG53 formed a vicious cycle in the pathogenesis of metabolic disorders where aberrant insulin signaling led to hyper-activation of GSK3β, which in turn, phosphorylated MG53 and enhanced its E3 ligase activity, and further impaired insulin sensitivity. Importantly, S255A mutant eliminated the E3 ligase activity while retained cell protective function of MG53. Consequently, the S255A mutant, but not the wild type MG53, protected the heart against ischemia/reperfusion injury in db/db mice with advanced diabetes, although both elicited cardioprotection in normal mice. Moreover, in S255A knock-in mice, S255A mutant also mitigated ischemia/reperfusion-induced myocardial damage in the diabetic setting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; S255 phosphorylation is a biased regulation of MG53 E3 ligase activity. The MG53-S255A mutant provides a promising approach for the treatment of acute myocardial injury, especially in patients with metabolic disorders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Protein phosphatase 1 regulates phosphorylation of gasdermin D and pyroptosis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36205355/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36205355/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We report that phosphorylation of gasdermin D (GSDMD)-NT, cleaved by inflammatory caspases, could inhibit pyroptosis. Phosphatase 1 (PP1) is responsible for the regulation of GSDMD phosphorylation and the capacity of GSDMD to induce cell death. Our findings reveal a critical regulatory mechanism as it provides insight into pyroptosis processes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clathrin-associated AP-1 controls termination of STING signalling</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36261523/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36261523/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stimulator of interferon genes (STING) functions downstream of cyclic GMP-AMP synthase in DNA sensing or as a direct receptor for bacterial cyclic dinucleotides and small molecules to activate immunity during infection, cancer and immunotherapy. Precise regulation of STING is essential to ensure balanced immune responses and prevent detrimental autoinflammation. After activation, STING, a transmembrane protein, traffics from the endoplasmic reticulum to the Golgi, where its phosphorylation by the protein kinase TBK1 enables signal transduction. The mechanism that ends STING signalling at the Golgi remains unknown. Here we show that adaptor protein complex 1 (AP-1) controls the termination of STING-dependent immune activation. We find that AP-1 sorts phosphorylated STING into clathrin-coated transport vesicles for delivery to the endolysosomal system, where STING is degraded. We identify a highly conserved dileucine motif in the cytosolic C-terminal tail (CTT) of STING that, together with TBK1-dependent CTT phosphorylation, dictates the AP-1 engagement of STING. A cryo-electron microscopy structure of AP-1 in complex with phosphorylated STING explains the enhanced recognition of TBK1-activated STING. We show that suppression of AP-1 exacerbates STING-induced immune responses. Our results reveal a structural mechanism of negative regulation of STING and establish that the initiation of signalling is inextricably associated with its termination to enable transient activation of immunity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Energy homeostasis mediated by the LcSnRK1α-LcbZIP1/3 signaling pathway modulates litchi fruit senescence</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35634876/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35634876/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cellular energy status is a key factor deciding the switch-on of the senescence of horticultural crops. Despite the established significance of the conserved energy master regulator sucrose non-fermenting 1 (SNF1)-related protein kinase 1 (SnRK1) in plant development, its working mechanism and related signaling pathway in the regulation of fruit senescence remain enigmatic. Here, we demonstrate that energy deficit accelerates fruit senescence, whereas exogenous ATP treatment delays it. The transient suppression of &lt;em&gt;LcSnRK1α&lt;/em&gt; in litchi (&lt;em&gt;Litchi chinensis&lt;/em&gt; Sonn.) fruit inhibited the expression of energy metabolism-related genes, while its ectopic expression in tomato (&lt;em&gt;Solanum lycopersicum&lt;/em&gt;) promoted ripening and a high energy level. Biochemical analyses revealed that LcSnRK1α interacted with and phosphorylated the transcription factors LcbZIP1 and LcbZIP3, which directly bound to the promoters to activate the expression of &lt;em&gt;DARK-INDUCIBLE 10&lt;/em&gt; (&lt;em&gt;LcDIN10&lt;/em&gt;), &lt;em&gt;ASPARAGINE SYNTHASE 1&lt;/em&gt; (&lt;em&gt;LcASN1&lt;/em&gt;), and &lt;em&gt;ANTHOCYANIN SYNTHASE&lt;/em&gt; (&lt;em&gt;LcANS&lt;/em&gt;), thereby fine-tuning the metabolic reprogramming to ensure energy and redox homeostasis. Altogether, these observations reveal a post-translational modification mechanism by which &lt;em&gt;LcSnRK1α&lt;/em&gt;-mediated phosphorylation of LcbZIP1 and LcbZIP3 regulates the expression of metabolic reprogramming-related genes, consequently modulating litchi fruit senescence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HIPK2 phosphorylates HDAC3 for NF-κB acetylation to ameliorate colitis-associated colorectal carcinoma and sepsis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34244427/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34244427/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although inflammation is critical for the clearance of pathogens, uncontrolled inflammation also contributes to the development of multiple diseases such as cancer and sepsis. Since NF-κB-mediated transactivation in the nucleus is pivotal downstream of various stimuli to induce inflammation, searching the nuclear-localized targets specifically regulating NF-κB activation will provide important therapeutic application. Here, we have identified that homeodomain-interacting protein kinase 2 (HIPK2), a nuclear serine/threonine kinase, increases its expression in inflammatory macrophages. Importantly, HIPK2 deficiency or overexpression could enhance or inhibit inflammatory responses in LPS-stimulated macrophages, respectively. HIPK2-deficient mice were more susceptible to LPS-induced endotoxemia and CLP-induced sepsis. Adoptive transfer of &lt;em&gt;Hipk2&lt;sup&gt;+/-&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; bone marrow cells (BMs) also aggravated AOM/DSS-induced colorectal cancer. Mechanistically, HIPK2 bound and phosphorylated histone deacetylase 3 (HDAC3) at serine 374 to inhibit its enzymatic activity, thus reducing the deacetylation of p65 at lysine 218 to suppress NF-κB activation. Notably, the HDAC3 inhibitors protected wild-type or &lt;em&gt;Hipk2&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; BMs-reconstituted mice from LPS-induced endotoxemia. Our findings suggest that the HIPK2-HDAC3-p65 module in macrophages restrains excessive inflammation, which may represent a new layer of therapeutic mechanism for colitis-associated colorectal cancer and sepsis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IL-6 regulates autophagy and chemotherapy resistance by promoting BECN1 phosphorylation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34131122/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34131122/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Extracellular cytokines are enriched in the tumor microenvironment and regulate various important properties of cancers, including autophagy. However, the precise molecular mechanisms underlying the link between autophagy and extracellular cytokines remain to be elucidated. In the present study, we demonstrate that IL-6 activates autophagy through the IL-6/JAK2/BECN1 pathway and promotes chemotherapy resistance in colorectal cancer (CRC). Mechanistically, IL-6 triggers the interaction between JAK2 and BECN1, where JAK2 phosphorylates BECN1 at Y333. We demonstrate that BECN1 Y333 phosphorylation is crucial for BECN1 activation and IL-6-induced autophagy by regulating PI3KC3 complex formation. Furthermore, we investigate BECN1 Y333 phosphorylation as a predictive marker for poor CRC prognosis and chemotherapy resistance. Combination treatment with autophagy inhibitors or pharmacological agents targeting the IL-6/JAK2/BECN1 signaling pathway may represent a potential strategy for CRC cancer therapy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Atg1 kinase in fission yeast is activated by Atg11-mediated dimerization and cis-autophosphorylation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32909946/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32909946/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Autophagy is a proteolytic pathway that is conserved from yeasts to mammals. Atg1 kinase is essential for autophagy, but how its activity is controlled remains insufficiently understood. Here, we show that, in the fission yeast &lt;em&gt;Schizosaccharomyces pombe&lt;/em&gt;, Atg1 kinase activity requires Atg11, the ortholog of mammalian FIP200/RB1CC1, but does not require Atg13, Atg17, or Atg101. Remarkably, a 62 amino acid region of Atg11 is sufficient for the autophagy function of Atg11 and for supporting the Atg1 kinase activity. This region harbors an Atg1-binding domain and a homodimerization domain. Dimerizing Atg1 is the main role of Atg11, as it can be bypassed by artificially dimerizing Atg1. In an Atg1 dimer, only one Atg1 molecule needs to be catalytically active, suggesting that Atg1 activation can be achieved through cis-autophosphorylation. We propose that mediating Atg1 oligomerization and activation may be a conserved function of Atg11/FIP200 family proteins and cis-autophosphorylation may be a general mechanism of Atg1 activation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Autophagy regulates fatty acid availability for oxidative phosphorylation through mitochondria-endoplasmic reticulum contact sites</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32792483/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32792483/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Autophagy has been associated with oncogenesis with one of its emerging key functions being its contribution to the metabolism of tumors. Therefore, deciphering the mechanisms of how autophagy supports tumor cell metabolism is essential. Here, we demonstrate that the inhibition of autophagy induces an accumulation of lipid droplets (LD) due to a decrease in fatty acid β-oxidation, that leads to a reduction of oxidative phosphorylation (OxPHOS) in acute myeloid leukemia (AML), but not in normal cells. Thus, the autophagic process participates in lipid catabolism that supports OxPHOS in AML cells. Interestingly, the inhibition of OxPHOS leads to LD accumulation with the concomitant inhibition of autophagy. Mechanistically, we show that the disruption of mitochondria-endoplasmic reticulum (ER) contact sites (MERCs) phenocopies OxPHOS inhibition. Altogether, our data establish that mitochondria, through the regulation of MERCs, controls autophagy that, in turn finely tunes lipid degradation to fuel OxPHOS supporting proliferation and growth in leukemia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prediction of kinase-specific phosphorylation sites in proteins</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tool/2020-04-12-pkspsp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/tool/2020-04-12-pkspsp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In eukaryotes, protein phosphorylation is specifically catalyzed by numerous protein kinases (PKs), faithfully orchestrates various biological processes, and reversibly determines cellular dynamics and plasticity. Here we report an updated algorithm of &lt;a href=&#34;%28http://gps.biocuckoo.cn/%29&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Group-based Prediction System (PGS)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 5.0 to improve the performance for predicting kinase-specific phosphorylation sites (p-sites). Two novel methods, position weight determination (PWD) and scoring matrix optimization (SMO), were developed. Compared with other existing tools, &lt;a href=&#34;http://gps.biocuckoo.cn/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GPS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 5.0 exhibits a highly competitive accuracy. Besides serine/threonine or tyrosine kinases, &lt;a href=&#34;http://gps.biocuckoo.cn/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GPS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 5.0 also supports the prediction of dual-specificity kinase-specific p-sites. In the classical module of &lt;a href=&#34;http://gps.biocuckoo.cn/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GPS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 5.0, 617 individual predictors were constructed for predicting p-sites of 479 human PKs. To extend the application of &lt;a href=&#34;http://gps.biocuckoo.cn/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GPS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 5.0, a species-specific module was implemented to predict kinase-specific p-sites for 44,795 PKs in 161 eukaryotes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.phosphonet.ca/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PhosphoNET&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is an open-access, online resource developed by Kinexus Bioinformatics Corporation to foster the study of cell signalling systems to advance biomedical research in academia and industry. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.phosphonet.ca/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PhosphoNET&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is the worlds largest repository of known and predicted information on human phosphorylation sites, their evolutionary conservation, the identities of protein kinases that may target these sites and related phosphosites. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.phosphonet.ca/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PhosphoNET&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; presently holds data on over 950,000 known and putative phosphorylation sites (P-sites) in over 20,000 human proteins that have been collected from the scientific literature and other reputable websites. Over 19% of these phosphosites have been experimentally validated. The rest have been predicted with a novel P-Site Predictor algorithm developed at Kinexus with academic partners at the University of British Columbia and Simon Fraser University.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;With the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.phosphonet.ca/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PhosphoNET&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Evolution module, this website also provides information about cognate proteins in over 20 other species that may share these human phosphosites. This helps to define the most functionally important phosphosites as these are expected to be highly conserved in nature.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;With the Kinase Predictor module, listings are provided for the top 50 human protein kinases that are likely to phosphorylate each of these phosphosites using another proprietary kinase substrate prediction algorithm developed at Kinexus.  Our kinase substrate predictions are based on deduced consensus phosphorylation site amino acid frequency scoring matrices that we have determined for each of ~500 different human protein kinases. The specificity matrices are generated directly from the primary amino acid sequences of the catalytic domains of these kinases, and when available, have proven to correlate strongly with substrate prediction matrices based on alignment of known substrates of these kinases. The higher the score, the better the prospect that a kinase will phosphorylate a given site. Over 30 million kinase-substrate phosphosite pairs are quantified in &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.phosphonet.ca/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PhosphoNET&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Kinexus Bioinformatics Corporation has the capability to test most of these putative interactions in vitro for our clients.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;With the Phosphosite Match module, we have identified those phosphosites that show the greatest amino acid identity to a selected target human phosphosite. This tool is useful to identify related phosphosites that might be targeted the same protein kinases, phosphatases and/or adapter proteins. This type of query might also help identify potential off-targets for cross-reactive proteins that are detected with phosphosite-specific antibodies that were generated to recognize target phosphosites.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/tag/databases/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Databases&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/tool/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Tools &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Phosphorylation-Mediated IFN-γR2 Membrane Translocation Is Required to Activate Macrophage Innate Response</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/30318148/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/30318148/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Erratum in:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674%2820%2930214-2&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Phosphorylation-Mediated IFN-γR2 Membrane Translocation Is Required to Activate Macrophage Innate Response&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a critical step during innate response, the cytoplasmic β subunit (IFN-γR2) of interferon-γ receptor (IFN-γR) is induced and translocates to plasma membrane to join α subunit to form functional IFN-γR to mediate IFN-γ signaling. However, the mechanism driving membrane translocation and its significance remain largely unknown. We found, unexpectedly, that mice deficient in E-selectin, an endothelial cell-specific adhesion molecule, displayed impaired innate activation of macrophages upon Listeria monocytogenes infection yet had increased circulating IFN-γ. Inflammatory macrophages from E-selectin-deficient mice had less surface IFN-γR2 and impaired IFN-γ signaling. BTK elicited by extrinsic E-selectin engagement phosphorylates cytoplasmic IFN-γR2, facilitating EFhd2 binding and promoting IFN-γR2 trafficking from Golgi to cell membrane. Our findings demonstrate that membrane translocation of cytoplasmic IFN-γR2 is required to activate macrophage innate response against intracellular bacterial infection, identifying the assembly of functional cytokine receptors on cell membrane as an important layer in innate activation and cytokine signaling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
