<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>microRNAs | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/micrornas/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/micrornas/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>microRNAs</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>microRNAs</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/micrornas/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Heparan sulfate proteoglycan-mediated internalization of extracellular vesicles ameliorates liver fibrosis by targeting hepatic stellate cells</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/2022-12-14-1024/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/2022-12-14-1024/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Accumulating evidence shows that stem cell-derived extracellular vesicles (EVs) have shown great promise for tissue regeneration and are considered an alternative to cell-based therapy. However, the mechanisms by which EVs induce tissue repair have not been well demonstrated. Previous work indicates that activation of hepatic stellate cells (HSCs) may contribute to the progression of liver fibrosis. Here, we investigate the therapeutic potential of EVs derived from human placental mesenchymal stem cells (hP-MSCs) for the treatment of carbon tetrachloride (CCl4)-induced liver injury. Our data revealed that EVs derived from hP-MSCs effectively ameliorate liver injury by attenuating inflammation and fibrosis. Further data revealed that heparan sulfate proteoglycans (HSPGs) on the surface of HSCs mediate the internalization of EVs. Furthermore, EVs could inhibit the epithelial–mesenchymal transition (EMT) process in HSCs through the downregulated TGF-/Smad pathway, which was mediated by miR-744-5p in EVs. Meanwhile, glycosaminoglycans on the surface of EVs play a crucial anti-inflammatory role. In conclusion, our results provide evidence that hP-MSC-derived EVs promote the recovery of liver injury by targeting HSPGs on HSCs and inhibiting liver inflammation through glycosaminoglycans from EVs. These findings may provide a novel theoretical basis for the treatment of liver fibrosis based on EVs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ImmReg: the regulon atlas of immune-related pathways across cancer types</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34755873/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34755873/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read to learn more:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Li Y., Jiang T., Zhou W., Li J., Li X., Wang Q., Jin X., Yin J., Chen L., Zhang Y. et al. &lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/32081859/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Pan-cancer characterization of immune-related lncRNAs identifies potential oncogenic biomarkers&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-020-14802-2&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nature Communications&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. 2020; 11:1000.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Immune system gene regulation perturbation has been found to be a major cause of the development of various types of cancer. Numbers of mechanisms contribute to gene expression regulation, thus, systematically identification of potential regulons of immune-related pathways is critical to cancer immunotherapy. Here, we comprehensively chart the landscape of transcription factors, microRNAs, RNA binding proteins and long noncoding RNAs regulation in 17 immune-related pathways across 33 cancers. The potential immunology regulons are likely to exhibit higher expressions in immune cells, show expression perturbations in cancer, and are significantly correlated with immune cell infiltrations. We also identify a panel of clinically relevant immunology regulons across cancers. Moreover, the regulon atlas of immune-related pathways helps prioritizing cancer-related genes (i.e. ETV7, miR-146a-5p, ZFP36 and HCP5). We further identified two molecular subtypes of glioma (cold and hot tumour phenotypes), which were characterized by differences in immune cell infiltrations, expression of checkpoints, and prognosis. Finally, we developed a user-friendly resource, &lt;a href=&#34;http://bio-bigdata.hrbmu.edu.cn/ImmReg/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;ImmReg&lt;/a&gt;, with multiple modules to visualize, browse, and download immunology regulation. Our study provides a comprehensive landscape of immunology regulons, which will shed light on future development of RNA-based cancer immunotherapies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Circular RNA AFF4 modulates osteogenic differentiation in BM-MSCs by activating SMAD1/5 pathway through miR-135a-5p/FNDC5/Irisin axis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34145212/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34145212/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bone marrow-derived mesenchymal stem cells (BM-MSCs), the common progenitor cells of adipocytes and osteoblasts, have been recognized as the key mediator during bone formation. Herein, our study aim to investigate molecular mechanisms underlying circular RNA (circRNA) AFF4 (circ_AFF4)-regulated BM-MSCs osteogenesis. BM-MSCs were characterized by FACS, ARS, and ALP staining. Expression patterns of circ_AFF4, miR-135a-5p, FNDC5/Irisin, SMAD1/5, and osteogenesis markers, including ALP, BMP4, RUNX2, Spp1, and Colla1 were detected by qRT-PCR, western blot, or immunofluorescence staining, respectively. Interactions between circ_AFF4 and miR-135a-5p, FNDC5, and miR-135a-5p were analyzed using web tools including TargetScan, miRanda, and miRDB, and further confirmed by luciferase reporter assay and RNA pull-down. Complex formation between Irisin and Integrin αV was verified by Co-immunoprecipitation. To further verify the functional role of circ_AFF4 in vivo during bone formation, we conducted animal experiments harboring circ_AFF4 knockdown, and born samples were evaluated by immunohistochemistry, hematoxylin and eosin, and Masson staining. Circ_AFF4 was upregulated upon osteogenic differentiation induction in BM-MSCs, and miR-135a-5p expression declined as differentiation proceeds. Circ_AFF4 knockdown significantly inhibited osteogenesis potential in BM-MSCs. Circ_AFF4 stimulated FNDC5/Irisin expression through complementary binding to its downstream target molecule miR-135a-5p. Irisin formed an intermolecular complex with Integrin αV and activated the SMAD1/5 pathway during osteogenic differentiation. Our work revealed that circ_AFF4, acting as a sponge of miR-135a-5p, triggers the promotion of FNDC5/Irisin via activating the SMAD1/5 pathway to induce osteogenic differentiation in BM-MSCs. These findings gained a deeper insight into the circRNA-miRNA regulatory system in the bone marrow microenvironment and may improve our understanding of bone formation-related diseases at physiological and pathological levels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>miRNA-mediated loss of m6A increases nascent translation in glioblastoma</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33684100/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33684100/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Within the glioblastoma cellular niche, glioma stem cells (GSCs) can give rise to differentiated glioma cells (DGCs) and, when necessary, DGCs can reciprocally give rise to GSCs to maintain the cellular equilibrium necessary for optimal tumor growth. Here, using ribosome profiling, transcriptome and m&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;A RNA sequencing, we show that GSCs from patients with different subtypes of glioblastoma share a set of transcripts, which exhibit a pattern of m&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;A loss and increased protein translation during differentiation. The target sequences of a group of miRNAs overlap the canonical RRACH m&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;A motifs of these transcripts, many of which confer a survival advantage in glioblastoma. Ectopic expression of the RRACH-binding miR-145 induces loss of m&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;A, formation of FTO/AGO1/ILF3/miR-145 complexes on a clinically relevant tumor suppressor gene (CLIP3) and significant increase in its nascent translation. Inhibition of miR-145 maintains RRACH m&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;A levels of CLIP3 and inhibits its nascent translation. This study highlights a critical role of miRNAs in assembling complexes for m&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;A demethylation and induction of protein translation during GSC state transition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Online tools decoding RNA-RNA regulatory networks</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tool/2020-11-10-rri/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/tool/2020-11-10-rri/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://circinteractome.nia.nih.gov/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;CircInteractome&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; predicts the miRNAs which can potentially target the circRNAs using the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.targetscan.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Targetscan&lt;/a&gt; prediction tool. This computational tool enables the prediction and mapping of binding sites for RBPs and miRNAs on reported circRNAs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights of &lt;a href=&#34;%28https://circinteractome.nia.nih.gov/%29&#34;&gt;CircInteractome&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Searches circRNAs name&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Searches the genomic position and best-matching transcripts of the circRNA&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Retrieves genomic and mature circRNA sequences&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Searches RBPs binding to a circRNA and to sequences upstream/downstream of the circRNA&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Identifies RBPs binding to the circRNA junctions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Identifies miRNAs targeting a circRNA&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Designs divergent primers for circRNAs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Designs siRNAs Specific to circRNA&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://starbase.sysu.edu.cn/index.php&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;ENCORI (The Encyclopedia of RNA Interactomes)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is an openly licensed and state-of-the-art platform to decode the cellular interaction networks among thousands of RNA binding proteins (RBPs) and various RNAs. We have identified millions of RBP-RNA and RNA-RNA interactions through analyzing thousands of CLIP-seq and various high-throughput sequencing data by developing new software and tools, and studied their functions and mechanisms in human diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/tag/databases/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Databases&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/tool/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Tools &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>microRNA-199a-3p inhibits hepatic apoptosis and hepatocarcinogenesis by targeting PDCD4</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33099584/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33099584/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hepatic apoptosis and the initiated liver inflammation play the initial roles in inflammation-induced hepatocarcinogenesis. Molecular mechanisms underlying the regulation of hepatocyte apoptosis and their roles in hepatocarcinogenesis have attracted much attention. A set of microRNAs (miRNAs) have been determined to be dysregulated in hepatocellular carcinoma (HCC) and participated in cancer progression, however, the roles of these dysregulated miRNAs in carcinogenesis are still poorly understood. We previously analyzed the dysregulated miRNAs in HCC using high-throughput sequencing, and found that miR-199a/b-3p was abundantly expressed in human normal liver while markedly decreased in HCC, which promotes HCC progression. Whether miR-199a/b-3p participates in HCC carcinogenesis is still unknown up to now. Hence, we focused on the role and mechanism of miR-199a/b-3p in hepatocarcinogenesis in this study. Hepatic miR-199a/b-3p was determined to be expressed by miR-199a-2 gene in mice, and we constructed miR-199a-2 knockout and hepatocyte-specific miR-199a-2 knockout mice. Diethylnitrosamine (DEN)-induced hepatocarcinogenesis were markedly increased by hepatocyte-specific miR-199a-3p knockout, which is mediated by the enhanced hepatocyte apoptosis and hepatic injury by DEN administration. In acetaminophen (APAP)-induced acute hepatic injury model, hepatocyte-specific miR-199a-3p knockout also aggravated hepatic apoptosis. By proteomic screening and reporter gene validation, we identified and verified that hepatic programed cell death 4 (PDCD4), which promotes apoptosis, was directly targeted by miR-199a-3p. Furthermore, we confirmed that miR-199a-3p-suppressed hepatocyte apoptosis and hepatic injury by targeting and suppressing PDCD4. Thus, hepatic miR-199a-3p inhibits hepatocyte apoptosis and hepatocarcinogenesis, and decreased miR-199a-3p in hepatocytes may aggravate hepatic injury and HCC development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Web tools to analyse your miRNAs</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tool/2020-08-07-web-tool-anal-mirna/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/tool/2020-08-07-web-tool-anal-mirna/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://tools4mirs.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tools4miRs&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a first, manually curated platform gathering at the present over 170 methods for the broadly-defined miRNA analysis. All tools in &lt;a href=&#34;https://tools4mirs.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tools4miRs&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; are classified in the four general and seven more detailed categories. In each of the aforementioned sections user can additionally filter available methods according to his research needs, capabilities and preferences. Beside basic summary seen at first glance, the user can get detailed information concerning each tool. &lt;a href=&#34;https://tools4mirs.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tools4miRs&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is also a web-based target prediction meta-server incorporating user-designated target prediction methods in the analysis of user-provided data. Results generated by described meta-server can be presented in basic and extended form, while user can can additionally filter them using Union, Intersection or Consensus method. &lt;a href=&#34;https://tools4mirs.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tools4miRs&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is free, open-access service which will be systematically updated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mirbase.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;miRBase&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; database is a searchable database of published miRNA sequences and annotation. Each entry in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mirbase.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;miRBase&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Sequence database represents a predicted hairpin portion of a miRNA transcript (termed mir in the database), with information on the location and sequence of the mature miRNA sequence (termed miR). Both hairpin and mature sequences are available for searching and browsing, and entries can also be retrieved by name, keyword, references and annotation. All sequence and annotation data are also available for download.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dianalab.e-ce.uth.gr/html/diana/web/index.php?r=tarbasev8&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;DIANA-TarBase&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; was initially released in 2006 and it was the first database aiming to catalogue published experimentally validated miRNA:gene interactions. And it is one part of &lt;a href=&#34;http://diana.imis.athena-innovation.gr/DianaTools/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;DIANA&lt;/a&gt; suites. Actually, &lt;a href=&#34;http://diana.imis.athena-innovation.gr/DianaTools/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;DIANA&lt;/a&gt; provides several powerful tools facilitating your analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mirdb.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;miRDB&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is an online database for miRNA target prediction and functional annotations. All the targets in &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirdb.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;miRDB&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; were predicted by a bioinformatics tool, MirTarget, which was developed by analyzing thousands of miRNA-target interactions from high-throughput sequencing experiments. Common features associated with miRNA binding and target downregulation have been identified and used to predict miRNA targets with machine learning methods. &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirdb.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;miRDB&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; hosts predicted miRNA targets in five species: human, mouse, rat, dog and chicken. Users may also provide their own sequences for custom target prediction using the updated prediction algorithm. In addition, through combined computational analyses and literature mining, functionally active miRNAs in humans and mice were identified. These miRNAs, as well as associated functional annotations, are presented in the FuncMir Collection in &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirdb.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;miRDB&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. As a recent update, &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirdb.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;miRDB&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; presents the expression profiles of hundreds of cell lines and the user may limit their search for miRNA targets that are expressed in a cell line of interest. To facilitate the prediction of miRNA functions, &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirdb.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;miRDB&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; presents a new web interface for integrative analysis of target prediction and Gene Ontology data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://mirwalk.umm.uni-heidelberg.de/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;miRWalk&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is an improved version of the previous database (i.e. &lt;a href=&#34;http://mirwalk.umm.uni-heidelberg.de/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;miRWalk&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;). The new version of &lt;a href=&#34;http://mirwalk.umm.uni-heidelberg.de/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;miRWalk&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; stores predicted data obtained with a maschine learning algorithm including experimentally verified miRNA-target interactions. The focus lies on accuracy, simplicity, user-friendly design and mostly up to date informations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.targetscan.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;TargetScan&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; predicts biological targets of miRNAs by searching for the presence of conserved 8mer, 7mer, and 6mer sites that match the seed region of each miRNA. As options, predictions with only poorly conserved sites and predictions with nonconserved miRNAs are also provided. Also identified are sites with mismatches in the seed region that are compensated by conserved 3&amp;rsquo; pairing. In mammals, predictions are ranked based on the predicted efficacy of targeting as calculated using a biochemical model of miRNA-mediated repression, which was extended to all miRNA sequences using a convolutional neural network. As an option, predictions are also ranked on the basis of targeting efficacy estimated using cumulative weighted context++ scores of the sites. As another option, predictions are ranked by their probability of conserved targeting. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.targetscan.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;TargetScanHuman&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; considers matches to human 3&amp;rsquo; UTRs and their orthologs, as defined by &lt;a href=&#34;%28http://www.genome.ucsc.edu/%29&#34;&gt;UCSC whole-genome&lt;/a&gt; alignments. Conserved targeting has also been detected within open reading frames (ORFs).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://starbase.sysu.edu.cn/index.php&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;ENCORI (The Encyclopedia of RNA Interactomes)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is an openly licensed and state-of-the-art platform to decode the cellular interaction networks among thousands of RNA binding proteins (RBPs) and various RNAs. We have identified millions of RBP-RNA and RNA-RNA interactions through analyzing thousands of CLIP-seq and various high-throughput sequencing data by developing new software and tools, and studied their functions and mechanisms in human diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cuilab.cn/transmir&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;TransmiR&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a database for transcription factor (TF)-microRNA (miRNA) regulations, through which one can find regulatory relations between TFs and miRNAs. This website has been tested by using Chrome, Microsoft Edge and Firefox browsers. Microsoft IE may not work well. More interestings can be found at Cui Lab of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cuilab.cn/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Bioinformatics and Systems Biology&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://pictar.mdc-berlin.de/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;PicTar&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is an algorithm for the identification of microRNA targets. This searchable website provides details (3&amp;rsquo; UTR alignments with predicted sites, links to various public databases etc) regarding:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;microRNA target predictions in vertebrates&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;microRNA target predictions in seven Drosophila species&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;microRNA targets in three nematode species&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;human microRNA targets that are not conserved but co-expressed (i.e. the microRNA and mRNA are expressed in the same tissue)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dashr2.lisanwanglab.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;DASHR (Database of small human non-coding RNAs)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a database developed at the University of Pennsylvania with the most comprehensive expression and processing information to date on all major classes of human small non-coding RNA (sncRNA) genes and mature sncNA annotations, expression levels, sequence and RNA processing information across 185 human tissues, cell types, and cell lines. The content of the database derives from integrating annotation data with curation, annotation, and computational analysis of 802 small-RNA (smRNA-seq) deep sequencing datasets with over 22 billion reads from &amp;gt;60 independent studies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://rna.sysu.edu.cn/deepbase3/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;deepBase&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a popular and openly licensed resource to facilitate the integrative and interactive display and analysis of expression, evolution, function of various ncRNAs by deeply mining thousands of high-throughput sequencing data from tissue, cancer and exosome samples. &lt;a href=&#34;https://rna.sysu.edu.cn/deepbase3/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;deepBase&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; provided the most comprehensive expression analysis of sRNAs and lncRNAs, the expression patterns of tRFs and snoRNAs from thousands of cancer and normal samples, the correlations between ncRNAs and patients’ survival and the function prediction of ncRNAs in tumor tumorigenesis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://promirna.molgen.mpg.de/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PROmiRNA&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a program for annotating miRNA promoters in human, as well as other species. It uses deepCAGE data from the FANTOM4 Consortium and integrated cage tag counts and other promoter features, such as CpG content, conservation and TATA box affinity, to score the potential of a candidate regions to be a promoter. Given a list of genomic regions of interest, in the form of a gff file, &lt;a href=&#34;http://promirna.molgen.mpg.de/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PROmiRNA&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; returns the most probable promoter locations, together with the posterior probabilities calculated by the model. More informations on how to run &lt;a href=&#34;http://promirna.molgen.mpg.de/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PROmiRNA&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; on your regions of interest can be found in the README file inside the &lt;a href=&#34;http://promirna.molgen.mpg.de/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PROmiRNA&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; directory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/tag/databases/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Databases&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/tool/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Tools &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LncRNA PVT1 promotes gemcitabine resistance of pancreatic cancer via activating Wnt/β-catenin and autophagy pathway through modulating the miR-619-5p/Pygo2 and miR-619-5p/ATG14 axes</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32727463/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32727463/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pancreatic cancer is one of the most lethal malignancies and has an extremely poor diagnosis and prognosis. The development of resistance to gemcitabine is still a major challenge. The long noncoding RNA PVT1 was reported to be involved in carcinogenesis and chemoresistance; however, the mechanism by which PVT1 regulates the sensitivity of pancreatic cancer to gemcitabine remains poorly understood.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The viability of pancreatic cancer cells was assessed by MTT assay in vitro and xenograft tumor formation assay in vivo. The expression levels of PVT1 and miR-619-5p were detected by quantitative real-time polymerase chain reaction (qRT-PCR). Western blotting analysis and qRT-PCR were performed to assess the protein and mRNA levels of Pygo2 and ATG14, respectively. Autophagy was explored via autophagic flux detection under confocal microscopy and autophagic vacuole investigation under transmission electron microscopy (TEM). The functional role and mechanism of PVT1 were further investigated by gain- and loss-of-function assays in vitro.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the present study, we demonstrated that PVT1 was up-regulated in gemcitabine-resistant pancreatic cancer cell lines. Gain- and loss-of-function assays revealed that PVT1 impaired sensitivity to gemcitabine in vitro and in vivo. We further found that PVT1 up-regulated the expression of both Pygo2 and ATG14 and thus regulated Wnt/β-catenin signaling and autophagic activity to overcome gemcitabine resistance through sponging miR-619-5p. Moreover, we discovered three TCF/LEF binding elements (TBEs) in the promoter region of PVT1, and activation of Wnt/β-catenin signaling mediated by the up-regulation of Pygo2 increased PVT1 expression by direct binding to the TBE region. Furthermore, PVT1 was discovered to interact with ATG14, thus promoting assembly of the autophagy specific complex I (PtdIns3K-C1) and ATG14-dependent class III PtdIns3K activity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These data indicate that PVT1 plays a critical role in the sensitivity of pancreatic cancer to gemcitabine and highlight its potential as a valuable target for pancreatic cancer therapy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LncRNA-HGBC stabilized by HuR promotes gallbladder cancer progression by regulating miR-502-3p/SET/AKT axis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/31752906/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/31752906/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Erratum in:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Correction to: &lt;a href=&#34;https://molecular-cancer.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12943-021-01386-8&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;LncRNA-HGBC stabilized by HuR promotes gallbladder cancer progression by regulating miR-502-3p/SET/AKT axis&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Backgrounds:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Long non-coding RNAs (lncRNAs) are essential factors that regulate tumor development and metastasis via diverse molecular mechanisms in a broad type of cancers. However, the pathological roles of lncRNAs in gallbladder carcinoma (GBC) remain largely unknown. Here we discovered a novel lncRNA termed lncRNA Highly expressed in GBC (lncRNA-HGBC) which was upregulated in GBC tissue and aimed to investigate its role and regulatory mechanism in the development and progression of GBC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The expression level of lncRNA-HGBC in GBC tissue and different cell lines was determined by quantitative real-time PCR. The full length of lncRNA-HGBC was obtained by 5&amp;rsquo; and 3&amp;rsquo; rapid amplification of the cDNA ends (RACE). Cellular localization of lncRNA-HGBC was detected by fluorescence in situ hybridization (FISH) assays and subcellular fractionation assay. In vitro and in vivo assays were preformed to explore the biological effects of lncRNA-HGBC in GBC cells. RNA pull-down assay, mass spectrometry, and RNA immunoprecipitation (RIP) assay were used to identify lncRNA-HGBC-interacting proteins. Dual luciferase reporter assays, AGO2-RIP, and MS2-RIP assays were performed to verify the interaction between lncRNA-HGBC and miR-502-3p.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We found that lncRNA-HGBC was upregulated in GBC and its upregulation could predict poor survival. Overexpression or knockdown of lncRNA-HGBC in GBC cell lines resulted in increased or decreased, respectively, cell proliferation and invasion in vitro and in xenografted tumors. LncRNA-HGBC specifically bound to RNA binding protein Hu Antigen R (HuR) that in turn stabilized lncRNA-HGBC. LncRNA-HGBC functioned as a competitive endogenous RNA to bind to miR-502-3p that inhibits target gene SET. Overexpression, knockdown or mutation of lncRNA-HGBC altered the inhibitory effects of miR-502-3p on SET expression and downstream activation of AKT. Clinically, lncRNA-HGBC expression was negatively correlated with miR-502-3p, but positively correlated with SET and HuR in GBC tissue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our study demonstrates that lncRNA-HGBC promotes GBC metastasis via activation of the miR-502-3p-SET-AKT cascade, pointing to lncRNA-HGBC as a new prognostic predictor and a therapeutic target.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Network of Noncoding Regulatory RNAs Acts in the Mammalian Brain</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/29887379/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/29887379/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Noncoding RNAs (ncRNAs) play increasingly appreciated gene-regulatory roles. Here, we describe a regulatory network centered on four ncRNAs-a long ncRNA, a circular RNA, and two microRNAs-using gene editing in mice to probe the molecular consequences of disrupting key components of this network. The long ncRNA Cyrano uses an extensively paired site to miR-7 to trigger destruction of this microRNA. Cyrano-directed miR-7 degradation is much more effective than previously described examples of target-directed microRNA degradation, which come primarily from studies of artificial and viral RNAs. By reducing miR-7 levels, Cyrano prevents repression of miR-7-targeted mRNAs and enables accumulation of Cdr1as, a circular RNA known to regulate neuronal activity. Without Cyrano, excess miR-7 causes cytoplasmic destruction of Cdr1as in neurons, in part through enhanced slicing of Cdr1as by a second miRNA, miR-671. Thus, several types of ncRNAs can collaborate to establish a sophisticated regulatory network.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
