<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>microRNAs | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/micrornas/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/micrornas/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>microRNAs</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>microRNAs</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/micrornas/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>miRNome profiling of lung cancer metastases revealed a key role for miRNA-PD-L1 axis in the modulation of chemotherapy response</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36587234/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36587234/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Locally advanced non-small cell lung cancer (NSCLC) is frequent at diagnosis and requires multimodal treatment approaches. Neoadjuvant chemotherapy (NACT) followed by surgery is the treatment of choice for operable locally advanced NSCLC (Stage IIIA). However, the majority of patients are NACT-resistant and show persistent lymph nodal metastases (LNmets) and an adverse outcome. Therefore, the identification of mechanisms and biomarkers of NACT resistance is paramount for ameliorating the prognosis of patients with Stage IIIA NSCLC. Here, we investigated the miRNome and transcriptome of chemo-naïve LNmets collected from patients with Stage IIIA NSCLC (N = 64). We found that a microRNA signature accurately predicts NACT response. Mechanistically, we discovered a miR-455-5p/PD-L1 regulatory axis which drives chemotherapy resistance, hallmarks metastases with active IFN-γ response pathway (an inducer of PD-L1 expression), and impacts T cells viability and relative abundances in tumor microenvironment (TME). Our data provide new biomarkers to predict NACT response and add molecular insights relevant for improving the management of patients with locally advanced NSCLC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Heparan sulfate proteoglycan-mediated internalization of extracellular vesicles ameliorates liver fibrosis by targeting hepatic stellate cells</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/2022-12-14-1024/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/2022-12-14-1024/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Accumulating evidence shows that stem cell-derived extracellular vesicles (EVs) have shown great promise for tissue regeneration and are considered an alternative to cell-based therapy. However, the mechanisms by which EVs induce tissue repair have not been well demonstrated. Previous work indicates that activation of hepatic stellate cells (HSCs) may contribute to the progression of liver fibrosis. Here, we investigate the therapeutic potential of EVs derived from human placental mesenchymal stem cells (hP-MSCs) for the treatment of carbon tetrachloride (CCl4)-induced liver injury. Our data revealed that EVs derived from hP-MSCs effectively ameliorate liver injury by attenuating inflammation and fibrosis. Further data revealed that heparan sulfate proteoglycans (HSPGs) on the surface of HSCs mediate the internalization of EVs. Furthermore, EVs could inhibit the epithelial–mesenchymal transition (EMT) process in HSCs through the downregulated TGF-/Smad pathway, which was mediated by miR-744-5p in EVs. Meanwhile, glycosaminoglycans on the surface of EVs play a crucial anti-inflammatory role. In conclusion, our results provide evidence that hP-MSC-derived EVs promote the recovery of liver injury by targeting HSPGs on HSCs and inhibiting liver inflammation through glycosaminoglycans from EVs. These findings may provide a novel theoretical basis for the treatment of liver fibrosis based on EVs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pan-cancer analyses reveal molecular and clinical characteristics of cuproptosis regulators</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/imt2.68/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/imt2.68/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therapeutics that discriminate between the genetic makeup of normal cells and tumour cells are valuable for treating and understanding cancer. Small molecules with oncogene-selective lethality may reveal novel functions of oncoproteins and enable the creation of more selective drugs. Here we describe the mechanism of action of the selective anti-tumour agent erastin, involving the RAS-RAF-MEK signalling pathway functioning in cell proliferation, differentiation and survival. Erastin exhibits greater lethality in human tumour cells harbouring mutations in the oncogenes HRAS, KRAS or BRAF. Using affinity purification and mass spectrometry, we discovered that erastin acts through mitochondrial voltage-dependent anion channels (VDACs)&amp;ndash;a novel target for anti-cancer drugs. We show that erastin treatment of cells harbouring oncogenic RAS causes the appearance of oxidative species and subsequent death through an oxidative, non-apoptotic mechanism. RNA-interference-mediated knockdown of VDAC2 or VDAC3 caused resistance to erastin, implicating these two VDAC isoforms in the mechanism of action of erastin. Moreover, using purified mitochondria expressing a single VDAC isoform, we found that erastin alters the permeability of the outer mitochondrial membrane. Finally, using a radiolabelled analogue and a filter-binding assay, we show that erastin binds directly to VDAC2. These results demonstrate that ligands to VDAC proteins can induce non-apoptotic cell death selectively in some tumour cells harbouring activating mutations in the RAS-RAF-MEK pathway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MiR-199a-3p-regulated alveolar macrophage-derived secretory autophagosomes exacerbate lipopolysaccharide-induced acute respiratory distress syndrome</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36523634/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36523634/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Purpose:&lt;/em&gt; Acute respiratory distress syndrome (ARDS) is a prevalent illness in intensive care units. Extracellular vesicles and particles released from activated alveolar macrophages (AMs) assist in ARDS lung injury and the inflammatory process through mechanisms that are unclear. This study investigated the role of AM-derived secretory autophagosomes (SAPs) in lung injury and microRNA (MiR)-199a-3p-regulated inflammation associated with ARDS in vitro and in a murine model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; The ARDS model in mouse was established by intratracheal LPS lipopolysaccharide (LPS) injection. The agomirs or antagomirs of MiR-199a-3p were injected into the caudal vein to figure out whether MiR-199a-3p could influence ARDS inflammation and lung injury, whereas the mimics or inhibitors of MiR-199a-3p, siRNA of Rab8a, or PAK4 inhibitor were transfected or applied to RAW264.7 cells to evaluate the mechanism of SAP release. Culture supernatants of RAW264.7 cells treated with LPS or bronchoalveolar lavage fluid from mice were collected for the isolation of SAPs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; We found that MiR-199a-3p was over-expressed in the lungs of ARDS mice. The MiR-199a-3p antagomir alleviated, whereas the MiR-199a-3p agomir exacerbated LPS-induced inflammation in mice by promoting AM-derived SAP secretion. In addition, MiR-199a-3p over-expression exacerbated LPS-induced ARDS via activating Rab8a, and Rab8a silencing significantly suppressed the promoting influence of the MiR-199a-3p mimic on SAP secretion. Furthermore, MiR-199a-3p mimic activated Rab8a by directly inhibiting PAK4 expression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/em&gt; The novel finding of this study is that MiR-199a-3p participated in the regulation of SAP secretion and the inflammatory process via targeting of PAK4/Rab8a, and is a potential therapeutic candidate for ARDS treatment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reprogramming of T cell-derived small extracellular vesicles using IL2 surface engineering induces potent anti-cancer effects through miRNA delivery</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36447429/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36447429/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;T cell-derived small extracellular vesicles (sEVs) exhibit anti-cancer effects. However, their anti-cancer potential should be reinforced to enhance clinical applicability. Herein, we generated interleukin-2-tethered sEVs (IL2-sEVs) from engineered Jurkat T cells expressing IL2 at the plasma membrane via a flexible linker to induce an autocrine effect. IL2-sEVs increased the anti-cancer ability of CD8&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T cells without affecting regulatory T (T&lt;sub&gt;reg&lt;/sub&gt; ) cells and down-regulated cellular and exosomal PD-L1 expression in melanoma cells, causing their increased sensitivity to CD8+ T cell-mediated cytotoxicity. Its effect on CD8&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T and melanoma cells was mediated by several IL2-sEV-resident microRNAs (miRNAs), whose expressions were upregulated by the autocrine effects of IL2. Among the miRNAs, miR-181a-3p and miR-223-3p notably reduced the PD-L1 protein levels in melanoma cells. Interestingly, miR-181a-3p increased the activity of CD8&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T cells while suppressing Treg cell activity. IL2-sEVs inhibited tumour progression in melanoma-bearing immunocompetent mice, but not in immunodeficient mice. The combination of IL2-sEVs and existing anti-cancer drugs significantly improved anti-cancer efficacy by decreasing PD-L1 expression in vivo. Thus, IL2-sEVs are potential cancer immunotherapeutic agents that regulate both immune and cancer cells by reprogramming miRNA levels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Uterine macrophages as treatment targets for therapy of premature rupture of membranes by modified ADSC-EVs through a circRNA/miRNA/NF-κB pathway</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36402996/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36402996/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Circular RNA (circRNA) is a type of stable non-coding RNA that modifies macrophage inflammation by sponging micro RNAs (miRNAs), binding to RNA-binding proteins, and undergoing translation into peptides. Activated M1 phenotype macrophages secrete matrix metalloproteinases to participate in softening of the cervix uteri to promote vaginal delivery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; In this study, the premature rupture of membranes (PROM) mouse model was used to analyze the role of macrophages in this process. Profiling of circRNAs was performed using a competing endogenous RNA microarray, and their functions were elucidated in vitro. Meanwhile, adipose tissue-derived stem cell-secreted extracellular vesicles (EVs) were applied as a vehicle to transport small interfering RNAs (siRNAs) targeting the circRNAs to demonstrate their biological function in vivo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; The miRNA &lt;em&gt;miR-1931&lt;/em&gt; is dependent on the nuclear factor kappa-B (NF-κB) pathway but negatively regulates its activation by targeting the NF-κB signaling transducer TRAF6 to prevent polarization of M1 macrophages and inhibit matrix metalloproteinase (MMP) secretion. The host gene of circRNA &lt;em&gt;B4GALNT1&lt;/em&gt;, also an NF-κB pathway-dependent gene, circularizes to form &lt;em&gt;circRNA_0002047&lt;/em&gt;, which sponges &lt;em&gt;miR-1931&lt;/em&gt; to maintain NF-κB pathway activation and MMP secretion in vitro. In the PROM model, EVs loaded with siRNAs targeting circRNAs demonstrated that the circRNAs reduced &lt;em&gt;miR-1931&lt;/em&gt; expression to maintain NF-κB pathway activation and MMP secretion for accelerating PROM in vivo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; Our data provide insights into understanding PROM pathogenesis and improving PROM treatment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exosome modification to better alleviates endoplasmic reticulum stress induced chondrocyte apoptosis and osteoarthritis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36370754/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36370754/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Osteoarthritis (OA) is characterized by cartilage matrix degeneration and chondrocyte apoptosis. Prolonged endoplasmic reticulum (ER) stress participates in chondrocyte apoptosis and cartilage degeneration in OA progression. miR-486-5p could suppress the apoptosis of nucleus pulposus cells and cardiomyocyte, yet whether miR-486-5p modified exosomes could modulate ER stress and apoptosis of chondrocytes remain unknown. We validated the increased inflammation and ER stress in OA synovium and cartilage, and the inhibition of ER stress could attenuate the IL-1β induced chondrocyte apoptosis. Administration of exogenous miR-486-5p could inhibit the ER stress, alleviate chondrocytes apoptosis and promote matrix regeneration. In comparison with direct administration of miR-486-5p and miR-486-5p overexpressing ADSCs, miR-486-5p modified exosomes indicated a better effect in modulating chondrocyte homeostasis. MiR-486-5p containing exosomes could also regulate macrophage polarization. Our IVIS imaging data validated that intraarticular injection of miR-486-5p containing exosomes could sustain for at least 7 days. MiR-486-5p containing exosomes showed a better effect on alleviating rats OA compared with direct administration of miR-486-5p and miR-486-5p overexpressing ADSCs. Our data demonstrated that miR-486-5p modified exosomes have a better effect on alleviating chondrocyte apoptosis and osteoarthritis. This study provides evidence of this efficient strategy of exosomal miRNA delivery and the miRNA-based therapy for OA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mesenchymal stem cell-derived extracellular vesicles attenuate tPA-induced blood-brain barrier disruption in murine ischemic stroke models</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36367475/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36367475/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Intracerebral hemorrhage following blood-brain barrier (BBB) disruption resulting from thrombolysis of ischemic stroke with tissue plasminogen activator (tPA) remains a critical clinical problem. Mesenchymal stem cell-derived extracellular vesicles (MSC-EVs) are promising nanotherapeutic agents that have the potential to repair the BBB after ischemic stroke; however, whether they can attenuate BBB disruption and hemorrhagic transformation after tPA thrombolysis is largely unknown. Here, we observed that MSC-EVs efficiently passed through the BBB and selectively accumulated in injured brain regions in ischemic stroke model mice in real time using aggregation-induced emission luminogens (AIEgens), which exhibit better tracking ability than the commercially available tracer DiR. Moreover, tPA administration promoted the homing of MSC-EVs to the ischemic brain and increased the uptake of MSC-EVs by astrocytes. Furthermore, the accumulated MSC-EVs attenuated the tPA-induced disruption of BBB integrity and alleviated hemorrhage by inhibiting astrocyte activation and inflammation. Mechanistically, miR-125b-5p delivered by MSC-EVs played an indispensable role in maintaining BBB integrity by targeting Toll-like receptor 4 (TLR4) and inhibiting nuclear transcription factor-kappaB (NF-κB) signaling in astrocytes. This study provides a noninvasive method for real-time tracking of MSC-EVs in the ischemic brain after tPA treatment and highlights the potential of MSC-EVs as thrombolytic adjuvants for ischemic stroke. STATEMENT OF SIGNIFICANCE: Although tPA thrombolysis is the most effective pharmaceutical strategy for acute ischemic stroke, its clinical application and therapeutic efficacy are challenged by tPA-induced BBB disruption and hemorrhagic transformation. Our study demonstrated that MSC-EVs can act as an attractive thrombolytic adjuvant to repair the BBB and improve thrombolysis in a mouse ischemic stroke model. Notably, by labeling MSC-EVs with AIEgens, we achieved accurate real-time imaging of MSC-EVs in the ischemic brain and therapeutic visualization. MSC-EVs inhibit astrocyte activation and associated inflammation through miR-125b-5p/TLR4/NF-κB pathway. Consequently, we revealed that MSC-EVs combined with tPA thrombolysis may be a promising approach for the treatment of ischemic stroke in clinical setting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two circPPFIA1s negatively regulate liver metastasis of colon cancer via miR-155-5p/CDX1 and HuR/RAB36</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36224588/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36224588/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Circular RNAs (circRNAs) play a critical role in colorectal cancer (CRC) progression, including metastasis. However, the detailed molecular mechanism is not fully understood.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; Differentially expressed circRNAs between primary KM12C and liver metastatic KM12L4 colon cancer cells were identified by microarray. The expression of circRNAs was measured by semi-quantitative (semi-qPCR) and real time-quantitative PCR (RT-qPCR). Metastatic potential including invasive and migratory abilities, and liver metastasis were examined by transwell assays and intrasplenic injection, respectively. CircPPFIA1-associated microRNA (miRNA) and RNA-binding protein (RBP) were screened by an antisense oligonucleotide (ASO) pulldown experiment. The effects of circPPFIA1 on target gene expression were evaluated by RT-qPCR and western blot analyses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; By analyzing circRNA microarray data, we identified two anti-metastatic circRNAs generated from PPFIA1 with different length, which named circPPFIA1-L (long) and -S (short). They were significantly downregulated in liver metastatic KM12L4 cells compared to primary KM12C cells. The knockdown of circPPFIA1s in KM12C enhanced metastatic potential and increased liver metastasis. Conversely, overexpression of circPPFIA1s weakened metastatic potential and inhibited liver metastasis. circPPFIA1s were found to function as sponges of oncogenic miR-155-5p and Hu antigen R (HuR) by an ASO pulldown experiment. circPPFIA1s upregulated tumor-suppressing CDX1 expression and conversely downregulated oncogenic RAB36 by decoying miR-155-5p and by sequestering HuR, respectively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/em&gt; Our findings demonstrate that circPPFIA1s inhibit the liver metastasis of CRC via the miR-155-5p/CDX1 and HuR/RAB36 pathways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hypoxia-induced exosomal circPDK1 promotes pancreatic cancer glycolysis via c-myc activation by modulating miR-628-3p/BPTF axis and degrading BIN1</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36068586/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36068586/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; circRNA has been established to play a pivotal role in tumorigenesis development in a variety of cancers; nevertheless, the biological functions and molecular mechanisms of hypoxia-induced exosomal circRNAs in pancreatic cancer remain largely unknown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; Differentially expressed circRNAs in exosomes between hypoxic exosomes and normoxic exosomes in PC cells were verified by RNA sequencing. The expression of circPDK1 in PC tumors and PC patients was evaluated by qRT-PCR and ISH, and the biological functions of circPDK1 in PC were verified through a series of in vitro and in vivo experiments. Using Western blotting, Co-IP, RNA pull-down, ChIP, RIP, dual-luciferase assays, and rescue experiments, the underlying mechanism of circPDK1 was verified.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; CircPDK1 was highly abundant in PC tumor tissues and serum exosomes and was associated with poor survival. Exosomal circPDK1 significantly promoted PC cell proliferation, migration, and glycolysis both in vitro and in vivo. Mechanistically, circPDK1 could be activated by HIF1A at the transcriptional level and sponges miR-628-3p to activate the BPTF/c-myc axis. In addition, circPDK1 serves as a scaffold that enhances the interaction between UBE2O and BIN1, inducing the UBE2O-mediated degradation of BIN1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; We found that circPDK1 was activated by HIF1A at the transcriptional level by modulating the miR-628-3p/BPTF axis and degrading BIN1. Exosomal circPDK1 is a promising biomarker for PC diagnosis and prognosis and represents a potential therapeutic target for PC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dental stem cell-derived extracellular vesicles transfer miR-330-5p to treat traumatic brain injury by regulating microglia polarization</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36064768/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36064768/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Traumatic brain injury (TBI) contributes to the key causative elements of neurological deficits. However, no effective therapeutics have been developed yet. In our previous work, extracellular vesicles (EVs) secreted by stem cells from human exfoliated deciduous teeth (SHED) offered new insights as potential strategies for functional recovery of TBI. The current study aims to elucidate the mechanism of action, providing novel therapeutic targets for future clinical interventions. With the miRNA array performed and Real-time PCR validated, we revealed the crucial function of miR-330-5p transferred by SHED-derived EVs (SHED-EVs) in regulating microglia, the critical immune modulator in central nervous system. MiR-330-5p targeted Ehmt2 and mediated the transcription of CXCL14 to promote M2 microglia polarization and inhibit M1 polarization. Identified in our in vivo data, SHED-EVs and their effector miR-330-5p alleviated the secretion of inflammatory cytokines and resumed the motor functional recovery of TBI rats. In summary, by transferring miR-330-5p, SHED-EVs favored anti-inflammatory microglia polarization through Ehmt2 mediated CXCL14 transcription in treating traumatic brain injury.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Circular RNA circFIRRE drives osteosarcoma progression and metastasis through tumorigenic-angiogenic coupling</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35986280/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35986280/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Disappointing clinical efficacy of standard treatment has been proven in refractory metastatic osteosarcoma, and the emerging anti-angiogenic regimens are still in the infantile stage. Thus, there is an urgent need to develop novel therapeutic approach for osteosarcoma lung metastasis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;circFIRRE was selected from RNA-sequencing of 4 matched osteosarcoma and adjacent samples. The expression of circFIRRE was verified in clinical osteosarcoma samples and cell lines via quantitative real-time polymerase chain reaction (RT-qPCR). The effect of circFIRRE was investigated in cell lines in vitro models, ex vivo models and in vivo xenograft tumor models, including proliferation, invasion, migration, metastasis and angiogenesis. Signaling regulatory mechanism was evaluated by RT-qPCR, Western blot, RNA pull-down and dual-luciferase reporter assays.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article, a novel circular RNA, circFIRRE (hsa_circ_0001944) was screened out and identified from RNA-sequencing, and was upregulated in both osteosarcoma cell lines and tissues. Clinically, aberrantly upregulated circFIRRE portended higher metastatic risk and worse prognosis in osteosarcoma patients. Functionally, in vitro, ex vivo and in vivo experiments demonstrated that circFIRRE could drive primary osteosarcoma progression and lung metastasis by inducing both tumor cells and blood vessels, we call as “tumorigenic-angiogenic coupling”. Mechanistically, upregulated circFIRRE was induced by transcription factor YY1, and partially boosted the mRNA and protein level of LUZP1 by sponging miR-486-3p and miR-1225-5p.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We identified circFIRRE as a master regulator in the tumorigenesis and angiogenesis of osteosarcoma, which could be purposed as a novel prognostic biomarker and therapeutic target for refractory osteosarcoma.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Circular RNA circSFMBT2 downregulation by HBx promotes hepatocellular carcinoma metastasis via the miR-665/TIMP3 axis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36159591/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36159591/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hepatitis B virus X protein (HBx) is considered as an oncogene in tumorigenesis and progression of hepatocellular carcinoma (HCC). In recent years, the important role of circular RNAs (circRNAs) in HCC has been increasingly demonstrated. However, the regulatory mechanisms of HBx on circRNAs remains largely unknown. In this study, we identified that a novel circRNA, circSFMBT2, was markedly downregulated by HBx. Low expression of circSFMBT2 was correlated with poor prognosis and vascular invasion. Functionally, overexpression of circSFMBT2 significantly inhibited HCC metastasis both in vitro and in vivo. The mechanism of circSFMBT2 was to as a sponge of miR-665, which is a negative regulator of tissue inhibitor of metalloproteinases 3 (TIMP3). However, HBx downregulated circSFMBT2 via the interaction with DExH-box helicase 9 (DHX9), which binds to flanking circRNA-forming introns. In conclusion, circSFMBT2, which is downregulated by HBx, acts as a tumor suppressor to inhibit tumor metastasis through the miR-665/TIMP3 axis. Our study suggests that circSFMBT2 could be a potential prognostic biomarker and therapeutic target for HCC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CircSV2b participates in oxidative stress regulation through miR-5107-5p-Foxk1-Akt1 axis in Parkinson&#39;s disease</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35973363/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35973363/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a novel type of non-coding RNAs, covalently closed circular RNAs (circRNAs) are ubiquitously expressed in eukaryotes. Emerging studies have indicated that dysregulation of circRNAs was related to neurological diseases. However, the biogenesis, regulation, function, and mechanism of circRNAs in Parkinson&amp;rsquo;s disease (PD) remain largely unclear. In this study, thirty-three differentially expressed circRNAs (DECs) were detected by RNA-sequencing between the MPTP-induced PD mice model and the wild-type mice. Quantitative real-time PCR was used to determine the RNA level of DECs in the striatum (STR), substantia nigra pars compacta (SNpc), and serum exosomes, and it was found that circSV2b was downregulated in PD mice. Then, functional experiments in vivo were employed to explore the effect of circSV2b in PD. For the mechanism study, dual-luciferase reporter, fluorescence in situ hybridization (FISH), RNA immunoprecipitation (RIP), RNA pull-down, gene editing, and CUT &amp;amp; Tag were performed in vitro to confirm that circSV2b directly sponged miR-5107-5p and alleviated the suppression of the expression of the target gene Foxk1, and then positively regulated Akt1 transcription. In vivo, the mechanistic analysis demonstrated that circSV2b overexpression resisted oxidative stress damage through the ceRNA-Akt1 axis in PD models. Taken together, these findings suggested that the miR-5107-5p-Foxk1-Akt1 axis might serve as a key target of circSV2b overexpression in PD treatment, and highlighted the significant change of circSV2b in serum exosomes. Therefore, circSV2b might be a novel biomarker for the diagnosis and treatment of PD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A novel circular RNA, circIgfbp2, links neural plasticity and anxiety through targeting mitochondrial dysfunction and oxidative stress-induced synapse dysfunction after traumatic brain injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35918398/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35918398/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Traumatic brain injury (TBI) can lead to different neurological and psychiatric disorders. Circular RNAs (circRNAs) are highly expressed in the nervous system and enriched in synapses; yet, the underlying role and mechanisms of circRNAs in neurological impairment and dysfunction are still not fully understood. In this study, we investigated the expression of circRNAs and their relation with neurological dysfunction after TBI. RNA-Seq was used to detect differentially expressed circRNAs in injured brain tissue, revealing that circIgfbp2 was significantly increased. Up-regulated hsa_circ_0058195, which was highly homologous to circIgfbp2, was further confirmed in the cerebral cortex specimens and serum samples of patients after TBI. Moreover, correlation analysis showed a positive correlation between hsa_circ_0058195 levels and the Self-Rating Anxiety Scale scores in these subjects. Furthermore, knockdown of circIgfbp2 in mice relieved anxiety-like behaviors and sleep disturbances induced by TBI. Knockdown of circIgfbp2 in H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; treated HT22 cells alleviated mitochondrial dysfunction, while its overexpression reversed the process. Mechanistically, we discovered that circIgfbp2 targets miR-370-3p to regulate BACH1, and down-regulating BACH1 alleviated mitochondrial dysfunction and oxidative stress-induced synapse dysfunction. In conclusion, inhibition of circIgfbp2 alleviated mitochondrial dysfunction and oxidative stress-induced synapse dysfunction after TBI through the miR-370-3p/BACH1/HO-1 axis. Thus, circIgfbp2 might be a novel therapeutic target for anxiety and sleep disorders after TBI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CircCEMIP promotes anoikis-resistance by enhancing protective autophagy in prostate cancer cells</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35655258/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35655258/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Circular RNAs (circRNAs) are essential participants in the development and progression of various malignant tumors. Previous studies have shown that cell migration-inducing protein (CEMIP) accelerates prostate cancer (PCa) anoikis resistance (AR) by activating autophagy. This study focused on the effect of circCEMIP on PCa metastasis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; This study gradually revealed the role of circ_0004585 in PCa anoikis resistance via quantitative real-time PCR (qRT-PCR) analysis, western blotting, pull-down assays, and dual fluorescence reporter assays.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; Functionally, circ_0004585 promoted PCa cells invasion and metastasis both in vitro and in vivo. Mechanistically, circ_0004585 directly interacted with miR-1248 to upregulate target gene expression. Furthermore, target prediction and dual-luciferase reporter assays identified transmembrane 9 superfamily member 4 (TM9SF4) as a potential miR-1248 target. Pathway analysis revealed that TM9SF4 activated autophagy to promote PCa cells anoikis resistance via mTOR phosphorylation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; These results demonstrated that circ_0004585 played an oncogenic role during PCa invasion and metastasis by targeting the miR-1248/TM9SF4 axis while providing new insight into therapeutic strategy development for metastatic PCa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LncRNA-PACERR induces pro-tumour macrophages via interacting with miR-671-3p and m6A-reader IGF2BP2 in pancreatic ductal adenocarcinoma</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35526050/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35526050/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; LncRNA-PACERR plays critical role in the polarization of tissue-associated macrophages (TAMs). In this study, we found the function and molecular mechanism of PACERR in TAMs to regulate pancreatic ductal adenocarcinoma (PDAC) progression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; We used qPCR to analyse the expression of PACERR in TAMs and M1-tissue-resident macrophages (M1-NTRMs) which were isolated from 46 PDAC tissues. The function of PACERR on macrophages polarization and PDAC proliferation, migration and invasion were confirmed through in vivo and in vitro assays. The molecular mechanism of PACERR was discussed via fluorescence in situ hybridization (FISH), RNA pull-down, ChIP-qPCR, RIP-qPCR and luciferase assays.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; LncRNA-PACERR was high expression in TAMs and associated with poor prognosis in PDAC patients. Our finding validated that LncRNA-PACERR increased the number of M2-polarized cells and facilized cell proliferation, invasion and migration in vitro and in vivo. Mechanistically, LncRNA-PACERR activate KLF12/p-AKT/c-myc pathway by binding to miR-671-3p. And LncRNA-PACERR which bound to IGF2BP2 acts as an m6A-dependent manner to enhance the stability of KLF12 and c-myc in cytoplasm. In addition, the promoter of LncRNA-PACERR was a target of KLF12 and LncRNA-PACERR recruited EP300 to increase the acetylation of histone by interacting with KLF12 in nucleus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; This study found that LncRNA-PACERR functions as key regulator of TAMs in PDAC microenvironment and revealed the novel mechanisms in cytoplasm and in nucleus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Long noncoding RNA LINC01606 protects colon cancer cells from ferroptotic cell death and promotes stemness by SCD1-Wnt/β-catenin-TFE3 feedback loop signalling</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35485210/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35485210/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Ferroptosis is principally caused by iron catalytic activity and intracellular lipid peroxidation. Long noncoding RNAs (lncRNAs) play crucial roles in tumorigenesis. However, the potential interplay between lncRNA LINC01606 and ferroptosis in colon cancer remains elusive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; The expression level of LNC01606 in colon cancer tissue was detected by quantitative real-time polymerase chain reaction. The functional role of LNC01606 was investigated by gain- and loss-of-function assays both in vitro and in vivo. The LINC01606-SCD1-Wnt/β-catenin-TFE3 axis were screened and validated by DNA/RNA pull down, gas chromatography-mass spectrometry, RNA immunoprecipitation and dual-luciferase reporter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; The expression of lncRNA LINC01606 was frequently upregulated in human colon cancer and strongly associated with a poor prognosis. LINC01606 functioned as an oncogene and promotes colon cancer cell growth, invasion and stemness both in vitro and in vivo. Moreover, LINC01606 protected colon cancer cells from ferroptosis by decreasing the concentration of iron, lipid reactive oxygen species, mitochondrial superoxide and increasing mitochondrial membrane potential. Mechanistically, LINC01606 enhanced the expression of stearoyl-CoA desaturase 1 (SCD1), serving as a competing endogenous RNA to modulate miR-423-5p expression, subsequently activating the canonical Wnt/β-catenin signaling, and transcription factor binding to IGHM enhancer 3 (TFE3) increased LINC01606 transcription after recruitment to the promoter regions of LINC01606. Furthermore, we confirmed that upregulated LINC01606 and Wnt/β-catenin formed a positive feedback regulatory loop, further inhibiting ferroptosis and enhancing stemness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; LINC01606 functions as an oncogene to facilitate tumor cell stemness, proliferation and inhibit ferroptosis and is a promising therapeutic target for colon cancer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Circular RNA circ-MTHFD1L induces HR repair to promote gemcitabine resistance via the miR-615-3p/RPN6 axis in pancreatic ductal adenocarcinoma</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35459186/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35459186/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Chemoresistance of pancreatic cancer is the main reason for the poor treatment effect of pancreatic cancer patients. Exploring chemotherapy resistance-related genes has been a difficult and hot topic of oncology. Numerous studies implicate the key roles of circular RNAs (circRNAs) in the development of pancreatic cancer. However, the regulation of circRNAs in the process of pancreatic ductal adenocarcinoma (PDAC) chemotherapy resistance is not yet fully clear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; Based on the cross-analysis of the Gene Expression Omnibus (GEO) database and the data of our center, we explored a new molecule, hsa_circ_0078297 (circ-MTHFD1L), related to chemotherapy resistance. QRT-PCR was used to detect the expression of circRNAs, miRNAs, and mRNAs in human PDAC tissues and their matched normal tissues. The interaction between circ-MTHFD1L and miR-615-3p/RPN6 signal axis was confirmed by a series of experiments such as Dual-luciferase reporter assay, fluorescence in situ hybridization (FISH) RNA immunoprecipitation (RIP) assays.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; Circ-MTHFD1L was significantly increased in PDAC tissues and cells. And in PDAC patients, the higher the expression level of circ-MTHFD1L, the worse the prognosis. Mechanism analysis showed that circ-MTHFD1L, as an endogenous miR-615-3p sponge, upregulates the expression of RPN6, thereby promoting DNA damage repair and exerting its effect on enhancing gemcitabine chemotherapy resistance. More importantly, we also found that Silencing circ-MTHFD1L combined with olaparib can increase the sensitivity of pancreatic cancer to gemcitabine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/em&gt; Circ-MTHFD1L maintains PDAC gemcitabine resistance through the miR-615-3p/RPN6 signal axis. Circ-MTHFD1L may be a molecular marker for the effective treatment of PDAC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Photocaged amplified FRET nanoflares: spatiotemporal controllable of mRNA-powered nanomachines for precise and sensitive microRNA imaging in live cells</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34935962/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34935962/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is considerable interest in creating a precise and sensitive strategy for in situ visualizing and profiling intracellular miRNA. Present here is a novel photocaged amplified FRET nanoflare (PAFN), which spatiotemporal controls of mRNA-powered nanomachine for precise and sensitive miRNA imaging in live cells. The PAFN could be activated remotely by light, be triggered by specific low-abundance miRNA and fueled by high-abundance mRNA. It offers high spatiotemporal control over the initial activity of nanomachine at desirable time and site, and a &amp;lsquo;one-to-more&amp;rsquo; ratiometric signal amplification model. The PAFN, an unprecedented design, is quiescent during the delivery process. However, upon reaching the interest tumor site, it can be selectively activated by light, and then be triggered by specific miRNA, avoiding undesirable early activation and reducing nonspecific signals, allowing precise and sensitive detection of specific miRNA in live cells. This strategy may open new avenues for creating spatiotemporally controllable and endogenous molecule-powered nanomachine, facilitating application at biological and medical imaging.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ImmReg: the regulon atlas of immune-related pathways across cancer types</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34755873/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34755873/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read to learn more:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Li Y., Jiang T., Zhou W., Li J., Li X., Wang Q., Jin X., Yin J., Chen L., Zhang Y. et al. &lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/32081859/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Pan-cancer characterization of immune-related lncRNAs identifies potential oncogenic biomarkers&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-020-14802-2&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nature Communications&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. 2020; 11:1000.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Immune system gene regulation perturbation has been found to be a major cause of the development of various types of cancer. Numbers of mechanisms contribute to gene expression regulation, thus, systematically identification of potential regulons of immune-related pathways is critical to cancer immunotherapy. Here, we comprehensively chart the landscape of transcription factors, microRNAs, RNA binding proteins and long noncoding RNAs regulation in 17 immune-related pathways across 33 cancers. The potential immunology regulons are likely to exhibit higher expressions in immune cells, show expression perturbations in cancer, and are significantly correlated with immune cell infiltrations. We also identify a panel of clinically relevant immunology regulons across cancers. Moreover, the regulon atlas of immune-related pathways helps prioritizing cancer-related genes (i.e. ETV7, miR-146a-5p, ZFP36 and HCP5). We further identified two molecular subtypes of glioma (cold and hot tumour phenotypes), which were characterized by differences in immune cell infiltrations, expression of checkpoints, and prognosis. Finally, we developed a user-friendly resource, &lt;a href=&#34;http://bio-bigdata.hrbmu.edu.cn/ImmReg/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;ImmReg&lt;/a&gt;, with multiple modules to visualize, browse, and download immunology regulation. Our study provides a comprehensive landscape of immunology regulons, which will shed light on future development of RNA-based cancer immunotherapies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Circular RNA AFF4 modulates osteogenic differentiation in BM-MSCs by activating SMAD1/5 pathway through miR-135a-5p/FNDC5/Irisin axis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34145212/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34145212/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bone marrow-derived mesenchymal stem cells (BM-MSCs), the common progenitor cells of adipocytes and osteoblasts, have been recognized as the key mediator during bone formation. Herein, our study aim to investigate molecular mechanisms underlying circular RNA (circRNA) AFF4 (circ_AFF4)-regulated BM-MSCs osteogenesis. BM-MSCs were characterized by FACS, ARS, and ALP staining. Expression patterns of circ_AFF4, miR-135a-5p, FNDC5/Irisin, SMAD1/5, and osteogenesis markers, including ALP, BMP4, RUNX2, Spp1, and Colla1 were detected by qRT-PCR, western blot, or immunofluorescence staining, respectively. Interactions between circ_AFF4 and miR-135a-5p, FNDC5, and miR-135a-5p were analyzed using web tools including TargetScan, miRanda, and miRDB, and further confirmed by luciferase reporter assay and RNA pull-down. Complex formation between Irisin and Integrin αV was verified by Co-immunoprecipitation. To further verify the functional role of circ_AFF4 in vivo during bone formation, we conducted animal experiments harboring circ_AFF4 knockdown, and born samples were evaluated by immunohistochemistry, hematoxylin and eosin, and Masson staining. Circ_AFF4 was upregulated upon osteogenic differentiation induction in BM-MSCs, and miR-135a-5p expression declined as differentiation proceeds. Circ_AFF4 knockdown significantly inhibited osteogenesis potential in BM-MSCs. Circ_AFF4 stimulated FNDC5/Irisin expression through complementary binding to its downstream target molecule miR-135a-5p. Irisin formed an intermolecular complex with Integrin αV and activated the SMAD1/5 pathway during osteogenic differentiation. Our work revealed that circ_AFF4, acting as a sponge of miR-135a-5p, triggers the promotion of FNDC5/Irisin via activating the SMAD1/5 pathway to induce osteogenic differentiation in BM-MSCs. These findings gained a deeper insight into the circRNA-miRNA regulatory system in the bone marrow microenvironment and may improve our understanding of bone formation-related diseases at physiological and pathological levels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>miRNA-mediated loss of m6A increases nascent translation in glioblastoma</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33684100/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33684100/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Within the glioblastoma cellular niche, glioma stem cells (GSCs) can give rise to differentiated glioma cells (DGCs) and, when necessary, DGCs can reciprocally give rise to GSCs to maintain the cellular equilibrium necessary for optimal tumor growth. Here, using ribosome profiling, transcriptome and m&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;A RNA sequencing, we show that GSCs from patients with different subtypes of glioblastoma share a set of transcripts, which exhibit a pattern of m&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;A loss and increased protein translation during differentiation. The target sequences of a group of miRNAs overlap the canonical RRACH m&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;A motifs of these transcripts, many of which confer a survival advantage in glioblastoma. Ectopic expression of the RRACH-binding miR-145 induces loss of m&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;A, formation of FTO/AGO1/ILF3/miR-145 complexes on a clinically relevant tumor suppressor gene (CLIP3) and significant increase in its nascent translation. Inhibition of miR-145 maintains RRACH m&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;A levels of CLIP3 and inhibits its nascent translation. This study highlights a critical role of miRNAs in assembling complexes for m&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;A demethylation and induction of protein translation during GSC state transition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Online tools decoding RNA-RNA regulatory networks</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tool/2020-11-10-rri/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/tool/2020-11-10-rri/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://circinteractome.nia.nih.gov/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;CircInteractome&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; predicts the miRNAs which can potentially target the circRNAs using the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.targetscan.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Targetscan&lt;/a&gt; prediction tool. This computational tool enables the prediction and mapping of binding sites for RBPs and miRNAs on reported circRNAs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights of &lt;a href=&#34;%28https://circinteractome.nia.nih.gov/%29&#34;&gt;CircInteractome&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Searches circRNAs name&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Searches the genomic position and best-matching transcripts of the circRNA&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Retrieves genomic and mature circRNA sequences&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Searches RBPs binding to a circRNA and to sequences upstream/downstream of the circRNA&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Identifies RBPs binding to the circRNA junctions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Identifies miRNAs targeting a circRNA&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Designs divergent primers for circRNAs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Designs siRNAs Specific to circRNA&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://starbase.sysu.edu.cn/index.php&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;ENCORI (The Encyclopedia of RNA Interactomes)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is an openly licensed and state-of-the-art platform to decode the cellular interaction networks among thousands of RNA binding proteins (RBPs) and various RNAs. We have identified millions of RBP-RNA and RNA-RNA interactions through analyzing thousands of CLIP-seq and various high-throughput sequencing data by developing new software and tools, and studied their functions and mechanisms in human diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/tag/databases/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Databases&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/tool/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Tools &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>microRNA-199a-3p inhibits hepatic apoptosis and hepatocarcinogenesis by targeting PDCD4</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33099584/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33099584/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hepatic apoptosis and the initiated liver inflammation play the initial roles in inflammation-induced hepatocarcinogenesis. Molecular mechanisms underlying the regulation of hepatocyte apoptosis and their roles in hepatocarcinogenesis have attracted much attention. A set of microRNAs (miRNAs) have been determined to be dysregulated in hepatocellular carcinoma (HCC) and participated in cancer progression, however, the roles of these dysregulated miRNAs in carcinogenesis are still poorly understood. We previously analyzed the dysregulated miRNAs in HCC using high-throughput sequencing, and found that miR-199a/b-3p was abundantly expressed in human normal liver while markedly decreased in HCC, which promotes HCC progression. Whether miR-199a/b-3p participates in HCC carcinogenesis is still unknown up to now. Hence, we focused on the role and mechanism of miR-199a/b-3p in hepatocarcinogenesis in this study. Hepatic miR-199a/b-3p was determined to be expressed by miR-199a-2 gene in mice, and we constructed miR-199a-2 knockout and hepatocyte-specific miR-199a-2 knockout mice. Diethylnitrosamine (DEN)-induced hepatocarcinogenesis were markedly increased by hepatocyte-specific miR-199a-3p knockout, which is mediated by the enhanced hepatocyte apoptosis and hepatic injury by DEN administration. In acetaminophen (APAP)-induced acute hepatic injury model, hepatocyte-specific miR-199a-3p knockout also aggravated hepatic apoptosis. By proteomic screening and reporter gene validation, we identified and verified that hepatic programed cell death 4 (PDCD4), which promotes apoptosis, was directly targeted by miR-199a-3p. Furthermore, we confirmed that miR-199a-3p-suppressed hepatocyte apoptosis and hepatic injury by targeting and suppressing PDCD4. Thus, hepatic miR-199a-3p inhibits hepatocyte apoptosis and hepatocarcinogenesis, and decreased miR-199a-3p in hepatocytes may aggravate hepatic injury and HCC development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Web tools to analyse your miRNAs</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tool/2020-08-07-web-tool-anal-mirna/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/tool/2020-08-07-web-tool-anal-mirna/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://tools4mirs.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tools4miRs&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a first, manually curated platform gathering at the present over 170 methods for the broadly-defined miRNA analysis. All tools in &lt;a href=&#34;https://tools4mirs.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tools4miRs&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; are classified in the four general and seven more detailed categories. In each of the aforementioned sections user can additionally filter available methods according to his research needs, capabilities and preferences. Beside basic summary seen at first glance, the user can get detailed information concerning each tool. &lt;a href=&#34;https://tools4mirs.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tools4miRs&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is also a web-based target prediction meta-server incorporating user-designated target prediction methods in the analysis of user-provided data. Results generated by described meta-server can be presented in basic and extended form, while user can can additionally filter them using Union, Intersection or Consensus method. &lt;a href=&#34;https://tools4mirs.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tools4miRs&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is free, open-access service which will be systematically updated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mirbase.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;miRBase&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; database is a searchable database of published miRNA sequences and annotation. Each entry in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mirbase.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;miRBase&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Sequence database represents a predicted hairpin portion of a miRNA transcript (termed mir in the database), with information on the location and sequence of the mature miRNA sequence (termed miR). Both hairpin and mature sequences are available for searching and browsing, and entries can also be retrieved by name, keyword, references and annotation. All sequence and annotation data are also available for download.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dianalab.e-ce.uth.gr/html/diana/web/index.php?r=tarbasev8&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;DIANA-TarBase&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; was initially released in 2006 and it was the first database aiming to catalogue published experimentally validated miRNA:gene interactions. And it is one part of &lt;a href=&#34;http://diana.imis.athena-innovation.gr/DianaTools/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;DIANA&lt;/a&gt; suites. Actually, &lt;a href=&#34;http://diana.imis.athena-innovation.gr/DianaTools/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;DIANA&lt;/a&gt; provides several powerful tools facilitating your analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mirdb.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;miRDB&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is an online database for miRNA target prediction and functional annotations. All the targets in &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirdb.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;miRDB&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; were predicted by a bioinformatics tool, MirTarget, which was developed by analyzing thousands of miRNA-target interactions from high-throughput sequencing experiments. Common features associated with miRNA binding and target downregulation have been identified and used to predict miRNA targets with machine learning methods. &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirdb.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;miRDB&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; hosts predicted miRNA targets in five species: human, mouse, rat, dog and chicken. Users may also provide their own sequences for custom target prediction using the updated prediction algorithm. In addition, through combined computational analyses and literature mining, functionally active miRNAs in humans and mice were identified. These miRNAs, as well as associated functional annotations, are presented in the FuncMir Collection in &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirdb.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;miRDB&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. As a recent update, &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirdb.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;miRDB&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; presents the expression profiles of hundreds of cell lines and the user may limit their search for miRNA targets that are expressed in a cell line of interest. To facilitate the prediction of miRNA functions, &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirdb.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;miRDB&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; presents a new web interface for integrative analysis of target prediction and Gene Ontology data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://mirwalk.umm.uni-heidelberg.de/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;miRWalk&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is an improved version of the previous database (i.e. &lt;a href=&#34;http://mirwalk.umm.uni-heidelberg.de/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;miRWalk&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;). The new version of &lt;a href=&#34;http://mirwalk.umm.uni-heidelberg.de/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;miRWalk&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; stores predicted data obtained with a maschine learning algorithm including experimentally verified miRNA-target interactions. The focus lies on accuracy, simplicity, user-friendly design and mostly up to date informations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.targetscan.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;TargetScan&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; predicts biological targets of miRNAs by searching for the presence of conserved 8mer, 7mer, and 6mer sites that match the seed region of each miRNA. As options, predictions with only poorly conserved sites and predictions with nonconserved miRNAs are also provided. Also identified are sites with mismatches in the seed region that are compensated by conserved 3&amp;rsquo; pairing. In mammals, predictions are ranked based on the predicted efficacy of targeting as calculated using a biochemical model of miRNA-mediated repression, which was extended to all miRNA sequences using a convolutional neural network. As an option, predictions are also ranked on the basis of targeting efficacy estimated using cumulative weighted context++ scores of the sites. As another option, predictions are ranked by their probability of conserved targeting. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.targetscan.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;TargetScanHuman&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; considers matches to human 3&amp;rsquo; UTRs and their orthologs, as defined by &lt;a href=&#34;%28http://www.genome.ucsc.edu/%29&#34;&gt;UCSC whole-genome&lt;/a&gt; alignments. Conserved targeting has also been detected within open reading frames (ORFs).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://starbase.sysu.edu.cn/index.php&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;ENCORI (The Encyclopedia of RNA Interactomes)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is an openly licensed and state-of-the-art platform to decode the cellular interaction networks among thousands of RNA binding proteins (RBPs) and various RNAs. We have identified millions of RBP-RNA and RNA-RNA interactions through analyzing thousands of CLIP-seq and various high-throughput sequencing data by developing new software and tools, and studied their functions and mechanisms in human diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cuilab.cn/transmir&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;TransmiR&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a database for transcription factor (TF)-microRNA (miRNA) regulations, through which one can find regulatory relations between TFs and miRNAs. This website has been tested by using Chrome, Microsoft Edge and Firefox browsers. Microsoft IE may not work well. More interestings can be found at Cui Lab of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cuilab.cn/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Bioinformatics and Systems Biology&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://pictar.mdc-berlin.de/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;PicTar&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is an algorithm for the identification of microRNA targets. This searchable website provides details (3&amp;rsquo; UTR alignments with predicted sites, links to various public databases etc) regarding:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;microRNA target predictions in vertebrates&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;microRNA target predictions in seven Drosophila species&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;microRNA targets in three nematode species&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;human microRNA targets that are not conserved but co-expressed (i.e. the microRNA and mRNA are expressed in the same tissue)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dashr2.lisanwanglab.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;DASHR (Database of small human non-coding RNAs)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a database developed at the University of Pennsylvania with the most comprehensive expression and processing information to date on all major classes of human small non-coding RNA (sncRNA) genes and mature sncNA annotations, expression levels, sequence and RNA processing information across 185 human tissues, cell types, and cell lines. The content of the database derives from integrating annotation data with curation, annotation, and computational analysis of 802 small-RNA (smRNA-seq) deep sequencing datasets with over 22 billion reads from &amp;gt;60 independent studies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://rna.sysu.edu.cn/deepbase3/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;deepBase&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a popular and openly licensed resource to facilitate the integrative and interactive display and analysis of expression, evolution, function of various ncRNAs by deeply mining thousands of high-throughput sequencing data from tissue, cancer and exosome samples. &lt;a href=&#34;https://rna.sysu.edu.cn/deepbase3/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;deepBase&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; provided the most comprehensive expression analysis of sRNAs and lncRNAs, the expression patterns of tRFs and snoRNAs from thousands of cancer and normal samples, the correlations between ncRNAs and patients’ survival and the function prediction of ncRNAs in tumor tumorigenesis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://promirna.molgen.mpg.de/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PROmiRNA&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a program for annotating miRNA promoters in human, as well as other species. It uses deepCAGE data from the FANTOM4 Consortium and integrated cage tag counts and other promoter features, such as CpG content, conservation and TATA box affinity, to score the potential of a candidate regions to be a promoter. Given a list of genomic regions of interest, in the form of a gff file, &lt;a href=&#34;http://promirna.molgen.mpg.de/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PROmiRNA&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; returns the most probable promoter locations, together with the posterior probabilities calculated by the model. More informations on how to run &lt;a href=&#34;http://promirna.molgen.mpg.de/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PROmiRNA&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; on your regions of interest can be found in the README file inside the &lt;a href=&#34;http://promirna.molgen.mpg.de/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PROmiRNA&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; directory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/tag/databases/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Databases&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/tool/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Tools &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LncRNA PVT1 promotes gemcitabine resistance of pancreatic cancer via activating Wnt/β-catenin and autophagy pathway through modulating the miR-619-5p/Pygo2 and miR-619-5p/ATG14 axes</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32727463/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32727463/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pancreatic cancer is one of the most lethal malignancies and has an extremely poor diagnosis and prognosis. The development of resistance to gemcitabine is still a major challenge. The long noncoding RNA PVT1 was reported to be involved in carcinogenesis and chemoresistance; however, the mechanism by which PVT1 regulates the sensitivity of pancreatic cancer to gemcitabine remains poorly understood.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The viability of pancreatic cancer cells was assessed by MTT assay in vitro and xenograft tumor formation assay in vivo. The expression levels of PVT1 and miR-619-5p were detected by quantitative real-time polymerase chain reaction (qRT-PCR). Western blotting analysis and qRT-PCR were performed to assess the protein and mRNA levels of Pygo2 and ATG14, respectively. Autophagy was explored via autophagic flux detection under confocal microscopy and autophagic vacuole investigation under transmission electron microscopy (TEM). The functional role and mechanism of PVT1 were further investigated by gain- and loss-of-function assays in vitro.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the present study, we demonstrated that PVT1 was up-regulated in gemcitabine-resistant pancreatic cancer cell lines. Gain- and loss-of-function assays revealed that PVT1 impaired sensitivity to gemcitabine in vitro and in vivo. We further found that PVT1 up-regulated the expression of both Pygo2 and ATG14 and thus regulated Wnt/β-catenin signaling and autophagic activity to overcome gemcitabine resistance through sponging miR-619-5p. Moreover, we discovered three TCF/LEF binding elements (TBEs) in the promoter region of PVT1, and activation of Wnt/β-catenin signaling mediated by the up-regulation of Pygo2 increased PVT1 expression by direct binding to the TBE region. Furthermore, PVT1 was discovered to interact with ATG14, thus promoting assembly of the autophagy specific complex I (PtdIns3K-C1) and ATG14-dependent class III PtdIns3K activity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These data indicate that PVT1 plays a critical role in the sensitivity of pancreatic cancer to gemcitabine and highlight its potential as a valuable target for pancreatic cancer therapy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LncRNA-HGBC stabilized by HuR promotes gallbladder cancer progression by regulating miR-502-3p/SET/AKT axis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/31752906/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/31752906/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Erratum in:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Correction to: &lt;a href=&#34;https://molecular-cancer.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12943-021-01386-8&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;LncRNA-HGBC stabilized by HuR promotes gallbladder cancer progression by regulating miR-502-3p/SET/AKT axis&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Backgrounds:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Long non-coding RNAs (lncRNAs) are essential factors that regulate tumor development and metastasis via diverse molecular mechanisms in a broad type of cancers. However, the pathological roles of lncRNAs in gallbladder carcinoma (GBC) remain largely unknown. Here we discovered a novel lncRNA termed lncRNA Highly expressed in GBC (lncRNA-HGBC) which was upregulated in GBC tissue and aimed to investigate its role and regulatory mechanism in the development and progression of GBC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The expression level of lncRNA-HGBC in GBC tissue and different cell lines was determined by quantitative real-time PCR. The full length of lncRNA-HGBC was obtained by 5&amp;rsquo; and 3&amp;rsquo; rapid amplification of the cDNA ends (RACE). Cellular localization of lncRNA-HGBC was detected by fluorescence in situ hybridization (FISH) assays and subcellular fractionation assay. In vitro and in vivo assays were preformed to explore the biological effects of lncRNA-HGBC in GBC cells. RNA pull-down assay, mass spectrometry, and RNA immunoprecipitation (RIP) assay were used to identify lncRNA-HGBC-interacting proteins. Dual luciferase reporter assays, AGO2-RIP, and MS2-RIP assays were performed to verify the interaction between lncRNA-HGBC and miR-502-3p.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We found that lncRNA-HGBC was upregulated in GBC and its upregulation could predict poor survival. Overexpression or knockdown of lncRNA-HGBC in GBC cell lines resulted in increased or decreased, respectively, cell proliferation and invasion in vitro and in xenografted tumors. LncRNA-HGBC specifically bound to RNA binding protein Hu Antigen R (HuR) that in turn stabilized lncRNA-HGBC. LncRNA-HGBC functioned as a competitive endogenous RNA to bind to miR-502-3p that inhibits target gene SET. Overexpression, knockdown or mutation of lncRNA-HGBC altered the inhibitory effects of miR-502-3p on SET expression and downstream activation of AKT. Clinically, lncRNA-HGBC expression was negatively correlated with miR-502-3p, but positively correlated with SET and HuR in GBC tissue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our study demonstrates that lncRNA-HGBC promotes GBC metastasis via activation of the miR-502-3p-SET-AKT cascade, pointing to lncRNA-HGBC as a new prognostic predictor and a therapeutic target.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Temporospatial guidance of activity-dependent gene expression by microRNA: mechanisms and functional implications for neural plasticity</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/30535081/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/30535081/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MicroRNA are major regulators of neuronal gene expression at the post-transcriptional and translational levels. This layer of control is critical for spatially and temporally restricted gene expression, facilitating highly dynamic changes to cellular structure and function associated with neural plasticity. Investigation of microRNA function in the neural system, however, is at an early stage, and many aspects of the mechanisms employing these small non-coding RNAs remain unclear. In this article, we critically review current knowledge pertaining to microRNA function in neural activity, with emphasis on mechanisms of microRNA repression, their subcellular remodelling and functional impacts on neural plasticity and behavioural phenotypes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Network of Noncoding Regulatory RNAs Acts in the Mammalian Brain</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/29887379/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/29887379/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Noncoding RNAs (ncRNAs) play increasingly appreciated gene-regulatory roles. Here, we describe a regulatory network centered on four ncRNAs-a long ncRNA, a circular RNA, and two microRNAs-using gene editing in mice to probe the molecular consequences of disrupting key components of this network. The long ncRNA Cyrano uses an extensively paired site to miR-7 to trigger destruction of this microRNA. Cyrano-directed miR-7 degradation is much more effective than previously described examples of target-directed microRNA degradation, which come primarily from studies of artificial and viral RNAs. By reducing miR-7 levels, Cyrano prevents repression of miR-7-targeted mRNAs and enables accumulation of Cdr1as, a circular RNA known to regulate neuronal activity. Without Cyrano, excess miR-7 causes cytoplasmic destruction of Cdr1as in neurons, in part through enhanced slicing of Cdr1as by a second miRNA, miR-671. Thus, several types of ncRNAs can collaborate to establish a sophisticated regulatory network.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Distinct non-coding RNA cargo of extracellular vesicles from M1 and M2 human primary macrophages</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36544271/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jun 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36544271/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Macrophages are important antigen presenting cells which can release extracellular vesicles (EVs) carrying functional cargo including non-coding RNAs. Macrophages can be broadly classified into M1 &amp;lsquo;classical&amp;rsquo; and M2 &amp;lsquo;alternatively-activated&amp;rsquo; macrophages. M1 macrophages have been linked with inflammation-associated pathologies, whereas a switch towards an M2 phenotype indicates resolution of inflammation and tissue regeneration. Here, we provide the first comprehensive analysis of the small RNA cargo of EVs from human M1 and M2 primary macrophages. Using small RNA sequencing, we identified several types of small non-coding RNAs in M1 and M2 macrophage EVs including miRNAs, isomiRs, tRNA fragments, piRNA, snRNA, snoRNA and Y-RNA fragments. Distinct differences were observed between M1 and M2 EVs, with higher relative abundance of miRNAs, and lower abundance of tRNA fragments in M1 compared to M2 EVs. MicroRNA-target enrichment analysis identified several gene targets involved in gene expression and inflammatory signalling pathways. EVs were also enriched in tRNA fragments, primarily originating from the 5&amp;rsquo; end or the internal region of the full length tRNAs, many of which were differentially abundant in M1 and M2 EVs. Similarly, several other small non-coding RNAs, namely snRNAs, snoRNAs and Y-RNA fragments, were differentially enriched in M1 and M2 EVs; we discuss their putative roles in macrophage EVs. In conclusion, we show that M1 and M2 macrophages release EVs with distinct RNA cargo, which has the potential to contribute to the unique effect of these cell subsets on their microenvironment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
