<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>LC-MS | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/lc-ms/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/lc-ms/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>LC-MS</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>LC-MS</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/lc-ms/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interrogation of the mammalian gut-brain axis using LC-MS/MS-based targeted metabolomics with in vitro bacterial and organoid cultures and in vivo gnotobiotic mouse models</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/36352124/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/36352124/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interest in the communication between the gastrointestinal tract and central nervous system, known as the gut-brain axis, has prompted the development of quantitative analytical platforms to analyze microbe- and host-derived signals. This protocol enables investigations into connections between microbial colonization and intestinal and brain neurotransmitters and contains strategies for the comprehensive evaluation of metabolites in in vitro (organoids) and in vivo mouse model systems. Here we present an optimized workflow that includes procedures for preparing these gut-brain axis model systems: (stage 1) growth of microbes in defined media; (stage 2) microinjection of intestinal organoids; and (stage 3) generation of animal models including germ-free (no microbes), specific-pathogen-free (complete gut microbiota) and specific-pathogen-free re-conventionalized (germ-free mice associated with a complete gut microbiota from a specific-pathogen-free mouse), and &lt;em&gt;Bifidobacterium dentium&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Bacteroides ovatus&lt;/em&gt; mono-associated mice (germ-free mice colonized with a single gut microbe). We describe targeted liquid chromatography-tandem mass spectrometry-based metabolomics methods for analyzing microbially derived short-chain fatty acids and neurotransmitters from these samples. Unlike other protocols that commonly examine only stool samples, this protocol includes bacterial cultures, organoid cultures and in vivo samples, in addition to monitoring the metabolite content of stool samples. The incorporation of three experimental models (microbes, organoids and animals) enhances the impact of this protocol. The protocol requires 3 weeks of murine colonization with microbes and ~1-2 weeks for liquid chromatography-tandem mass spectrometry-based instrumental and quantitative analysis, and sample post-processing and normalization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Metabolite annotation from knowns to unknowns through knowledge-guided multi-layer metabolic networking</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36333358/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36333358/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Liquid chromatography - mass spectrometry (LC-MS) based untargeted metabolomics allows to measure both known and unknown metabolites in the metabolome. However, unknown metabolite annotation is a major challenge in untargeted metabolomics. Here, we develop an approach, namely, &lt;a href=&#34;http://metdna.zhulab.cn/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;knowledge-guided multi-layer network (KGMN)&lt;/a&gt;, to enable global metabolite annotation from knowns to unknowns in untargeted metabolomics. The &lt;a href=&#34;http://metdna.zhulab.cn/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;KGMN&lt;/a&gt; approach integrates three-layer networks, including knowledge-based metabolic reaction network, knowledge-guided MS/MS similarity network, and global peak correlation network. To demonstrate the principle, we apply &lt;a href=&#34;http://metdna.zhulab.cn/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;KGMN&lt;/a&gt; in an in vitro enzymatic reaction system and different biological samples, with ~100-300 putative unknowns annotated in each data set. Among them, &amp;gt;80% unknown metabolites are corroborated with in silico MS/MS tools. Finally, we validate 5 metabolites that are absent in common MS/MS libraries through repository mining and synthesis of chemical standards. Together, the &lt;a href=&#34;http://metdna.zhulab.cn/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;KGMN&lt;/a&gt; approach enables efficient unknown annotations, and substantially advances the discovery of recurrent unknown metabolites for common biological samples from model organisms, towards deciphering dark matter in untargeted metabolomics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>massDatabase: utilities for the operation of the public compound and pathway database</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35944213/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35944213/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Summary: One of the major challenges in liquid chromatography coupled to mass spectrometry data is converting many metabolic feature entries to biological function information, such as metabolite annotation and pathway enrichment, which are based on the compound and pathway databases. Multiple online databases have been developed. However, no tool has been developed for operating all these databases for biological analysis. Therefore, we developed &lt;a href=&#34;https://massdatabase.tidymass.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;massDatabase&lt;/a&gt;, an R package that operates the online public databases and combines with other tools for streamlined compound annotation and pathway enrichment. &lt;a href=&#34;https://massdatabase.tidymass.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;massDatabase&lt;/a&gt; is a flexible, simple and powerful tool that can be installed on all platforms, allowing the users to leverage all the online public databases for biological function mining. A detailed tutorial and a case study are provided in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/uploads/35944213_supplementary_data.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Supplementary Material&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TidyMass an object-oriented reproducible analysis framework for LC-MS data</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35902589/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35902589/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reproducibility, traceability, and transparency have been long-standing issues for metabolomics data analysis. Multiple tools have been developed, but limitations still exist. Here, we present the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tidymass.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;tidyMass&lt;/a&gt; project, a comprehensive R-based computational framework that can achieve the traceable, shareable, and reproducible workflow needs of data processing and analysis for LC-MS-based untargeted metabolomics. TidyMass is an ecosystem of R packages that share an underlying design philosophy, grammar, and data structure, which provides a comprehensive, reproducible, and object-oriented computational framework. The modular architecture makes &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tidymass.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;tidyMass&lt;/a&gt; a highly flexible and extensible tool, which other users can improve and integrate with other tools to customize their own pipeline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Itaconate inhibits TET DNA dioxygenases to dampen inflammatory responses</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35256775/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35256775/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As one of the most induced genes in activated macrophages, immune-responsive gene 1 (IRG1) encodes a mitochondrial metabolic enzyme catalysing the production of itaconic acid (ITA). Although ITA has an anti-inflammatory property, the underlying mechanisms are not fully understood. Here we show that ITA is a potent inhibitor of the TET-family DNA dioxygenases. ITA binds to the same site on TET2 as the co-substrate α-ketoglutarate, inhibiting TET2 catalytic activity. Lipopolysaccharide treatment, which induces Irg1 expression and ITA accumulation, inhibits Tet activity in macrophages. Transcriptome analysis reveals that TET2 is a major target of ITA in suppressing lipopolysaccharide-induced genes, including those regulated by the NF-κB and STAT signalling pathways. In vivo, ITA decreases the levels of 5-hydroxymethylcytosine, reduces lipopolysaccharide-induced acute pulmonary oedema as well as lung and liver injury, and protects mice against lethal endotoxaemia, depending on the catalytic activity of Tet2. Our study thus identifies ITA as an immune modulatory metabolite that selectively inhibits TET enzymes to dampen the inflammatory responses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Platelet-Derived Drug Targets and Biomarkers of Ischemic Stroke-The First Dynamic Human LC-MS Proteomic Study</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35268287/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35268287/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Objective:&lt;/em&gt; The aim of this dynamic LC-MS (liquid chromatography and mass spectrometry) human platelet proteomic study was to identify the potential proteins candidates for biomarkers of acute ischemic stroke (AIS), their changes during the acute phase of stroke and to define potential novel drug targets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; A total of 32 patients (18-80 years old) were investigated that presented symptoms of AIS lasting less than 24 h from the onset, confirmed by neurological examination and/or new cerebral ischemia visualized in the CT (computed-tomography) scans. The analysis of platelet proteome was performed using LC-MS at baseline, and then on the third and seventh day from the onset of symptoms. The control group was demographically matched without any clinical signs of acute brain injury.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; The differences between platelets, at 24 h after first symptoms of stroke subjects and the control group included: β-amyloid A4 and amyloid-like protein 2, coactosin-like protein, thymidine phosphorylase 4 (TYMP-4), interferon regulatory factor 7 (IRF7), vitamin K-dependent protein S, histone proteins (H2A type 1 and 1-A, H2A types 2B and J, H2Av, -z, and -x), and platelet basic protein. The dynamic changes in the platelet protein concentration involved thrombospondin-1, thrombospondin-2, filamin A, B, and C.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; This is the first human dynamic LC-MS proteomic study that differentiates platelet proteome in the acute phase of ischemic stroke in time series and compares the results with healthy controls. Identified proteins may be considered as future markers of ischemic stroke or therapeutic drug targets. Thymidine phosphorylase 4 (TYMP-4) holds promise as an interesting drug target in the management or prevention of ischemic stroke.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Newly established LC-MS/MS method for measurement of plasma BH4 as a predictive biomarker for kidney injury in diabetes</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34808334/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34808334/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For the first time LC-MS/MS with our own established protocol was used on human samples.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It was confirmed that BH4 is negatively associated with ACR in diabetic human subjects and both BH4 and CPI 2h are independent risk factors for ACR progression.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;BH4 can be protective for early renal function decline suggesting its deficiency may induce damage on renal function other than ACR progression.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Objective:&lt;/em&gt; The clinical research on BH4 is limited because of the difficulties on its measurement. In this study, we used our own established LC-MS/MS method to examine the plasma BH4 levels in diabetes to determine whether it could be used as a biomarker for the prediction of kidney injury in those patients.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; Hospitalized diabetes patients in Renmin Hospital of Wuhan University from Jan to Aug 2021 were recruited. To assess the association between plasma BH4 with ACR or eGFR in diabetes, a total of 142 patients with type 2 diabetes (T2DM) were enrolled. They were divided into three groups by albuminuria levels: normoalbuminuria (n = 68), microalbuminuria (n = 48), and macroalbuminuria (n = 26) according to ACR; or into two groups by eGFR: eGFR≥90 or eGFR&amp;lt;90 ml/min for correlation and logistic regression analysis. Plasma BH4 level was measured by LC-MS/MS along with other biochemical indices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; Plasma BH4 concentrations were decreased as ACR progressed. BH4 (r = -0.55, P &amp;lt; 0.001) and 2h C-Peptide (CP-2h) (r = -0.248, P = 0.003) levels were negatively correlated with ACR. Moreover, multivariable logistic regression analysis showed BH4 concentrations (B = -0.468, P &amp;lt; 0.001) and CP-2h (B = -0.257, P = 0.028) were independently associated with ACR progression. ROC curve showed that BH4 level has a predictive value on ACR (95%CI 0.686-0.841, sensitivity 69.1%, specificity 73%). Moreover, in diabetes patients with eGFR≥90 ml/min, plasma BH4 level (P = 0.008) is higher than those in diabetes with eGFR&amp;lt;90 ml/min and BH4 was remained independently associated with eGFR after multivariable logistic regression analysis (B = -0.193, P = 0.048).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/em&gt; Our established LC-MS/MS method could be used on human plasma BH4 measurements and our data suggested that BH4 level can be used as a biomarker for kidney injury in diabetes indicated by its association with ACR progression and early renal function decline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A guide to mass spectrometric analysis of extracellular vesicle proteins for biomarker discovery</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/34747512/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/34747512/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Exosomes (small extracellular vesicles) in living organisms play an important role in processes such as cell proliferation or intercellular communication. Recently, exosomes have been extensively investigated for biomarker discoveries for various diseases. An important aspect of exosome analysis involves the development of enrichment methods that have been introduced for successful isolation of exosomes. These methods include ultracentrifugation, size exclusion chromatography, polyethylene glycol-based precipitation, immunoaffinity-based enrichment, ultrafiltration, and asymmetric flow field-flow fractionation among others. To confirm the presence of exosomes, various characterization methods have been utilized such as Western blot analysis, atomic force microscopy, electron microscopy, optical methods, zeta potential, visual inspection, and mass spectrometry. Recent advances in high-resolution separations, high-performance mass spectrometry and comprehensive proteome databases have all contributed to the successful analysis of exosomes from patient samples. Herein we review various exosome enrichment methods, characterization methods, and recent trends of exosome investigations using mass spectrometry-based approaches for biomarker discovery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SLAW: A Scalable and Self-Optimizing Processing Workflow for Untargeted LC-MS</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34735114/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34735114/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Metabolomics has been shown to be promising for diverse applications in basic, applied, and clinical research. These applications often require large-scale data, and while the technology to perform such experiments exists, downstream analysis remains challenging. Different tools exist in a variety of ecosystems, but they often do not scale to large data and are not integrated into a single coherent workflow. Moreover, the outcome of processing is very sensitive to a multitude of algorithmic parameters. Hence, parameter optimization is not only critical but also challenging. We present &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/zamboni-lab/SLAW&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;SLAW&lt;/a&gt;, a scalable and yet easy-to-use workflow for processing untargeted LC-MS data in metabolomics and lipidomics. The capabilities of &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/zamboni-lab/SLAW&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;SLAW&lt;/a&gt; include (1) state-of-the-art peak-picking algorithms, (2) a new automated parameter optimization routine, (3) an efficient sample alignment procedure, (4) gap filling by data recursion, and (5) the extraction of consolidated MS&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; and an isotopic pattern across all samples. Importantly, both the workflow and the parameter optimization were designed for robust analysis of untargeted studies with thousands of individual LC-MS&lt;sup&gt;n&lt;/sup&gt; runs. We compared &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/zamboni-lab/SLAW&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;SLAW&lt;/a&gt; to two state-of-the-art workflows based on openMS and XCMS. &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/zamboni-lab/SLAW&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;SLAW&lt;/a&gt; was able to detect and align more reproducible features in all data sets considered. &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/zamboni-lab/SLAW&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;SLAW&lt;/a&gt; scaled well, and its analysis of a data set with 2500 LC-MS files consumed 40% less memory and was 6 times faster than that using the XCMS-based workflow. &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/zamboni-lab/SLAW&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;SLAW&lt;/a&gt; also extracted 2-fold more isotopic patterns and MS&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; spectra, which in 60% of the cases led to positive matches against a spectral library.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enriching extracellular vesicles for mass spectrometry</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/34632607/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/34632607/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Extracellular vesicles from plasma, other body fluids and cell culture media hold great promise in the search for biomarkers. Exosomes in particular, the vesicle type that is secreted after being produced in the endocytic pathway and having a diameter of 30-150 nm, are considered to be a conveyance for signaling molecules and, therefore, to hold valuable information regarding the health and activity status of the cells from which they are released. The vesicular nature of exosomes is central to all methods used to separate them from the highly abundant proteins in plasma and other fluids. The enrichment of the vesicles is essential for mass spectrometry-based analysis as they represent only a very small component of all plasma proteins. The progression of isolation techniques for exosomes from ultracentrifugation through chromatographic separation using hydrophobic packing materials shows that effective enrichment is possible and that high throughput approaches to exosome enrichment are achievable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Metabolic reaction network-based recursive metabolite annotation for untargeted metabolomics</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/30944337/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/30944337/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Large-scale metabolite annotation is a challenge in liquid chromatogram-mass spectrometry (LC-MS)-based untargeted metabolomics. Here, we develop a metabolic reaction network (MRN)-based recursive algorithm (MetDNA) that expands metabolite annotations without the need for a comprehensive standard spectral library. MetDNA is based on the rationale that seed metabolites and their reaction-paired neighbors tend to share structural similarities resulting in similar MS2 spectra. MetDNA characterizes initial seed metabolites using a small library of MS2 spectra, and utilizes their experimental MS2 spectra as surrogate spectra to annotate their reaction-paired neighbor metabolites, which subsequently serve as the basis for recursive analysis. Using different LC-MS platforms, data acquisition methods, and biological samples, we showcase the utility and versatility of MetDNA and demonstrate that about 2000 metabolites can cumulatively be annotated from one experiment. Our results demonstrate that MetDNA substantially expands metabolite annotation, enabling quantitative assessment of metabolic pathways and facilitating integrative multi-omics analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
