<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Phase Separation | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/phase-separation/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/phase-separation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Phase Separation</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Phase Separation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/phase-separation/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spermine enhances antiviral and anticancer responses by stabilizing DNA binding with the DNA sensor cGAS</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36724787/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36724787/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Self-nonself discrimination is vital for the immune system to mount responses against pathogens while maintaining tolerance toward the host and innocuous commensals during homeostasis. Here, we investigated how indiscriminate DNA sensors, such as cyclic GMP-AMP synthase (cGAS), make this self-nonself distinction. Screening of a small-molecule library revealed that spermine, a well-known DNA condenser associated with viral DNA, markedly elevates cGAS activation. Mechanistically, spermine condenses DNA to enhance and stabilize cGAS-DNA binding, optimizing cGAS and downstream antiviral signaling. Spermine promotes condensation of viral, but not host nucleosome, DNA. Deletion of viral DNA-associated spermine, by propagating virus in spermine-deficient cells, reduced cGAS activation. Spermine depletion subsequently attenuated cGAS-mediated antiviral and anticancer immunity. Collectively, our results reveal a pathogenic DNA-associated molecular pattern that facilitates nonself recognition, linking metabolism and pathogen recognition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rabphilin-3A undergoes phase separation to regulate GluN2A mobility and surface clustering</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36693856/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36693856/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;N-methyl-D-aspartate receptors (NMDARs) are essential for excitatory neurotransmission and synaptic plasticity. GluN2A and GluN2B, two predominant Glu2N subunits of NMDARs in the hippocampus and the cortex, display distinct clustered distribution patterns and mobility at synaptic and extrasynaptic sites. However, how GluN2A clusters are specifically organized and stabilized remains poorly understood. Here, we found that the previously reported GluN2A-specific binding partner Rabphilin-3A (Rph3A) has the ability to undergo phase separation, which relies on arginine residues in its N-terminal domain. Rph3A phase separation promotes GluN2A clustering by binding GluN2A&amp;rsquo;s C-terminal domain. A complex formed by Rph3A, GluN2A, and the scaffolding protein PSD95 promoted Rph3A phase separation. Disrupting Rph3A&amp;rsquo;s phase separation suppressed the synaptic and extrasynaptic surface clustering, synaptic localization, stability, and synaptic response of GluN2A in hippocampal neurons. Together, our results reveal the critical role of Rph3A phase separation in determining the organization and stability of GluN2A in the neuronal surface.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Niche stiffness sustains cancer stemness via TAZ and NANOG phase separation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36646707/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36646707/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Emerging evidence shows that the biomechanical environment is required to support cancer stem cells (CSCs), which play a crucial role in drug resistance. However, how mechanotransduction signals regulate CSCs and its clinical significance has remained unclear. Using clinical-practice ultrasound elastography for patients&amp;rsquo; lesions and atomic force microscopy for surgical samples, we reveal that increased matrix stiffness is associated with poor responses to neoadjuvant chemotherapy, worse prognosis, and CSC enrichment in patients with breast cancer. Mechanically, TAZ activated by biomechanics enhances CSC properties via phase separation with NANOG. TAZ-NANOG phase separation, which is dependent on acidic residues in the N-terminal activation domain of NANOG, promotes the transcription of SOX2 and OCT4. Therapeutically, targeting NANOG or TAZ reduces CSCs and enhances the chemosensitivity in vivo. Collectively, this study demonstrated that the phase separation of a pluripotency transcription factor links mechanical cues in the niche to the fate of CSCs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A brief guideline for studies of phase-separated biomolecular condensates</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/36400991/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/36400991/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cells are exquisitely compartmentalized to achieve precise spatiotemporal regulation of myriad processes and pathways. Phase separation offers one way to achieve territorial organization in the cellular context, via the creation of membrane-less organelles (MLOs). MLOs formed through phase separation are associated with numerous critical biological functions. Although hundreds of publications on related topics are produced each year, robust criteria for the determination of biologically meaningful phase separation are yet to be well established. Here we present some principles and propose a few guidelines for phase-separation studies in biology. Specifically, we provide an in-depth experiment pipeline for phase-separation studies, including mechanisms of the molecular driving forces, ways to correlate in vivo and in vitro observations, and strategies to relate the phase-separation phenomenon to biological functions. We also intend to contribute to streamlining the aforementioned diagnostic criteria by further stressing a few common caveats in the field.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Regulation of cGAS activity by RNA-modulated phase separation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36382803/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36382803/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cyclic GMP-AMP synthase (cGAS) is a double-stranded DNA (dsDNA) sensor that functions in the innate immune system. Upon binding dsDNA, cGAS and dsDNA form phase-separated condensates in which cGAS catalyzes the synthesis of 2&#39;3&amp;rsquo;-cyclic GMP-AMP that subsequently triggers a STING-dependent, type I interferon (IFN-I) response. Here, we show that cytoplasmic RNAs regulate cGAS activity. We discover that RNAs do not activate cGAS but rather promote phase separation of cGAS in vitro. In cells, cGAS colocalizes with RNA and forms complexes with RNA. In the presence of cytoplasmic dsDNA, RNAs colocalize with phase-separated condensates of cGAS and dsDNA. Further in vitro assays showed that RNAs promote the formation of cGAS-containing phase separations and enhance cGAS activity when the dsDNA concentration is low. Cotransfection of RNA with a small amount of dsDNA into THP1 cells significantly enhances the production of the downstream signaling molecule interferon beta (IFNB). This enhancement can be blocked by a cGAS-specific inhibitor. Thus, cytoplasmic RNAs could regulate cGAS activity by modulating the formation of cGAS-containing condensates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WNK kinases sense molecular crowding and rescue cell volume via phase separation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36318922/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36318922/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Endogenous WNK1 forms hyperosmotic stress-induced condensates&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The intrinsically disordered C-terminal domain mediates WNK1 phase separation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Phase behavior of the WNK1 CTD is evolutionarily conserved despite sequence divergence&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WNK1 is a molecular crowding sensor and mediator of regulatory volume increase&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When challenged by hypertonicity, dehydrated cells must recover their volume to survive. This process requires the phosphorylation-dependent regulation of SLC12 cation chloride transporters by WNK kinases, but how these kinases are activated by cell shrinkage remains unknown. Within seconds of cell exposure to hypertonicity, WNK1 concentrates into membraneless condensates, initiating a phosphorylation-dependent signal that drives net ion influx via the SLC12 cotransporters to restore cell volume. WNK1 condensate formation is driven by its intrinsically disordered C terminus, whose evolutionarily conserved signatures are necessary for efficient phase separation and volume recovery. This disorder-encoded phase behavior occurs within physiological constraints and is activated in vivo by molecular crowding rather than changes in cell size. This allows kinase activity despite an inhibitory ionic milieu and permits cell volume recovery through condensate-mediated signal amplification. Thus, WNK kinases are physiological crowding sensors that phase separate to coordinate a cell volume rescue response.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>USP15 promotes cGAS activation through deubiquitylation and liquid condensation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36243958/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36243958/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Double-stranded DNA (dsDNA) is recognized as a danger signal by cyclic GMP-AMP synthase (cGAS), which triggers innate immune responses. cGAS activity must be properly regulated to maintain immune homeostasis. However, the mechanism by which cGAS activation is controlled remains to be better understood. In this study, we identified USP15 as a cGAS-interacting partner. USP15 promoted DNA-induced cGAS activation and downstream innate immune responses through a positive feedback mechanism. Specifically, USP15 deubiquitylated cGAS and promoted its activation. In the absence of DNA, USP15 drove cGAS dimerization and liquid condensation through the USP15 intrinsic disordered region (IDR), which prepared cGAS for a rapid response to DNA. Upon DNA stimulation, USP15 was induced to express and boost cGAS activation, functioning as an efficient amplifier in innate immune signal transduction. In summary, the positive role played by USP15-mediated cGAS activation may be a novel regulatory mechanism in the fine-tuning of innate immunity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spatiotemporal regulation of insulin signaling by liquid-liquid phase separation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35790738/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35790738/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Insulin signals through its receptor to recruit insulin receptor substrates (IRS) and phosphatidylinositol 3-kinase (PI3K) to the plasma membrane for production of phosphatidylinositol-3,4,5-trisphosphate (PIP3) from phosphatidylinositol-4,5-bisphosphate [PI(4,5)P2], which consequently activates protein kinase B (PKB). How insulin signals transduce from the plasma membrane into the cytoplasm is not clearly understood. Here we show that liquid-liquid phase separation (LLPS) plays a critical role in spatiotemporal control of insulin signaling through regulating multiple components including IRS1. Both protein concentration and insulin stimulation can drive the formation of intracellular IRS1 condensates through LLPS. Components including PI(4,5)P2, p85-PI3K and PDK1 are constitutively present in IRS1 condensates whereas production of PIP3 and recruitment of PKB in them are induced by insulin. Thus, IRS1 condensates function as intracellular signal hubs to mediate insulin signaling, whose formation is impaired in insulin resistant cells. Collectively, these data reveal an important function of LLPS in spatiotemporal control of insulin signaling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Super enhancers as master gene regulators in the pathogenesis of hematologic malignancies</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/35150791/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/35150791/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Transcriptional deregulation of multiple oncogenes, tumor suppressors and survival pathways is a cancer cell hallmark. Super enhancers (SE) are long stretches of active enhancers in close linear proximity that ensure extraordinarily high expression levels of key genes associated with cell lineage, function and survival. SE landscape is intrinsically prone to changes and reorganization during the course of normal cell differentiation. This functional plasticity is typically utilized by cancer cells, which remodel their SE landscapes to ensure oncogenic transcriptional reprogramming. Multiple recent studies highlighted structural genetic mechanisms in non-coding regions that create new SE or hijack already existing ones. In addition, alterations in abundance/activity of certain SE-associated proteins or certain viral infections can elicit new super enhancers and trigger SE-driven transcriptional changes. For these reasons, SE profiling emerged as a powerful tool for discovering the core transcriptional regulatory circuits in tumor cells. This, in turn, provides new insights into cancer cell biology, and identifies main nodes of key cellular pathways to be potentially targeted. Since SEs are susceptible to inhibition, their disruption results in exponentially amassing &amp;lsquo;butterfly&amp;rsquo; effect on gene expression and cell function. Moreover, many of SE elements are druggable, opening new therapeutic opportunities. Indeed, SE targeting drugs have been studied preclinically in various hematologic malignancies with promising effects. Herein, we review the unique features of SEs, present different cis- and trans-acting mechanisms through which hematologic tumor cells acquire SEs, and finally, discuss the potential of SE targeting in the therapy of hematologic malignancies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>circVAMP3 Drives CAPRIN1 Phase Separation and Inhibits Hepatocellular Carcinoma by Suppressing c-Myc Translation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35072355/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35072355/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Previous studies have identified the regulatory roles of circular RNAs (circRNAs) in human cancers. However, the molecular mechanisms of circRNAs in hepatocellular carcinoma (HCC) remain largely unknown. This study screens the expression profile of circRNAs in HCC and identifies circVAMP3 as a significantly downregulated circRNA in HCC tissues. HCC patients with low circVAMP3 expression present poor prognosis. circVAMP3 negatively regulates the proliferation and metastasis of HCC cells in vitro and in vivo by driving phase separation of CAPRIN1 and promoting stress granule formation in cells, which can downregulate the protein level of Myc proto-oncogene protein by inhibiting c-Myc translation. Furthermore, circVAMP3 is widely expressed in many human tissues and is downregulated in related cancers. Therefore, circVAMP3 is a potential prognostic indicator for HCC and may serve as a therapeutic target for HCC treatment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Phase separation drives RNA virus-induced activation of the NLRP6 inflammasome</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34678144/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34678144/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;dsRNA induces liquid-liquid phase separation (LLPS) of NLRP6 &lt;em&gt;in vitro&lt;/em&gt; and in cells&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ASC solidifies LLPS of NLRP6 and RNA to promote inflammasome activation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Poly-Lysine region in NLRP6 is critical for multivalent interaction and LLPS&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Phase separation of NLRP6 promotes inflammasome activation in intestine and liver&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NLRP6 is important in host defense by inducing functional outcomes including inflammasome activation and interferon production. Here, we show that NLRP6 undergoes liquid-liquid phase separation (LLPS) upon interaction with double-stranded RNA (dsRNA) &lt;em&gt;in vitro&lt;/em&gt; and in cells, and an intrinsically disordered poly-lysine sequence (K350-354) of NLRP6 is important for multivalent interactions, phase separation, and inflammasome activation. &lt;em&gt;Nlrp6&lt;/em&gt;-deficient or &lt;em&gt;Nlrp6&lt;sup&gt;K350-354A&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; mutant mice show reduced inflammasome activation upon mouse hepatitis virus or rotavirus infection, and in steady state stimulated by intestinal microbiota, implicating NLRP6 LLPS in anti-microbial immunity. Recruitment of ASC via helical assembly solidifies NLRP6 condensates, and ASC further recruits and activates caspase-1. Lipoteichoic acid, a known NLRP6 ligand, also promotes NLRP6 LLPS, and DHX15, a helicase in NLRP6-induced interferon signaling, co-forms condensates with NLRP6 and dsRNA. Thus, LLPS of NLRP6 is a common response to ligand stimulation, which serves to direct NLRP6 to distinct functional outcomes depending on the cellular context.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Viral tegument proteins restrict cGAS-DNA phase separation to mediate immune evasion</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34015248/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34015248/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DNA-induced liquid-liquid phase separation of cyclic GMP-AMP synthase (cGAS) triggers a potent response to detect pathogen infection and promote innate immune signaling. Whether and how pathogens manipulate cGAS-DNA condensation to mediate immune evasion is unknown. We report the identification of a structurally related viral tegument protein family, represented by ORF52 and VP22 from gamma- and alpha-herpesvirinae, respectively, that employs a conserved mechanism to restrict cGAS-DNA phase separation. ORF52/VP22 proteins accumulate into, and effectively disrupt, the pre-formed cGAS-DNA condensation both in vitro and in cells. The inhibition process is dependent on DNA-induced liquid-liquid phase separation of the viral protein rather than a direct interaction with cGAS. Moreover, highly abundant ORF52 proteins carried within viral particles are able to target cGAS-DNA phase separation in early infection stage. Our results define ORF52/VP22-type tegument proteins as a family of inhibitors targeting cGAS-DNA phase separation and demonstrate a mechanism for how viruses overcome innate immunity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
