<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Epstein-Barr virus | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/epstein-barr-virus/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/epstein-barr-virus/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Epstein-Barr virus</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Epstein-Barr virus</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/epstein-barr-virus/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Facts and Hopes in the Relationship of EBV with Cancer Immunity and Immunotherapy</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/35686929/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/35686929/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Epstein-Barr virus (EBV), the first identified human tumor virus, infects and takes up residency in almost every human. However, EBV genome-positive tumors arise in only a tiny minority of infected people, presumably when the virus-carrying tumor cells are able to evade immune surveillance. Traditional views regard viral antigens as the principal targets of host immune surveillance against virus-infected cells. However, recent findings indicate that EBV-infected/-transformed B cells elicit both cytotoxic CD8&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; and CD4&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T-cell responses against a wide range of overexpressed cellular antigens known to function as tumor-associated antigens (TAA), in addition to various EBV-encoded antigens. This not only broadens the ways by which the immune system controls EBV infection and prevents it from causing cancers, but also potentially extends immune protection toward EBV-unrelated cancers by targeting shared TAAs. The goal of this review is to incorporate these new findings with literature data and discuss future directions for improved understanding of EBV-induced antitumor immunity, as well as the hopes for rational immune strategies for cancer prevention and therapy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
