<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cross-talk | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/cross-talk/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/cross-talk/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Cross-talk</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Cross-talk</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/cross-talk/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ras drives malignancy through stem cell crosstalk with the microenvironment</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36450983/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36450983/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Squamous cell carcinomas are triggered by marked elevation of RAS-MAPK signalling and progression from benign papilloma to invasive malignancy. At tumour-stromal interfaces, a subset of tumour-initiating progenitors, the cancer stem cells, obtain increased resistance to chemotherapy and immunotherapy along this pathway. The distribution and changes in cancer stem cells during progression from a benign state to invasive squamous cell carcinoma remain unclear. Here we show in mice that, after oncogenic RAS activation, cancer stem cells rewire their gene expression program and trigger self-propelling, aberrant signalling crosstalk with their tissue microenvironment that drives their malignant progression. The non-genetic, dynamic cascade of intercellular exchanges involves downstream pathways that are often mutated in advanced metastatic squamous cell carcinomas with high mutational burden. Coupling our clonal skin HRAS&lt;sup&gt;G12V&lt;/sup&gt; mouse model with single-cell transcriptomics, chromatin landscaping, lentiviral reporters and lineage tracing, we show that aberrant crosstalk between cancer stem cells and their microenvironment triggers angiogenesis and TGFβ signalling, creating conditions that are conducive for hijacking leptin and leptin receptor signalling, which in turn launches downstream phosphoinositide 3-kinase (PI3K)-AKT-mTOR signalling during the benign-to-malignant transition. By functionally examining each step in this pathway, we reveal how dynamic temporal crosstalk with the microenvironment orchestrated by the stem cells profoundly fuels this path to malignancy. These insights suggest broad implications for cancer therapeutics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Organ Crosstalk in Acute Kidney Injury: Evidence and Mechanisms</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/36431113/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/36431113/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acute kidney injury (AKI) is becoming a public health problem worldwide. AKI is usually considered a complication of lung, heart, liver, gut, and brain disease, but recent findings have supported that injured kidney can also cause dysfunction of other organs, suggesting organ crosstalk existence in AKI. However, the organ crosstalk in AKI and the underlying mechanisms have not been broadly reviewed or fully investigated. In this review, we summarize recent clinical and laboratory findings of organ crosstalk in AKI and highlight the related molecular mechanisms. Moreover, their crosstalk involves inflammatory and immune responses, hemodynamic change, fluid homeostasis, hormone secretion, nerve reflex regulation, uremic toxin, and oxidative stress. Our review provides important clues for the intervention for AKI and investigates important therapeutic potential from a new perspective.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The microbiota and the gut-liver axis in primary sclerosing cholangitis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/36352157/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/36352157/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Primary sclerosing cholangitis (PSC) offers unique opportunities to explore the gut-liver axis owing to the close association between liver disease and colonic inflammation. It is well established that the gut microbiota in people with PSC differs from that of healthy individuals, but details of the microbial factors that demarcate PSC from inflammatory bowel disease (IBD) without PSC are poorly understood. In this Review, we aim to provide an overview of the latest literature on the gut microbiome in PSC and PSC with IBD, critically examining hypotheses on how microorganisms could contribute to the pathogenesis of PSC. A particular emphasis will be put on pathogenic features of the gut microbiota that might explain the occurrence of bile duct inflammation and liver disease in the context of IBD, and we postulate the potential existence of a specific yet unknown factor related to the gut-liver axis as causative in PSC. Available data are scrutinized in the perspective of therapeutic approaches related to the gut-liver axis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Liver-heart cross-talk mediated by coagulation factor XI protects against heart failure</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36137043/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36137043/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tissue-tissue communication by endocrine factors is a vital mechanism for physiologic homeostasis. A systems genetics analysis of transcriptomic and functional data from a cohort of diverse, inbred strains of mice predicted that coagulation factor XI (FXI), a liver-derived protein, protects against diastolic dysfunction, a key trait of heart failure with preserved ejection fraction. This was confirmed using gain- and loss-of-function studies, and FXI was found to activate the bone morphogenetic protein (BMP)-SMAD1/5 pathway in the heart. The proteolytic activity of FXI is required for the cleavage and activation of extracellular matrix-associated BMP7 in the heart, thus inhibiting genes involved in inflammation and fibrosis. Our results reveal a protective role of FXI in heart injury that is distinct from its role in coagulation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Diacerein attenuate LPS-induced acute lung injury via inhibiting ER stress and apoptosis: Impact on the crosstalk between SphK1/S1P, TLR4/NFκB/STAT3, and NLRP3/IL-1β signaling pathways</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36055546/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36055546/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Aims:&lt;/em&gt; Acute lung injury (ALI) is a life-threatening clinical problem with high mortality rate and limited treatments or preventive options that represents a major challenge for clinicians. Diacerein (DIA) is a multi-target anthraquinone derivative with potent anti-inflammatory action. The aim of this study is to assess the protective effect of DIA and its potential molecular targets against lipopolysaccharide (LPS)-induced ALI in rats.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Materials and methods:&lt;/em&gt; Adult male Sprague-Dawley rats were orally administrated DIA (50 mg/kg) for 5 consecutive days followed by a single intraperitoneal injection of LPS (5mg/kg).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Key findings:&lt;/em&gt; DIA mitigated oxidative lung injury in LPS-challenged rats via significantly decreasing lung wet/dry (W/D) ratio, inflammatory cells infiltration, and lipid peroxidation, with concomitant elevation in enzymatic and non-enzymatic antioxidant levels in lung tissue. Likewise, DIA alleviated endoplasmic reticulum stress and markedly halted inflammation triggered by LPS challenge in pulmonary tissue by suppressing NLRP3/IL-1β and TLR4/NF-κB signaling with parallel decrease in proinflammatory cytokine levels. Interestingly, DIA down regulated Sphk1/S1P axis, reduced GSK-3β and STAT3 proteins expression, and markedly decreased caspase-3 besides increasing Bcl-2 levels in lung tissue of LPS-challenged animals. These biochemical findings was simultaneously associated with marked improvement in histological alterations of lung tissue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Significance:&lt;/em&gt; These findings verify the protective effect of DIA against LPS-induced ALI through targeting oxidative stress, endoplasmic reticulum stress, and apoptosis. Importantly, DIA halted the hyperinflammatory state triggered by LPS via multi-faceted inhibitory effect on different signaling pathways, hence DIA could potentially reduce mortality in patients with ALI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Antibiotic-induced microbiome depletion improves LPS-induced acute lung injury via gut-lung axis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35981631/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35981631/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Aims:&lt;/em&gt; Acute lung injury (ALI) is an acute inflammatory disorder. However, the precise mechanisms underlying the pathology of ALI remain elusive. An increasing evidence suggests the role of the gut-microbiota axis in the pathology of lung injury. This study aimed to investigate whether antibiotic-induced microbiome depletion could affect ALI in mice after lipopolysaccharide (LPS) administration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Main methods:&lt;/em&gt; The effects of antibiotic cocktail (ABX) on ALI in the mice after intratracheally administration of LPS (5 mg/kg) were examined. Furthermore, 16s rRNA analysis and measurement of short-chain fatty acids in feces samples and metabolomics analysis of blood samples were performed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Key findings:&lt;/em&gt; LPS significantly increased the interleukin-6 (IL-6) levels in the bronchoalveolar lavage fluid (BALF) of water-treated mice. Interestingly, an ABX significantly attenuated the LPS-induced increase in IL-6 in BALF and lung injury scores. Furthermore, ABX and/or LPS treatment markedly altered the α- and β-diversity of the gut microbiota. There were significant differences in the α- and β-diversity of the water + LPS group and ABX + LPS group. LEfSe analysis identified &lt;em&gt;Enterococusfaecalis&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Clostriumtertium&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Bacteroidescaecimyris&lt;/em&gt; as potential microbial markers for ABX + LPS group. Untargeted metabolomics analysis identified several plasma metabolites responsible for discriminating water + LPS group from ABX + LPS group. There were correlations between the relative abundance of the microbiome and plasma metabolites. Integrative network analysis showed correlations between IL-6 levels in BALF and several gut microbes (or plasma metabolites).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Significance:&lt;/em&gt; These data suggest that ABX-induced microbiome depletion could protect against LPS-induced ALI via the gut-microbiota-lung axis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wildfires and extracellular vesicles: Exosomal MicroRNAs as mediators of cross-tissue cardiopulmonary responses to biomass smoke</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35863239/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35863239/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Multiple wildfire-relevant exposure conditions were tested in mice.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Extracellular vesicles (EVs) were evaluated in circulating plasma.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Exposures altered EV-encapsulated microRNAs involved in cell stress and hypoxia.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Exposures disrupted cell stress and hypoxia pathways in lung and heart tissues.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enhanced responses occurred from flaming vs. smoldering burn conditions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Introduction:&lt;/em&gt; Wildfires are a threat to public health world-wide that are growing in intensity and prevalence. The biological mechanisms that elicit wildfire-associated toxicity remain largely unknown. The potential involvement of cross-tissue communication via extracellular vesicles (EVs) is a new mechanism that has yet to be evaluated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; Female CD-1 mice were exposed to smoke condensate samples collected from the following biomass burn scenarios: flaming peat; smoldering peat; flaming red oak; and smoldering red oak, representing lab-based simulations of wildfire scenarios. Lung tissue, bronchoalveolar lavage fluid (BALF) samples, peripheral blood, and heart tissues were collected 4 and 24 h post-exposure. Exosome-enriched EVs were isolated from plasma, physically characterized, and profiled for microRNA (miRNA) expression. Pathway-level responses in the lung and heart were evaluated through RNA sequencing and pathway analyses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; Markers of cardiopulmonary tissue injury and inflammation from BALF samples were significantly altered in response to exposures, with the greatest changes occurring from flaming biomass conditions. Plasma EV miRNAs relevant to cardiovascular disease showed exposure-induced expression alterations, including miR-150, miR-183, miR-223-3p, miR-30b, and miR-378a. Lung and heart mRNAs were identified with differential expression enriched for hypoxia and cell stress-related pathways. Flaming red oak exposure induced the greatest transcriptional response in the heart, a large portion of which were predicted as regulated by plasma EV miRNAs, including miRNAs known to regulate hypoxia-induced cardiovascular injury. Many of these miRNAs had published evidence supporting their transfer across tissues. A follow-up analysis of miR-30b showed that it was increased in expression in the heart of exposed mice in the absence of changes to its precursor molecular, pri-miR-30b, suggesting potential transfer from external sources (e.g., plasma).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Discussion:&lt;/em&gt; This study posits a potential mechanism through which wildfire exposures induce cardiopulmonary responses, highlighting the role of circulating plasma EVs in intercellular and systems-level communication between tissues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IL-17A aggravates asthma-induced intestinal immune injury by promoting neutrophil trafficking</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35815539/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35815539/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the concept of the gut-lung axis reinforced in recent years, emerging evidence has shown that intestinal homeostasis is vital for lung health. Nevertheless, the impacts of lung homeostasis on intestinal tracts and their mechanism are rarely studied. Our results showed that papain-induced asthmatic mice exhibited apparent colonic injuries compared with controls, including increased intestinal permeability, neutrophil and Th17 infiltration in the colonic lamina propria. Moreover, the intranasal administration of papain aggravated such colonic injuries in mice with dextran sulfate sodium-induced colitis, as evidenced by increased occult blood scores, shortened colon length, and accumulated neutrophils. The level of IL-17A was also higher in the serum of asthmatic mice than wild-type mice. Interestingly, the pathologic scores, the proportion of Th17 cells, and neutrophil infiltration in the colon were markedly reduced after IL-17A blocking. Similarly, longer length, lower pathologic scores, and fewer neutrophils were also observed in the colon of IL-17-deficient asthmatic mice. More importantly, we demonstrated that severe gastrointestinal symptoms could accompany clinical asthmatics. The frequencies of Th17 cells and the mRNA expression of IL-17A in the peripheral blood of these patients were significantly enhanced. Besides, the gastrointestinal symptom rating scale scores positively correlated with the frequencies of Th17 in asthmatics. These findings enlighten that IL-17A aggravates asthma-induced intestinal immune injury by promoting neutrophil trafficking, which facilitates the exploration of new potential biomarkers to treat asthma.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crosstalk between autophagy inhibitors and endosome-related secretory pathways: a challenge for autophagy-based treatment of solid cancers</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/34706732/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/34706732/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Autophagy is best known for its role in organelle and protein turnover, cell quality control, and metabolism. The autophagic machinery has, however, also adapted to enable protein trafficking and unconventional secretory pathways so that organelles (such as autophagosomes and multivesicular bodies) delivering cargo to lysosomes for degradation can change their mission from fusion with lysosomes to fusion with the plasma membrane, followed by secretion of the cargo from the cell. Some factors with key signalling functions do not enter the conventional secretory pathway but can be secreted in an autophagy-mediated manner.Positive clinical results of some autophagy inhibitors are encouraging. Nevertheless, it is becoming clear that autophagy inhibition, even within the same cancer type, can affect cancer progression differently. Even next-generation inhibitors of autophagy can have significant non-specific effects, such as impacts on endosome-related secretory pathways and secretion of extracellular vesicles (EVs). Many studies suggest that cancer cells release higher amounts of EVs compared to non-malignant cells, which makes the effect of autophagy inhibitors on EVs secretion highly important and attractive for anticancer therapy. In this review article, we discuss how different inhibitors of autophagy may influence the secretion of EVs and summarize the non-specific effects of autophagy inhibitors with a focus on endosome-related secretory pathways. Modulation of autophagy significantly impacts not only the quantity of EVs but also their content, which can have a deep impact on the resulting pro-tumourigenic or anticancer effect of autophagy inhibitors used in the antineoplastic treatment of solid cancers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Circadian regulation of cancer cell and tumor microenvironment crosstalk</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/34272133/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/34272133/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Circadian rhythms regulate a remarkable variety of physiologic functions in living organisms. Circadian disruption is associated with tumorigenesis and tumor progression through effects on cancer cell biological properties, including proliferation, DNA repair, apoptosis, metabolism, and stemness. Emerging evidence indicates that circadian clocks also play an influential role in the tumor microenvironment (TME). This review outlines recent discoveries on how cancer cell clock components (including circadian clock and clock genes/proteins) regulate TME biology and, reciprocally, how TME clock components affect tumor growth, metastasis, and therapeutic response. An improved understanding of how clock components regulate the symbiosis between cancer cells and the TME will inform the development of novel clock-oriented therapeutic strategies, including immunotherapy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
