<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Parthanatos | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/parthanatos/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/parthanatos/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Parthanatos</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Parthanatos</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/parthanatos/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>ROS-triggered endothelial cell death mechanisms: Focus on pyroptosis, parthanatos, and ferroptosis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/36389728/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/36389728/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The endothelium is a single layer of epithelium covering the surface of the vascular system, and it represents a physical barrier between the blood and vessel wall that plays an important role in maintaining intravascular homeostasis. However, endothelial dysfunction or endothelial cell death can cause vascular barrier disruption, vasoconstriction and diastolic dysfunction, vascular smooth muscle cell proliferation and migration, inflammatory responses, and thrombosis, which are closely associated with the progression of several diseases, such as atherosclerosis, hypertension, coronary atherosclerotic heart disease, ischemic stroke, acute lung injury, acute kidney injury, diabetic retinopathy, and Alzheimer&amp;rsquo;s disease. Oxidative stress caused by the overproduction of reactive oxygen species (ROS) is an important mechanism underlying endothelial cell death. Growing evidence suggests that ROS can trigger endothelial cell death in various ways, including pyroptosis, parthanatos, and ferroptosis. Therefore, this review will systematically illustrate the source of ROS in endothelial cells (ECs); reveal the molecular mechanism by which ROS trigger pyroptosis, parthanatos, and ferroptosis in ECs; and provide new ideas for the research and treatment of endothelial dysfunction-related diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>KDM6B promotes PARthanatos via suppression of O6-methylguanine DNA methyltransferase repair and sustained checkpoint response</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35648484/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35648484/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Poly(ADP-ribose) polymerase-1 (PARP-1) is a DNA damage sensor and contributes to both DNA repair and cell death processes. However, how PARP-1 signaling is regulated to switch its function from DNA repair to cell death remains largely unknown. Here, we found that PARP-1 plays a central role in alkylating agent-induced PARthanatic cancer cell death. Lysine demethylase 6B (KDM6B) was identified as a key regulator of PARthanatos. Loss of KDM6B protein or its demethylase activity conferred cancer cell resistance to PARthanatic cell death in response to alkylating agents. Mechanistically, KDM6B knockout suppressed methylation at the promoter of O&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;-methylguanine-DNA methyltransferase (MGMT) to enhance MGMT expression and its direct DNA repair function, thereby inhibiting DNA damage-evoked PARP-1 hyperactivation and subsequent cell death. Moreover, KDM6B knockout triggered sustained Chk1 phosphorylation and activated a second XRCC1-dependent repair machinery to fix DNA damage evading from MGMT repair. Inhibition of MGMT or checkpoint response re-sensitized KDM6B deficient cells to PARthanatos induced by alkylating agents. These findings provide new molecular insights into epigenetic regulation of PARP-1 signaling mediating DNA repair or cell death and identify KDM6B as a biomarker for prediction of cancer cell vulnerability to alkylating agent treatment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PAAN/MIF nuclease inhibition prevents neurodegeneration in Parkinson&#39;s disease</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35545089/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35545089/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Parthanatos-associated apoptosis-inducing factor (AIF) nuclease (PAAN), also known as macrophage migration inhibitor factor (MIF), is a member of the PD-D/E(X)K nucleases that acts as a final executioner in parthanatos. PAAN&amp;rsquo;s role in Parkinson&amp;rsquo;s disease (PD) and whether it is amenable to chemical inhibition is not known. Here, we show that neurodegeneration induced by pathologic α-synuclein (α-syn) occurs via PAAN/MIF nuclease activity. Genetic depletion of PAAN/MIF and a mutant lacking nuclease activity prevent the loss of dopaminergic neurons and behavioral deficits in the α-syn preformed fibril (PFF) mouse model of sporadic PD. Compound screening led to the identification of PAANIB-1, a brain-penetrant PAAN/MIF nuclease inhibitor that prevents neurodegeneration induced by α-syn PFF, AAV-α-syn overexpression, or MPTP intoxication in vivo. Our findings could have broad relevance in human pathologies where parthanatos plays a role in the development of cell death inhibitors targeting the druggable PAAN/MIF nuclease.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NAMPT-derived NAD&#43; fuels PARP1 to promote skin inflammation through parthanatos cell death</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34748530/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34748530/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Several studies have revealed a correlation between chronic inflammation and nicotinamide adenine dinucleotide (NAD+) metabolism, but the precise mechanism involved is unknown. Here, we report that the genetic and pharmacological inhibition of nicotinamide phosphoribosyltransferase (Nampt), the rate-limiting enzyme in the salvage pathway of NAD+ biosynthesis, reduced oxidative stress, inflammation, and keratinocyte DNA damage, hyperproliferation, and cell death in zebrafish models of chronic skin inflammation, while all these effects were reversed by NAD+ supplementation. Similarly, genetic and pharmacological inhibition of poly(ADP-ribose) (PAR) polymerase 1 (Parp1), overexpression of PAR glycohydrolase, inhibition of apoptosis-inducing factor 1, inhibition of NADPH oxidases, and reactive oxygen species (ROS) scavenging all phenocopied the effects of Nampt inhibition. Pharmacological inhibition of NADPH oxidases/NAMPT/PARP/AIFM1 axis decreased the expression of pathology-associated genes in human organotypic 3D skin models of psoriasis. Consistently, an aberrant induction of NAMPT and PARP activity, together with AIFM1 nuclear translocation, was observed in lesional skin from psoriasis patients. In conclusion, hyperactivation of PARP1 in response to ROS-induced DNA damage, fueled by NAMPT-derived NAD+, mediates skin inflammation through parthanatos cell death.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
