<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Gasdermins | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/gasdermins/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/gasdermins/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Gasdermins</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Gasdermins</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/gasdermins/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>PANoptosis-like cell death in ischemia/reperfusion injury of retinal neurons</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35900430/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35900430/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We screened small molecules to identify two compounds, which we named RSL3 and RSL5, that have increased lethality in the presence of oncogenic RAS. Counter screening with biologically active compounds defined aspects of the mechanism of action for RSL3 and RSL5, such as a nonapoptotic, MEK-dependent, and iron-dependent oxidative cell death. Erastin, a previously reported compound with RAS-selective lethality, showed similar properties. RNA interference experiments targeting voltage-dependent anion channel 3 (VDAC3), a target of erastin, demonstrated that RSL5 is a scaffold that acts through VDACs to activate the observed pathway. RSL3 activated a similar death mechanism but in a VDAC-independent manner. We found that cells transformed with oncogenic RAS have increased iron content relative to their normal cell counterparts through upregulation of transferrin receptor 1 and downregulation of ferritin heavy chain 1 and ferritin light chain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Protein phosphatase 1 regulates phosphorylation of gasdermin D and pyroptosis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36205355/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36205355/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We report that phosphorylation of gasdermin D (GSDMD)-NT, cleaved by inflammatory caspases, could inhibit pyroptosis. Phosphatase 1 (PP1) is responsible for the regulation of GSDMD phosphorylation and the capacity of GSDMD to induce cell death. Our findings reveal a critical regulatory mechanism as it provides insight into pyroptosis processes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A bacterial phospholipid phosphatase inhibits host pyroptosis by hijacking ubiquitin</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36227980/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36227980/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Pyroptosis is a proinflammatory form of programmed cell death adopted by mammalian hosts to control infections, but how pathogens evade this immune response remains largely unexplored. Chai et al. found that PtpB, a known protein phosphatase secreted by &lt;em&gt;Mycobacterium tuberculosis&lt;/em&gt;, acts as a phospholipid phosphatase that dephosphorylates host plasma membrane phosphoinositides upon activation by ubiquitin to inhibit pyroptosis. These findings reveal a delicate strategy by which pathogens suppress pyroptosis by altering host membrane composition, and provide a potential tuberculosis treatment by targeting the PtpB-ubiquitin interacting interface.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The inflammasome-mediated cleavage of gasdermin D (GSDMD) causes pyroptosis and inflammatory cytokine release to control pathogen infection, but how pathogens evade this immune response remains largely unexplored. Here we identify the known protein phosphatase PtpB from Mycobacterium tuberculosis as a phospholipid phosphatase inhibiting the host inflammasome-pyroptosis pathway. Mechanistically, PtpB dephosphorylated phosphatidylinositol-4-monophosphate and phosphatidylinositol-(4,5)-bisphosphate in host cell membrane, thus disrupting the membrane localization of the cleaved GSDMD to inhibit cytokine release and pyroptosis of macrophages. Notably, this phosphatase activity requires PtpB binding to ubiquitin. Disrupting phospholipid phosphatase activity or the ubiquitin-interacting motif of PtpB enhanced host GSDMD-dependent immune responses and reduced intracellular pathogen survival. Thus, pathogens inhibit pyroptosis and counteract host immunity by altering host membrane composition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Introduction&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pyroptosis is a proinflammatory form of programmed cell death characterized by membrane pore formation that allows the release of intracellular inflammatory mediators, a process that is elicited by the inflammasome-mediated cleavage and activation of gasdermin D (GSDMD). Growing evidence supports a critical role for pyroptosis in the control of infections by mammalian hosts, but how pathogens evade this immune response remains largely unexplored.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rationale&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Mycobacterium tuberculosis&lt;/em&gt; (Mtb), an ancient pathogen that causes tuberculosis (TB), has developed numerous intracellular survival strategies to evade host immunity and to drive the occurrence and development of TB. One notable feature evolved by Mtb is a set of eukaryotic-like effectors, but their host targets and regulatory roles in pathogen–host interactions remain largely unclear. In this study, we sought to identify the key pathogenic regulators of inflammasome-pyroptosis pathways from Mtb eukaryotic-like effectors, information that could improve our understanding of TB pathogenesis and provide potential targets for novel anti-TB treatment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We examined the whole genome of Mtb to predict its secreted eukaryotic-like proteins possessing eukaryotic-like motifs or domains that might target host factors directly. These Mtb effector proteins were then subjected to further experimental analyses using an inflammasome reconstitution system for screening inhibitors of inflammasome-pyroptosis pathways. Out of 201 predicted Mtb-secreted eukaryotic proteins, six Mtb proteins (Rv0153c, Rv0561c, Rv0824c, Rv0861c, Rv1515c, and Rv1679) exhibited strong inhibitory effects on both NOD-like receptor protein 3 (NLRP3) and absent in melanoma 2 (AIM2) inflammasome pathways. Among these proteins, PtpB (i.e., Rv0153c) was most abundantly secreted by Mtb during infection. We thus focused on PtpB and further confirmed its inhibitory effect on AIM2 or NLRP3 inflammasome-mediated interleukin-1β (IL-1β) secretion. Subsequent experiments demonstrated that PtpB inhibited gasdermin D (GSDMD)–dependent cytokine release and pyroptosis to promote Mtb intracellular survival in macrophages. Mechanistically, Mtb-secreted PtpB could target and dephosphorylate host plasma membrane phosphatidylinositol-4-monophosphate (PI4P) and phosphatidylinositol-(4,5)-bisphosphate [PI(4,5)P2] to inhibit the membrane localization of the N-terminal cleavage fragment of GSDMD (GSDMD-N), thus preventing GSDMD-mediated immune responses. This phosphoinositide phosphatase activity requires binding of PtpB to ubiquitin. Accordingly, disrupting phospholipid phosphatase activity or the unusual ubiquitin-interacting motif (UIM)–like domain of PtpB markedly enhanced host innate immune responses and reduced intracellular pathogen survival in mice in a GSDMD-dependent manner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We demonstrate that GSDMD-mediated pyroptosis and inflammatory cytokine release play a critical role in host anti-infection immunity, which is counteracted by Mtb effector protein PtpB. Our data reveal a role of the pathogen-derived phospholipid phosphatase in the regulation of GSDMD-dependent pyroptosis and cytokine releases, extending our understanding of the elaborate regulatory mechanism of cellular inflammasome-pyroptosis signaling pathways during pathogen infection. The present study also presents a strategy by which pathogens hijack ubiquitin to inhibit host pyroptosis by altering the phospholipid composition of the host membrane. Our discovery of the PtpB UIM-like domain, which is not homologous to any human protein, may provide potential selectivity for the development of anti-TB therapies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gasdermin D maintains bone mass by rewiring the endo-lysosomal pathway of osteoclastic bone resorption</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36243012/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36243012/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gasdermin D (GSDMD)-mediated pyroptosis induces immunogenic cell death and promotes inflammation. However, the functions of GSDMD in tissue homeostasis remain unclear. Here, we identify a physiological function of GSDMD in osteoclasts via a non-lytic p20-generated protein, which prevents bone loss to maintain bone homeostasis. In the late stage of RANKL-induced osteoclastogenesis, GSDMD underwent cleavage, which is dependent on RIPK1 and caspase-8/-3, to yield this p20 product. Gsdmd-deficient osteoclasts showed normal differentiation but enhanced bone resorption with excessive lysosomal activity. Mice with complete or myeloid-specific Gsdmd deletion exhibited increased trabecular bone loss and more severe aging/ovariectomy-induced osteoporosis. GSDMD p20 was preferentially localized to early endosomes and limited endo-lysosomal trafficking and maturation, relying on its oligomerization and control of phosphoinositide conversion by binding to phosphatidylinositol 3-phosphate (PI(3)P). We have thus identified an anti-osteoclastic function of GSDMD as a checkpoint for lysosomal maturation and secretion and linked this to bone homeostasis and endosome-lysosome biology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Streptococcal pyrogenic exotoxin B cleaves GSDMA and triggers pyroptosis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35110732/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35110732/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Erratum in:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author Correction: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-022-05109-x&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Streptococcal pyrogenic exotoxin B cleaves GSDMA and triggers pyroptosis&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gasdermins, a family of five pore-forming proteins (GSDMA-GSDME) in humans expressed predominantly in the skin, mucosa and immune sentinel cells, are key executioners of inflammatory cell death (pyroptosis), which recruits immune cells to infection sites and promotes protective immunity. Pore formation is triggered by gasdermin cleavage. Although the proteases that activate GSDMB, C, D and E have been identified, how GSDMA-the dominant gasdermin in the skin-is activated, remains unknown. Streptococcus pyogenes, also known as group A Streptococcus (GAS), is a major skin pathogen that causes substantial morbidity and mortality worldwide. Here we show that the GAS cysteine protease SpeB virulence factor triggers keratinocyte pyroptosis by cleaving GSDMA after Gln246, unleashing an active N-terminal fragment that triggers pyroptosis. Gsdma1 genetic deficiency blunts mouse immune responses to GAS, resulting in uncontrolled bacterial dissemination and death. GSDMA acts as both a sensor and substrate of GAS SpeB and as an effector to trigger pyroptosis, adding a simple one-molecule mechanism for host recognition and control of virulence of a dangerous microbial pathogen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NLRC4 inflammasome-dependent cell death occurs by a complementary series of three death pathways and determines lethality in mice</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34678072/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34678072/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inflammasome is an innate immune defense mechanism, but its overactivation can lead to host death. Here, we show that cell death dictates mouse death caused by NLRC4 inflammasome overactivation. To execute NLRC4-dependent cell death, three death paways complement each other in a specific order: Pyroptosis pathway requiring caspase-1 and GSDMD is the default path; impairment of it initiates ASC-mediated caspase-8–dependent apoptosis; when these two pathways are blocked, caspase-1 triggers intrinsthic apoptotic pathway. Blocking one or two of these death pathways inhibits induction of various cytokines and lipid mediators, but mice still succumb, and only genetic deletions that block all death paths prevent NLRC4-mediated cell death, tissue damage, and mice death. In addition, infection of nonpropagative &lt;em&gt;Salmonella&lt;/em&gt;-caused mice death is attenuated by blocking these death pathways. Thus, to reduce the lethality of infection-related diseases, preventing cell death might be necessary when propagation of infected pathogen was controlled by other means.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shigella evades pyroptosis by arginine ADP-riboxanation of caspase-11</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34671164/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34671164/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mouse caspase-11 and human caspase-4 and caspase-5 recognize cytosolic lipopolysaccharide (LPS) to induce pyroptosis by cleaving the pore-forming protein GSDMD. This non-canonical inflammasome defends against Gram-negative bacteria. Shigella flexneri, which causes bacillary dysentery, lives freely within the host cytosol where these caspases reside. However, the role of caspase-11-mediated pyroptosis in S. flexneri infection is unknown. Here we show that caspase-11 did not protect mice from S. flexneri infection, in contrast to infection with another cytosolic bacterium, Burkholderia thailandensis. S. flexneri evaded pyroptosis mediated by caspase-11 or caspase 4 (hereafter referred to as caspase-11/4) using a type III secretion system (T3SS) effector, OspC3. OspC3, but not its paralogues OspC1 and 2, covalently modified caspase-11/4; although it used the NAD&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; donor, this modification was not ADP-ribosylation. Biochemical dissections uncovered an ADP-riboxanation modification on Arg314 and Arg310 in caspase-4 and caspase-11, respectively. The enzymatic activity was shared by OspC1 and 2, whose ankyrin-repeat domains, unlike that of OspC3, could not recognize caspase-11/4. ADP-riboxanation of the arginine blocked autoprocessing of caspase-4/11 as well as their recognition and cleavage of GSDMD. ADP-riboxanation of caspase-11 paralysed pyroptosis-mediated defence in Shigella-infected mice and mutation of ospC3 stimulated caspase-11- and GSDMD-dependent anti-Shigella humoral immunity, generating a vaccine-like protective effect. Our study establishes ADP-riboxanation of arginine as a bacterial virulence mechanism that prevents LPS-induced pyroptosis.Up to 40% of patients with inflammatory bowel disease present with psychosocial disturbances. We previously identified a gut vascular barrier that controls the dissemination of bacteria from the intestine to the liver. Here, we describe a vascular barrier in the brain choroid plexus (PVB) that is modulated in response to intestinal inflammation through bacteria-derived lipopolysaccharide. The inflammatory response induces PVB closure after gut vascular barrier opening by the up-regulation of the wingless-type, catenin-beta 1 (Wnt/β-catenin) signaling pathway, rendering it inaccessible to large molecules. In a model of genetically driven closure of choroid plexus endothelial cells, we observed a deficit in short-term memory and anxiety-like behavior, suggesting that PVB closure may correlate with mental deficits. Inflammatory bowel disease–related mental symptoms may thus be the consequence of a deregulated gut–brain vascular axis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Control of gasdermin D oligomerization and pyroptosis by the Ragulator-Rag-mTORC1 pathway</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34289345/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34289345/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The process of pyroptosis is mediated by inflammasomes and a downstream effector known as gasdermin D (GSDMD). Upon cleavage by inflammasome-associated caspases, the N-terminal domain of GSDMD forms membrane pores that promote cytolysis. Numerous proteins promote GSDMD cleavage, but none are known to be required for pore formation after GSDMD cleavage. Herein, we report a forward genetic screen that identified the Ragulator-Rag complex as being necessary for GSDMD pore formation and pyroptosis in macrophages. Mechanistic analysis revealed that Ragulator-Rag is not required for GSDMD cleavage upon inflammasome activation but rather promotes GSDMD oligomerization in the plasma membrane. Defects in GSDMD oligomerization and pore formation can be rescued by mitochondrial poisons that stimulate reactive oxygen species (ROS) production, and ROS modulation impacts the ability of inflammasome pathways to promote pore formation downstream of GSDMD cleavage. These findings reveal an unexpected link between key regulators of immunity (inflammasome-GSDMD) and metabolism (Ragulator-Rag).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The metabolite α-KG induces GSDMC-dependent pyroptosis through death receptor 6-activated caspase-8</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34012073/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34012073/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pyroptosis is a form of regulated cell death mediated by gasdermin family members, among which the function of GSDMC has not been clearly described. Herein, we demonstrate that the metabolite α-ketoglutarate (α-KG) induces pyroptosis through caspase-8-mediated cleavage of GSDMC. Treatment with DM-αKG, a cell-permeable derivative of α-KG, elevates ROS levels, which leads to oxidation of the plasma membrane-localized death receptor DR6. Oxidation of DR6 triggers its endocytosis, and then recruits both pro-caspase-8 and GSDMC to a DR6 receptosome through protein-protein interactions. The DR6 receptosome herein provides a platform for the cleavage of GSDMC by active caspase-8, thereby leading to pyroptosis. Moreover, this α-KG-induced pyroptosis could inhibit tumor growth and metastasis in mouse models. Interestingly, the efficiency of α-KG in inducing pyroptosis relies on an acidic environment in which α-KG is reduced by MDH1 and converted to L-2HG that further boosts ROS levels. Treatment with lactic acid, the end product of glycolysis, builds an improved acidic environment to facilitate more production of L-2HG, which makes the originally pyroptosis-resistant cancer cells more susceptible to α-KG-induced pyroptosis. This study not only illustrates a pyroptotic pathway linked with metabolites but also identifies an unreported principal axis extending from ROS-initiated DR6 endocytosis to caspase-8-mediated cleavage of GSDMC for potential clinical application in tumor therapy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intracellular immune sensing promotes inflammation via gasdermin D-driven release of a lectin alarmin</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33398185/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33398185/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inflammatory caspase sensing of cytosolic lipopolysaccharide (LPS) triggers pyroptosis and the concurrent release of damage-associated molecular patterns (DAMPs). Collectively, DAMPs are key determinants that shape the aftermath of inflammatory cell death. However, the identity and function of the individual DAMPs released are poorly defined. Our proteomics study revealed that cytosolic LPS sensing triggered the release of galectin-1, a β-galactoside-binding lectin. Galectin-1 release is a common feature of inflammatory cell death, including necroptosis. In vivo studies using galectin-1-deficient mice, recombinant galectin-1 and galectin-1-neutralizing antibody showed that galectin-1 promotes inflammation and plays a detrimental role in LPS-induced lethality. Mechanistically, galectin-1 inhibition of CD45 (&lt;em&gt;Ptprc&lt;/em&gt;) underlies its unfavorable role in endotoxin shock. Finally, we found increased galectin-1 in sera from human patients with sepsis. Overall, we uncovered galectin-1 as a bona fide DAMP released as a consequence of cytosolic LPS sensing, identifying a new outcome of inflammatory cell death.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Granzyme A from cytotoxic lymphocytes cleaves GSDMB to trigger pyroptosis in target cells</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32299851/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32299851/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Introduction&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In cellular immunity, cytotoxic T lymphocytes (CTLs) and natural killer (NK) cells use perforin to deliver serine protease granzymes into target cells to kill them. Gasdermins are pore-forming proteins that execute pyroptosis, a form of proinflammatory cell death. Gasdermin D (GSDMD) is cleaved by caspase-1/4/5/11 upon inflammasome activation, releasing the pore-forming domain for plasma membrane disruption. Gasdermin E (GSDME) is similarly cleaved by caspase-3, converting apoptosis to pyroptosis. The functional mechanism for other gasdermins is unknown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rationale&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The view that granzymes induce target-cell apoptosis was proposed two decades ago, when apoptosis was thought to be the dominant form of programmed cell death and assays to ascertain apoptosis were insufficiently accurate. Furthermore, granzyme cytotoxicity was only assessed in a few cell types. Discovery of the gasdermin family, which are true cell death executors, has altered our understanding of programmed cell death. In this work, we explored whether members of the gasdermin family might respond to granzymes and induce pyroptosis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Results&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The expression of gasdermin B (GSDMB) but no other gasdermins in human embryonic kidney (HEK) 293T cells induced pyroptotic killing by NK cells, accompanied by an interdomain cleavage of GSDMB. These processes were blocked by inhibiting the perforin–granzyme pathway. In vitro profiling of all five human granzymes identified granzyme A (GZMA), which readily cleaved GSDMB, predominantly at Lys&lt;sup&gt;244&lt;/sup&gt; within the interdomain linker. This cleavage unmasked the pore-forming activity of GSDMB. GZMA, delivered into GSDMB-reconstituted cells by electroporation or perforin, induced extensive pyroptosis with interdomain cleavage of GSDMB. These effects were diminished by a K229A/K244A (KK/A) mutation of GSDMB. In cells normally undergoing apoptosis upon GZMA delivery, the additional expression of GZMA-cleavable GSDMB converted apoptosis into pyroptosis. Pyroptotic killing by NK cells was blocked by both the KK/AA mutation and a knockdown of &lt;em&gt;GZMA&lt;/em&gt; expression. Among 39 cell lines, three, including the esophageal carcinoma (OE19 cells), expressed GSDMB and underwent pyroptosis upon GZMA delivery. Knockout experiments revealed that pyroptosis in OE19 cells required the interdomain cleavage of GSDMB. Furthermore, GSDMB expression was up-regulated by interferon-γ (IFN-γ). Approximately one-third of GSDMB-negative cell lines showed IFN-γ–induced GSDMB expression. IFN-γ promoted GZMA- or NK cell–induced pyroptosis in several target cells. Primary T cells, including anti-CD19 chimeric-antigen receptor (CAR) T cells and NY-ESO-1–specific T cell receptor (TCR)–engineered T cells (TCR T cells), also induced pyroptosis in GSDMB-reconstituted cells through cleavage of GSDMB by GZMA. Introducing GZMA-cleavable GSDMB into mouse cancer cells promoted tumor clearance in mice. &lt;em&gt;GSDMB&lt;/em&gt; was highly expressed in certain tissues, particularly digestive tract epithelia, including the derived tumors. GSDMB appeared to be silenced in gastric and esophageal cancers. The Cancer Genome Atlas database recorded a strong positive correlation between &lt;em&gt;GSDMB&lt;/em&gt; expression and patient survival for bladder carcinoma and skin cutaneous melanoma.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conclusion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GZMA from cytotoxic lymphocytes cleaves and activates GSDMB to induce target cell pyroptosis. This immune effector mechanism promotes CTL-mediated tumor clearance in mice. High GSDMB expression in the digestive system suggests the importance of GSDMB-mediated immunity in these tissues and will guide immunotherapy for related cancers. Our findings suggest that substrates such as gasdermins, rather than their upstream proteases, determine the nature of cell death.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Structural Mechanism for GSDMD Targeting by Autoprocessed Caspases in Pyroptosis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32109412/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32109412/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The pyroptosis execution protein GSDMD is cleaved by inflammasome-activated caspase-1 and LPS-activated caspase-11/4/5. The cleavage unmasks the pore-forming domain from GSDMD-C-terminal domain. How the caspases recognize GSDMD and its connection with caspase activation are unknown. Here, we show site-specific caspase-4/11 autoprocessing, generating a p10 product, is required and sufficient for cleaving GSDMD and inducing pyroptosis. The p10-form autoprocessed caspase-4/11 binds the GSDMD-C domain with a high affinity. Structural comparison of autoprocessed and unprocessed capase-11 identifies a β sheet induced by the autoprocessing. In caspase-4/11-GSDMD-C complex crystal structures, the β sheet organizes a hydrophobic GSDMD-binding interface that is only possible for p10-form caspase-4/11. The binding promotes dimerization-mediated caspase activation, rendering a cleavage independently of the cleavage-site tetrapeptide sequence. Crystal structure of caspase-1-GSDMD-C complex shows a similar GSDMD-recognition mode. Our study reveals an unprecedented substrate-targeting mechanism for caspases. The hydrophobic interface suggests an additional space for developing inhibitors specific for pyroptotic caspases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bacterial Endotoxin Activates the Coagulation Cascade through Gasdermin D-Dependent Phosphatidylserine Exposure</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/31836429/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/31836429/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deletion of caspase-11 prevents disseminated intravascular coagulation (DIC) in sepsis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deletion of GSDMD prevents caspase-11- and TF-mediated DIC in endotoxemia&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GSDMD deficiency inhibits endotoxin-induced TF activation by reducing PS exposure&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Activation of GSDMD by caspase-11 triggers Ca2+-dependent PS exposure through TMEM16F&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Summary&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Excessive activation of the coagulation system leads to life-threatening disseminated intravascular coagulation (DIC). Here, we examined the mechanisms underlying the activation of coagulation by lipopolysaccharide (LPS), the major cell-wall component of Gram-negative bacteria. We found that caspase-11, a cytosolic LPS receptor, activated the coagulation cascade. Caspase-11 enhanced the activation of tissue factor (TF), an initiator of coagulation, through triggering the formation of gasdermin D (GSDMD) pores and subsequent phosphatidylserine exposure, in a manner independent of cell death. GSDMD pores mediated calcium influx, which induced phosphatidylserine exposure through transmembrane protein 16F, a calcium-dependent phospholipid scramblase. Deletion of &lt;em&gt;Casp11&lt;/em&gt;, ablation of &lt;em&gt;Gsdmd&lt;/em&gt;, or neutralization of phosphatidylserine or TF prevented LPS-induced DIC. In septic patients, plasma concentrations of interleukin (IL)-1α and IL-1β, biomarkers of GSDMD activation, correlated with phosphatidylserine exposure in peripheral leukocytes and DIC scores. Our findings mechanistically link immune recognition of LPS to coagulation, with implications for the treatment of DIC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
