<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Immunosuppression | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/immunosuppression/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/immunosuppression/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Immunosuppression</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Immunosuppression</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/immunosuppression/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>SHP2 deneddylation mediates tumor immunosuppression in colon cancer via the CD47/SIRPα axis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36626230/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36626230/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SIPRα on macrophages binds with CD47 to resist pro-engulfment signals, but how the downstream signal of SIPRα controls tumor-infiltrating macrophages (TIMs) is still poorly clarified. Here we reported that the CD47/SIRPα axis requires the deneddylation of tyrosine phosphatase SHP2. Mechanistically, SHP2 is constitutively neddylated on K358 and K364 sites, thus its auto-inhibited conformation is maintained. In response to CD47-liganded SIRPα, SHP2 is deneddylated by SENP8, which leads to the dephosphorylation of relevant substrates at the phagocytic cup and subsequent inhibition of macrophage phagocytosis. Furthermore, neddylation inactivated myeloid-SHP2 and greatly boosted the efficacy of colorectal cancer (CRC) immunotherapy. Importantly, we observed that the supplementation with SHP2 allosteric inhibitors sensitized the immune treatment-resistant CRC to immunotherapy. Our results emphasized that the CRC subtype which is unresponsive to immunotherapy relies on SIRPαhiSHP2hiNEDD8lo TIMs, and highlighted the need to further combine the strategy of SHP2 targeting in colorectal cancer therapy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Immunosuppressive lncRNA LINC00624 promotes tumor progression and therapy resistance through ADAR1 stabilization</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36252997/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36252997/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Despite the success of HER2-targeted therapy in achieving prolonged survival in approximately 50% of treated individuals, treatment resistance is still an important challenge for HER2+ breast cancer (BC) patients. The influence of both adaptive and innate immune responses on the therapeutic outcomes of HER2+BC patients has been extensively demonstrated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; Long non-coding RNAs expressed in non-pathological complete response (pCR) HER2 positive BC were screened and validated by RNA-seq. Survival analysis were made by Kaplan-Meier method. Cell death assay and proliferation assay were performed to confirm the phenotype of LINC00624. RT-qPCR and western blot were used to assay the IFN response. Xenograft mouse model were used for in vivo confirmation of anti-neu treatment resistance. RNA pull-down and immunoblot were used to confirm the interaction of ADAR1 and LINC00624. ADAR1 recombinant protein were purified from baculovirus expression system. B16-OVA cells were used to study antigen presentation both in vitro and in vivo. Flow cytometry was used to determine the tumor infiltrated immune cells of xenograft model. Antisense oligonucleotides (ASOs) were used for in vivo treatment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; In this study, we found that LINC00624 blocked the antitumor effect of HER2- targeted therapy both in vitro and in vivo by inhibiting type I interferon (IFN) pathway activation. The double-stranded RNA-like structure of LINC00624 can bind and be edited by the adenosine (A) to inosine (I) RNA-editing enzyme adenosine deaminase RNA specific 1 (ADAR1), and this editing has been shown to release the growth inhibition and attenuate the innate immune response caused by the IFN response. Notably, LINC00624 promoted the stabilization of ADAR1 by inhibiting its ubiquitination-induced degradation triggered by β-TrCP. In contrast, LINC00624 inhibited major histocompatibility complex (MHC) class I antigen presentation and limited CD8+T cell infiltration in the cancer microenvironment, resulting in immune checkpoint blockade inhibition and anti-HER2 treatment resistance mediated through ADAR1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; In summary, these results suggest that LINC00624 is a cancer immunosuppressive lncRNA and targeting LINC00624 through ASOs in tumors expressing high levels of LINC00624 has great therapeutic potential in future clinical applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sepsis-induced immunosuppression: mechanisms, diagnosis and current treatment options</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/36209190/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/36209190/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sepsis is a common complication of combat injuries and trauma, and is defined as a life-threatening organ dysfunction caused by a dysregulated host response to infection. It is also one of the significant causes of death and increased health care costs in modern intensive care units. The use of antibiotics, fluid resuscitation, and organ support therapy have limited prognostic impact in patients with sepsis. Although its pathophysiology remains elusive, immunosuppression is now recognized as one of the major causes of septic death. Sepsis-induced immunosuppression is resulted from disruption of immune homeostasis. It is characterized by the release of anti-inflammatory cytokines, abnormal death of immune effector cells, hyperproliferation of immune suppressor cells, and expression of immune checkpoints. By targeting immunosuppression, especially with immune checkpoint inhibitors, preclinical studies have demonstrated the reversal of immunocyte dysfunctions and established host resistance. Here, we comprehensively discuss recent findings on the mechanisms, regulation and biomarkers of sepsis-induced immunosuppression and highlight their implications for developing effective strategies to treat patients with septic shock.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Terbinafine prevents colorectal cancer growth by inducing dNTP starvation and reducing immune suppression</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35765243/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35765243/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Existing evidence indicates that gut fungal dysbiosis might play a key role in the pathogenesis of colorectal cancer (CRC). We sought to explore whether reversing the fungal dysbiosis by terbinafine, an approved antifungal drug, might inhibit the development of CRC. A population-based study from Sweden identified a total of 185 patients who received terbinafine after their CRC diagnosis and found that they had a decreased risk of death (hazard ratio = 0.50) and metastasis (hazard ratio = 0.44) compared with patients without terbinafine administration. In multiple mouse models of CRC, administration of terbinafine decreased the fungal load, the fungus-induced myeloid-derived suppressor cell (MDSC) expansion, and the tumor burden. Fecal microbiota transplantation from mice without terbinafine treatment reversed MDSC infiltration and partially restored tumor proliferation. Mechanistically, terbinafine directly impaired tumor cell proliferation by reducing the ratio of nicotinamide adenine dinucleotide phosphate (NADP+) to reduced form of nicotinamide adenine dinucleotide phosphate (NADPH), suppressing the activity of glucose-6-phosphate dehydrogenase (G6PD), resulting in nucleotide synthesis disruption, deoxyribonucleotide (dNTP) starvation, and cell-cycle arrest. Collectively, terbinafine can inhibit CRC by reversing fungal dysbiosis, suppressing tumor cell proliferation, inhibiting fungus-induced MDSC infiltration, and restoring antitumor immune response.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dual inhibition of TGFβ signaling and CSF1/CSF1R reprograms tumor-infiltrating macrophages and improves response to chemotherapy via suppressing PD-L1</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35718267/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35718267/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;TGF promotes resistance to chemotherapy in CRC via PD-L1.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chemotherapy-treated cancer cells secrete CSF1 to recruit M2-TAMs for TGF production within tumor microenvironment.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dual inhibition on CSF1R&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; M2-TAMs recruitment and TGF signaling increases the response to chemotherapy in CRC.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TGFβ contributes to chemoresistance in advanced colorectal cancer (CRC) via diverse immune-microenvironment mechanisms. Here, we found that cancer cell autonomous TGFβ directly triggered tumor programmed cell death 1 ligand 1 (PD-L1) upregulation, resulting in resistance to chemotherapy. Inhibition of tumor PD-L1 expression sensitized cancer cells to chemotherapy, reduced lung metastasis and increased the influx of CD8&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T cells. However, chemorefractory cancer cell-derived CSF1 recruited TAMs for TGFβ-mediated PD-L1 upregulation via a vicious cycle. High infiltration of macrophages was clinically correlated with the status of tumor PD-L1 after chemotherapy treatment in CRC patients. We found that depletion of immunosuppressive CSF1R&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; TAM infiltration and blockade of the TGFβ receptor resulted in an increased influx of cytotoxic CD8&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T and effector memory CD8&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; cells, a reduction in regulatory T cells, and a synergistic inhibition of tumor growth when combined with chemotherapy. These findings show that CSF1R&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; TAMs and TGFβ are the dominant components that regulate PD-L1 expression within the immunosuppressive tumor microenvironment, providing a therapeutic strategy for advanced CRC patients.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Single-cell transcriptome profiling of the immune space-time landscape reveals dendritic cell regulatory program in polymicrobial sepsis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35832091/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35832091/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rationale:&lt;/em&gt; Evident immunosuppression has been commonly seen among septic patients, and it is demonstrated to be a major driver of morbidity. Nevertheless, a comprehensive view of the host immune response to sepsis is lacking as the majority of studies on immunosuppression have focused on a specific type of immune cells.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; We applied multi-compartment, single-cell RNA sequencing (scRNA-seq) to dissect heterogeneity within immune cell subsets during sepsis progression on cecal ligation and puncture (CLP) mouse model. Flow cytometry and multiplex immunofluorescence tissue staining were adopted to identify the presence of &amp;lsquo;mature DCs enriched in immunoregulatory molecules&amp;rsquo; (mregDC) upon septic challenge. To explore the function of mregDC, sorted mregDC were co-cultured with naïve CD4&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T cells. Intracellular signaling pathways that drove mregDC program were determined by integrating scRNA-seq and bulk-seq data, combined with inhibitory experiments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; ScRNA-seq analysis revealed that sepsis induction was associated with substantial alterations and heterogeneity of canonical immune cell types, including T, B, natural killer (NK), and myeloid cells, across three immune-relevant tissue sites. We found a unique subcluster of conventional dendritic cells (cDCs) that was characterized by specific expression of maturation- and migration-related genes, along with upregulation of immunoregulatory molecules, corresponding to the previously described &amp;lsquo;mregDCs&amp;rsquo; in cancer. Flow cytometry and in stiu immunofluorescence staining confirmed the presence of sepsis-induced mregDC at protein level. Functional experiments showed that sepsis-induced mregDCs potently activated naive CD4&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T cells, while promoted CD4&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T cell conversion to regulatory T cells. Further observations indicated that the mregDC program was initiated via TNFRSF-NF-κB- and IFNGR2-JAK-STAT3-dependent pathways within 24 h of septic challenge. Additionally, we confirmed the detection of mregDC in human sepsis using publicly available data from a recently published single-cell study of COVID-19 patients.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; Our study generates a comprehensive single-cell immune landscape for polymicrobial sepsis, in which we identify the significant alterations and heterogeneity in immune cell subsets that take place during sepsis. Moreover, we find a conserved and potentially targetable immunoregulatory program within DCs that associates with hyperinflammation and organ dysfunction early following sepsis induction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The dual role of glioma exosomal microRNAs: glioma eliminates tumor suppressor miR-1298-5p via exosomes to promote immunosuppressive effects of MDSCs</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35501306/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35501306/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clear evidence shows that tumors could secrete microRNAs (miRNAs) via exosomes to modulate the tumor microenvironment (TME). However, the mechanisms sorting specific miRNAs into exosomes are still unclear. In order to study the biological function and characterization of exosomal miRNAs, we performed whole-transcriptome sequencing in 59 patients&amp;rsquo; whole-course cerebrospinal fluid (CSF) small extracellular vesicles (sEV) and matched glioma tissue samples. The results demonstrate that miRNAs could be divided into exosome-enriched miRNAs (ExomiRNAs) and intracellular-retained miRNAs (CLmiRNAs), and exosome-enriched miRNAs generally play a dual role. Among them, miR-1298-5p was enriched in CSF exosomes and suppressed glioma progression in vitro and vivo experiments. Interestingly, exosomal miR-1298-5p could promote the immunosuppressive effects of myeloid-derived suppressor cells (MDSCs) to facilitate glioma. Therefore, we found miR-1298-5p had different effects on glioma cells and MDSCs. Mechanically, downstream signaling pathway analyses showed that miR-1298-5p plays distinct roles in glioma cells and MDSCs via targeting SETD7 and MSH2, respectively. Moreover, reverse verification was performed on the intracellular-retained miRNA miR-9-5p. Thus, we confirmed that tumor-suppressive miRNAs in glioma cells could be eliminated through exosomes and target tumor-associated immune cells to induce tumor-promoting phenotypes. Glioma could get double benefit from it. These findings uncover the mechanisms that glioma selectively sorts miRNAs into exosomes and modulates tumor immunity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Combined protein and nucleic acid imaging reveals virus-dependent B cell and macrophage immunosuppression of tissue microenvironments</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35447093/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35447093/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Development of a method (PANINI) for multiplexed nucleic acid and protein imaging&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Identification of orchestrated immune events in response to SIV infection&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IL-10 levels in B cells and macrophages correlate with immunosuppression&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tissue microenvironmental cues can influence SIV viral transcription state&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Understanding the mechanisms of HIV tissue persistence necessitates the ability to visualize tissue microenvironments where infected cells reside; however, technological barriers limit our ability to dissect the cellular components of these HIV reservoirs. Here, we developed protein and nucleic acid in situ imaging (PANINI) to simultaneously quantify DNA, RNA, and protein levels within these tissue compartments. By coupling PANINI with multiplexed ion beam imaging (MIBI), we measured over 30 parameters simultaneously across archival lymphoid tissues from healthy or simian immunodeficiency virus (SIV)-infected nonhuman primates. PANINI enabled the spatial dissection of cellular phenotypes, functional markers, and viral events resulting from infection. SIV infection induced IL-10 expression in lymphoid B cells, which correlated with local macrophage M2 polarization. This highlights a potential viral mechanism for conditioning an immunosuppressive tissue environment for virion production. The spatial multimodal framework here can be extended to decipher tissue responses in other infectious diseases and tumor biology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ketogenesis Attenuates KLF5-Dependent Production of CXCL12 to Overcome the Immunosuppressive Tumor Microenvironment in Colorectal Cancer</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35247887/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35247887/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The dynamic composition of the tumor microenvironment (TME) can markedly alter the response to targeted therapies for colorectal cancer. Cancer-associated fibroblasts (CAF) are major components of TMEs that can direct and induce infiltration of immunosuppressive cells through secreted cytokines such as CXCL12. Ketogenic diets (KD) can inhibit tumor growth and enhance the anticancer effects of immune checkpoint blockade. However, the role of ketogenesis on the immunosuppressive TME is not known. Here, we show that decreased ketogenesis is a signature of colorectal cancer and that an increase in ketogenesis using a KD decreases CXCL12 production in tumors, serum, liver, and lungs. Moreover, increasing ketogenesis by overexpression of the ketogenic enzyme 3-hydroxy-3-methylglutaryl-CoA synthase 2 (HMGCS2) or treatment with the ketone body β-hydroxybutyrate markedly decreased expression of KLF5, which binds the CXCL12 promoter and induces CXCL12 expression in CAFs. KD decreased intratumoral accumulation of immunosuppressive cells, increased infiltration of natural killer and cytotoxic T cells, and enhanced the anticancer effects of PD-1 blockade in murine-derived colorectal cancer. Furthermore, increasing ketogenesis inhibited colorectal cancer migration, invasion, and metastasis in vitro and in vivo. Overall, ketogenesis is downregulated in the colorectal cancer TME, and increased ketogenesis represses KLF5-dependent CXCL12 expression to improve the immunosuppressive TME, which leads to the enhanced efficacy of immunotherapy and reduced metastasis. Importantly, this work demonstrates that downregulation of de novo ketogenesis in the TME is a critical step in colorectal cancer progression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lactylation-driven METTL3-mediated RNA m6A modification promotes immunosuppression of tumor-infiltrating myeloid cells</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35320754/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35320754/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;H3K18 lactylation increases Mettl3 expression in tumor-infiltrating myeloid cells&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;METTL3-mediated m&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;A modification on Jak1 mRNA promotes its protein translation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;METTL3/m&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;A/JAK1/STAT3 axis strengthens immunosuppressive functions of myeloid cells&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lactylation on zinc-finger domain of METTL3 enhances its capture of m&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;A-modified RNA&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FUT8-mediated aberrant N-glycosylation of B7H3 suppresses the immune response in triple-negative breast cancer</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33976130/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33976130/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most patients with triple negative breast cancer (TNBC) do not respond to anti-PD1/PDL1 immunotherapy, indicating the necessity to explore immune checkpoint targets. B7H3 is a highly glycosylated protein. However, the mechanisms of B7H3 glycosylation regulation and whether the sugar moiety contributes to immunosuppression are unclear. Here, we identify aberrant B7H3 glycosylation and show that N-glycosylation of B7H3 at NXT motif sites is responsible for its protein stability and immunosuppression in TNBC tumors. The fucosyltransferase FUT8 catalyzes B7H3 core fucosylation at N-glycans to maintain its high expression. Knockdown of FUT8 rescues glycosylated B7H3-mediated immunosuppressive function in TNBC cells. Abnormal B7H3 glycosylation mediated by FUT8 overexpression can be physiologically important and clinically relevant in patients with TNBC. Notably, the combination of core fucosylation inhibitor 2F-Fuc and anti-PDL1 results in enhanced therapeutic efficacy in B7H3-positive TNBC tumors. These findings suggest that targeting the FUT8-B7H3 axis might be a promising strategy for improving anti-tumor immune responses in patients with TNBC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Immunosuppressive effects of mesenchymal stem cells on lung B cell gene expression in LPS-induced acute lung injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32977837/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32977837/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Immune system disorders play important roles in acute lung injury (ALI), and mesenchymal stem cell (MSC) treatment can reduce inflammation during ALI. In this study, we compared the changes in lung B cells during MSC treatment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; We investigated the effects of MSCs on lung B cells in a mouse model of lipopolysaccharide (LPS)-induced ALI. MSCs were administered intratracheally 4 h after LPS. As vehicle-treated controls, mice were treated with phosphate-buffered saline (PBS) containing 2% C57BL/6 (PBS group). Histopathological changes, survival rate, inflammatory factor levels, and the number of neutrophils in bronchoalveolar lavage fluid (BALF) were determined. Single-cell RNA sequencing (scRNA-Seq) analysis was performed to evaluate the transcriptional changes in lung B cells between the PBS, LPS, and LPS/MSC groups on days 3 and 7.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; MSC treatment ameliorated LPS-induced ALI, as indicated by the reductions in mortality, the levels of chemokines and cytokines in BALF, and the severity of lung tissue histopathology in ALI mice. Lung B cells in the PBS group remained undifferentiated and had an inhibitory phenotype. Based on our scRNA-Seq results, the differentially expressed genes (DEGs) in lung B cells in both the PBS group and LPS group were involved in chemotaxis processes and some proinflammatory pathways. MSC treatment inhibited the expression of chemokine genes that were upregulated by LPS and were related to the recruitment of neutrophils into lung tissues. Immunoglobulin-related gene expression was decreased in lung B cells of mice treated with LPS/MSC for 7 days. The DEGs regulated by MSCs were enriched in biological processes, including humoral immune response and apoptotic signaling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; Lung B cells played an important role in the effects of treatment of ALI with MSCs. These observations provide new insights into the mechanisms underlying the effects of MSC treatment for ALI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
