<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Womb | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/womb/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/womb/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Womb</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Womb</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/womb/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Landscape of pathogenic mutations in premature ovarian insufficiency</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36732629/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36732629/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Premature ovarian insufficiency (POI) is a major cause of female infertility due to early loss of ovarian function. POI is a heterogeneous condition, and its molecular etiology is unclear. To identify genetic variants associated with POI, here we performed whole-exome sequencing in a cohort of 1,030 patients with POI. We detected 195 pathogenic/likely pathogenic variants in 59 known POI-causative genes, accounting for 193 (18.7%) cases. Association analyses comparing the POI cohort with a control cohort of 5,000 individuals without POI identified 20 further POI-associated genes with a significantly higher burden of loss-of-function variants. Functional annotations of these novel 20 genes indicated their involvement in ovarian development and function, including gonadogenesis (LGR4 and PRDM1), meiosis (CPEB1, KASH5, MCMDC2, MEIOSIN, NUP43, RFWD3, SHOC1, SLX4 and STRA8) and folliculogenesis and ovulation (ALOX12, BMP6, H1-8, HMMR, HSD17B1, MST1R, PPM1B, ZAR1 and ZP3). Cumulatively, pathogenic and likely pathogenic variants in known POI-causative and novel POI-associated genes contributed to 242 (23.5%) cases. Further genotype-phenotype correlation analyses indicated that genetic contribution was higher in cases with primary amenorrhea compared to that in cases with secondary amenorrhea. This study expands understanding of the genetic landscape underlying POI and presents insights that have the potential to improve the utility of diagnostic genetic screenings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ALKBH5-mediated m6A modification of circCCDC134 facilitates cervical cancer metastasis by enhancing HIF1A transcription</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36028854/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36028854/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Metastasis is the main cause of mortality in cervical cancer (CC). Circular RNAs (circRNAs) have been demonstrated to play a crucial role in carcinoma biology. However, the expression and function of circRNAs in cervical cancer metastasis are still unclear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; In the present study, we identified a circRNA with an N6-methyladenosine (m6A) modification, circCCDC134, whose expression was increased in CC tissues by circRNA-Seq and qPCR. CircCCDC134 upregulation in CC was fine-tuned by ALKBH5-mediated m6A modification, which enhanced its stability in a YTHDF2-dependent manner. The functional experiments illustrated that circCCDC134 enhanced tumour proliferation and metastasis in vitro and in vivo. For the comprehensive identification of RNA-binding proteins, circRNA pull-down and mass spectrometry (ChIRP-MS), chromatin immunoprecipitation-seq (Chip-seq), RNA binding protein immunoprecipitation (RIP) and luciferase reporter assays were used to perform mechanistic investigations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; The results revealed that circCCDC134 recruited p65 in the nucleus and acted as a miR-503-5p sponge to regulate the expression of MYB in the cytoplasm, ultimately stimulating HIF1A transcription and facilitating CC growth and metastasis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/em&gt; These findings indicate that circCCDC134 is an important therapeutic target and provide new regulatory model insights for exploring the carcinogenic mechanism of circCCDC134 in CC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>METTL3 potentiates progression of cervical cancer by suppressing ER stress via regulating m6A modification of TXNDC5 mRNA</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35987795/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35987795/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;N6-methyladenosine (m&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;A) is the most abundant chemical modification on mRNA and plays significant roles in many bioprocesses. However, the functions of m&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;A on cervical cancer (CC) tumorigenesis remain unclear. Here we found methyltransferase-like 3 (METTL3), a core member of the m&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;A methyltransferase family, was greatly upregulated as an independent prognostic factor in CC. Mechanistically, the transcription factor ETS1 recruited P300 and WDR5 which separately mediated H3K27ac and H3K4me3 histone modification in the promoter of METTL3 and induced METTL3 transcription activation. Furthermore, we identified TXNDC5 as a target of METTL3-mediated m&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;A modification through MeRIP-seq, and revealed that METTL3-mediated TXNDC5 expression relied on the m&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;A reader-dependent manner. Functionally, we verified that METTL3 promoted proliferation and metastasis of CC cells by regulating of TXNDC5 expression through in vitro and in vivo experiments. In addition, our study verified the effect of METTL3/TXNDC5 axis on ER stress. Taken together, METTL3 facilitates the malignant progression of CC, suggesting that METTL3 might be a potential prognostic biomarker and therapeutic target for CC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Epigenomic and enhancer dysregulation in uterine leiomyomas</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/35199155/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/35199155/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Uterine leiomyomas, also known as uterine fibroids or myomas, are the most common benign gynecological tumors and are found in women of reproductive and postmenopausal age. There is an exceptionally high prevalence of this tumor in women by the age of 50 years. Black women are particularly affected, with an increased incidence, earlier age of onset, larger and faster growing fibroids and greater severity of symptoms as compared to White women. Although advances in identifying genetic and environmental factors to delineate these fibroids have already been made, only recently has the role of epigenomics in the pathogenesis of this disease been considered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Objective and rationale:&lt;/em&gt; Over recent years, studies have identified multiple epigenomic aberrations that may contribute to leiomyoma development and growth. This review will focus on the most recent discoveries in three categories of epigenomic changes found in uterine fibroids, namely aberrant DNA methylation, histone tail modifications and histone variant exchange, and their translation into altered target gene architecture and transcriptional outcome. The findings demonstrating how the altered 3D shape of the enhancer can regulate gene expression from millions of base pairs away will be discussed. Additionally, translational implications of these discoveries and potential roadblocks in leiomyoma treatment will be addressed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Search methods:&lt;/em&gt; A comprehensive PubMed search was performed to identify published articles containing keywords relevant to the focus of the review, such as: uterine leiomyoma, uterine fibroids, epigenetic alterations, epigenomics, stem cells, chromatin modifications, extracellular matrix [ECM] organization, DNA methylation, enhancer, histone post-translational modifications and dysregulated gene expression. Articles until September 2021 were explored and evaluated to identify relevant updates in the field. Most of the articles focused on in the discussion were published between 2015 and 2021, although some key discoveries made before 2015 were included for background information and foundational purposes. We apologize to the authors whose work was not included because of space restrictions or inadvertent omission.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Outcomes:&lt;/em&gt; Chemical alterations to the DNA structure and of nucleosomal histones, without changing the underlying DNA sequence, have now been implicated in the phenotypic manifestation of uterine leiomyomas. Genome-wide DNA methylation analysis has revealed subsets of either suppressed or overexpressed genes accompanied by aberrant promoter methylation. Furthermore, differential promoter access resulting from altered 3D chromatin structure and histone modifications plays a role in regulating transcription of key genes thought to be involved in leiomyoma etiology. The dysregulated genes function in tumor suppression, apoptosis, angiogenesis, ECM formation, a variety of cancer-related signaling pathways and stem cell differentiation. Aberrant DNA methylation or histone modification is also observed in altering enhancer architecture, which leads to changes in enhancer-promoter contact strength, producing novel explanations for the overexpression of high mobility group AT-hook 2 and gene dysregulation found in mediator complex subunit 12 mutant fibroids. While many molecular mechanisms and epigenomic features have been investigated, the basis for the racial disparity observed among those in the Black population remains unclear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Wider implications:&lt;/em&gt; A comprehensive understanding of the exact pathogenesis of uterine leiomyoma is lacking and requires attention as it can provide clues for prevention and viable non-surgical treatment. These findings will widen our knowledge of the role epigenomics plays in the mechanisms related to uterine leiomyoma development and highlight novel approaches for the prevention and identification of epigenome targets for long-term non-invasive treatment options of this significantly common disease.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Long noncoding RNA EIF1AX-AS1 promotes endometrial cancer cell apoptosis by affecting EIF1AX mRNA stabilization</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35080085/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35080085/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Long noncoding RNAs (lncRNAs) have been found to play an important role in the occurrence and development of endometrial carcinoma (EC). Here, using RNA sequencing analysis, we systemically screened and identified the lncRNA eukaryotic translation initiation factor 1A, X-linked (EIF1AX)-AS1, which is aberrantly downregulated in clinical EC tissues and closely correlated with tumor type. &lt;em&gt;EIF1AX-AS1&lt;/em&gt; markedly inhibited EC cell proliferation and promoted apoptosis in vitro and in vivo. Mechanistically, &lt;em&gt;EIF1AX-AS1&lt;/em&gt; interacts with &lt;em&gt;EIF1AX&lt;/em&gt; mRNA and poly C binding protein 1 (PCBP1), which promote &lt;em&gt;EIF1AX&lt;/em&gt; mRNA degradation. Intriguingly, by interacting with internal ribosome entry site-related protein Y-box binding protein 1 (YBX-1), EIF1AX promotes c-Myc translation through the internal ribosome entry site pathway. c-Myc promotes &lt;em&gt;EIF1AX&lt;/em&gt; transcription and thus forms a feed-forward loop to regulate EC cell proliferation. Taken together, these data reveal new insights into the biology driving EC proliferation and highlights the potential of lncRNAs as biomarkers for prognosis and future therapeutic targets for cancer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
