<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Regeneration | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/regeneration/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/regeneration/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Regeneration</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Regeneration</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/regeneration/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>YAP-regulated type II alveolar epithelial cell differentiation mediated by human umbilical cord-derived mesenchymal stem cells in acute respiratory distress syndrome</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36701989/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36701989/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;hUC-MSCs reduced lung injury and inflammation in mice with LPS-induced ARDS.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dynamic YAP regulation on AECII was mediated by hUC-MSCs in LPS-induced ARDS.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Inactivation of YAP facilitated LPS-induced AECII differentiation in response to hUC-MSCs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;hUC-MSCs may have potential in the treatment of ARDS.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acute respiratory distress syndrome (ARDS) contributes to higher mortality worldwide. Human umbilical cord-derived mesenchymal stem cells (hUC-MSCs) have immunomodulatory and regenerative potential. However, the effects of hUC-MSCs as an ARDS treatment remain unclear. We investigated the role of hUC-MSCs in the differentiation of type II alveolar epithelial cells (AECII) by regulating Yes-associated protein (YAP) in ARDS. Male C57BL/6JNarl mice were intratracheally (i.t.) administered lipopolysaccharide (LPS) to induce an ARDS model, followed by a single intravenous (i.v.) dose of hUC-MSCs. hUC-MSCs improved pulmonary function, decreased inflammation on day 3, and mitigated lung injury by reducing the lung injury score and increasing lung aeration (%) in mice on day 7 (&lt;em&gt;p&lt;/em&gt; &amp;lt; 0.05). hUC-MSCs inactivated YAP on AECII and facilitated cell differentiation by decreasing Pro-surfactant protein C (Pro-SPC) and galectin 3 (LGALS3) while increasing podoplanin (T1α) in lungs of mice (&lt;em&gt;p&lt;/em&gt; &amp;lt; 0.05). In AECII MLE-12 cells, both coculture with hUC-MSCs after LPS exposure and the YAP inhibitor, verteporfin, reduced Pro-SPC and LGALS3, whereas the YAP inhibitor increased T1α expression (&lt;em&gt;p&lt;/em&gt; &amp;lt; 0.05). In conclusion, hUC-MSCs ameliorated lung injury of ARDS and regulated YAP to facilitate AECII differentiation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A natural biological adhesive from snail mucus for wound repair</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36693849/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36693849/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The discovery of natural adhesion phenomena and mechanisms has advanced the development of a new generation of tissue adhesives in recent decades. In this study, we develop a natural biological adhesive from snail mucus gel, which consists a network of positively charged protein and polyanionic glycosaminoglycan. The malleable bulk adhesive matrix can adhere to wet tissue through multiple interactions. The biomaterial exhibits excellent haemostatic activity, biocompatibility and biodegradability, and it is effective in accelerating the healing of full-thickness skin wounds in both normal and diabetic male rats. Further mechanistic study shows it effectively promotes the polarization of macrophages towards the anti-inflammatory phenotype, alleviates inflammation in chronic wounds, and significantly improves epithelial regeneration and angiogenesis. Its abundant heparin-like glycosaminoglycan component is the main active ingredient. These findings provide theoretical and material insights into bio-inspired tissue adhesives and bioengineered scaffold designs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Renal interstitial cells promote nephron regeneration by secreting prostaglandin E2</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36645741/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36645741/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In organ regeneration, progenitor and stem cells reside in their native microenvironment, which provides dynamic physical and chemical cues essential to their survival, proliferation, and differentiation. However, the types of cells that form the native microenvironment for renal progenitor cells (RPCs) have not been clarified. Here, single-cell sequencing of zebrafish kidney reveals fabp10a as a principal marker of renal interstitial cells (RICs), which can be specifically labeled by GFP under the control of fabp10a promoter in the fabp10a:GFP transgenic zebrafish. During nephron regeneration, the formation of nephrons is supported by RICs that form a network to wrap the RPC aggregates. RICs that are in close contact with RPC aggregates express Cyclooxygenase 2 (Cox2) and secrete prostaglandin E2 (PGE2). Inhibiting PGE2 production prevents nephrogenesis by reducing the proliferation of RPCs. PGE2 cooperates with Wnt4a to promote nephron maturation by regulating β-catenin stability of RPC aggregates. Overall, these findings indicate that RICs provide a necessary microenvironment for rapid nephrogenesis during nephron regeneration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intradermally delivered mRNA-encapsulating extracellular vesicles for collagen-replacement therapy</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36635419/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36635419/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The success of messenger RNA therapeutics largely depends on the availability of delivery systems that enable the safe, effective and stable translation of genetic material into functional proteins. Here we show that extracellular vesicles (EVs) produced via cellular nanoporation from human dermal fibroblasts, and encapsulating mRNA encoding for extracellular-matrix α1 type-I collagen (COL1A1) induced the formation of collagen-protein grafts and reduced wrinkle formation in the collagen-depleted dermal tissue of mice with photoaged skin. We also show that the intradermal delivery of the mRNA-loaded EVs via a microneedle array led to the prolonged and more uniform synthesis and replacement of collagen in the dermis of the animals. The intradermal delivery of EV-based COL1A1 mRNA may make for an effective protein-replacement therapy for the treatment of photoaged skin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bioactive glass-elicited stem cell-derived extracellular vesicles regulate M2 macrophage polarization and angiogenesis to improve tendon regeneration and functional recovery</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36641814/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36641814/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Effective countermeasures for tendon injury remains unsatisfactory. Mesenchymal stem cell-derived extracellular vesicles (MSC-EVs)-based therapy via regulation of Mφ-mediated angiogenesis has emerged as a promising strategy for tissue regeneration. Still, approaches to tailor the functions of EVs to treat tendon injuries have been limited. We reported a novel strategy by applying MSC-EVs boosted with bioactive glasses (BG). BG-elicited EVs (EVB) showed up-regulation of medicinal miRNAs, including miR-199b-3p and miR-125a-5p, which play a pivotal role in M2 Mφ-mediated angiogenesis. EVB accelerated angiogenesis via the reprogrammed anti-inflammatory M2 Mφs compared with naïve MSC-EVs (EVN). In rodent Achilles tendon rupture model, EVB local administration activated anti-inflammatory responses via M2 polarization and led to a spatial correlation between M2 Mφs and newly formed blood vessels. Our results showed that EVB outperformed EVN in promoting tenogenesis and in reducing detrimental morphological changes without causing heterotopic ossification. Biomechanical test revealed that EVB significantly improved ultimate load, stiffness, and tensile modulus of the repaired tendon, along with a positive correlation between M2/M1 ratio and biomechanical properties. On the basis of the boosted nature to reprogram regenerative microenvironment, EVB holds considerable potential to be developed as a next-generation therapeutic modality for enhancing functional regeneration to achieve satisfying tendon regeneration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Effects of short-term high-concentration exposure to PM2.5 on pulmonary tissue damage and repair ability as well as innate immune events</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36632972/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36632972/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Short-term heavy air pollution still occurs frequently worldwide, especially during the winter heating period in some developing countries, which is usually accompanied by the temporary explosive growth of PM&lt;sub&gt;2.5&lt;/sub&gt;. The pulmonary damage caused by PM&lt;sub&gt;2.5&lt;/sub&gt; exposure has been determined, but there have been few studies on the repair ability after the cessation of exposure and the important role of innate immune events. This study established a short-term (30 days) high-concentration (15 mg/kg body weight) PM&lt;sub&gt;2.5&lt;/sub&gt; exposure and recovery (15 days of exposure cessation) model by intratracheal instillation. The results showed that short-term PM&lt;sub&gt;2.5&lt;/sub&gt; exposure increased the content of collagen fiber in rat lung tissue, which was significantly repaired after recovery by 15 days of exposure cessation. Meanwhile, exposure to PM&lt;sub&gt;2.5&lt;/sub&gt; also caused changes in lung epithelial function, macrophage polarization and cell autophagy function. Most of these changes could be restored or reversed to a certain extent after recovery. However, there were also some biomarkers, including CLDN18.1, SP-A, SP-D, iNOS, CD206, Beclin1, p62 and LC3B, that were still significantly different between the exposure and control groups after recovery, suggesting that some toxic effects, especially epithelial function damage, were not completely repaired. In addition, there was a significant correlation between pulmonary fibrosis and innate immunity. The present study demonstrated that short-term high-concentration exposure to PM&lt;sub&gt;2.5&lt;/sub&gt; could cause temporary lung tissue damage and related innate immune events in rats, and the repair ability existed after the cessation of exposure, but part of the damage that required special attention still persisted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Endothelial cell-derived exosomes boost and maintain repair-related phenotypes of Schwann cells via miR199-5p to promote nerve regeneration</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36624511/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36624511/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Schwann cells (SCs) respond to nerve injury by transforming into the repair-related cell phenotype, which can provide the essential signals and spatial cues to promote axonal regeneration and induce target reinnervation. Endothelial cells (ECs) contribute to intraneural angiogenesis contributing to creating a permissive microenvironment. The coordination between ECs and SCs within injury sites is crucial in the regeneration process, however, it still unclear. As the intercellular vital information mediators in the nervous system, exosomes have been proposed to take a significant role in regulating regeneration. Thus, the main purpose of this study is to determine the facilitative effect of ECs-derived exosomes on SCs and to seek the underlying mechanism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; In the present study, we collected exosomes from media of ECs. We demonstrated that exosomes derived from ECs possessed the favorable neuronal affinity both in vitro and in vivo. Further research indicated that EC-exosomes (EC-EXO) could boost and maintain repair-related phenotypes of SCs, thereby enhancing axonal regeneration, myelination of regenerated axons and neurologically functional recovery of the injured nerve. MiRNA sequencing in EXO-treated SCs and control SCs indicated that EC-EXO significantly up-regulated expression of miR199-5p. Furthermore, this study demonstrated that EC-EXO drove the conversion of SC phenotypes in a PI3K/AKT/PTEN-dependent manner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/em&gt; In conclusion, our research indicates that the internalization of EC-EXO in SCs can promote nerve regeneration by boosting and maintaining the repair-related phenotypes of SCs. And the mechanism may be relevant to the up-regulated expression of miR199-5p and activation of PI3K/AKT/PTEN signaling pathway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Immunity to the microbiota promotes sensory neuron regeneration</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36640762/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36640762/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Microbiota-induced T cells accelerate sensory neuron regeneration upon injury&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Injury promotes the expression of IL-17RA in dorsal root ganglion sensory neurons&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IL-17/IL-17RA axis promotes peripheral sensory neuron regeneration&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tissue immunity and responses to injury depend on the coordinated action and communication among physiological systems. Here, we show that, upon injury, adaptive responses to the microbiota directly promote sensory neuron regeneration. At homeostasis, tissue-resident commensal-specific T cells colocalize with sensory nerve fibers within the dermis, express a transcriptional program associated with neuronal interaction and repair, and promote axon growth and local nerve regeneration following injury. Mechanistically, our data reveal that the cytokine interleukin-17A (IL-17A) released by commensal-specific Th17 cells upon injury directly signals to sensory neurons via IL-17 receptor A, the transcription of which is specifically upregulated in injured neurons. Collectively, our work reveals that in the context of tissue damage, preemptive immunity to the microbiota can rapidly bridge biological systems by directly promoting neuronal repair, while also identifying IL-17A as a major determinant of this fundamental process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A DLG1-ARHGAP31-CDC42 axis is essential for the intestinal stem cell response to fluctuating niche Wnt signaling</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36640764/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36640764/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Polarity of the mammalian intestinal epithelium is independent of &lt;em&gt;Dlg1&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Loss of &lt;em&gt;Dlg1&lt;/em&gt; in ISCs results in cell death under high Wnt conditions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ISCs lacking &lt;em&gt;Dlg1&lt;/em&gt; have impaired cell division and migration&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Canonical WNT ligands activate non-canonical Wnt signaling via DLG1-ARHGAP31-CDC42&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A central factor in the maintenance of tissue integrity is the response of stem cells to variations in the levels of niche signals. In the gut, intestinal stem cells (ISCs) depend on Wnt ligands for self-renewal and proliferation. Transient increases in Wnt signaling promote regeneration after injury or in inflammatory bowel diseases, whereas constitutive activation of this pathway leads to colorectal cancer. Here, we report that Discs large 1 (&lt;em&gt;Dlg1&lt;/em&gt;), although dispensable for polarity and cellular turnover during intestinal homeostasis, is required for ISC survival in the context of increased Wnt signaling. RNA sequencing (RNA-seq) and genetic mouse models demonstrated that DLG1 regulates the cellular response to increased canonical Wnt ligands. This occurs via the transcriptional regulation of &lt;em&gt;Arhgap31&lt;/em&gt;, a GTPase-activating protein that deactivates CDC42, an effector of the non-canonical Wnt pathway. These findings reveal a DLG1-ARHGAP31-CDC42 axis that is essential for the ISC response to increased niche Wnt signaling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bionic artificial penile Tunica albuginea</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/matt.2022.11.032/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/matt.2022.11.032/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A method for preparing hydrogels with parallel wavy fibers was developed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ATA with a bionic double-layer structure was prepared&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ATA has bionic mechanical properties and biocompatibility and can repair TA injury&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This approach could provide a common platform for future tissue analog preparations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The mammalian tunica albuginea (TA) is characterized by a double-layer orthogonal structure composed of stacked parallel wavy collagen fibers. During an erection, these fibers undergo sequential straightening and stretching to mediate the soft-to-firm transition. Inspired by the delicate strain-adaptive structure of natural TA, we propose an artificial TA (ATA) composed of a strain-stiffening hydrogel consisting of aligned yet crimped fibers. This delicate structure is produced via the stretching of an isotropic polyvinyl alcohol gel followed by covalent cross-linking. ATA possesses several key mechanical features of natural TA, including rapid strain stiffening over small intervals of deformation, excellent fatigue resistance to sustain cyclic bursts, and high toughness to withstand pointwise acupuncture during suturing. Furthermore, ATA displays the capability to repair injuries and restore normal erectile function of the TA-damaged penile tissue in a pig model. Our study demonstrates that ATA has great promise for penile injury repair.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Progress and potential&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A mammalian tunica albuginea (TA) is characterized by a double-layer orthogonal structure composed of stacked parallel wavy collagen fibrils. A TA mimic fiber with directional crimping was synthesized in this study by stretching an isotropic polyvinyl alcohol gel followed by covalent cross-linking to permanently fix the parallel aligned curved structures. Similar to the sequential response of the crimped structure in natural TA, the curved fibers first straighten to absorb strain and then stretch to induce a soft-to-firm transition. The proposed method paves the way for building a variety of weight-bearing organizations. Through the imitation of the structure, performance matching can be achieved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commensal microbiome promotes hair follicle regeneration by inducing keratinocyte HIF-1α signaling and glutamine metabolism</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36598999/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36598999/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tissue injury induces metabolic changes in stem cells, which likely modulate regeneration. Using a model of organ regeneration called wound-induced hair follicle neogenesis (WIHN), we identified skin-resident bacteria as key modulators of keratinocyte metabolism, demonstrating a positive correlation between bacterial load, glutamine metabolism, and regeneration. Specifically, through comprehensive multiomic analysis and single-cell RNA sequencing in murine skin, we show that bacterially induced hypoxia drives increased glutamine metabolism in keratinocytes with attendant enhancement of skin and hair follicle regeneration. In human skin wounds, topical broad-spectrum antibiotics inhibit glutamine production and are partially responsible for reduced healing. These findings reveal a conserved and coherent physiologic context in which bacterially induced metabolic changes improve the tolerance of stem cells to damage and enhance regenerative capacity. This unexpected proregenerative modulation of metabolism by the skin microbiome in both mice and humans suggests important methods for enhancing regeneration after injury.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TRIM27 maintains gut homeostasis by promoting intestinal stem cell self-renewal</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36596873/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36596873/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dysregulation of gut homeostasis is associated with irritable bowel syndrome (IBS), a chronic functional gastrointestinal disorder affecting approximately 11.2% of the global population. The poorly understood pathogenesis of IBS has impeded its treatment. Here, we report that the E3 ubiquitin ligase tripartite motif-containing 27 (TRIM27) is weakly expressed in IBS but highly expressed in inflammatory bowel disease (IBD), a frequent chronic organic gastrointestinal disorder. Accordingly, knockout of &lt;em&gt;Trim27&lt;/em&gt; in mice causes spontaneously occurring IBS-like symptoms, including increased visceral hyperalgesia and abnormal stool features, as observed in IBS patients. Mechanistically, TRIM27 stabilizes β-catenin and thus activates Wnt/β-catenin signaling to promote intestinal stem cell (ISC) self-renewal. Consistent with these findings, &lt;em&gt;Trim27&lt;/em&gt; deficiency disrupts organoid formation, which is rescued by reintroducing TRIM27 or β-catenin. Furthermore, Wnt/β-catenin signaling activator treatment ameliorates IBS symptoms by promoting ISC self-renewal. Taken together, these data indicate that TRIM27 is critical for maintaining gut homeostasis, suggesting that targeting the TRIM27/Wnt/β-catenin axis could be a potential treatment strategy for IBS. Our study also indicates that TRIM27 might serve as a potential biomarker for differentiating IBS from IBD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generation of bioactive MSC-EVs for bone tissue regeneration by tauroursodeoxycholic acid treatment</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36586671/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36586671/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Extracellular vesicles (EVs) are nano-sized carriers that reflect the parent cell&amp;rsquo;s information and are known to mediate cell-cell communication. In order to overcome the disadvantages of mesenchymal stem cells (MSCs) in cell therapy, such as unexpected differentiation leading to tumorization, immune rejection, and other side effects, EVs derived from MSCs (MSC-EVs) with the tissue regenerative function have been studied as new cell-free therapeutics. However, therapeutic applications of EVs require overcoming several challenges. First, the production efficiency of MSC-EVs should be increased at least as much as the quantity of them are required to their clinical application; second, MSC-EVs needs to show various functionality further, thereby increasing tissue regeneration efficiency. In this study, we treated tauroursodeoxycholic acid (TUDCA), a biological derivative known to regulate cholesterol, to MSCs and investigated whether TUDCA treatment would be able to increase EV production efficiency and tissue regenerative capacity of EVs. Indeed, it appears that TUDCA priming to MSC increases the yield of MSC-EVs &amp;gt;2 times by reducing the cellular cholesterol level in MSCs and increasing the exocytosis-related CAV1 expression. Interestingly, it was found that the EVs derived from TUDCA-primed MSCs (T-EV) contained higher amounts of anti-inflammatory cytokines (IL1RN, IL6, IL10, and IL11) and osteogenic proteins (ALP, RUNX2, BMP2, BMPR1, and BMPR2) than those in control MSC-EVs (C-EV). Besides, it was shown that T-EV not only regulated M1/M2 macrophages differentiation of monocytes, also effectively increased the osteogenic differentiation of MSCs as well as bone tissue regeneration in a bone defect rat model. Based on these results, it is concluded that TUDCA treatment to MSC as a new approach endows EV with high-yield production and functionality. Thus, we strongly believe T-EV would be a powerful therapeutic material for bone tissue regeneration and potentially could be expanded to other types of tissue regeneration for clinical applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rngtt governs biliary-derived liver regeneration initiation by transcriptional regulation of mTORC1 and Dnmt1 in zebrafish</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/hep.0000000000000186/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/hep.0000000000000186/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In cases of end-stage liver diseases, the proliferation of existing hepatocytes is compromised, a feature of human chronic liver disease, in which most hepatocytes are dysfunctional. So far, liver transplantation represents the only curative therapeutic solution for advanced liver diseases, and the shortage of donor organs leads to high morbidity and mortality worldwide. The promising treatment is to prompt the biliary epithelial cells (BECs) transdifferentiation. However, the critical factors governing the initiation of BEC-derived liver regeneration are largely unknown. The zebrafish has advantages in large-scale genetic screens to identify the critical factors involved in liver regeneration. Here, we combined N-ethyl-N-nitrosourea screen, positional cloning, transgenic lines, antibody staining, and in situ hybridization methods and identified a liver regeneration defect mutant (lrd) using the zebrafish extensive liver injury model. Through positional cloning and genomic sequencing, we mapped the mutation site to rngtt. Loss of rngtt lead to the defects of BEC dedifferentiation, bipotential progenitor cell activation, and cell proliferation in the initiation stage of liver regeneration. The transdifferentiation from BECs to hepatocytes did not occur even at the late stage of liver regeneration. Mechanically, Rngtt transcriptionally regulates the attachment of mRNA cap to mTORC1 components and dnmt1 to maintain the activation of mTORC1 and DNA methylation in BECs after severe liver injury and prompt BEC to hepatocyte conversion. Furthermore, rptor and dnmt1 mutants displayed the same liver regeneration defects as rngtt mutation. In conclusion, our results suggest Rngtt is a new factor that initiates BEC-derived liver regeneration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transcript shortening via alternative polyadenylation promotes gene expression during fracture healing</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36596777/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36596777/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maturation of the 3&amp;rsquo; end of almost all eukaryotic messenger RNAs (mRNAs) requires cleavage and polyadenylation. Most mammalian mRNAs are polyadenylated at different sites within the last exon, generating alternative polyadenylation (APA) isoforms that have the same coding region but distinct 3&amp;rsquo; untranslated regions (UTRs). The 3&amp;rsquo;UTR contains motifs that regulate mRNA metabolism; thus, changing the 3&amp;rsquo;UTR length via APA can significantly affect gene expression. Endochondral ossification is a central process in bone healing, but the impact of APA on gene expression during this process is unknown. Here, we report the widespread occurrence of APA, which impacts multiple pathways that are known to participate in bone healing. Importantly, the progression of endochondral ossification involves global 3&amp;rsquo;UTR shortening, which is coupled with an increased abundance of shortened transcripts relative to other transcripts; these results highlight the role of APA in promoting gene expression during endochondral bone formation. Our mechanistic studies of transcripts that undergo APA in the fracture callus revealed an intricate regulatory network in which APA enhances the expression of the collagen, type I, alpha 1 (Col1a1) and Col1a2 genes, which encode the 2 subunits of the abundantly expressed protein collagen 1. APA exerts this effect by shortening the 3&amp;rsquo;UTRs of the Col1a1 and Col1a2 mRNAs, thus removing the binding sites of miR-29a-3p, which would otherwise strongly promote the degradation of both transcripts. Taken together, our study is the first to characterize the crucial roles of APA in regulating the 3&amp;rsquo;UTR landscape and modulating gene expression during fracture healing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neutrophil Extracellular Traps Delay Diabetic Wound Healing by Inducing Endothelial-to-Mesenchymal Transition via the Hippo pathway</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36594092/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36594092/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Diabetic foot ulcers (DFUs) are among the most frequent complications of diabetes with significant morbidity and mortality. Diabetes can trigger neutrophils to undergo histone citrullination by protein arginine deiminase 4 (encoded by Padi4 in mice) and release neutrophil extracellular traps (NETs). The specific mechanism of NETs-mediated wound healing impairment in diabetes remains unknown. In this study, we show neutrophils are more susceptible to NETosis in diabetic wound environments. Via in vitro experiments and in vivo models of wound healing using wide-type and Padi4 -/- mice, we demonstrate NETs can induce the activation of PAK2 via the membrane receptor TLR-9. Then PAK2 phosphorylates the intracellular protein Merlin/NF2 to inhibit the Hippo-YAP pathway. YAP binds to transcription factor SMAD2 and translocates from the cytoplasm into the nucleus to promote endothelial-to-mesenchymal transition (EndMT), which ultimately impedes angiogenesis and delays wound healing. Suppression of the Merlin/YAP/SMAD2 pathway can attenuate NET-induced EndMT. Inhibition of NETosis accelerates wound healing by reducing EndMT and promoting angiogenesis. Cumulatively, these data suggest NETosis delays diabetic wound healing by inducing EndMT via the Hippo-YAP pathway. Increased understanding of the molecular mechanism that regulates NETosis and EndMT will be of considerable value for providing cellular targets amenable to therapeutic intervention for DFUs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Senescence atlas reveals an aged-like inflamed niche that blunts muscle regeneration</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36544018/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36544018/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tissue regeneration requires coordination between resident stem cells and local niche cells1,2. Here we identify that senescent cells are integral components of the skeletal muscle regenerative niche that repress regeneration at all stages of life. The technical limitation of senescent-cell scarcity3 was overcome by combining single-cell transcriptomics and a senescent-cell enrichment sorting protocol. We identified and isolated different senescent cell types from damaged muscles of young and old mice. Deeper transcriptome, chromatin and pathway analyses revealed conservation of cell identity traits as well as two universal senescence hallmarks (inflammation and fibrosis) across cell type, regeneration time and ageing. Senescent cells create an aged-like inflamed niche that mirrors inflammation associated with ageing (inflammageing4) and arrests stem cell proliferation and regeneration. Reducing the burden of senescent cells, or reducing their inflammatory secretome through CD36 neutralization, accelerates regeneration in young and old mice. By contrast, transplantation of senescent cells delays regeneration. Our results provide a technique for isolating in vivo senescent cells, define a senescence blueprint for muscle, and uncover unproductive functional interactions between senescent cells and stem cells in regenerative niches that can be overcome. As senescent cells also accumulate in human muscles, our findings open potential paths for improving muscle repair throughout life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tubular epithelial cells-derived small extracellular vesicle-VEGF-A promotes peritubular capillary repair in ischemic kidney injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36528739/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36528739/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Peritubular capillaries (PTCs) are closely related to renal tubules in structure and function, and both are pivotal regulators in the development and progression of acute kidney injury (AKI). However, the mechanisms that underlie the interaction between PTCs and tubules during AKI remain unclear. Here we explored a new mode of tubulovascular crosstalk mediated by small extracellular vesicles (sEV) after AKI. In response to renal ischemia/reperfusion (I/R) injury, endothelial proliferation of PTCs and tubular expression of vascular endothelial growth factor-A (VEGF-A) were increased, accompanied by a remarkable redistribution of cytoplasmic VEGF-A to the basolateral side of tubular cells. Meanwhile, the secretion mode of VEGF-A was converted in the injured tubular cells, which showed a much greater tendency to secrete VEGF-A via sEV other than the free form. Interestingly, tubular cell-derived VEGF-A-enriched sEV (sEV-VEGF-A) turned out to promote endothelial proliferation which was regulated by VEGF receptors 1 and 2. Furthermore, inhibition of renal sEV secretion by Rab27a knockdown resulted in a significant decrease in the proliferation of peritubular endothelial cells in vivo. Importantly, taking advantage of the newly recognized endogenous repair response of PTCs, exogenous supplementation of VEGF-A + sEV efficiently recused PTC rarefaction, improved renal perfusion, and halted the AKI to CKD transition. Taken together, our study uncovered a novel intrinsic repair response after AKI through renal tubule-PTC crosstalk via sEV-VEGF-A, which could be exploited as a promising therapeutic angiogenesis strategy in diseases with ischemia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fibroblast inflammatory priming determines regenerative versus fibrotic skin repair in reindeer</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36493752/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36493752/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reindeer antler velvet regenerates after wounding whereas back skin forms a scar&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fibroblasts direct site-specific immune cell recruitment and differentiation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fibroblast fate reversion and absence of inflammatory signals enables regeneration&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Obstructing fibroblast inflammatory signals enhances skin regeneration&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Summary&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adult mammalian skin wounds heal by forming fibrotic scars. We report that full-thickness injuries of reindeer antler skin (velvet) regenerate, whereas back skin forms fibrotic scar. Single-cell multi-omics reveal that uninjured velvet fibroblasts resemble human fetal fibroblasts, whereas back skin fibroblasts express inflammatory mediators mimicking pro-fibrotic adult human and rodent fibroblasts. Consequently, injury elicits site-specific immune responses: back skin fibroblasts amplify myeloid infiltration and maturation during repair, whereas velvet fibroblasts adopt an immunosuppressive phenotype that restricts leukocyte recruitment and hastens immune resolution. Ectopic transplantation of velvet to scar-forming back skin is initially regenerative, but progressively transitions to a fibrotic phenotype akin to the scarless fetal-to-scar-forming transition reported in humans. Skin regeneration is diminished by intensifying, or enhanced by neutralizing, these pathologic fibroblast-immune interactions. Reindeer represent a powerful comparative model for interrogating divergent wound healing outcomes, and our results nominate decoupling of fibroblast-immune interactions as a promising approach to mitigate scar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Targeting endogenous kidney regeneration using anti-IL11 therapy in acute and chronic models of kidney disease</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36470928/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36470928/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The kidney has large regenerative capacity, but this is compromised when kidney damage is excessive and renal tubular epithelial cells (TECs) undergo SNAI1-driven growth arrest. Here we investigate the role of IL11 in TECs, kidney injury and renal repair. IL11 stimulation of TECs induces ERK- and p90RSK-mediated GSK3β inactivation, SNAI1 upregulation and pro-inflammatory gene expression. Mice with acute kidney injury upregulate IL11 in TECs leading to SNAI1 expression and kidney dysfunction, which is not seen in Il11 deleted mice or in mice administered a neutralizing IL11 antibody in either preemptive or treatment modes. In acute kidney injury, anti-TGFβ reduces renal fibrosis but exacerbates inflammation and tubule damage whereas anti-IL11 reduces all pathologies. Mice with TEC-specific deletion of Il11ra1 have reduced pathogenic signaling and are protected from renal injury-induced inflammation, fibrosis, and failure. In a model of chronic kidney disease, anti-IL11 therapy promotes TEC proliferation and parenchymal regeneration, reverses fibroinflammation and restores renal mass and function. These data highlight IL11-induced mesenchymal transition of injured TECs as an important renal pathology and suggest IL11 as a therapeutic target for restoring stalled endogenous regeneration in the diseased kidney.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tropoelastin Improves Post-Infarct Cardiac Function</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36453283/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36453283/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Myocardial infarction (MI) is among the leading causes of death worldwide. Following MI, necrotic cardiomyocytes are replaced by a stiff collagen-rich scar. Compared to collagen, the extracellular matrix protein elastin has high elasticity and may have more favorable properties within the cardiac scar. We sought to improve post-MI healing by introducing tropoelastin, the soluble subunit of elastin, to alter scar mechanics early after MI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods and results:&lt;/em&gt; We developed an ultrasound-guided direct intramyocardial injection method to administer tropoelastin directly into the left ventricular anterior wall of rats subjected to induced MI. Experimental groups included shams and infarcted rats injected with either PBS vehicle control or tropoelastin. Compared to vehicle treated controls, echocardiography assessments showed tropoelastin significantly improved left ventricular ejection fraction (64.7±4.4% versus 46.0±3.1% control) and reduced left ventricular dyssynchrony (11.4±3.5 ms versus 31.1±5.8 ms control) 28 days post-MI. Additionally, tropoelastin reduced post-MI scar size (8.9±1.5% versus 20.9±2.7% control) and increased scar elastin (22±5.8% versus 6.2±1.5% control) as determined by histological assessments. RNA sequencing (RNAseq) analyses of rat infarcts showed that tropoelastin injection increased genes associated with elastic fiber formation 7 days post-MI and reduced genes associated with immune response 11 days post-MI. To show translational relevance, we performed immunohistochemical analyses on human ischemic heart disease cardiac samples and showed an increase in tropoelastin within fibrotic areas. Using RNA-seq we also demonstrated the tropoelastin gene ELN is upregulated in human ischemic heart disease and during human cardiac fibroblast-myofibroblast differentiation. Furthermore, we showed by immunocytochemistry that human cardiac fibroblast synthesize increased elastin in direct response to tropoelastin treatment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; We demonstrate for the first time that purified human tropoelastin can significantly repair the infarcted heart in a rodent model of MI and that human cardiac fibroblast synthesize elastin. Since human cardiac fibroblasts are primarily responsible for post-MI scar synthesis, our findings suggest exciting future clinical translation options designed to therapeutically manipulate this synthesis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Injectable double-network hydrogel for corneal repair</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/cej.2022.140698/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/cej.2022.140698/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Injuries to the cornea can cause corneal opacity or even blindness. Especially scald wounds and chemical burns to the cornea can usually lead to loss of corneal epithelium function and deep damage to the corneal stroma. Injectable hydrogel has been widely applied in corneal tissue engineering because it is easy to handle and can completely fill the defect area with minimally invasive surgical procedures. To reduce the risk and complications of penetrating keratoplasty and lamellar keratoplasty and to meet the demand for donated cornea, an injectable double-network (IDN) hydrogel based on methacrylated gelatin (Gel-MA) and oxidized hyaluronic acid (OHA) was constructed for focal corneal defect repairing. The Gel-MA/OHA IDN hydrogel had an interconnected porous microstructure and tunable mechanical properties with a modulus between 3.4 and 176.4 kPa. The hydrogel could promote cell adhesion and proliferation and afford the sustained release of hydrophilic/hydrophobic drugs. &lt;em&gt;In-vivo&lt;/em&gt; corneal repair was performed by injecting the precursors into the pre-drilled epithelial-stromal defects of New Zealand White rabbits followed by immediate &lt;em&gt;in-situ&lt;/em&gt; UV crosslinking. The results showed that the hydrogel had a strong capacity to promote corneal regeneration. Optical coherence tomography, slip lamp, fluorescein staining, scanning electron microscopy (SEM), and haematoxylin &amp;amp; eosin (H&amp;amp;E) staining were employed to illustrate the effectiveness and safety of corneal tissue regeneration. All the results showed that the optimized Gel-MA/OHA IDN hydrogel possessed excellent biocompatibility and could promote cornea repair &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt;. This study suggests that the injectable biocompatible double network hydrogel may provide a good choice for corneal repair and regeneration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generation of neural organoids for spinal-cord regeneration via the direct reprogramming of human astrocytes</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36424465/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36424465/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Organoids with region-specific architecture could facilitate the repair of injuries of the central nervous system. Here we show that human astrocytes can be directly reprogrammed into early neuroectodermal cells via the overexpression of &lt;em&gt;OCT4&lt;/em&gt;, the suppression of &lt;em&gt;p53&lt;/em&gt; and the provision of the small molecules CHIR99021, SB431542, RepSox and Y27632. We also report that the activation of signalling mediated by fibroblast growth factor, sonic hedgehog and bone morphogenetic protein 4 in the reprogrammed cells induces them to form spinal-cord organoids with functional neurons specific to the dorsal and ventral domains. In mice with complete spinal-cord injury, organoids transplanted into the lesion differentiated into spinal-cord neurons, which migrated and formed synapses with host neurons. The direct reprogramming of human astrocytes into neurons may pave the way for in vivo neural organogenesis from endogenous astrocytes for the repair of injuries to the central nervous system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Do Extracellular Vesicles Play a Key Role in the Maintenance of Bone Homeostasis and Regeneration? A Comprehensive Review of Literature</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/36419718/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/36419718/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The maintenance of bone homeostasis includes both bone resorption by osteoclasts and bone formation by osteoblasts. These two processes are in dynamic balance to maintain a constant amount of bone for accomplishing its critical functions in daily life. Multiple cell type communications are involved in these two complex and continuous processes. In recent decades, an increasing number of studies have shown that osteogenic and osteoclastic extracellular vesicles play crucial roles in regulating bone homeostasis through paracrine, autosecretory and endocrine signaling. Elucidating the functional roles of extracellular vesicles in the maintenance of bone homeostasis may contribute to the design of new strategies for bone regeneration. Hence, we review the recent understandings of the classification, production process, extraction methods, structure, contents, functions and applications of extracellular vesicles in bone homeostasis. We highlight the contents of various bone-derived extracellular vesicles and their interactions with different cells in the bone microenvironment during bone homeostasis. We also summarize the recent advances in EV-loaded biomaterial scaffolds for bone regeneration and repair.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GLI1&#43; cells are a source of repair-supportive mesenchymal cells (RSMCs) during airway epithelial regeneration</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36333491/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36333491/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Repair-supportive mesenchymal cells (RSMCs) have been recently reported in the context of naphthalene (NA)-induced airway injury and regeneration. These cells transiently express smooth muscle actin (&lt;em&gt;Acta2&lt;/em&gt;) and are enriched with platelet-derived growth factor receptor alpha (&lt;em&gt;Pdgfra&lt;/em&gt;) and fibroblast growth factor 10 (&lt;em&gt;Fgf10&lt;/em&gt;) expression. Genetic deletion of Ctnnb1 (gene coding for beta catenin) or &lt;em&gt;Fgf10&lt;/em&gt; in these cells using the &lt;em&gt;Acta2-Cre-ERT2&lt;/em&gt; driver line after injury (defined as NA-Tam condition; Tam refers to tamoxifen) led to impaired repair of the airway epithelium. In this study, we demonstrate that RSMCs are mostly captured using the &lt;em&gt;Acta2-Cre-ERT2&lt;/em&gt; driver when labeling occurs after (NA-Tam condition) rather than before injury (Tam-NA condition), and that their expansion occurs mostly between days 3 and 7 following NA treatment. Previous studies have shown that lineage-traced peribronchial GLI1+ cells are transiently amplified after NA injury. Here, we report that &lt;em&gt;Gli1&lt;/em&gt; expression is enriched in RSMCs. Using lineage tracing with Gli1&lt;sup&gt;Cre-ERT2&lt;/sup&gt; mice combined with genetic inactivation of &lt;em&gt;Fgf10&lt;/em&gt;, we show that GLI1+ cells with &lt;em&gt;Fgf10&lt;/em&gt; deletion fail to amplify around the injured airways, thus resulting in impaired airway epithelial repair. Interestingly, &lt;em&gt;Fgf10&lt;/em&gt; expression is not upregulated in GLI1+ cells following NA treatment, suggesting that epithelial repair is mostly due to the increased number of &lt;em&gt;Fgf10&lt;/em&gt;-expressing GLI1+ cells. Co-culture of SCGB1A1+ cells with GLI1+ cells isolated from non-injured or injured lungs showed that GLI1+ cells from these two conditions are similarly capable of supporting bronchiolar organoid (or bronchiolosphere) formation. Single-cell RNA sequencing on sorted lineage-labeled cells showed that the RSMC signature resembles that of alveolar fibroblasts. Altogether, our study provides strong evidence for the involvement of mesenchymal progenitors in airway epithelial regeneration and highlights the critical role played by &lt;em&gt;Fgf10&lt;/em&gt;-expressing GLI1+ cells in this context.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A composite hydrogel containing resveratrol-laden nanoparticles and platelet-derived extracellular vesicles promotes wound healing in diabetic mice</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36309190/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36309190/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Diabetic wounds are difficult to heal because of persistent inflammation and limited angiogenesis. Resveratrol (RES) is an anti-inflammatory and antioxidant agent. Platelet-derived extracellular vesicles (PDEVs) are rich in growth factors and cytokines, which promote proliferation and angiogenesis. However, single drug treatment has limited efficacy and delivery efficiency. Bioengineering can improve the limited effect of single drugs by combining drugs and materials to obtain complementary or cooperative bioengineered drugs. In this study, gelatin methacrylate (GelMA) and silk fibroin glycidyl methacrylate (SFMA) were used to synthesize GelMA/SFMA composite hydrogels with suitable mechanical properties, swelling ratio and biodegradability. The composite hydrogel was used as a wound dressing for sustained drug release. RES was loaded into mesoporous silica nanoparticles (MSNs) to synthesize MSN-RES to enhance the release dynamic, and MSN-RES and PDEVs were combined with the composite hydrogels to form GelMA/SFMA/MSN-RES/PDEVs hydrogels. The GelMA/SFMA/MSN-RES/PDEVs had low cytotoxicity and good biocompatibility, inhibited macrophage iNOS expression, and promoted the tube formation by human umbilical vein endothelial cells (HUVECs) in vitro. In a diabetic mouse wound model, the GelMA/SFMA/MSN-RES/PDEVs hydrogels decreased the expression of pro-inflammatory factors TNF-α and iNOS, increased the expression of anti-inflammatory factors TGF-β1 and Arg-1, promoted angiogenesis, and accelerated wound healing. Interestingly, the GelMA/SFMA/MSN-RES/PDEVs hydrogels promoted the expression of extracellular purinergic signaling pathway-related CD73 and adenosine 2A receptor (A2A-R). Therefore, the GelMA/SFMA/MSN-RES/PDEVs hydrogels could be used as wound dressings to regulate the inflammation and angiogenesis of diabetic wounds and accelerate wound healing. STATEMENT OF SIGNIFICANCE: Drugs often fail to function because of a continuous oxidative stress microenvironment and inflammation. Here, a GelMA/SFMA hydrogel, with enhanced mechanical properties and liquid absorption ability, is proposed for sustained release of drugs. In addition to carrying platelet-derived extracellular vesicles (PDEVs) with pro-angiogenic effects, the hydrogels were also loaded with nanoparticle-encapsulated resveratrol with anti-inflammatory activities, aiming to reduce inflammation and oxidative stress in the wound microenvironment, such that the wound could receive proliferative repair signals to achieve sequential treatment and heal quickly. We also experimentally predicted that the regulatory mechanism of the GelMA/SFMA/MSN-RES/PDEVs in wound healing might be related to the extracellular purinergic signaling pathway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>After the Storm: Regeneration, Repair, and Reestablishment of Homeostasis Between the Alveolar Epithelium and Innate Immune System Following Viral Lung Injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/36270292/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/36270292/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The mammalian lung has an enormous environmental-epithelial interface that is optimized to accomplish the principal function of the respiratory system, gas exchange. One consequence of evolving such a large surface area is that the lung epithelium is continuously exposed to toxins, irritants, and pathogens. Maintaining homeostasis in this environment requires a delicate balance of cellular signaling between the epithelium and innate immune system. Following injury, the epithelium can be either fully regenerated in form and function or repaired by forming dysplastic scar tissue. In this review, we describe the major mechanisms of damage, regeneration, and repair within the alveolar niche where gas exchange occurs. With a focus on viral infection, we summarize recent work that has established how epithelial proliferation is arrested during infection and how the innate immune system guides its reconstitution during recovery. The consequence of these processes going awry are also considered, with an emphasis on how this will impact postpandemic pulmonary biology and medicine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lung epithelium development and airway regeneration</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/36299482/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/36299482/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The lung is composed of a highly branched airway structure, which humidifies and warms the inhaled air before entering the alveolar compartment. In the alveoli, a thin layer of epithelium is in close proximity with the capillary endothelium, allowing for an efficient exchange of oxygen and carbon dioxide. During development proliferation and differentiation of progenitor cells generates the lung architecture, and in the adult lung a proper function of progenitor cells is needed to regenerate after injury. Malfunctioning of progenitors during development results in various congenital lung disorders, such as Congenital Diaphragmatic Hernia (CDH) and Congenital Pulmonary Adenomatoid Malformation (CPAM). In addition, many premature neonates experience continuous insults on the lung caused by artificial ventilation and supplemental oxygen, which requires a highly controlled mechanism of airway repair. Malfunctioning of airway progenitors during regeneration can result in reduction of respiratory function or (chronic) airway diseases. Pathways that are active during development are frequently re-activated upon damage. Understanding the basic mechanisms of lung development and the behavior of progenitor cell in the ontogeny and regeneration of the lung may help to better understand the underlying cause of lung diseases, especially those occurring in prenatal development or in the immediate postnatal period of life. This review provides an overview of lung development and the cell types involved in repair of lung damage with a focus on the airway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Single-cell spatial transcriptomics reveals a dynamic control of metabolic zonation and liver regeneration by endothelial cell Wnt2 and Wnt9b</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36220068/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36220068/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Conserved expression of Wnt2 and Wnt9b in liver endothelial cells is identified&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wnt2 and Wnt9b deletion from endothelial cells affects gene expression in zone 3&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Endothelial Wnt2 and Wnt9b deletion affects liver regeneration after hepatectomy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Late treatment with Wnt agonist rescues regeneration after acetaminophen overdose&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Summary&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The conclusive identity of Wnts regulating liver zonation (LZ) and regeneration (LR) remains unclear despite an undisputed role of β-catenin. Using single-cell analysis, we identified a conserved Wnt2 and Wnt9b expression in endothelial cells (ECs) in zone 3. EC-elimination of Wnt2 and Wnt9b led to both loss of β-catenin targets in zone 3, and re-appearance of zone 1 genes in zone 3, unraveling dynamicity in the LZ process. Impaired LR observed in the knockouts phenocopied models of defective hepatic Wnt signaling. Administration of a tetravalent antibody to activate Wnt signaling rescued LZ and LR in the knockouts and induced zone 3 gene expression and LR in controls. Administration of the agonist also promoted LR in acetaminophen overdose acute liver failure (ALF) fulfilling an unmet clinical need. Overall, we report an unequivocal role of EC-Wnt2 and Wnt9b in LZ and LR and show the role of Wnt activators as regenerative therapy for ALF.
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Antibacterial, adhesive, and MSC exosomes encapsulated microneedles with spatio-temporal variation functions for diabetic wound healing</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/nantod.2022.101630/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/nantod.2022.101630/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MSC-exos therapy show encouraging potential in diabetic wound treatment, but is hampered by insufficient delivery.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A novel spatio-temporal-varying adhesive microneedle patch that combines the advantages of MSC-exos and antibacterial AgNPs for improving wound healing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Efficiency tissue repair and bacteria killing were achieved by the proposed MN patch.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chronic wounds affect healthcare systems and increase the risk of infection. Despite the clinical demand for improving healing, an effective and safe therapeutic approach is still lacking. Here, we present a novel spatio-temporal-varying adhesive microneedle (MN) patch encapsulated with mesenchymal stem cell-derived exosomes (MSC-exos) and antibacterial Ag nanoparticles (AgNPs) for improving wound healing. This MN patch is fabricated by replicating a predesigned flexible template. Consisting of porous methacrylate gelatin hydrogels, the MN tips can continuously deliver anti-inflammatory and pro-angiogenic MSC-exos to wound beds, which can accelerate healing by improving cell functions, remodeling blood vessels and restoring immune systems. Besides, the silk-fibroin-composed MN back enables the patch to stick to the skin well and fix at the wounded site, thus avoiding secondary bandage. By incorporating AgNPs in the MN back, the MN patch is endowed with the ability to efficiently resist microbial contamination and further benefits wound repair. Such a composite MN patch performs well in relieving inflammation, promoting angiogenesis, and suppressing wound-infecting bacteria during wound injury in diabetic rats, with no adverse effects observed. All the features make this multifunctional MN patch potentially valuable for clinical applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Macrophage-specific inhibition of the histone demethylase JMJD3 decreases STING and pathologic inflammation in diabetic wound repair</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36127466/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36127466/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Macrophage plasticity is critical for normal tissue repair following injury. In pathologic states such as diabetes, macrophage plasticity is impaired, and macrophages remain in a persistent proinflammatory state; however, the reasons for this are unknown. Here, using single-cell RNA sequencing of human diabetic wounds, we identified increased JMJD3 in diabetic wound macrophages, resulting in increased inflammatory gene expression. Mechanistically, we report that in wound healing, JMJD3 directs early macrophage-mediated inflammation via JAK1,3/STAT3 signaling. However, in the diabetic state, we found that IL-6, a cytokine increased in diabetic wound tissue at later time points post-injury, regulates JMJD3 expression in diabetic wound macrophages via the JAK1,3/STAT3 pathway and that this late increase in JMJD3 induces NFκB-mediated inflammatory gene transcription in wound macrophages via an H3K27me3 mechanism. Interestingly, RNA sequencing of wound macrophages isolated from mice with JMJD3-deficient myeloid cells (Jmjd3&lt;sup&gt;f/f&lt;/sup&gt;Lyz2&lt;sup&gt;Cre+&lt;/sup&gt;) identified that the STING gene (Tmem173) is regulated by JMJD3 in wound macrophages. STING limits inflammatory cytokine production by wound macrophages during healing. However, in diabetic mice, its role changes to limit wound repair and enhance inflammation. This finding is important since STING is associated with chronic inflammation, and we found STING to be elevated in human and murine diabetic wound macrophages at late time points. Finally, we demonstrate that macrophage-specific, nanoparticle inhibition of JMJD3 in diabetic wounds significantly improves diabetic wound repair by decreasing inflammatory cytokines and STING. Taken together, this work highlights the central role of JMJD3 in tissue repair and identifies cell-specific targeting as a viable therapeutic strategy for nonhealing diabetic wounds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Injectable adhesive self-healing biocompatible hydrogel for haemostasis, wound healing, and postoperative tissue adhesion prevention in nephron-sparing surgery</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36100176/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36100176/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Statement of significance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Extended warm ischemia time during nephron sparing surgery negatively affected postoperative renal function due to the need for hemostasis at the wound with abundant blood supply, and postoperative wound healing and additional adhesions caused by the surgical procedure deserve attention. Based on the efficient and stable adhesion properties of hydrogels and the ability to promote wound healing. Herein, a series of adhesive self-healing biocompatible hydrogels were prepared based on free-radical polymerization of acryloyl-6-aminocaproic acid (AA) and N-acryloyl 2-glycine (NAG) and the ionic coordination between Ca2+ with the abundant carboxyl groups in AA and NAG. AA/NAG/Ca hydrogel showed hemostasis property in nephron sparing surgery model, promote kidney wound healing, and could perform anti-postoperative adhesion efficacy in an abdomen-caecum adhesion model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nephron-sparing surgery is a well-established treatment in patients with T1a renal cell carcinoma; however, the complex suturing process prolongs warm ischaemia time, affects the preservation of normal renal parenchymal function, and causes avoidable postoperative tissue adhesion complications, including chronic abdominal pain, intestinal obstruction, and female infertility. Hence, the design of multifunctional biomaterials with haemostasis, postoperative wound management, and postoperative tissue adhesion prevention properties for nephron-sparing surgeries is urgently needed. In this study, a series of injectable adhesive multifunctional biocompatible hydrogels were designed based on the free-radical polymerisation of monomers acryloyl-6-aminocaproic acid (AA) and N-acryloyl 2-glycine (NAG), and the ionic coordination between Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt; and the abundant carboxyl groups in AA and NAG. AA/NAG/Ca (AA, NAG, and Ca refer to acryloyl-6-aminocaproic acid, N-acryloyl 2-glycine and calcium chloride, respectively) hydrogel exhibited good mechanical properties, swelling and adhesion properties, flexibility, in vitro blood-clotting ability, and cytocompatibility. In vivo experiments on liver injury models and rat/rabbit nephron-sparing surgery models elucidated that the AA/NAG/Ca hydrogel had haemostasis performance and wound healing properties that led to short bleeding time, reduced bleeding volume, and well-organised nephron structures. An abdomen-caecum adhesion model indicated that the AA/NAG/Ca hydrogel showed excellent anti-adhesion properties. In summary, this multifunctional hydrogel exhibited potential for improving haemostasis and wound management in nephron-sparing surgeries, showing potential for clinical application. STATEMENT OF SIGNIFICANCE: Extended warm ischemia time during nephron sparing surgery negatively affected postoperative renal function due to the need for hemostasis at the wound with abundant blood supply, and postoperative wound healing and additional adhesions caused by the surgical procedure deserve attention. Based on the efficient and stable adhesion properties of hydrogels and the ability to promote wound healing. Herein, a series of adhesive self-healing biocompatible hydrogels were prepared based on free-radical polymerization of acryloyl-6-aminocaproic acid (AA) and N-acryloyl 2-glycine (NAG) and the ionic coordination between Ca2+ with the abundant carboxyl groups in AA and NAG. AA/NAG/Ca hydrogel showed hemostasis property in nephron sparing surgery model, promote kidney wound healing, and could perform anti-postoperative adhesion efficacy in an abdomen-caecum adhesion model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Injury-induced pulmonary tuft cells are heterogenous, arise independent of key Type 2 cytokines, and are dispensable for dysplastic repair</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36073526/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36073526/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the lung bears significant regenerative capacity, severe viral pneumonia can chronically impair lung function by triggering dysplastic remodeling. The connection between these enduring changes and chronic disease remains poorly understood. We recently described the emergence of tuft cells within Krt5+ dysplastic regions after influenza injury. Using bulk and single-cell transcriptomics, we characterized and delineated multiple distinct tuft cell populations that arise following influenza clearance. Distinct from intestinal tuft cells which rely on Type 2 immune signals for their expansion, neither IL-25 nor IL-4ra signaling are required to drive tuft cell development in dysplastic/injured lungs. In addition, tuft cell expansion occurred independently of type I or type III interferon signaling. Furthermore, tuft cells were also observed upon bleomycin injury, suggesting that their development may be a general response to severe lung injury. While intestinal tuft cells promote growth and differentiation of surrounding epithelial cells, in the lungs of tuft cell deficient mice, Krt5+ dysplasia still occurs, goblet cell production is unchanged, and there remains no appreciable contribution of Krt5+ cells into more regionally appropriate alveolar Type 2 cells. Together, these findings highlight unexpected differences in signals necessary for murine lung tuft cell amplification and establish a framework for future elucidation of tuft cell functions in pulmonary health and disease.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generation of Plvap-CreER and Car4-CreER for genetic targeting of distinct lung capillary populations</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36028133/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36028133/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It has been reported recently that there are two distinct subpopulations of capillary endothelial cells in the mammalian lungs: gCap (general capillary) and aCap (aerocyte). They are identified by two unique markers, respectively: plasmalemmal vesicle-associated protein (PLVAP) and carbonic anhydrase IV (CAR4). Here, we report two novel knock-in mouse lines Plvap-CreER and Car4-CreER, which genetically target gCap and aCap, respectively. Induced by tamoxifen, the Plvap-CreER and Car4-CreER alleles mediate specific and efficient Cre-loxP recombinations in PLVAP&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; gCap and CAR4&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; aCap, respectively, in the lungs. These two mouse lines are useful genetic tools to investigate cell fates and functions of PLVAP&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; and CAR4&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; cells in lung homeostasis, injury and repair.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Circulating Hepatocyte Growth Factor Reflects Activation of Vascular Repair in Response to Stress</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36061342/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36061342/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;HGF is released by stressed human vascular cells and promotes vascular cell repair responses in autocrine and/or paracrine ways.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Subjects with a low capacity to express HGF in response to systemic stress have an increased cardiovascular risk.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Human atherosclerotic plaques with a low content of HGF have a more unstable phenotype.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The present study shows that subjects with a low ability to express HGF in response to metabolic stress have an increased risk to suffer cardiovascular events.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hepatocyte growth factor (HGF) is released by stressed human vascular cells and promotes vascular cell repair responses in both autocrine and paracrine ways. Subjects with a low capacity to express HGF in response to systemic stress have an increased cardiovascular risk. Human atherosclerotic plaques with a low content of HGF have a more unstable phenotype. The present study shows that subjects with a low ability to express HGF in response to metabolic stress have an increased risk to suffer myocardial infarction and stroke.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ischaemic tissue released microvesicles induce monocyte reprogramming and increase tissue repair by a tissue factor-dependent mechanism</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34406379/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34406379/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Aims:&lt;/em&gt; Despite increasing evidence that monocytes may acquire endothelial features, it remains unclear how monocytes participate in angiogenesis after ischaemic damage. We investigated whether ischaemic cells can release microvesicles (MVs) and promote neovascularization in a model of peripheral artery disease (PAD).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods and results:&lt;/em&gt; To model PAD, we used an in vivo experimental model of hind-limb ischaemia (HLI) in mice. MVs were isolated from the ischaemic muscle and from peripheral blood at different times after unilateral femoral artery ligation. MVs were phenotypically characterized to identify cell origin. HLI in mice induced the release of MVs with a much higher content of tissue factor (TF) than non-HLI control mice both in the MVs isolated from the affected limb muscle area and from blood. MVs were mainly released from endothelial cells (ECs) and induced Mo differentiation to endothelial cell-like (ECL) cells. Differentiation to ECL cells encompassed highly strict hierarchical transcription factor activation, initiated by ETS1 activation. MVs secreted by microvascular ECs over-expressing TF (upTF-EMVs), were injected in the ischaemic hind-limb in parallel with control EMVs (from random siRNA-treated cells) or EMVs released by silenced TF ECs. In animals treated with upTF-EMVs in the ischaemic zone, there was a highly significant increase in functional new vessels formation (seen by magnetic resonance angiography), a concomitant increase in the pool of circulating Ly6Clow Mo expressing vascular EC markers, and a significantly higher number of Mo/macrophages surrounding and integrating the newly formed collaterals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/em&gt; Ischaemia-activated ECs release EMVs rich in TF that induce monocyte differentiation into ECL cells and the formation of new vessels in the ischaemic zone. TF by this mechanism of formation of new blood microvessels can contribute to ischaemic tissue repair.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lgr5 &#43; cell fate regulation by coordination of metabolic nuclear receptors during liver repair</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36168631/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36168631/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Leucine-rich repeat-containing G protein-coupled receptor 5 (&lt;em&gt;Lgr5&lt;/em&gt;) is a target gene of Wnt/β-Catenin which plays a vital role in hepatic development and regeneration. However, the regulation of &lt;em&gt;Lgr5&lt;/em&gt; gene and the fate of &lt;em&gt;Lgr5&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; cells in hepatic physiology and pathology are little known. This study aims to clarify the effect of metabolic nuclear receptors on &lt;em&gt;Lgr5&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; cell fate in liver.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; We performed cell experiments with primary hepatocytes, Hep 1-6, Hep G2, and Huh 7 cells, and animal studies with wild-type (WT), farnesoid X receptor (FXR) knockout mice, peroxisome proliferator-activated receptor α (PPARα) knockout mice and &lt;em&gt;Lgr5&lt;/em&gt;-Cre&lt;sup&gt;ERT2&lt;/sup&gt;; Rosa26-mTmG mice. GW4064 and CDCA were used to activate FXR. And GW7647 or Wy14643 was used for PPARα activation. Regulation of &lt;em&gt;Lgr5&lt;/em&gt; by FXR and PPARα was determined by QRT-PCR, western blot (WB) and RNAscope® &lt;em&gt;in situ&lt;/em&gt; hybridization (ISH) and immunofluorescence (IF), luciferase reporter assay, electrophoretic mobility shift assay (EMSA) and chromatin immunoprecipitation (ChIP). Diethyl 1,4-dihydro-2,4,6-trimethyl-3,5-pyridinedicarboxylate (DDC) diet was used to induce liver injury.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; Pharmacologic activation of FXR induced &lt;em&gt;Lgr5&lt;/em&gt; expression, whereas activation of PPARα suppressed &lt;em&gt;Lgr5&lt;/em&gt; expression. Furthermore, FXR and PPARα competed for binding to shared site on &lt;em&gt;Lgr5&lt;/em&gt; promoter with opposite transcriptional outputs. DDC diet triggered the transition of &lt;em&gt;Lgr5&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; cells from resting state to proliferation. FXR activation enhanced &lt;em&gt;Lgr5&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; cell expansion mainly by symmetric cell division, but PPARα activation prevented &lt;em&gt;Lgr5&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; cell proliferation along with asymmetric cell division.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/em&gt; Our findings unravel the opposite regulatory effects of FXR and PPARα on &lt;em&gt;Lgr5&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; cell fate in liver under physiological and pathological conditions, which will greatly assist novel therapeutic development targeting nuclear receptors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Repair effect of photobiomodulation combined with human umbilical cord mesenchymal stem cells on rats with acute lung injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36029758/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36029758/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acute lung injury (ALI) impaired the function of blood oxygen exchange function, resulting in tissue hypoxia and patient death. Recently, human umbilical cord mesenchymal stem cells (hUCMSCs) are thought to mitigate the effects of ALI, which boosts researchers&amp;rsquo; interest in employing stem cell-based therapies to manage ALI. However, as a novel therapy, hUCMSCs still face various limitations such as migrating weakly and insufficient proliferation in vivo. Photobiomodulation (PBM) effciently promotes cell proliferation, migration and homing, which presents a promising strategy for overcoming above limitations. In this study, PBM was emerged to intervene hUCMSCs through detecting cell proliferation, oxidative stress-related factors and inflammatory factors. These results assuredly confirmed that PBM enhanced the antioxidant capacity of cells and improved cell survival in vitro experiments. In vivo, PBM-intervened hUCMSCs intuitively reduce thickness of alveolar septum, excessive secretion of inflammatory factors, relieves bleeding, edema and fibrosis. As a physical intervention, PBM further strengthens the therapeutic effect of hUCMSCs and depicted a hopeful therapy in ALI treatment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JMJD3 activated hyaluronan synthesis drives muscle regeneration in an inflammatory environment</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35926054/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35926054/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Muscle stem cells (MuSCs) reside in a specialized niche that ensures their regenerative capacity. Although we know that innate immune cells infiltrate the niche in response to injury, it remains unclear how MuSCs adapt to this altered environment for initiating repair. Here, we demonstrate that inflammatory cytokine signaling from the regenerative niche impairs the ability of quiescent MuSCs to reenter the cell cycle. The histone H3 lysine 27 (H3K27) demethylase JMJD3, but not UTX, allowed MuSCs to overcome inhibitory inflammation signaling by removing trimethylated H3K27 (H3K27me3) marks at the Has2 locus to initiate production of hyaluronic acid, which in turn established an extracellular matrix competent for integrating signals that direct MuSCs to exit quiescence. Thus, JMJD3-driven hyaluronic acid synthesis plays a proregenerative role that allows MuSC adaptation to inflammation and the initiation of muscle repair.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Origin and function of activated fibroblast states during zebrafish heart regeneration</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35864193/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35864193/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The adult zebrafish heart has a high capacity for regeneration following injury. However, the composition of the regenerative niche has remained largely elusive. Here, we dissected the diversity of activated cell states in the regenerating zebrafish heart based on single-cell transcriptomics and spatiotemporal analysis. We observed the emergence of several transient cell states with fibroblast characteristics following injury, and we outlined the proregenerative function of collagen-12-expressing fibroblasts. To understand the cascade of events leading to heart regeneration, we determined the origin of these cell states by high-throughput lineage tracing. We found that activated fibroblasts were derived from two separate sources: the epicardium and the endocardium. Mechanistically, we determined Wnt signalling as a regulator of the endocardial fibroblast response. In summary, our work identifies specialized activated fibroblast cell states that contribute to heart regeneration, thereby opening up possible approaches to modulating the regenerative capacity of the vertebrate heart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dedifferentiated Schwann cell-derived TGF-β3 is essential for the neural system to promote wound healing</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35910794/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35910794/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rationale:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wound healing is among the most complicated physiological processes and requires the synchronization of various cell types with distinct roles to re-establish the condition of the original skin. Patients affected by peripheral neuropathies often experience failure to heal. Loss of Schwann cells (SCs), a crucial population of peripheral nervous system cells in skin, may contribute to chronic wounds. However, the role of SCs in wound healing are poorly understood.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Methods:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The activity of SCs was investigated by using a cell atlas of the wound healing process, which was generated by integrating single-cell RNA sequencing (scRNA-seq) libraries covering different states of mouse back skin. The results of in silico analysis were validated by in vitro cell culture and in vivo mouse model. Selective inhibitors and conditional RNAi by virus transfection were utilized to investigate the role of SCs in wound healing. Findings from mouse experiments were further verified in scRNA-seq analysis of diabetic patients.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Results:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our in silico analysis revealed the heterogeneous cellular components of skin and the dynamic interactions of neural crest derived cells (NCs) with other cell types. We found that SCs dedifferentiated at an early stage of wound repair with upregulated Wnt signaling. We also identified dedifferentiated SC (dSC) defect in diabetic wounds in both mouse and human. Wnt inhibition at the wound site repressed SC dedifferentiation, leading to defective repair. Furthermore, dSCs derived TGF-β3, which is context-dependent, promoted the migration of fibroblasts and keratinocytes. Moreover, TGF-β3 supplementation enhanced the healing of chronic wounds in diabetic mice with impaired SCs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our study thus advances the understanding of the roles of neural-derived cells in skin regeneration and suggests a potential therapeutic strategy for wound healing disorders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>14-3-3ζ inhibits maladaptive repair in renal tubules by regulating YAP and reduces renal interstitial fibrosis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35840657/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35840657/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acute kidney injury (AKI) refers to a group of common clinical syndromes characterized by acute renal dysfunction, which may lead to chronic kidney disease (CKD), and this process is called the AKI-CKD transition. The transcriptional coactivator YAP can promote the AKI-CKD transition by regulating the expression of profibrotic factors, and 14-3-3 protein zeta (14-3-3ζ), an important regulatory protein of YAP, may prevent the AKI-CKD transition. We established an AKI-CKD model in mice by unilateral renal ischemia-reperfusion injury and overexpressed 14-3-3ζ in mice using a fluid dynamics-based gene transfection technique. We also overexpressed and knocked down 14-3-3ζ in vitro. In AKI-CKD model mice, 14-3-3ζ expression was significantly increased at the AKI stage. During the development of chronic disease, the expression of 14-3-3ζ tended to decrease, whereas active YAP was consistently overexpressed. In vitro, we found that 14-3-3ζ can combine with YAP, promote the phosphorylation of YAP, inhibit YAP nuclear translocation, and reduce the expression of fibrosis-related proteins. In an in vivo intervention experiment, we found that the overexpression of 14-3-3ζ slowed the process of renal fibrosis in a mouse model of AKI-CKD. These findings suggest that 14-3-3ζ can affect the expression of fibrosis-related proteins by regulating YAP, inhibit the maladaptive repair of renal tubular epithelial cells, and prevent the AKI-CKD transition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intermediary Role of Lung Alveolar Type 1 Cells in Epithelial Repair upon Sendai Virus Infection</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35679221/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35679221/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The lung epithelium forms the first barrier against respiratory pathogens and noxious chemicals; however, little is known about how more than 90% of this barrier, made of AT1 (alveolar type 1) cells, responds to injury. Using the Sendai virus to model natural infection in mice, we find evidence that AT1 cells have an intermediary role by persisting in areas depleted of AT2 cells, upregulating IFN responsive genes, and receding from invading airway cells. Sendai virus infection mobilizes airway cells to form alveolar SOX2&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; (Sry-box 2&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt;) clusters without differentiating into AT1 or AT2 cells. Large AT2 cell-depleted areas remain covered by AT1 cells, which we name &amp;ldquo;AT2-less regions&amp;rdquo;, and are replaced by SOX2&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; clusters spreading both basally and luminally. AT2 cell proliferation and differentiation are largely confined to topologically distal regions and form &lt;em&gt;de novo&lt;/em&gt; alveolar surface, with limited contribution to &lt;em&gt;in situ&lt;/em&gt; repairs of AT2-less regions. Time-course single-cell RNA sequencing profiling and RNAscope validation suggest enhanced immune responses and altered growth signals in AT1 cells. Our comprehensive spatiotemporal and genomewide study highlights the hitherto unappreciated role of AT1 cells in lung injury-repair.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Single-cell analysis highlights differences in druggable pathways underlying adaptive or fibrotic kidney regeneration</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35821371/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35821371/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The kidney has tremendous capacity to repair after acute injury, however, pathways guiding adaptive and fibrotic repair are poorly understood. We developed a model of adaptive and fibrotic kidney regeneration by titrating ischemic injury dose. We performed detailed biochemical and histological analysis and profiled transcriptomic changes at bulk and single-cell level (&amp;gt; 110,000 cells) over time. Our analysis highlights kidney proximal tubule cells as key susceptible cells to injury. Adaptive proximal tubule repair correlated with fatty acid oxidation and oxidative phosphorylation. We identify a specific maladaptive/profibrotic proximal tubule cluster after long ischemia, which expresses proinflammatory and profibrotic cytokines and myeloid cell chemotactic factors. Druggability analysis highlights pyroptosis/ferroptosis as vulnerable pathways in these profibrotic cells. Pharmacological targeting of pyroptosis/ferroptosis in vivo pushed cells towards adaptive repair and ameliorates fibrosis. In summary, our single-cell analysis defines key differences in adaptive and fibrotic repair and identifies druggable pathways for pharmacological intervention to prevent kidney fibrosis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Insulin-incubated palladium clusters promote recovery after brain injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35752849/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35752849/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Traumatic brain injury (TBI) is a cause of disability and death worldwide, but there are currently no specific treatments for this condition. Release of excess reactive oxygen species (ROS) in the injured brain leads to a series of pathological changes; thus, eliminating ROS could be a potential therapeutic strategy. Herein, we synthesized insulin-incubated ultrasmall palladium (Pd@insulin) clusters via green biomimetic chemistry. The Pd@insulin clusters, which were 3.2 nm in diameter, exhibited marked multiple ROS-scavenging ability testified by the theoretical calculation. Pd@insulin could be rapidly excreted via kidney-urine metabolism and induce negligible adverse effects after a long-time treatment in vivo. In a TBI mouse model, intravenously injected Pd@insulin clusters aggregated in the injured cortex, effectively suppressed excessive ROS production, and significantly rescued motor function, cognition and spatial memory. We found that the positive therapeutic effects of the Pd@insulin clusters were mainly attributed to their ROS-scavenging ability, as they inhibited excessive neuroinflammation, reduced cell apoptosis, and prevented neuronal loss. Therefore, the ability of Pd@insulin clusters to effectively eliminate ROS, as well as their simple structure, easy synthesis, low toxicity, and rapid metabolism may facilitate their clinical translation for TBI treatment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Regeneration-Associated Transitional State Cells in Pulmonary Fibrosis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/35743199/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/35743199/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pulmonary fibrosis is a chronic, progressive fibrosing interstitial disease. It is characterized by fibroblast proliferation, myofibroblast activation, and massive extracellular matrix deposition. These processes result in loss of lung parenchyma function. The transdifferentiation of alveolar epithelial type II (AEC2) to alveolar epithelial type I cells (AEC1) plays an important role in the epithelial repair after lung injury. Pulmonary fibrosis begins when this transdifferentiation process is blocked. Several recent studies have found that novel transitional state cells (intermediate states in the transdifferentiation of AEC2 to AEC1) can potentially regenerate the alveolar epithelium surface and promote a repair process. During the AEC2 to AEC1 trans-differentiation process after injury, AEC2 lose their specific markers and become transitional state cells. Furthermore, transdifferentiation of transitional state cells into AEC1 is the critical step for lung repair. However, transitional cells stagnate in the intermediate states in which failure of transdifferentiation to AEC1 may induce an inadequate repair process and pulmonary fibrosis. In this review, we focus on the traits, origins, functions, and activation of signaling pathways of the transitional state cell and its communication with other cells. We also provide a new opinion on pulmonary fibrosis pathogenesis mechanisms and novel therapeutic targets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lockd promotes myoblast proliferation and muscle regeneration via binding with DHX36 to facilitate 5&#39; UTR rG4 unwinding and Anp32e translation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35675771/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35675771/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Lockd&lt;/em&gt; is highly induced in activated satellite cells and promotes cell proliferation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Lockd&lt;/em&gt; interacts with DHX36 and regulates the translation of DHX36-bound mRNAs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Lockd&lt;/em&gt;/DHX36 regulate &lt;em&gt;Anp32e&lt;/em&gt; translation via modulating the 5′ UTR rG4 structure&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Lockd&lt;/em&gt; stabilizes the interaction of DHX36 and EIF3B proteins&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adult muscle stem cells, also known as satellite cells (SCs), play pivotal roles in muscle regeneration, and long non-coding RNA (lncRNA) functions in SCs remain largely unknown. Here, we identify a lncRNA, &lt;em&gt;Lockd&lt;/em&gt;, which is induced in activated SCs upon acute muscle injury. We demonstrate that &lt;em&gt;Lockd&lt;/em&gt; promotes SC proliferation; deletion of &lt;em&gt;Lockd&lt;/em&gt; leads to cell-cycle arrest, and &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt; repression of &lt;em&gt;Lockd&lt;/em&gt; in mouse muscles hinders regeneration process. Mechanistically, we show that &lt;em&gt;Lockd&lt;/em&gt; directly interacts with RNA helicase DHX36 and the 5&amp;rsquo;end of &lt;em&gt;Lockd&lt;/em&gt; possesses the strongest binding with DHX36. Furthermore, we demonstrate that &lt;em&gt;Lockd&lt;/em&gt; stabilizes the interaction between DHX36 and EIF3B proteins; synergistically, this complex unwinds the RNA G-quadruplex (rG4) structure formed at &lt;em&gt;Anp32e&lt;/em&gt; mRNA 5&amp;rsquo; UTR and promotes the translation of ANP32E protein, which is required for myoblast proliferation. Altogether, our findings identify a regulatory &lt;em&gt;Lockd&lt;/em&gt;/DHX36/Anp32e axis that promotes myoblast proliferation and acute-injury-induced muscle regeneration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Persistent Activation of Autophagy After Cisplatin Nephrotoxicity Promotes Renal Fibrosis and Chronic Kidney Disease</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35707397/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35707397/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Autophagy, a highly conserved catabolic pathway in eukaryotic cells, contributes to the maintenance of the homeostasis and function of the kidney. Upon acute kidney injury (AKI), autophagy is activated in renal tubular cells to act as an intrinsic protective mechanism. However, the role of autophagy in the development of chronic kidney pathologies including renal fibrosis after AKI remains unclear. In this study, we detected a persistent autophagy activation in mouse kidneys after nephrotoxicity of repeated low dose cisplatin (RLDC) treatment. 3-methyladenine (3-MA) and chloroquine (CQ), respective inhibitors of autophagy at the initiation and degradation stages, blocked autophagic flux and improved kidney repair in post-RLDC mice, as indicated by kidney weight, renal function, and less interstitial fibrosis. &lt;em&gt;In vitro&lt;/em&gt;, RLDC induced a pro-fibrotic phenotype in renal tubular cells, including the production and secretion of pro-fibrotic cytokines. Notably, autophagy inhibitors blocked RLDC-induced secretion of pro-fibrotic cytokines in these cells. Together, the results indicate that persistent autophagy after AKI induces pro-fibrotic cytokines in renal tubular cells, promoting renal fibrosis and chronic kidney disease.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Single-cell transcriptomic profiling of lung endothelial cells identifies dynamic inflammatory and regenerative subpopulations</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35511435/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35511435/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Studies have demonstrated the phenotypic heterogeneity of vascular endothelial cells (ECs) within a vascular bed; however, little is known about how distinct endothelial subpopulations in a particular organ respond to an inflammatory stimulus. We performed single-cell RNA-Seq of 35,973 lung ECs obtained during baseline as well as postinjury time points after inflammatory lung injury induced by LPS. Seurat clustering and gene expression pathway analysis identified 2 major subpopulations in the lung microvascular endothelium, a subpopulation enriched for expression of immune response genes such as MHC genes (immuneEC) and another defined by increased expression of vascular development genes such as Sox17 (devEC). The presence of immuneEC and devEC subpopulations was also observed in nonhuman primate lungs infected with SARS-CoV-2 and murine lungs infected with H1N1 influenza virus. After the peak of inflammatory injury, we observed the emergence of a proliferative lung EC subpopulation. Overexpression of Sox17 prevented inflammatory activation in ECs. Thus, there appeared to be a &amp;ldquo;division of labor&amp;rdquo; within the lung microvascular endothelium in which some ECs showed propensity for inflammatory signaling and others for endothelial regeneration. These results provide underpinnings for the development of targeted therapies to limit inflammatory lung injury and promote regeneration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Current kidney function parameters overestimate kidney tissue repair in reversible experimental kidney disease</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35483527/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35483527/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although underlying mechanisms and the clinical course of kidney disease progression are well described, less is known about potential disease reversibility. Therefore, to analyze kidney recovery, we adapted a commonly used murine chronic kidney disease (CKD) model of 2,8- dihydroxyadenine (2,8-DHA) crystal-induced nephropathy to study disease recovery and efficacy of disease-modifying interventions. The recovery phase after CKD was characterized by improved kidney function after two weeks which remained stable thereafter. By contrast, even after eight weeks recovery, tubular injury and inflammation were only partially reduced, and fibrosis persisted. Deep-learning-based histologic analysis of 8,604 glomeruli and 596,614 tubular cross sections revealed numerous tubules had undergone either prominent dilation or complete atrophy, leading to atubular glomeruli and irreversible nephron loss. We confirmed these findings in a second CKD model, reversible unilateral ureteral obstruction, in which a rapid improvement of glomerular filtration rate during recovery also did not reflect the permanent histologic kidney injury. In 2,8-DHA nephropathy, increased drinking volume was highly effective in disease prevention. However, in therapeutic approaches, high fluid intake was only effective in moderate but not severe CKD and established tissue injury was again poorly reflective of kidney function parameters. The injury was particularly localized in the medulla, which is often not analyzed. Thus, recovery after crystal- or obstruction-induced CKD is characterized by ongoing tissue injury, fibrosis, and nephron loss, but not reflected by standard measures of kidney function. Hence, our data might aid in designing kidney recovery studies and suggest the need for biomarkers specifically monitoring intra-kidney tissue injury.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reduced Sarcolemmal Membrane Repair Exacerbates Striated Muscle Pathology in a Mouse Model of Duchenne Muscular Dystrophy</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35563723/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35563723/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Duchenne muscular dystrophy (DMD) is a common X-linked degenerative muscle disorder that involves mutations in the DMD gene that frequently reduce the expression of the dystrophin protein, compromising the structural integrity of the sarcolemmal membrane and leaving it vulnerable to injury during cycles of muscle contraction and relaxation. This results in an increased frequency of sarcolemma disruptions that can compromise the barrier function of the membrane and lead to death of the myocyte. Sarcolemmal membrane repair processes can potentially compensate for increased membrane disruptions in DMD myocytes. Previous studies demonstrated that TRIM72, a muscle-enriched tripartite motif (TRIM) family protein also known as mitsugumin 53 (MG53), is a component of the cell membrane repair machinery in striated muscle. To test the importance of membrane repair in striated muscle in compensating for the membrane fragility in DMD, we crossed TRIM72/MG53 knockout mice into the mdx mouse model of DMD. These double knockout (DKO) mice showed compromised sarcolemmal membrane integrity compared to mdx mice, as measured by immunoglobulin G staining and ex vivo muscle laser microscopy wounding assays. We also found a significant decrease in muscle ex vivo contractile function as compared to mdx mice at both 6 weeks and 1.5 years of age. As the DKO mice aged, they developed more extensive fibrosis in skeletal muscles compared to mdx. Our findings indicate that TRIM72/MG53-mediated membrane repair can partially compensate for the sarcolemmal fragility associated with DMD and that the loss of membrane repair results in increased pathology in the DKO mice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Galectin-3 interferes with tissue repair and promotes cardiac dysfunction and comorbidities in a genetic heart failure model</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35441327/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35441327/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Galectin-3, a biomarker for heart failure (HF), has been associated with myocardial fibrosis. However, its causal involvement in HF pathogenesis has been questioned in certain models of cardiac injury-induced HF. To address this, we used desmin-deficient mice (&lt;em&gt;des&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt;), a model of progressive HF characterized by cardiomyocyte death, spontaneous inflammatory responses sustaining fibrosis, and galectin-3 overexpression. Genetic ablation or pharmacological inhibition of galectin-3 led to improvement of cardiac function and adverse remodeling features including fibrosis. Over the course of development of &lt;em&gt;des&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; cardiomyopathy, monitored for a period of 12 months, galectin-3 deficiency specifically ameliorated the decline in systolic function accompanying the acute inflammatory phase (4-week-old mice), whereas a more pronounced protective effect was observed in older mice, including the preservation of diastolic function. Interestingly, the cardiac repair activities during the early inflammatory phase were restored under galectin-3 deficiency by increasing the proliferation potential and decreasing apoptosis of fibroblasts, while galectin-3 absence modulated macrophage-fibroblast coupled functions and suppressed both pro-fibrotic activation of cardiac fibroblasts and pro-fibrotic gene expression in the &lt;em&gt;des&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; heart. In addition, galectin-3 also affected the emphysema-like comorbid pathology observed in the &lt;em&gt;des&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; mice, as its absence partially normalized lung compliance. Collectively galectin-3 was found to be causally involved in cardiac adverse remodeling, inflammation, and failure by affecting functions of cardiac fibroblasts and macrophages. In concordance with this role, the effectiveness of pharmacological inhibition in ameliorating cardiac pathology features establishes galectin-3 as a valid intervention target for HF, with additive benefits for treatment of associated comorbidities, such as pulmonary defects. Schematic illustrating top to bottom, the detrimental role of galectin-3 (Gal3) in heart failure progression: desmin deficiency-associated spontaneous myocardial inflammation accompanying cardiac cell death (reddish dashed border) is characterized by infiltration of macrophages (round cells) and up-regulation of Lgals3 (encoding secretable galectin-3, green) and detrimental macrophage-related genes (Ccr2 and Arg1). In this galectin-3-enriched milieu, the early up-regulation of profibrotic gene expression (Tgfb1, Acta2, Col1a1), in parallel to the suppression of proliferative activities and a potential of senescence induction by cardiac fibroblasts (spindle-like cells), collectively promote &lt;em&gt;des&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; cardiac fibrosis and dysfunction establishing heart failure (left panel). Additionally, galectin-3+ macrophage-enrichment accompanies the development of emphysema-like lung comorbidities. In the absence of galectin-3 (right panel), the effect of macrophage-fibroblast dipole and associated events are modulated (grey color depicts reduced expression or activities) leading to attenuated cardiac pathology in the &lt;em&gt;des&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; Lgals3&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt;_ mice. Pulmonary comorbidities are also limited.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Progenitor potential of lung epithelial organoid cells in a transplantation model</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35417699/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35417699/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Alveolar organoid cells engraft into the alveolar space&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Transplanted lung alveolar cells have transcriptional signature of native AT2 cells&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Transplanted alveolar cells proliferate and retain organoid-forming capacity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Organoid cells undergo changes to transitional cell states upon transplantation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lung progenitor cells are crucial for regeneration following injury, yet it is unclear whether lung progenitor cells can be functionally engrafted after transplantation. We transplanted organoid cells derived from alveolar type II (AT2) cells enriched by SCA1-negative status (SNO) or multipotent SCA1-positive progenitor cells (SPO) into injured mouse lungs. Transplanted SNO cells are retained in the alveolar regions, whereas SPO cells incorporate into airway and alveolar regions. Single-cell transcriptomics demonstrate that transplanted SNO cells are comparable to native AT2 cells. Transplanted SPO cells exhibit transcriptional hallmarks of alveolar and airway cells, as well as transitional cell states identified in disease. Transplanted cells proliferate after re-injury of recipient mice and retain organoid-forming capacity. Thus, lung epithelial organoid cells exhibit progenitor cell functions after reintroduction to the lung. This study reveals methods to interrogate lung progenitor cell potential and model transitional cell states relevant to pathogenic features of lung disease &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Biomimic Trained Immunity-MSCs Delivery Microcarriers for Acute Liver Failure Regeneration</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35411651/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35411651/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mesenchymal stem cells (MSCs) have a demonstrated value for acute liver failure (ALF) regeneration, while their delivery stratagems with long-term biological functions, low immune response, and high biocompatibility are still a challenge. Here, a lipopolysaccharide (LPS)-loaded photoresponsive cryogel porous microcarrier (CPM) for MSCs delivery and colonization is presented to promote defect liver regeneration. The CPMs are fabricated with graphene oxide, poly(N-isopropylacrylamide), and gelatin methacrylate (GelMA) via droplet microfluidic technology and a gradient-cooling procedure. Benefitting from the biocompatible GelMA component and the porous microstructure of the CPMs, MSCs can be nondestructively captured and abundantly delivered. Because the LPS can be released from the CPMs under NIR irradiation, the delivered MSCs are imparted with the feature of &amp;ldquo;trained immunity.&amp;rdquo; Thus, when the MSCs-laden CPMs are tailored into the liver matched patches by bioprinting and applied in ALF rats, they display superior anti-inflammatory and more significant liver regeneration properties than the untrained MSCs. These features make the CPMs an excellent MSCs delivery system for clinical applications in tissue repair.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The ZIP8/SIRT1 axis regulates alveolar progenitor cell renewal in aging and idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35389887/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35389887/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Type 2 alveolar epithelial cells (AEC2s) function as progenitor cells in the lung. We have shown previously that failure of AEC2 regeneration results in progressive lung fibrosis in mice and is a cardinal feature of idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis (IPF). In this study, we identified deficiency of a specific zinc transporter, SLC39A8 (ZIP8), in AEC2s from both IPF lungs and lungs of old mice. Loss of ZIP8 expression was associated with impaired renewal capacity of AEC2s and enhanced lung fibrosis. ZIP8 regulation of AEC2 progenitor function was dependent on SIRT1. Replenishment with exogenous zinc and SIRT1 activation promoted self-renewal and differentiation of AEC2s from lung tissues of IPF patients and old mice. Deletion of Zip8 in AEC2s in mice resulted in impaired AEC2 renewal, increased susceptibility to bleomycin injury, and development of spontaneous lung fibrosis. Therapeutic strategies to restore zinc metabolism and appropriate SIRT1 signaling could improve AEC2 progenitor function and mitigate ongoing fibrogenesis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bone tissue engineering using 3D silk scaffolds and human dental pulp stromal cells epigenetic reprogrammed with the selective histone deacetylase inhibitor MI192</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35362831/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35362831/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Epigenetics plays a critical role in regulating mesenchymal stem cells&amp;rsquo; (MSCs) fate for tissue repair and regeneration. There is increasing evidence that the inhibition of histone deacetylase (HDAC) isoform 3 can enhance MSC osteogenesis. This study investigated the potential of using a selective HDAC2 and 3 inhibitor, MI192, to promote human dental pulp stromal cells (hDPSCs) bone-like tissue formation in vitro and in vivo within porous Bombyx Mori silk scaffolds. Both 2 and 5 wt% silk scaffolds were fabricated and characterised. The 5 wt% scaffolds possess thicker internal lamellae, reduced scaffold swelling and degradation rates, whilst increased compressive modulus in comparison to the 2 wt% silk scaffold. MI192 pre-treatment of hDPSCs on 5 wt% silk scaffold significantly enhanced hDPSCs alkaline phosphatase activity (ALP). The expression of osteoblast-related genes (RUNX2, ALP, Col1a, OCN) was significantly upregulated in the MI192 pre-treated cells. Histological analysis confirmed that the MI192 pre-treated hDPSCs-silk scaffold constructs promoted bone extracellular matrix (ALP, Col1a, OCN) deposition and mineralisation compared to the untreated group. Following 6 weeks of subcutaneous implantation in nude mice, the MI192 pre-treated hDPSCs-silk scaffold constructs enhanced the vascularisation and extracellular matrix mineralisation compared to untreated control. In conclusion, these findings demonstrate the potential of using epigenetic reprogramming and silk scaffolds to promote hDPSCs bone formation efficacy, which provides evidence for clinical translation of this technology for bone augmentation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Small molecules facilitate single factor-mediated sweat gland cell reprogramming</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35351192/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35351192/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Large skin defects severely disrupt the overall skin structure and can irreversibly damage sweat glands (SG), thus impairing the skin&amp;rsquo;s physiological function. This study aims to develop a stepwise reprogramming strategy to convert fibroblasts into SG lineages, which may provide a promising method to obtain desirable cell types for the functional repair and regeneration of damaged skin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; The expression of the SG markers cytokeratin 5 (CK5), cytokeratin 10 (CK10), cytokeratin 18 (CK18), carcino-embryonic antigen (CEA), aquaporin 5 (AQP5) and α-smooth muscle actin (α-SMA) was assessed with quantitative PCR (qPCR), immunofluorescence and flow cytometry. Calcium activity analysis was conducted to test the function of induced SG-like cells (iSGCs). Mouse xenograft models were also used to evaluate the in vivo regeneration of iSGCs. BALB/c nude mice were randomly divided into a normal group, SGM treatment group and iSGC transplantation group. Immunocytochemical analyses and starch-iodine sweat tests were used to confirm the in vivo regeneration of iSGCs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; EDA overexpression drove HDF conversion into iSGCs in SG culture medium (SGM). qPCR indicated significantly increased mRNA levels of the SG markers CK5, CK18 and CEA in iSGCs, and flow cytometry data demonstrated (4.18 ± 0.04)% of iSGCs were CK5 positive and (4.36 ± 0.25)% of iSGCs were CK18 positive. The addition of chemical cocktails greatly accelerated the SG fate program. qPCR results revealed significantly increased mRNA expression of CK5, CK18 and CEA in iSGCs, as well as activation of the duct marker CK10 and luminal functional marker AQP5. Flow cytometry indicated, after the treatment of chemical cocktails, (23.05 ± 2.49)% of iSGCs expressed CK5+ and (55.79 ± 3.18)% of iSGCs expressed CK18+, respectively. Calcium activity analysis indicated that the reactivity of iSGCs to acetylcholine was close to that of primary SG cells [(60.79 ± 7.71)% vs. (70.59 ± 0.34)%, ns]. In vivo transplantation experiments showed approximately (5.2 ± 1.1)% of the mice were sweat test positive, and the histological analysis results indicated that regenerated SG structures were present in iSGCs-treated mice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/em&gt; We developed a SG reprogramming strategy to generate functional iSGCs from HDFs by using the single factor EDA in combination with SGM and small molecules. The generation of iSGCs has important implications for future in situ skin regeneration with SG restoration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A nitric oxide-eluting and REDV peptide-conjugated coating promotes vascular healing</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35366606/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35366606/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Drug-eluting stents (DESs) placement remarkably reduces the over-proliferation of smooth muscle cells (SMCs) and thus neointimal hyperplasia. However, the pharmacological agent also slows down the re-endothelization, delays injury vascular healing and increases the risk of in-stent restenosis (ISR). Here, inspired by mussel foot proteins (Mfps), a mimicking endothelium functional stent coating was efficiently fabricated by thiol-ene &amp;ldquo;click&amp;rdquo; reaction, consisting of catechol grafted chitosan (CS-C), zinc sulfate, and Arg-Glu-Asp-Val (REDV) peptide. The mimicking endothelium coating could continuously catalyze endogenous nitric oxide (NO) gas and maintain the bioactivity of REDV peptide. Compared with bare stents, the mimicking coatings significantly inhibited the acute thrombosis for the first 1-week, accelerated re-endothelization and decreased in-stent restenosis for 1- and 3-month after implantation. In addition, the synergistic effect of NO and REDV peptide also regulated inflammation response and promoted the expression of muscle fiber.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TAK1 is essential for endothelial barrier maintenance and repair after lung vascular injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35324316/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35324316/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TGF-β-activated kinase 1 (TAK1) plays crucial roles in innate and adaptive immune responses and is required for embryonic vascular development. However, TAK1&amp;rsquo;s role in regulating vascular barrier integrity is not well defined. Here we show that endothelial TAK1 kinase function is required to maintain and repair the injured lung endothelial barrier. We observed that inhibition of TAK1 with 5Z-7-oxozeaenol markedly reduced expression of β-catenin (β-cat) and VE-cadherin at endothelial adherens junctions and augmented protease-activated receptor-1 (PAR-1)- or toll-like receptor-4 (TLR-4)-induced increases in lung vascular permeability. In inducible endothelial cell (EC)-restricted TAK1 knockout (&lt;em&gt;TAK1&lt;sup&gt;i∆EC&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt;) mice, we observed that the lung endothelial barrier was compromised and in addition, &lt;em&gt;TAK1&lt;sup&gt;i∆EC&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; mice exhibited heightened sensitivity to septic shock. Consistent with these findings, we observed dramatically reduced β-cat expression in lung ECs of &lt;em&gt;TAK1&lt;sup&gt;i∆EC&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; mice. Further, either inhibition or knockdown of TAK1 blocked PAR-1- or TLR-4-induced inactivation of glycogen synthase kinase 3β (GSK3β), which in turn increased phosphorylation, ubiquitylation, and degradation of β-cat in ECs to destabilize the endothelial barrier. Importantly, we showed that TAK1 inactivates GSK3β through AKT activation in ECs. Thus our findings in this study point to the potential of targeting the TAK1-AKT-GSK3β axis as a therapeutic approach to treat uncontrolled lung vascular leak during sepsis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A transcriptomics-guided drug target discovery strategy identifies receptor ligands for lung regeneration</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35319981/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35319981/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aqp2&#43; Progenitor Cells Maintain and Repair Distal Renal Segments</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35318267/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35318267/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Adult progenitor cells presumably demonstrate clonogenicity, self-renewal, and multipotentiality, and can regenerate cells under various conditions. Definitive evidence demonstrating the existence of such progenitor cells in adult mammalian kidneys is lacking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Method:&lt;/em&gt; We performed in vivo lineage tracing and thymidine analogue labeling using adult tamoxifen-inducible (&lt;em&gt;Aqp2&lt;sup&gt;ECE/+&lt;/sup&gt;RFP/+&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Aqp2&lt;sup&gt;ECE/+&lt;/sup&gt;Brainbow/+&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Aqp2&lt;sup&gt;ECE/+&lt;/sup&gt;Brainbow/Brainbow&lt;/em&gt;) and WT mice. The tamoxifen-inducible mice were analyzed between 1 and 300 days postinduction. Alternatively, WT and tamoxifen-induced mice were subjected to unilateral ureteral obstruction and thymidine analogue labeling and analyzed 2-14 days post-surgery. Multiple cell-specific markers were used for high-resolution immunofluorescence confocal microscopy to identify the cell types derived from Aqp2&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; cells.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; Like their embryonic counterparts, adult cells expressing Aqp2 and V-ATPase subunits B1 and B2 (Aqp2&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt;B1B2&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt;) are the potential Aqp2&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; progenitor cells (APs). Adult APs rarely divide to generate daughter cells, either maintaining the property of the AP (self-renewal) or differentiating into DCT2/CNT/CD cells (multipotentiality), forming single cell-derived, multiple-cell clones (clonogenicity) during tissue maintenance. APs selectively and continuously regenerate DCT2/CNT/CD cells in response to injury resulting from ureteral ligation. AP proliferation demonstrated direct correlation with Notch activation and was inversely correlated with development of kidney fibrosis. Derivation of both intercalated and DCT2 cells was found to be cell division-dependent and -independent, most likely through AP differentiation which requires cell division and through direct conversion of APs and/or regular principal cells without cell division, respectively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/em&gt; Our study demonstrates that Aqp2&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt;B1B2&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; cells behave as adult APs to maintain and repair DCT2/CNT1/CNT2/CD segments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inhaled Placental Mesenchymal Stromal Cell Secretome from Two- and Three-Dimensional Cell Cultures Promotes Survival and Regeneration in Acute Lung Injury Model in Mice</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35408778/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35408778/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acute lung injury (ALI) and acute respiratory distress syndrome (ARDS) is a common clinical problem, leading to significant morbidity and mortality, and no effective pharmacotherapy exists. The problem of ARDS causing mortality became more apparent during the COVID-19 pandemic. Biotherapeutic products containing multipotent mesenchymal stromal cell (MMSC) secretome may provide a new therapeutic paradigm for human healthcare due to their immunomodulating and regenerative abilities. The content and regenerative capacity of the secretome depends on cell origin and type of cultivation (two- or three-dimensional (2D/3D)). In this study, we investigated the proteomic profile of the secretome from 2D- and 3D-cultured placental MMSC and lung fibroblasts (LFBs) and the effect of inhalation of freeze-dried secretome on survival, lung inflammation, lung tissue regeneration, fibrin deposition in a lethal ALI model in mice. We found that three inhaled administrations of freeze-dried secretome from 2D- and 3D-cultured placental MMSC and LFB protected mice from death, restored the histological structure of damaged lungs, and decreased fibrin deposition. At the same time, 3D MMSC secretome exhibited a more pronounced trend in lung recovery than 2D MMSC and LFB-derived secretome in some measures. Taking together, these studies show that inhalation of cell secretome may also be considered as a potential therapy for the management of ARDS in patients suffering from severe pneumonia, including severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 (SARS-CoV-2), however, their effectiveness requires further investigation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spatiotemporal reprogramming of differentiated cells underlies regeneration and neoplasia in the intestinal epithelium</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35314700/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35314700/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although the mammalian intestinal epithelium manifests robust regenerative capacity after various cytotoxic injuries, the underlying mechanism has remained unclear. Here we identify the cyclin-dependent kinase inhibitor p57 as a specific marker for a quiescent cell population located around the +4 position of intestinal crypts. Lineage tracing reveals that the p57&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; cells serve as enteroendocrine/tuft cell precursors under normal conditions but dedifferentiate and act as facultative stem cells to support regeneration after injury. Single-cell transcriptomics analysis shows that the p57&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; cells undergo a dynamic reprogramming process after injury that is characterized by fetal-like conversion and metaplasia-like transformation. Population-level analysis also detects such spatiotemporal reprogramming widely in other differentiated cell types. In intestinal adenoma, p57&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; cells manifest homeostatic stem cell activity, in the context of constitutively activated spatiotemporal reprogramming. Our results highlight a pronounced plasticity of the intestinal epithelium that supports maintenance of tissue integrity in normal and neoplastic contexts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Telomere shortening impairs alveolar regeneration</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35274784/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35274784/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Objectives:&lt;/em&gt; Short telomeres in alveolar type 2 (AT2) cells have been associated with many lung diseases. The study aimed to investigate the regeneration capacity of AT2 cells with short telomeres by knocking out Tert in mice (G4 &lt;em&gt;Tert&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt;) from the whole to the cellular level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Materials and methods:&lt;/em&gt; The lung injury model of mice was established by left pneumonectomy (PNX). The proliferation and differentiation of AT2 cells were observed by immunofluorescence staining in vivo and in vitro. The difference of the gene expression between control and G4 &lt;em&gt;Tert&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; group during the regeneration of AT2 cells was compared by RNA sequencing. The expression of tubulin polymerization promoting protein 3 (TPPP3) was reduced by adeno-associated virus delivery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; The alveolar regeneration in G4 &lt;em&gt;Tert&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; mice was impaired after PNX-induced lung injury. The regulation of cytoskeleton remodelling was defective in G4 &lt;em&gt;Tert&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; AT2 cells. The expression of TPPP3 was gradually increased during AT2 cell differentiation. The expression level of TPPP3 was reduced in G4 &lt;em&gt;Tert&lt;sup&gt;-/-&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; AT2 cells. Reducing TPPP3 expression in AT2 cells limits the microtubule remodelling and differentiation of AT2 cells.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/em&gt; Short telomeres in AT2 cells result in the reduced expression level of TPPP3, leading to impaired regeneration capacity of AT2 cells.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Loss of NPPA-AS1 promotes heart regeneration by stabilizing SFPQ-NONO heteromer-induced DNA repair</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35247074/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35247074/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The role of long non-coding RNA (lncRNA) in endogenous cardiac regeneration remains largely elusive. The mammalian cardiomyocyte is capable of regeneration for a brief period after birth. This fact allows the exploration of the roles of critical lncRNAs in the regulation of cardiac regeneration. Through a cardiac regeneration model by apical resection (AR) of the left ventricle in neonatal mice, we identified an lncRNA named natriuretic peptide A antisense RNA 1 (NPPA-AS1), which negatively regulated cardiomyocyte proliferation. In neonates, NPPA-AS1 deletion did not affect heart development, but was sufficient to prolong the postnatal window of regeneration after AR. In adult mice, NPPA-AS1 deletion improved cardiac function and reduced infarct size after myocardial infarction (MI), associated with a significant improvement in cardiomyocyte proliferation. Further analysis showed that NPPA-AS1 interacted with DNA repair-related molecule splicing factor, proline- and glutamine-rich (SFPQ). A heteromer of SFPQ and non-POU domain-containing octamer-binding protein (NONO) was required for double-strand DNA break repair, but NPPA-AS1 was competitively bound with SFPQ due to the overlapped binding sites of SFPQ and NONO. NPPA-AS1 deletion promoted the binding of SFPQ-NONO heteromer, decreased DNA damage, and activated cardiomyocyte cell cycle re-entry. Together, loss of NPPA-AS1 promoted cardiomyocyte proliferation by stabilizing SFPQ-NONO heteromer-induced DNA repair and exerted a therapeutic effect against MI in adult mice. Consequently, NPPA-AS1 may be a novel target for stimulating cardiac regeneration to treat MI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Construction of a magnesium hydroxide/graphene oxide/hydroxyapatite composite coating on Mg-Ca-Zn-Ag alloy to inhibit bacterial infection and promote bone regeneration</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35415306/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35415306/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A Mg(OH)&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;/GO/HA composite coating with high bonding strength was constructed on the surface of Mg–Ca–Zn–Ag alloy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The outer HA layer with excellent osteogenic activity recovered the high corrosion resistance of inner Mg(OH)&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; layer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Mg(OH)&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;/GO/HA composite coating promoted new bone regeneration significantly under both normal and infected conditions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The improved corrosion resistance, osteogenic activity, and antibacterial ability are the key factors for promoting the large-scale clinical application of magnesium (Mg)-based implants. In the present study, a novel nanocomposite coating composed of inner magnesium hydroxide, middle graphene oxide, and outer hydroxyapatite (Mg(OH)&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;/GO/HA) is constructed on the surface of Mg-0.8Ca-5Zn-1.5Ag by a combined strategy of hydrothermal treatment, electrophoretic deposition, and electrochemical deposition. The results of material characterization and electrochemical corrosion test showed that all the three coatings have high bonding strength, hydrophilicity and corrosion resistance. In vitro studies show that Mg(OH)&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; indeed improves the antibacterial activity of the substrate. The next GO and GO/HA coating procedures both promote the osteogenic differentiation of MC3T3-E1 cells and show no harm to the antibacterial activity of Mg(OH)&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; coating, but the latter exhibits the best promoting effect. In vivo studies demonstrate that the Mg alloy with the composite coating not only ameliorates osteolysis induced by bacterial invasion but also promotes bone regeneration under both normal and infected conditions. The current study provides a promising surface modification strategy for developing multifunctional Mg-based implants with good corrosion resistance, antibacterial ability and osteogenic activity to enlarge their biomedical applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modeling injury and repair in kidney organoids reveals that homologous recombination governs tubular intrinsic repair</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35235339/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35235339/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Erratum in:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Erratum for the Research Article, &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/scitranslmed.add0524&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Modeling injury and repair in kidney organoids reveals that homologous recombination governs tubular intrinsic repair&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; by N. Gupta et al.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kidneys have the capacity for intrinsic repair, preserving kidney architecture with return to a basal state after tubular injury. When injury is overwhelming or repetitive, however, that capacity is exceeded and incomplete repair results in fibrotic tissue replacing normal kidney parenchyma. Loss of nephrons correlates with reduced kidney function, which defines chronic kidney disease (CKD) and confers substantial morbidity and mortality to the worldwide population. Despite the identification of pathways involved in intrinsic repair, limited treatments for CKD exist, partly because of the limited throughput and predictivity of animal studies. Here, we showed that kidney organoids can model the transition from intrinsic to incomplete repair. Single-nuclear RNA sequencing of kidney organoids after cisplatin exposure identified 159 differentially expressed genes and 29 signal pathways in tubular cells undergoing intrinsic repair. Homology-directed repair (HDR) genes including Fanconi anemia complementation group D2 (&lt;em&gt;FANCD2&lt;/em&gt;) and RAD51 recombinase (&lt;em&gt;RAD51&lt;/em&gt;) were transiently up-regulated during intrinsic repair but were down-regulated in incomplete repair. Single cellular transcriptomics in mouse models of obstructive and hemodynamic kidney injury and human kidney samples of immune-mediated injury validated HDR gene up-regulation during tubular repair. Kidney biopsy samples with tubular injury and varying degrees of fibrosis confirmed loss of FANCD2 during incomplete repair. Last, we performed targeted drug screening that identified the DNA ligase IV inhibitor, SCR7, as a therapeutic candidate that rescued FANCD2/RAD51-mediated repair to prevent the progression of CKD in the cisplatin-induced organoid injury model. Our findings demonstrate the translational utility of kidney organoids to identify pathologic pathways and potential therapies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multi-omic analysis reveals divergent molecular events in scarring and regenerative wound healing</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35077667/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35077667/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Verteporfin (YAP inhibitor) treatment yields wound regeneration in mice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Divergent molecular pathways of scarring versus regeneration are defined by differential mechanical versus Wnt signaling&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Trps1 drives wound regeneration in the context of blocked mechanical signaling&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Summary&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regeneration is the holy grail of tissue repair, but skin injury typically yields fibrotic, non-functional scars. Developing pro-regenerative therapies requires rigorous understanding of the molecular progression from injury to fibrosis or regeneration. Here, we report the divergent molecular events driving skin wound cells toward scarring or regenerative fates. We profile scarring versus YAP-inhibition-induced wound regeneration at the transcriptional (single-cell RNA sequencing), protein (timsTOF proteomics), and tissue (extracellular matrix ultrastructural analysis) levels. Using cell-surface barcoding, we integrate these data to reveal fibrotic and regenerative “molecular trajectories” of healing. We show that disrupting YAP mechanotransduction yields regenerative repair by fibroblasts with activated Trps1 and Wnt signaling. Finally, via in vivo gene knockdown and overexpression in wounds, we identify Trps1 as a key regulatory gene that is necessary and partially sufficient for wound regeneration. Our findings serve as a multi-omic map of wound regeneration and could have therapeutic implications for pathologic fibroses.
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lung Injury Induces Alveolar Type 2 Cell Hypertrophy and Polyploidy with Implications for Repair and Regeneration</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35202558/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35202558/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Epithelial polyploidization after injury is a conserved phenomenon recently shown to improve barrier restoration during wound healing. Whether lung injury can induce alveolar epithelial polyploidy is not known. We show that bleomycin injury induces alveolar type 2 cell (AT2) hypertrophy and polyploidy. AT2 polyploidization is also seen in short term ex vivo cultures, where AT2-to-AT1 transdifferentiation is associated with substantial binucleation due to failed cytokinesis. Both hypertrophic and polyploid features of AT2 cells can be attenuated by inhibiting the integrated stress response using the small molecule ISRIB. These data suggest that AT2 hypertrophic growth and polyploidization may be a feature of alveolar epithelial injury. Because AT2 cells serve as facultative progenitors for the distal lung epithelium, a propensity for injury-induced binucleation has implications for AT2 self-renewal and regenerative potential upon reinjury, which may benefit from targeting the integrated stress response.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Efficient healing of large osseous segmental defects using optimized chemically modified messenger RNA encoding BMP-2</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35171668/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35171668/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Large segmental osseous defects heal poorly. Recombinant, human bone morphogenetic protein-2 (rhBMP-2) is used clinically to promote bone healing, but it is applied at very high doses that cause adverse side effects and raise costs while providing only incremental benefit. We describe a previously unexplored, alternative approach to bone regeneration using chemically modified messenger RNA (cmRNA). An optimized cmRNA encoding BMP-2 was delivered to critical-sized femoral osteotomies in rats. The cmRNA remained orthotopically localized and generated BMP locally for several days. Defects healed at doses ≥25 μg of BMP-2 cmRNA. By 4 weeks, all animals treated with 50 μg of BMP-2 cmRNA had bridged bone defects without forming the massive callus seen with rhBMP-2. Moreover, such defects recovered normal mechanical strength quicker and initiated bone remodeling faster. cmRNA regenerated bone via endochondral ossification, whereas rhBMP-2 drove intramembranous osteogenesis; cmRNA provides an innovative, safe, and highly translatable technology for bone healing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IRE1α drives lung epithelial progenitor dysfunction to establish a niche for pulmonary fibrosis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35170357/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35170357/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After lung injury, damage-associated transient progenitors (DATPs) emerge, representing a transitional state between injured epithelial cells and newly regenerated alveoli. DATPs express profibrotic genes, suggesting that they might promote idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis (IPF). However, the molecular pathways that induce and/or maintain DATPs are incompletely understood. Here we show that the bifunctional kinase/RNase-IRE1α-a central mediator of the unfolded protein response (UPR) to endoplasmic reticulum (ER) stress is a critical promoter of DATP abundance and function. Administration of a nanomolar-potent, monoselective kinase inhibitor of IRE1α (KIRA8)-or conditional epithelial IRE1α gene knockout-both reduce DATP cell number and fibrosis in the bleomycin model, indicating that IRE1α cell-autonomously promotes transition into the DATP state. IRE1α enhances the profibrotic phenotype of DATPs since KIRA8 decreases expression of integrin αvβ6, a key activator of transforming growth factor β (TGF-β) in pulmonary fibrosis, corresponding to decreased TGF-β-induced gene expression in the epithelium and decreased collagen accumulation around DATPs. Furthermore, IRE1α regulates DNA damage response (DDR) signaling, previously shown to promote the DATP phenotype, as IRE1α loss-of-function decreases H2AX phosphorylation, Cdkn1a (p21) expression, and DDR-associated secretory gene expression. Finally, KIRA8 treatment increases the differentiation of Krt19CreERT2-lineage-traced DATPs into type 1 alveolar epithelial cells after bleomycin injury, indicating that relief from IRE1α signaling enables DATPs to exit the transitional state. Thus, IRE1α coordinates a network of stress pathways that conspire to entrap injured cells in the DATP state. Pharmacological blockade of IRE1α signaling helps resolve the DATP state, thereby ameliorating fibrosis and promoting salutary lung regeneration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sec13 promotes oligodendrocyte differentiation and myelin repair through autocrine pleiotrophin signaling</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35143418/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35143418/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dysfunction of protein trafficking has been intensively associated with neurological diseases, including neurodegeneration, but whether and how protein transport contributes to oligodendrocyte (OL) maturation and myelin repair in white matter injury remains unclear. ER-to-Golgi trafficking of newly synthesized proteins is mediated by coat protein complex II (COPII). Here, we demonstrate that the COPII component Sec13 was essential for OL differentiation and postnatal myelination. Ablation of Sec13 in the OL lineage prevented OPC differentiation and inhibited myelination and remyelination after demyelinating injury in the central nervous system (CNS), while improving protein trafficking by tauroursodeoxycholic acid (TUDCA) or ectopic expression of COPII components accelerated myelination. COPII components were upregulated in OL lineage cells after demyelinating injury. Loss of Sec13 altered the secretome of OLs and inhibited the secretion of pleiotrophin (PTN), which was found to function as an autocrine factor to promote OL differentiation and myelin repair. These data suggest that Sec13-dependent protein transport is essential for OL differentiation and that Sec13-mediated PTN autocrine signaling is required for proper myelination and remyelination.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SARS-CoV-2 Infection and Lung Regeneration</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/35107300/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/35107300/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The lung is the primary site of severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 (SARS-CoV-2)-induced immunopathology whereby the virus enters the host cells by binding to angiotensin-converting enzyme 2 (ACE2). Sophisticated regeneration and repair programs exist in the lungs to replenish injured cell populations. However, known resident stem/progenitor cells have been demonstrated to express ACE2, raising a substantial concern regarding the long-term consequences of impaired lung regeneration after SARS-CoV-2 infection. Moreover, clinical treatments may also affect lung repair from antiviral drug candidates to mechanical ventilation. In this review, we highlight how SARS-CoV-2 disrupts a program that governs lung homeostasis. We also summarize the current efforts of targeted therapy and supportive treatments for COVID-19 patients. In addition, we discuss the pros and cons of cell therapy with mesenchymal stem cells or resident lung epithelial stem/progenitor cells in preventing post-acute sequelae of COVID-19. We propose that, in addition to symptomatic treatments being developed and applied in the clinic, targeting lung regeneration is also essential to restore lung homeostasis in COVID-19 patients.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extracellular vesicle-mediated cellular crosstalk in lung repair, remodelling and regeneration</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/35082125/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/35082125/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The unperturbed lung is highly quiescent, with a remarkably low level of cell turnover. However, once damaged, the lung shows an extensive regenerative capacity, with resident progenitor cell populations re-entering the cell cycle and differentiating to promote repair. This quick and dramatic repair response requires interactions among more than 40 different cell lineages in the lung, and defects in any of these processes can lead to various lung pathologies. Understanding the mechanisms of interaction in lung injury, repair and regeneration thus has considerable practical and therapeutic implications. Moreover, therapeutic strategies for replacing lung progenitor cells and their progeny through cell therapy have gained increasing attention. In the last decade, extracellular vesicles (EVs), including exosomes, have been recognised as paracrine mediators through the transfer of biological cargo. Recent work has revealed that EVs are involved in lung homeostasis and diseases. In addition, EVs derived from specific cells or tissues have proven to be a promising cell-free modality for the treatment of lung diseases. This review highlights the EV-mediated cellular crosstalk that regulates lung homeostasis and discusses the potential of EV therapeutics for lung regenerative medicine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MICU1-dependent mitochondrial calcium uptake regulates lung alveolar type 2 cell plasticity and lung regeneration</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35050901/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35050901/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lung alveolar type 2 (AT2) cells are progenitors for alveolar type 1 (AT1) cells. Although many factors regulate AT2 cell plasticity, the role of mitochondrial calcium (&lt;sub&gt;m&lt;/sub&gt;Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt;) uptake in controlling AT2 cells remains unclear. We previously identified that the miR-302 family supports lung epithelial progenitor cell proliferation and less differentiated phenotypes during development. Here, we report that a sustained elevation of miR-302 in adult AT2 cells decreases AT2-to-AT1 cell differentiation during the Streptococcus pneumoniae-induced lung injury repair. We identified that miR-302 targets and represses the expression of mitochondrial Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt; uptake 1 (MICU1), which regulates &lt;sub&gt;m&lt;/sub&gt;Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt; uptake through the &lt;sub&gt;m&lt;/sub&gt;Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt; uniporter channel by acting as a gatekeeper at low cytosolic Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt; levels. Our results reveal a marked increase in MICU1 protein expression and decreased &lt;sub&gt;m&lt;/sub&gt;Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt; uptake during AT2-to-AT1 cell differentiation in the adult lung. Deletion of &lt;em&gt;Micu1&lt;/em&gt; in AT2 cells reduces AT2-to-AT1 cell differentiation during steady-state tissue maintenance and alveolar epithelial regeneration after bacterial pneumonia. These studies indicate that &lt;sub&gt;m&lt;/sub&gt;Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt; uptake is extensively modulated during AT2-to-AT1 cell differentiation and that MICU1-dependent &lt;sub&gt;m&lt;/sub&gt;Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt; uniporter channel gating is a prominent mechanism modulating AT2-to-AT1 cell differentiation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Myeloid mineralocorticoid receptors contribute to skeletal muscle repair in muscular dystrophy and acute muscle injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35044859/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35044859/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Suppressing mineralocorticoid receptor (MR) activity with MR antagonists is therapeutic for chronic skeletal muscle pathology in Duchenne muscular dystrophy (DMD) mouse models. Although mechanisms underlying clinical MR antagonist efficacy for DMD cardiomyopathy and other cardiac diseases are defined, mechanisms in skeletal muscles are not fully elucidated. Myofiber MR knockout improves skeletal muscle force and a subset of dystrophic pathology. However, MR signaling in myeloid cells is known to be a major contributor to cardiac efficacy. To define contributions of myeloid MR in skeletal muscle function and disease, we performed parallel assessments of muscle pathology, cytokine levels, and myeloid cell populations resulting from myeloid MR genetic knockout in muscular dystrophy and acute muscle injury. Myeloid MR knockout led to lower levels of C-C motif chemokine receptor 2 (CCR2)-expressing macrophages, resulting in sustained myofiber damage after acute injury of normal muscle. In acute injury, myeloid MR knockout also led to increased local muscle levels of the enzyme that produces the endogenous MR agonist aldosterone, further supporting important contributions of MR signaling in normal muscle repair. In muscular dystrophy, myeloid MR knockout altered cytokine levels differentially between quadriceps and diaphragm muscles, which contain different myeloid populations. Myeloid MR knockout led to higher levels of fibrosis in dystrophic diaphragm. These results support important contributions of myeloid MR signaling to skeletal muscle repair in acute and chronic injuries and highlight the useful information gained from cell-specific genetic knockouts to delineate mechanisms of pharmacological efficacy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cartilaginous Extracellular Matrix Enriched with Human Gingival Mesenchymal Stem Cells Derived &#39;Matrix Bound Extracellular Vesicles&#39; Enabled Functional Reconstruction of Tracheal Defect</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34841733/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34841733/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stem cells derived extracellular vesicles (EVs) conceive cues essential for tissue repair. Mammalian cartilaginous extracellular matrix (cECM) may not be optimally inductive for tracheal regeneration because of the granulomatous, instead of regenerative, responses in injured adult mammalian tracheas. Given the high regenerative capacity of gingiva, it is hypothesized human gingival mesenchymal stem cells derived EVs (gEVs) can induce mammalian tracheal epithelia regeneration. Coculturing chondrocytes with GMSCs produce abundant &amp;ldquo;matrix bound gEVs (gMVs)&amp;rdquo; in forming cartilaginous ECM, which are further preserved in acellular cECM (cACM) following mild, short-period decellularization. The results show that gMVs-cACM could be well anchored on polyglycerol sebacate microporous patch thus enforce the surgical suturability and mechanical strength. In rabbit tracheal defect, the gMVs-cACM patch induces rapid regeneration of vascularized ciliated columnar epithelium, which supports long-term survival of animals. gMVs-cACM treated groups exhibit proliferation of tracheal progenitors-basal epithelial cells, as well as, activation of JAK2/STAT1 pathway in reparative cells. This study departs from conventional focuses on tissue derived ECM and introduces a new approach for tracheal tissue regeneration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hair shaft miniaturization causes stem cell depletion through mechanosensory signals mediated by a Piezo1-calcium-TNF-α axis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34624205/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34624205/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In aging, androgenic alopecia, and genetic hypotrichosis disorders, hair shaft miniaturization is often associated with hair follicle stem cell (HFSC) loss. However, the mechanism causing this stem cell depletion in vivo remains elusive. Here we show that hair shaft loss or a reduction in diameter shrinks the physical niche size, which results in mechanical compression of HFSCs and their apoptotic loss. Mechanistically, cell compression activates the mechanosensitive channel Piezo1, which triggers calcium influx. This confers tumor necrosis factor alpha (TNF-α) sensitivity in a hair-cycle-dependent manner in otherwise resistant HFSCs and induces ectopic apoptosis. Persistent hair shaft miniaturization during aging and genetic hypotrichosis disorders causes long-term HFSC loss by inducing continuous ectopic apoptosis through Piezo1. Our results identify an unconventional role of the inert hair shaft structure as a functional niche component governing HFSC survival and reveal a mechanosensory axis that regulates physical-niche-atrophy-induced stem cell depletion in vivo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bottom-up assembly of biomedical relevant fully synthetic extracellular vesicles</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34516902/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34516902/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Extracellular vesicles (EVs) are fundamental for intercellular communication and influence nearly every process in cell physiology. However, because of their intricate molecular complexity, quantitative knowledge on their signaling mechanisms is missing, particularly impeding their therapeutic application. We used a complementary and quantitative engineering approach based on sequential synthetic bottom-up assembly of fully functional EVs with precisely controlled lipid, protein, and RNA composition. We show that the functionalities of synthetic EVs are analogous to natural EVs and demonstrate their programmable therapeutic administration for wound healing and neovascularization therapy. We apply transcriptome profiling to systematically decode synergistic effects between individual EV constituents, enabling analytical dissection and a fundamental understanding of EV signaling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The cell cycle inhibitor P21 promotes the development of pulmonary fibrosis by suppressing lung alveolar regeneration</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35256943/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35256943/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The cell cycle inhibitor P21 has been implicated in cell senescence and plays an important role in the injury-repair process following lung injury. Pulmonary fibrosis (PF) is a fibrotic lung disorder characterized by cell senescence in lung alveolar epithelial cells. In this study, we report that P21 expression was increased in alveolar epithelial type 2 cells (AEC2s) in a time-dependent manner following multiple bleomycin-induced PF. Repeated injury of AEC2s resulted in telomere shortening and triggered P21-dependent cell senescence. AEC2s with elevated expression of P21 lost their self-renewal and differentiation abilities. In particular, elevated P21 not only induced cell cycle arrest in AEC2s but also bound to P300 and β-catenin and inhibited AEC2 differentiation by disturbing the P300-β-catenin interaction. Meanwhile, senescent AEC2s triggered myofibroblast activation by releasing profibrotic cytokines. Knockdown of &lt;em&gt;P21&lt;/em&gt; restored AEC2-mediated lung alveolar regeneration in mice with chronic PF. The results of our study reveal a mechanism of P21-mediated lung regeneration failure during PF development, which suggests a potential strategy for the treatment of fibrotic lung diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hypoxia adipose stem cell-derived exosomes promote high-quality healing of diabetic wound involves activation of PI3K/Akt pathways</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34233694/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34233694/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Refractory diabetic wounds can cause persistent inflammation and delayed healing due to hypoxia. Currently, no optimal solution is available. Exosomes of adipose stem cells (ADSCs-exo) may promote skin wound healing, however, molecular mechanisms remains mysterious. We found significantly enhanced survival and proliferation of adipose stem cells after hypoxia induction compared to normoxia. Here, we aimed to investigate if hypoxic adipose stem cells exosomes (HypADSCs-exo) participate in hypoxia adaptability and accelerate diabetic wound healing. Based on high-throughput sequencing, 215 microRNAs (miRNAs) were upregulated and 369 miRNAs downregulated in HypADSCs-exo compared to ADSCs-exo. Up-regulated miR-21-3p, miR-126-5p, miR-31-5p whereas down-regulated gene miR-99b and miR-146-a correlated with wound healing. According to Gene Ontology (GO) and Kyoto Encyclopedia of Genes and Genomes (KEGG), miRNAs might regulate cell metabolism, differentiation and Transforming growth factor-β (TGF-β) function. Consistently, HpyADSCs-exo could promote diabetic wounds healing and inhibit inflammation through PI3K/AKT signaling pathway. Collectively, HpyADSCs-exo can promote diabetic wound healing as an alternative strategy to improve wound healing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Age-dependent alveolar epithelial plasticity orchestrates lung homeostasis and regeneration</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33974915/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33974915/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regeneration of the architecturally complex alveolar niche of the lung requires precise temporal and spatial control of epithelial cell behavior. Injury can lead to a permanent reduction in gas exchange surface area and respiratory function. Using mouse models, we show that alveolar type 1 (AT1) cell plasticity is a major and unappreciated mechanism that drives regeneration, beginning in the early postnatal period during alveolar maturation. Upon acute neonatal lung injury, AT1 cells reprogram into alveolar type 2 (AT2) cells, promoting alveolar regeneration. In contrast, the ability of AT2 cells to regenerate AT1 cells is restricted to the mature lung. Unbiased genomic assessment reveals that this previously unappreciated level of plasticity is governed by the preferential activity of Hippo signaling in the AT1 cell lineage. Thus, cellular plasticity is a temporally acquired trait of the alveolar epithelium and presents an alternative mode of tissue regeneration in the postnatal lung.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Preventing Engrailed-1 activation in fibroblasts yields wound regeneration without scarring</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33888614/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33888614/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Skin scarring, the end result of adult wound healing, is detrimental to tissue form and function. &lt;em&gt;Engrailed-1&lt;/em&gt; lineage-positive fibroblasts (EPFs) are known to function in scarring, but &lt;em&gt;Engrailed-1&lt;/em&gt; lineage-negative fibroblasts (ENFs) remain poorly characterized. Using cell transplantation and transgenic mouse models, we identified a dermal ENF subpopulation that gives rise to postnatally derived EPFs by activating &lt;em&gt;Engrailed-1&lt;/em&gt; expression during adult wound healing. By studying ENF responses to substrate mechanics, we found that mechanical tension drives &lt;em&gt;Engrailed-1&lt;/em&gt; activation via canonical mechanotransduction signaling. Finally, we showed that blocking mechanotransduction signaling with either verteporfin, an inhibitor of Yes-associated protein (YAP), or fibroblast-specific transgenic YAP knockout prevents &lt;em&gt;Engrailed-1&lt;/em&gt; activation and promotes wound regeneration by ENFs, with recovery of skin appendages, ultrastructure, and mechanical strength. This finding suggests that there are two possible outcomes to postnatal wound healing: a fibrotic response (EPF-mediated) and a regenerative response (ENF-mediated).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interaction of the NRF2 and p63 transcription factors promotes keratinocyte proliferation in the epidermis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33764436/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33764436/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Epigenetic regulation of cell and tissue function requires the coordinated action of transcription factors. However, their combinatorial activities during regeneration remain largely unexplored. Here, we discover an unexpected interaction between the cytoprotective transcription factor NRF2 and p63- a key player in epithelial morphogenesis. Chromatin immunoprecipitation combined with sequencing and reporter assays identifies enhancers and promoters that are simultaneously activated by NRF2 and p63 in human keratinocytes. Modeling of p63 and NRF2 binding to nucleosomal DNA suggests their chromatin-assisted interaction. Pharmacological and genetic activation of NRF2 increases NRF2-p63 binding to enhancers and promotes keratinocyte proliferation, which involves the common NRF2-p63 target cyclin-dependent kinase 12. These results unravel a collaborative function of NRF2 and p63 in the control of epidermal renewal and suggest their combined activation as a strategy to promote repair of human skin and other stratified epithelia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bacteria induce skin regeneration via IL-1β signaling</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33798492/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33798492/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Germ-free mice have low skin regeneration&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Skin commensal microbiome and even pathological S. aureus induce regeneration&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bacteria induce regeneration through IL1β-keratinocyte-dependent IL1R/Myd88 signaling&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Commensal bacteria promote healing in humans&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Environmental factors that enhance regeneration are largely unknown. The immune system and microbiome are attributed roles in repairing and regenerating structure but their precise interplay is unclear. Here, we assessed the function of skin bacteria in wound healing and wound-induced hair follicle neogenesis (WIHN), a rare adult organogenesis model. WIHN levels and stem cell markers correlate with bacterial counts, being lowest in germ-free (GF), intermediate in conventional specific pathogen-free (SPF), and highest in wild-type mice, even those infected with pathogenic &lt;em&gt;Staphylococcus aureus&lt;/em&gt;. Reducing skin microbiota via cage changes or topical antibiotics decreased WIHN. Inflammatory cytokine IL-1β and keratinocyte-dependent IL-1R-MyD88 signaling are necessary and sufficient for bacteria to promote regeneration. Finally, in a small trial, a topical broad-spectrum antibiotic also slowed skin wound healing in adult volunteers. These results demonstrate a role for IL-1β to control morphogenesis and support the need to reconsider routine applications of topical prophylactic antibiotics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Long non-coding RNA HCAR promotes endochondral bone repair by upregulating VEGF and MMP13 in hypertrophic chondrocyte through sponging miR-15b-5p</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35224160/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35224160/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Endochondral bone formation is an important route for bone repair. Although emerging evidence has revealed the functions of long non-coding RNAs (lncRNAs) in bone and cartilage development, the effect of lncRNAs in endochondral bone repair is still largely unknown. Here, we identified a lncRNA, named Hypertrophic Chondrocyte Angiogenesis-related lncRNA (HCAR), and proved it to promote the endochondral bone repair by upregulating the expression of matrix metallopeptidase 13 (Mmp13) and vascular endothelial growth factor α (Vegfa) in hypertrophic chondrocytes. Lnc-HCAR knockdown in hypertrophic chondrocytes restrained the cartilage matrix remodeling and decrease the CD31hiEmcnhi vessels number in a bone repair model. Mechanistically, we proved that lnc-HCAR was mainly enriched in the cytoplasm using fluorescence in situ hybridization (FISH) assay, and it acted as a molecular sponge for miR-15b-5p. Further, in hypertrophic chondrocytes, lnc-HCAR competitively bound to miR-15b-5p to increase Vegfa and Mmp13 expression. Our results proved that lncRNA is deeply involved in endochondral bone repair, which will provide a new theoretical basis for future strategies for promoting fracture healing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inflammatory Signals Induce AT2 Cell-Derived Damage-Associated Transient Progenitors that Mediate Alveolar Regeneration</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32750316/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32750316/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tissue regeneration is a multi-step process mediated by diverse cellular hierarchies and states that are also implicated in tissue dysfunction and pathogenesis. Here we leveraged single-cell RNA sequencing in combination with in vivo lineage tracing and organoid models to finely map the trajectories of alveolar-lineage cells during injury repair and lung regeneration. We identified a distinct AT2-lineage population, damage-associated transient progenitors (DATPs), that arises during alveolar regeneration. We found that interstitial macrophage-derived IL-1β primes a subset of AT2 cells expressing Il1r1 for conversion into DATPs via a HIF1α-mediated glycolysis pathway, which is required for mature AT1 cell differentiation. Importantly, chronic inflammation mediated by IL-1β prevents AT1 differentiation, leading to aberrant accumulation of DATPs and impaired alveolar regeneration. Together, this stepwise mapping to cell fate transitions shows how an inflammatory niche controls alveolar regeneration by controlling stem cell fate and behavior.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Defining Epidermal Basal Cell States during Skin Homeostasis and Wound Healing Using Single-Cell Transcriptomics</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32187560/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32187560/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our knowledge of transcriptional heterogeneities in epithelial stem and progenitor cell compartments is limited. Epidermal basal cells sustain cutaneous tissue maintenance and drive wound healing. Previous studies have probed basal cell heterogeneity in stem and progenitor potential, but a comprehensive dissection of basal cell dynamics during differentiation is lacking. Using single-cell RNA sequencing coupled with RNAScope and fluorescence lifetime imaging, we identify three non-proliferative and one proliferative basal cell state in homeostatic skin that differ in metabolic preference and become spatially partitioned during wound re-epithelialization. Pseudotemporal trajectory and RNA velocity analyses predict a quasi-linear differentiation hierarchy where basal cells progress from Col17a1&lt;sup&gt;Hi&lt;/sup&gt;/Trp63&lt;sup&gt;Hi&lt;/sup&gt; state to early-response state, proliferate at the juncture of these two states, or become growth arrested before differentiating into spinous cells. Wound healing induces plasticity manifested by dynamic basal-spinous interconversions at multiple basal transcriptional states. Our study provides a systematic view of epidermal cellular dynamics, supporting a revised &amp;ldquo;hierarchical-lineage&amp;rdquo; model of homeostasis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In situ gas foaming based on magnesium particle degradation: A novel approach to fabricate injectable macroporous hydrogels</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/31918223/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/31918223/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Injectable hydrogels are attractive biomaterials for cell delivery in tissue engineering. However, the in vivo viability of transplanted cells remains limited. Typically, macroporous structures constructed in hydrogels are utilized to enhance oxygen and nutrients diffusion for cell survival and to promote integration between the material and host tissue. A new gas-foaming method to generate pores was proposed by directly adding Mg particles into cell-laden hydrogel solutions, taking advantage of the H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; gas formed during the degradation of Mg. The optimization design of the size and amount of Mg particles added into the hydrogels was investigated. Improved cell viability and proliferation were demonstrated in the group with Mg particles. Additionally, Mg&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt; ions generated during Mg degradation facilitated the osteogenic differentiation of stem cells encapsulated in hydrogels. Extensive vascularized bone regeneration in the femoral defects of rats revealed that the use of Mg particles as the foaming agent is feasible, endowing injectable hydrogels with optimized porosity and enhanced bioactivity, and providing a new strategy for future designs of porous hydrogels in tissue engineering.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Long-Term Culture Captures Injury-Repair Cycles of Colonic Stem Cells</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/31708126/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/31708126/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The colonic epithelium can undergo multiple rounds of damage and repair, often in response to excessive inflammation. The responsive stem cell that mediates this process is unclear, in part because of a lack of in vitro models that recapitulate key epithelial changes that occur in vivo during damage and repair. Here, we identify a Hopx&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; colitis-associated regenerative stem cell (CARSC) population that functionally contributes to mucosal repair in mouse models of colitis. Hopx&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; CARSCs, enriched for fetal-like markers, transiently arose from hypertrophic crypts known to facilitate regeneration. Importantly, we established a long-term, self-organizing two-dimensional (2D) epithelial monolayer system to model the regenerative properties and responses of Hopx&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; CARSCs. This system can reenact the &amp;ldquo;homeostasis-injury-regeneration&amp;rdquo; cycles of epithelial alterations that occur in vivo. Using this system, we found that hypoxia and endoplasmic reticulum stress, insults commonly present in inflammatory bowel diseases, mediated the cyclic switch of cellular status in this process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stem cell-driven lymphatic remodeling coordinates tissue regeneration</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/31672914/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/31672914/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tissues rely on stem cells (SCs) for homeostasis and wound repair. SCs reside in specialized microenvironments (niches) whose complexities and roles in orchestrating tissue growth are still unfolding. Here, we identify lymphatic capillaries as critical SC-niche components. In skin, lymphatics form intimate networks around hair follicle (HF) SCs. When HFs regenerate, lymphatic-SC connections become dynamic. Using a mouse model, we unravel a secretome switch in SCs that controls lymphatic behavior. Resting SCs express angiopoietin-like protein 7 (&lt;em&gt;Angptl7&lt;/em&gt;), promoting lymphatic drainage. Activated SCs switch to &lt;em&gt;Angptl4&lt;/em&gt;, triggering transient lymphatic dissociation and reduced drainage. When lymphatics are perturbed or the secretome switch is disrupted, HFs cycle precociously and tissue regeneration becomes asynchronous. In unearthing lymphatic capillaries as a critical SC-niche element, we have learned how SCs coordinate their activity across a tissue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mast cells are critical for controlling the bacterial burden and the healing of infected wounds</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/31548430/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/31548430/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Skin wound infections are a significant health problem, and antibiotic resistance is on the rise. Mast cells (MCs) have been shown to contribute to host-defense responses in certain bacterial infections, but their role in skin wound superinfection is unknown. We subjected 2 MC-deficient mouse strains to Pseudomonas aeruginosa skin wound infection and found significantly delayed wound closure in infected skin wounds. This delay was associated with impaired bacterial clearance in the absence of MCs. Engraftment of MCs restored both bacterial clearance and wound closure. Bacterial killing was dependent on IL-6 released from MCs, and engraftment with IL-6-deficient MCs failed to control wound infection. Treatment with recombinant IL-6 enhanced bacterial killing and resulted in the control of wound infection and normal wound healing in vivo. Taken together, our results demonstrate a defense mechanism for boosting host innate immune responses, namely effects of MC-derived IL-6 on antimicrobial functions of keratinocytes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use of three-dimensional organoids and lung-on-a-chip methods to study lung development, regeneration and disease</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/30262579/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/30262579/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Differences in lung anatomy between mice and humans, as well as frequently disappointing results when using animal models for drug discovery, emphasise the unmet need for in vitro models that can complement animal studies and improve our understanding of human lung physiology, regeneration and disease. Recent papers have highlighted the use of three-dimensional organoids and organs-on-a-chip to mimic tissue morphogenesis and function in vitro Here, we focus on the respiratory system and provide an overview of these in vitro models, which can be derived from primary lung cells and pluripotent stem cells, as well as healthy or diseased lungs. We emphasise their potential application in studies of respiratory development, regeneration and disease modelling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Human airway organoid engineering as a step toward lung regeneration and disease modeling</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/27815996/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/27815996/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Organoids represent both a potentially powerful tool for the study cell-cell interactions within tissue-like environments, and a platform for tissue regenerative approaches. The development of lung tissue-like organoids from human adult-derived cells has not previously been reported. Here we combined human adult primary bronchial epithelial cells, lung fibroblasts, and lung microvascular endothelial cells in supportive 3D culture conditions to generate airway organoids. We demonstrate that randomly-seeded mixed cell populations undergo rapid condensation and self-organization into discrete epithelial and endothelial structures that are mechanically robust and stable during long term culture. After condensation airway organoids generate invasive multicellular tubular structures that recapitulate limited aspects of branching morphogenesis, and require actomyosin-mediated force generation and YAP/TAZ activation. Despite the proximal source of primary epithelium used in the airway organoids, discrete areas of both proximal and distal epithelial markers were observed over time in culture, demonstrating remarkable epithelial plasticity within the context of organoid cultures. Airway organoids also exhibited complex multicellular responses to a prototypical fibrogenic stimulus (TGF-β1) in culture, and limited capacity to undergo continued maturation and engraftment after ectopic implantation under the murine kidney capsule. These results demonstrate that the airway organoid system developed here represents a novel tool for the study of disease-relevant cell-cell interactions, and establishes this platform as a first step toward cell-based therapy for chronic lung diseases based on de novo engineering of implantable airway tissues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
