<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Efferocytosis | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/efferocytosis/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/efferocytosis/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Efferocytosis</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Efferocytosis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/efferocytosis/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>SIRT6-regulated macrophage efferocytosis epigenetically controls inflammation resolution of diabetic periodontitis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36593966/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36593966/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rationale:&lt;/em&gt; Diabetes exacerbates the prevalence and severity of periodontitis, leading to severe periodontal destruction and ultimately tooth loss. Delayed resolution of inflammation is a major contributor to diabetic periodontitis (DP) pathogenesis, but the underlying mechanisms of this imbalanced immune homeostasis remain unclear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; We collected periodontium from periodontitis with or without diabetes to confirm the dysfunctional neutrophils and macrophages in aggravated inflammatory damage and impaired inflammation resolution. Our in vitro experiments confirmed that SIRT6 inhibited macrophage efferocytosis by restraining miR-216a-5p-216b-5p-217 cluster maturation through &amp;lsquo;&amp;rsquo;non-canonical&amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo; microprocessor complex (RNA pulldown, RIP, immunostaining, CHIP, Luciferase assays, and FISH). Moreover, we constructed m6SKO mice that underwent LIP-induced periodontitis to explore the in vitro and in vivo effect of SIRT6 on macrophage efferocytosis. Finally, antagomiR-217, a miRNA antagonism, was delivered into the periodontium to treat LIP-induced diabetic periodontitis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; We discovered that insufficient SIRT6 as a histone deacetylase in macrophages led to unresolved inflammation and aggravated periodontitis in both human and mouse DP with accumulated apoptotic neutrophil (AN) and higher generation of neutrophil extracellular traps. Mechanistically, we validated that macrophage underwent high glucose stimulation resulting in disturbance of the SIRT6-miR-216/217 axis that triggered impeded efferocytosis of AN through targeting the DEL-1/CD36 axis directly. Furthermore, we demonstrated the inhibitory role of SIRT6 for MIR217HG transcription and identified a non-canonical action of microprocessor that SIRT6 epigenetically hindered the splicing of the primary miR-216/217 via the complex of hnRNPA2B1, DGCR8, and Drosha. Notably, by constructing myeloid-specific deletion of SIRT6 mice and locally delivering antagomir-217 in DP models, we strengthened the in vivo effect of this axis in regulating macrophage efferocytosis and inflammation resolution in DP.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; Our findings delineated the emerging role of SIRT6 in mediating metabolic dysfunction-associated inflammation, and therapeutically targeting this regulatory axis might be a promising strategy for treating diabetes-associated inflammatory diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chimeric efferocytic receptors improve apoptotic cell clearance and alleviate inflammation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36563662/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36563662/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Design of chimeric receptors for efferocytosis (CHEF) to enhance efferocytosis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Boosting efferocytosis via CHEF attenuates multiple inflammatory insults &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Protein folding and misfolded protein degradation are rate-limiting steps in efferocytosis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CHEF expression can improve outcomes in ongoing disease&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our bodies turn over billions of cells daily via apoptosis and are in turn cleared by phagocytes via the process of &amp;ldquo;efferocytosis.&amp;rdquo; Defects in efferocytosis are now linked to various inflammatory diseases. Here, we designed a strategy to boost efferocytosis, denoted &amp;ldquo;chimeric receptor for efferocytosis&amp;rdquo; (CHEF). We fused a specific signaling domain within the cytoplasmic adapter protein ELMO1 to the extracellular phosphatidylserine recognition domains of the efferocytic receptors BAI1 or TIM4, generating BELMO and TELMO, respectively. CHEF-expressing phagocytes display a striking increase in efferocytosis. In mouse models of inflammation, BELMO expression attenuates colitis, hepatotoxicity, and nephrotoxicity. In mechanistic studies, BELMO increases ER-resident enzymes and chaperones to overcome protein-folding-associated toxicity, which was further validated in a model of ER-stress-induced renal ischemia-reperfusion injury. Finally, TELMO introduction after onset of kidney injury significantly reduced fibrosis. Collectively, these data advance a concept of chimeric efferocytic receptors to boost efferocytosis and dampen inflammation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Metabolic adaptation supports enhanced macrophage efferocytosis in limited-oxygen environments</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36584675/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36584675/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chronic physiological hypoxia enhances macrophage apoptotic cell uptake and degradation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chronic physiological hypoxia induces both primed and poised states in macrophages&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Both primed and poised state programs directly support enhanced continual efferocytosis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A noncanonical PPP loop supports enhanced efferocytosis and maintains redox homeostasis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apoptotic cell (AC) clearance (efferocytosis) is performed by phagocytes, such as macrophages, that inhabit harsh physiological environments. Here, we find that macrophages display enhanced efferocytosis under prolonged (chronic) physiological hypoxia, characterized by increased internalization and accelerated degradation of ACs. Transcriptional and translational analyses revealed that chronic physiological hypoxia induces two distinct but complimentary states. The first, &amp;ldquo;primed&amp;rdquo; state, consists of concomitant transcription and translation of metabolic programs in AC-naive macrophages that persist during efferocytosis. The second, &amp;ldquo;poised&amp;rdquo; state, consists of transcription, but not translation, of phagocyte function programs in AC-naive macrophages that are translated during efferocytosis. Mechanistically, macrophages efficiently flux glucose into a noncanonical pentose phosphate pathway (PPP) loop to enhance NADPH production. PPP-derived NADPH directly supports enhanced efferocytosis under physiological hypoxia by ensuring phagolysosomal maturation and redox homeostasis. Thus, macrophages residing under physiological hypoxia adopt states that support cell fitness and ensure performance of essential homeostatic functions rapidly and safely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resolution of post-lung transplant ischemia-reperfusion injury is modulated via Resolvin D1-FPR2 and Maresin 1-LGR6 signaling</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36628837/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36628837/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Dysregulation of inflammation-resolution pathways leads to postlung transplant (LTx) ischemia-reperfusion (IR) injury and allograft dysfunction. Our hypothesis is that combined treatment with specialized pro-resolving lipid mediators, that is, Resolvin D1 (RvD1) and Maresin-1 (MaR1), enhances inflammation-resolution of lung IR injury.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; Expression of RvD1 and MaR1 was analyzed in bronchoalveolar lavage (BAL) fluid of patients on days 0, 1, and 7 post-LTx. Lung IR injury was evaluated in C57BL/6 (WT), FPR2-/-, and LGR6 siRNA treated mice using a hilar-ligation model with or without administration with RvD1 and/or MaR1. A donation after circulatory death and murine orthotopic lung transplantation model was used to evaluate the protection by RvD1 and MaR1 against lung IR injury. In vitro studies analyzed alveolar macrophages and type II epithelial cell activation after treatment with RvD1 or MaR1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; RvD1 and MaR1 expressions in BAL from post-LTx patients was significantly increased on day 7 compared to days 0 and 1. Concomitant RvD1 and MaR1 treatment significantly mitigated early pulmonary inflammation and lung IR injury in WT mice, which was regulated via FPR2 and LGR6 receptors. In the murine orthotopic donation after cardiac death LTx model, RvD1 and MaR1 treatments significantly attenuated lung IR injury and increased PaO2 levels compared to saline-treated controls. Mechanistically, RvD1/FPR2 signaling on alveolar macrophages attenuated HMGB1 and TNF-α secretion and upregulated uptake of macrophage-dependent apoptotic neutrophils (efferocytosis), whereas MaR1/LGR6 signaling mitigated CXCL1 secretion by epithelial cells.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; Bioactive proresolving lipid mediator-dependent signaling that is, RvD1/FPR2 and MaR1/LGR6- offers a novel therapeutic strategy in post-LTx injury.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The EGFR/ErbB inhibitor neratinib modifies the neutrophil phosphoproteome and promotes apoptosis and clearance by airway macrophages</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35967296/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35967296/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dysregulated neutrophilic inflammation can be highly destructive in chronic inflammatory diseases due to prolonged neutrophil lifespan and continual release of histotoxic mediators in inflamed tissues. Therapeutic induction of neutrophil apoptosis, an immunologically silent form of cell death, may be beneficial in these diseases, provided that the apoptotic neutrophils are efficiently cleared from the tissue. Previous research in our group identified ErbB inhibitors as able to induce neutrophil apoptosis and reduce neutrophilic inflammation both &lt;em&gt;in vitro&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt;. Here, we extend that work using a clinical ErbB inhibitor, neratinib, which has the potential to be repurposed in inflammatory diseases. We show that neratinib reduces neutrophilic migration o an inflammatory site in zebrafish larvae. Neratinib upregulates efferocytosis and reduces the number of persisting neutrophil corpses in mouse models of acute, but not chronic, lung injury, suggesting that the drug may have therapeutic benefits in acute inflammatory settings. Phosphoproteomic analysis of human neutrophils shows that neratinib modifies the phosphorylation of proteins regulating apoptosis, migration, and efferocytosis. This work identifies a potential mechanism for neratinib in treating acute lung inflammation by upregulating the clearance of dead neutrophils and, through examination of the neutrophil phosphoproteome, provides important insights into the mechanisms by which this may be occurring.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inhaled Pro-Efferocytic Nanozymes Promote Resolution of Acute Lung Injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35859230/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35859230/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acute lung injury (ALI) is a significant contributor to the morbidity and mortality of sepsis. Characterized by uncontrolled inflammation and excessive inflammatory cells infiltration in lung, ALI has been exacerbated by impaired efferocytosis (clearance of apoptotic cells by macrophages). Through specific receptor recognition and activation of downstream signaling, efferocytic macrophages promote resolution of inflammation by efficiently engulfing dying cells, avoiding the consequent release of cellular inflammatory contents. Here, inspired by the intrinsic recovery mechanism of efferocytosis, an apoptotic cell membrane (ACM) coated antioxidant nanozyme (AOzyme) is engineered, thus obtaining an inhalable pro-efferocytic nanozyme (AOzyme@ACM). Notably, AOzyme@ACM can efficiently increase apoptotic cell removal by combing enhanced macrophages recognition of &amp;ldquo;eat me&amp;rdquo; signals through apoptotic body mimicking and scavenge of intracellular excessive reactive oxygen species (ROS), a significant barrier for efferocytosis. AOzyme@ACM can significantly inhibit inflammatory response, promote pro-resolving (M2) phenotype transition of macrophage, and alleviate ALI in endotoxemia mice compared with AOzyme group. By addressing the critical factor in the pathogenesis of sepsis-related ALI through restoring efferocytosis activity, the ACM-based antioxidant nanozyme in this study is envisioned to provide a promising strategy to treat this complex and challenging disease.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First we eat, then we do everything else: The dynamic metabolic regulation of efferocytosis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/34433074/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/34433074/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clearance of apoptotic cells, or &amp;ldquo;efferocytosis,&amp;rdquo; is essential for diverse processes including embryonic development, tissue turnover, organ regeneration, and immune cell development. The human body is estimated to remove approximately 1% of its body mass via apoptotic cell clearance daily. This poses several intriguing cell metabolism problems. For instance, phagocytes such as macrophages must induce or suppress metabolic pathways to find, engulf, and digest apoptotic cells. Then, phagocytes must manage the potentially burdensome biomass of the engulfed apoptotic cell. Finally, phagocytes reside in complex tissue architectures that vary in nutrient availability, the types of dying cells or debris that require clearance, and the neighboring cells they interact with. Here, we review advances in our understanding of these three key areas of phagocyte metabolism. We end by proposing a model of efferocytosis that integrates recent findings and establishes a new paradigm for testing how efferocytosis prevents chronic inflammatory disease and autoimmunity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
