<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>lncRNAs | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/lncrnas/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/lncrnas/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>lncRNAs</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>lncRNAs</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/lncrnas/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Databases make long non-coding RNAs closer</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tool/2021-03-12-db-lnc-rna/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/tool/2021-03-12-db-lnc-rna/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://v5.noncode.org/index.php&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;NONCODE&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is an integrated knowledge database dedicated to non-coding RNAs (excluding tRNAs and rRNAs). Now, there are 17 species in &lt;a href=&#34;http://v5.noncode.org/index.php&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;NONCODE&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (human, mouse, cow, rat, chicken, fruitfly, zebrafish, celegans, yeast, Arabidopsis, chimpanzee, gorilla, orangutan, rhesus macaque, opossum platypus and pig). The source of &lt;a href=&#34;http://v5.noncode.org/index.php&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;NONCODE&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; includes literature and other public databases. We searched &lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt; using key words &lt;code&gt;ncrna&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;noncoding&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;non-coding&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;no code&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;non-code&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;lncrna&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;lincrna&lt;/code&gt;. We retrieved the new identified lncRNAs and their annotation from the Supplementary Material or web site of these articles. Together with the newest data from &lt;a href=&#34;%28https://asia.ensembl.org/index.html%29&#34;&gt;Ensembl&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/refseq/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;RefSeq&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://lncrnadb.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;lncRNAdb&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gencodegenes.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;GENCODE&lt;/a&gt; were processed through a standard pipeline for each species.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://bicresources.jcbose.ac.in/zhumur/lncrbase/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;LncRBase&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a comprehensive database for long noncoding RNA (lncRNA) in Human and Mouse. With a total of 216562 lncRNA transcript entries,the database hosts information on basic lncRNA transcript features, with additional details on genomic location, overlapping small noncoding RNAs, associated Repeat Elements, associated imprinted genes, and lncRNA promoter information. Users can also search for microarray probes mapped to specific lncRNAs and associated disease information as well as search for lncRNA expression in a wide range of tissues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DIANA-&lt;a href=&#34;https://diana.e-ce.uth.gr/lncbasev3&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;LncBase&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; v3 is a reference repository with experimentally supported miRNA targets on non-coding transcripts. It catalogues approximately ~500,000 entries, corresponding to ~240,000 unique tissue and cell-type specific miRNA-lncRNA interactions. The incorporated interactions are defined by 15 distinct low-/high-throughput methodologies, corresponding to 243 distinct cell types/tissues and 162 experimental conditions. &lt;a href=&#34;https://diana.e-ce.uth.gr/lncbasev3&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;LncBase&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; indexes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;730 miRNA-lncRNA entries from manual curation of publications&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2,924 miRNA-lncRNA chimeric fragments&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2,094 interactions from the re-analysis of miRNA perturbation experiments&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;235,000 AGO-CLIP-Seq derived miRNA-lncRNA pairs from the re-analysis of 236 CLIP-Seq libraries with &lt;a href=&#34;www.microrna.gr/microCLIP&#34;&gt;microCLIP&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://starbase.sysu.edu.cn/index.php&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;ENCORI (The Encyclopedia of RNA Interactomes)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is an openly licensed and state-of-the-art platform to decode the cellular interaction networks among thousands of RNA binding proteins (RBPs) and various RNAs. We have identified millions of RBP-RNA and RNA-RNA interactions through analyzing thousands of CLIP-seq and various high-throughput sequencing data by developing new software and tools, and studied their functions and mechanisms in human diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bio-bigdata.net/LncACTdb/index.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;LncACTdb&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 3.0 is a comprehensive database of experimentally supported ceRNA interactions and personalized networks contributing to precision medicine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://lncipedia.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;LNCipedia&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a public database for long non-coding RNA (lncRNA) sequence and annotation. The current release contains 127,802 transcripts and 56,946 genes. Currently, &lt;a href=&#34;https://lncipedia.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;LNCipedia&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; offers 2,482 manually curated lncRNA articles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bio-bigdata.net/lnc2cancer/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lnc2Cancer&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, is a manually curated database that provides comprehensive experimentally supported associations between lncRNA or circRNA and human cancer. The current version of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bio-bigdata.net/lnc2cancer/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lnc2Cancer&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; documents 10,303 entries of associations between 2,659 human lncRNAs, 743 circRNAs and 216 human cancer subtypes through review of more than 1,5000 published papers. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bio-bigdata.net/lnc2cancer/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lnc2Cancer&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; also provides experimentally supported regulatory mechanism (microRNA, Transcription factor, variant, methylation and enhancer), biological function (cell growth, apoptosis, autophagy, Epithelial mesenchymal transformation, immune and coding ability) and clinical application (metastasis, recurrence, circulating, drug-resistant and prognostic) of lncRNAs and circRNAs in human cancer. Especially, an interactive analysis platform including RNA and single cell sequencing expression data is developed to help users explore lncRNAs in cancers with a standard processing pipeline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bio-bigdata.net/LnCeVar/index.jsp&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;LnCeVar&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a comprehensive database that aims to infer genomic variations that disturb lncRNA-associated ceRNA regulation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Manual curation of variation-ceRNA events from the published literature.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Manual curation of more than 2,000 experimentally supported circulating, drug-resistant and prognosis-related lncRNA biomarkers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Identification of somatic mutation-ceRNA events occurring in 33 cancers from TCGA and mutation profiles of over 1,000 cell lines from Cosmic.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Identification of CNV-ceRNA events in thousands of patients from TCGA.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Identification of SNP-ceRNA events from the 1000-Genome project.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://lncar.renlab.org/#welcome&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;lnCAR&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a catalog of human lncRNA expression profiles derived from re-annotation of public microarray expression data from over 57,000 samples spanning diverse cancers. &lt;a href=&#34;https://lncar.renlab.org/#welcome&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;lnCAR&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; enables the users to rapidly and intuitively explore differentially expressed lncRNAs of interest (annotated lncRNAs or any user-defined ones) in the context of different types of experiments. In addition, &lt;a href=&#34;https://lncar.renlab.org/#welcome&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;lnCAR&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is also a powerful platform for querying associations between lncRNA expression and cancer prognosis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Long non-coding RNAs (lncRNAs) are emerging as key factors in the regulation of various cellular processes and diseases. &lt;a href=&#34;http://bioinfo.life.hust.edu.cn/lncRNASNP#!/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;LncRNASNP&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a database providing comprehensive resources of single nucleotide polymorphisms (SNPs) in human/mouse lncRNAs. It contains SNPs in lncRNAs, SNP effects on lncRNA structure, mutation in lncRNAs and lncRNA:miRNA binding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Long noncoding RNAs (lncRNAs) play an important role in modulating gene expression or participating in some essential epigenetic regulation processes, including chromatin modification or DNA methylation. DNA methylation is a fundamental feature of epigenomes that can affect the expression of protein-coding or non-coding transcripts. &lt;a href=&#34;http://bio-bigdata.hrbmu.edu.cn/Lnc2Meth/index.jsp&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Lnc2Meth&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; aims to provide a comprehensive resource and web tool for clarifying the regulatory relationships between human lncRNAs and associated DNA methylation in diverse diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rna-society.org/rnalocate/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;RNALocate&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; aims to provide a resource for efficient manipulation, browsing and analysis of RNA subcellular localization. The second version of RNALocate documents more than 210,000 RNA-associated subcellular localization entries with experimental evidence, involving more than 110,000 RNAs with 171 subcellular localizations in 104 species. It will be of help in elucidating the entirety of RNA-associated subcellular localization, and developing new prediction methods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Long non-coding RNAs (lncRNAs) are expressed in a tissue-specific way, subcellular localizaitons of lncRNAs depend on the tissues or cell lines that they are expressed. Previous computational methods for predicting subcellular localizations of lncRNAs do not take this characteristic into account, they train a unified machine learning model for pooled lncRNAs from all available cell lines. It is of importance to develop a cell-line-specific computational method to predict lncRNA locations in different cell lines. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.csbio.sjtu.edu.cn/bioinf/lncLocator2/index.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;LncLocator&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 2.0, which trains a deep model per cell line for predicting lncRNA subcellular localization from sequences. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.csbio.sjtu.edu.cn/bioinf/lncLocator2/index.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;LncLocator&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 2.0 achieves varying effectiveness for different cell lines and demonstrates the necessity of training cell-line-specific models. Furthermore, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.csbio.sjtu.edu.cn/bioinf/lncLocator2/index.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;LncLocator&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 2.0 adopts Integrated Gradients to explain the proposed model, and find some potential patterns that determine the subcellular localizations of lncRNAs, suggesting that the subcellular localization of lncRNAs is linked to some specific nucleotides.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://lncatlas.crg.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;LncATLAS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is an easy to use web-based visualization tool to obtain useful information about expression localization of long non-coding class of RNAs. It is easy to use by just searching your lncRNA of interest in the search box. You can also use ENSEMBL gene IDs to select them. There are also some reference genes with a clear nuclear or cytoplasmatic expression profile. In some plots (3 and 4) you could also select the cell line from the dropdown menu to obtain a zoom into the distributions. Although many genes would have a similar profile among cell lines there might exist small changes. &lt;a href=&#34;https://lncatlas.crg.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;LncATLAS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; provides 6 charts that can be divided into 3 sections:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Inspect the cytoplasmic-nuclear localisation of your gene of interest (GOI): a barplot indicating the CN RCI values in each cell line for the selected gene(s)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Inspect the cytoplasmic-nuclear localisation of your GOI within the distribution of all genes: distribution of RCI values in each cell line for lncRNAs and mRNAs with the selected gene(s) highlighted&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Inspect the localisation of your GOI at sub-compartment level: localisation values within distributions for the K562 cell line subnuclear and subcytoplasmic compartments&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.exorbase.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;exoRBase&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a repository of extracellular vesicles (EVs) long RNAs (exLRs) derived from RNA-seq data analyses in different human body fluids. The exLRs contain messenger RNA (mRNA), long non-coding RNA (lncRNA), and circular RNA (circRNA). &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.exorbase.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;exoRBase&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 2.0 provides the comprehensive annotation and expression landscapes of exLRs. It will facilitate the identification of novel exLR signatures from human body fluids and will help discover new circulating biomarkers for the improvement of tumor diagnosis and therapy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://genome.igib.res.in/lncRNome/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;lncRNome&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a comprehensive searchable biologically oriented knowledgebase for long noncoding RNAs in Humans. The resource hosts information on over 17000 long noncoding RNAs in Human. The resource provides information on the types , chromosomal locations, description on the biological functions and disease associations of long noncoding RNAs. In addition, it provides access to datasets on protein-lncRNA interactions and genomic variations in lncRNA loci. The resource also provides a browsable interface for the datasets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://annolnc.gao-lab.org/index.php&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;AnnoLnc&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a web server to provide on-the-fly analysis for novel human or mouse lncRNAs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Long non-coding RNAs (lncRNAs) are an important category of non-coding RNAs (ncRNAs) which range from 200 nucleotides to multiple kilobases in length, with little or no protein-coding capacity. Circular RNAs (circRNAs) are widely expressed in diverse eukaryotic species and are characterized by covalently closed RNA loops through backsplicing events. Increasing evidence has highlighted the critical roles of lncRNAs and circRNAs in plenty of diseases development and progression. Here, we have updated the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rnanut.net/lncrnadisease/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;LncRNADisease&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; database to version 2.0 by integrating comprehensive experimentally supported and predicted ncRNA-disease associations curated from manual literatures and other resources. The new developments in &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rnanut.net/lncrnadisease/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;LncRNADisease&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; v2.0 include (I) over 40-fold ncRNA-disease associations enhancement compare to the previous version; (II) integrating experimentally supported circRNA-disease associations; (III) providing regulatory relationship among ncRNA, mRNA and miRNA; (IV) mapping disease name to the Disease Ontology and Medical Subject Headings (MeSH); (V) providing a confidence score for each ncRNA-disease association.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;RNA editing is a widespread post-transcriptional mechanism that can make discrete changes to specific nucleotide sequences within a RNA transcripts. RNA editing events can result in missense codon changes in mRNA, modulation of alternative splicing in mRNA, or modification of regulatory RNAs and their binding sites in small noncoding RNA, such as miRNA. Recent studies have developed computational methods to accurately detect more than 2 million A-to-I RNA editing from next-generation sequencing data in different species. However, the vast majority of these RNA sites are in noncoding regions of the genome and have unknown functional relevance. &lt;a href=&#34;http://bioinfo.life.hust.edu.cn/LNCediting/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;LNCediting&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; provides a comprehensive resource for the functional prediction of RNA editing in long noncoding RNAs (lncRNAs).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Long non-coding RNAs (lncRNAs) are emerging as key factors in the regulation of various cellular processes and diseases. &lt;a href=&#34;http://bioinfo.life.hust.edu.cn/lncRNASNP#!/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;LncRNASNP&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a database providing comprehensive resources of single nucleotide polymorphisms (SNPs) in human/mouse lncRNAs. It contains SNPs in lncRNAs, SNP effects on lncRNA structure, mutation in lncRNAs and lncRNA:miRNA binding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://rnasysu.com/chipbase3/index.php&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ChIPBase&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; v3.0 identified ~151,187,000 regulatory relationships between ~171,600 genes and ~3,000 regulators by analyzing ~55,000 ChIP-seq datasets, which represent a 30-fold expansion. Moreover, we de novo identified ~29,000 motif matrices of transcription factors. In addition, we constructed a novel “Enhancer” module to predict ~1,837,200 regulation regions functioning as poised, active or super enhancers under ~1300 conditions. Importantly, we constructed exhaustive coexpression maps between regulators and their target genes by integrating expression profiles of ∼65,000 normal and ∼15,000 tumor samples. We built a “Disease” module to obtain an atlas of the disease-associated variations in the regulation regions of genes. We also constructed an “EpiInter” module to explore potential interactions between epitranscriptome and epigenome. Finally, we designed “Network” module to provide extensive and gene-centred regulatory networks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Long noncoding RNAs (lncRNAs) play an important role in modulating gene expression or participating in some essential epigenetic regulation processes, including chromatin modification or DNA methylation. DNA methylation is a fundamental feature of epigenomes that can affect the expression of protein-coding or non-coding transcripts. Here, we constructed &lt;a href=&#34;http://bio-bigdata.hrbmu.edu.cn/Lnc2Meth/index.jsp&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lnc2Meth&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, aimed to provide a comprehensive resource and web tool for clarifying the regulatory relationships between human lncRNAs and associated DNA methylation in diverse diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This website &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gaemons.net/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Gaemons&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; hosts online services and databases developed by team of Dr Zhu and Dr Zhang at Southern Medical University, Guangzhou, China. And has have integrated LongTarget into &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gaemons.net/LongMan&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;LongMan&lt;/a&gt; to implement a seamless pipeline to implement this function.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;RNA editing is a widespread post-transcriptional mechanism that can make discrete changes to specific nucleotide sequences within a RNA transcripts. RNA editing events can result in missense codon changes in mRNA, modulation of alternative splicing in mRNA, or modification of regulatory RNAs and their binding sites in small noncoding RNA, such as miRNA. Recent studies have developed computational methods to accurately detect more than 2 million A-to-I RNA editing from next-generation sequencing data in different species. However, the vast majority of these RNA sites are in noncoding regions of the genome and have unknown functional relevance. &lt;a href=&#34;http://bioinfo.life.hust.edu.cn/LNCediting/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;LNCediting&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; provides a comprehensive resource for the functional prediction of RNA editing in long noncoding RNAs (lncRNAs).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;http://gtrd.biouml.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Gene Transcription Regulation Database (GTRD)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; contains uniformly annotated and processed NGS data related to gene transcription regulation: ChIP-seq, ChIP-exo, DNase-seq, MNase-seq, ATAC-seq and RNA-seq. With the latest release, the database has reached a new level of data integration. All cell types (cell lines and tissues) presented in the &lt;a href=&#34;http://gtrd.biouml.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;GTRD&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; were arranged into a dictionary and linked with different ontologies (BRENDA, Cell Ontology, Uberon, Cellosaurus and Experimental Factor Ontology) and with related experiments in specialized databases on transcription regulation (FANTOM5, ENCODE and GTEx). The updated version of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://gtrd.biouml.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;GTRD&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; provides an integrated view of transcription regulation through a dedicated web interface with advanced browsing and search capabilities, an integrated genome browser, and table reports by cell types, transcription factors, and genes of interest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://rna.sysu.edu.cn/deepbase3/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;deepBase&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a popular and openly licensed resource to facilitate the integrative and interactive display and analysis of expression, evolution, function of various ncRNAs by deeply mining thousands of high-throughput sequencing data from tissue, cancer and exosome samples. &lt;a href=&#34;https://rna.sysu.edu.cn/deepbase3/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;deepBase&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; provided the most comprehensive expression analysis of sRNAs and lncRNAs, the expression patterns of tRFs and snoRNAs from thousands of cancer and normal samples, the correlations between ncRNAs and patients’ survival and the function prediction of ncRNAs in tumor tumorigenesis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/tag/databases/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Databases&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/tool/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Tools &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Online tools decoding RNA-RNA regulatory networks</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tool/2020-11-10-rri/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/tool/2020-11-10-rri/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://circinteractome.nia.nih.gov/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;CircInteractome&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; predicts the miRNAs which can potentially target the circRNAs using the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.targetscan.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Targetscan&lt;/a&gt; prediction tool. This computational tool enables the prediction and mapping of binding sites for RBPs and miRNAs on reported circRNAs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights of &lt;a href=&#34;%28https://circinteractome.nia.nih.gov/%29&#34;&gt;CircInteractome&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Searches circRNAs name&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Searches the genomic position and best-matching transcripts of the circRNA&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Retrieves genomic and mature circRNA sequences&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Searches RBPs binding to a circRNA and to sequences upstream/downstream of the circRNA&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Identifies RBPs binding to the circRNA junctions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Identifies miRNAs targeting a circRNA&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Designs divergent primers for circRNAs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Designs siRNAs Specific to circRNA&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://starbase.sysu.edu.cn/index.php&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;ENCORI (The Encyclopedia of RNA Interactomes)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is an openly licensed and state-of-the-art platform to decode the cellular interaction networks among thousands of RNA binding proteins (RBPs) and various RNAs. We have identified millions of RBP-RNA and RNA-RNA interactions through analyzing thousands of CLIP-seq and various high-throughput sequencing data by developing new software and tools, and studied their functions and mechanisms in human diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/tag/databases/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Databases&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/tool/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Tools &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>lncRNA Sensing of a Viral Suppressor of RNAi Activates Non-canonical Innate Immune Signaling in Drosophila</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/31917956/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/31917956/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Antiviral immunity in insects is mediated by the RNA interference (RNAi) pathway. Viruses evade antiviral RNAi by expressing virulence factors known as viral suppressors of RNAi (VSR). Here, we report the identification of VINR, a Drosophila VSR-interacting long non-coding (lnc) RNA that activates non-canonical innate immune signaling upon detection of the dsRNA-binding VSR of Drosophila C virus (DCV). VINR is required for the induction of antimicrobial peptide (AMP) genes but dispensable for antiviral RNAi. VINR functions by preventing the ubiquitin proteasome-dependent degradation of Cactin, a coiled-coil and arginine-serine-rich domain-containing protein that regulates a non-cannonical antimicrobial pathway for AMP induction. CRISPR-Cas9 knockout of VINR in Drosophila cells enhances DCV replication independently of antiviral RNAi, and VINR-knockout adult flies exhibit enhanced disease susceptibility to DCV and bacteria. Our findings reveal a counter counter-defense strategy activated by a lncRNA in response to the viral suppression of the primary antiviral RNAi immunity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LncRNA PTPRE-AS1 modulates M2 macrophage activation and inflammatory diseases by epigenetic promotion of PTPRE</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/31844669/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/31844669/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Long noncoding RNAs (lncRNAs) are important regulators of diverse biological processes; however, their function in macrophage activation is undefined. We describe a new regulatory mechanism, where an unreported lncRNA, &lt;em&gt;PTPRE-AS1&lt;/em&gt;, targets receptor-type tyrosine protein phosphatase ε (PTPRE) to regulate macrophage activation. &lt;em&gt;PTPRE-AS1&lt;/em&gt; was selectively expressed in IL-4-stimulated macrophages, and its knockdown promoted M2 macrophage activation via MAPK/ERK 1/2 pathway. In vivo, PTPRE-AS1 deficiency enhanced IL-4-mediated M2 macrophage activation and accelerated pulmonary allergic inflammation while reducing chemical-induced colitis. Mechanistically, &lt;em&gt;PTPRE-AS1&lt;/em&gt; bound WDR5 directly, modulating H3K4me3 of the &lt;em&gt;PTPRE&lt;/em&gt; promoter to regulate &lt;em&gt;PTPRE&lt;/em&gt;-dependent signaling during M2 macrophage activation. Further, the expression of &lt;em&gt;PTPRE-AS1&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;PTPRE&lt;/em&gt; was significantly lower in peripheral blood mononuclear cells from patients with allergic asthma. These results provide evidence supporting the importance of &lt;em&gt;PTPRE-AS1&lt;/em&gt; in controlling macrophage function and the potential utility of &lt;em&gt;PTPRE-AS1&lt;/em&gt; as a target for controlling inflammatory diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A genome-wide long noncoding RNA CRISPRi screen identifies PRANCR as a novel regulator of epidermal homeostasis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/31804951/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/31804951/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Genome-wide association studies indicate that many disease susceptibility regions reside in non-protein-coding regions of the genome. Long noncoding RNAs (lncRNAs) are a major component of the noncoding genome, but their biological impacts are not fully understood. Here, we performed a CRISPR interference (CRISPRi) screen on 2263 epidermis-expressed lncRNAs and identified nine novel candidate lncRNAs regulating keratinocyte proliferation. We further characterized a top hit from the screen, progenitor renewal associated non-coding RNA (&lt;em&gt;PRANCR&lt;/em&gt;), using RNA interference-mediated knockdown and phenotypic analysis in organotypic human tissue. PRANCR regulates keratinocyte proliferation, cell cycle progression, and clonogenicity. &lt;em&gt;PRANCR&lt;/em&gt;-deficient epidermis displayed impaired stratification with reduced expression of differentiation genes that are altered in human skin diseases, including keratins 1 and 10, filaggrin, and loricrin. Transcriptome analysis showed that &lt;em&gt;PRANCR&lt;/em&gt; controls the expression of 1136 genes, with strong enrichment for late cell cycle genes containing a CHR promoter element. In addition, _PRANCR _depletion led to increased levels of both total and nuclear CDKN1A (also known as p21), which is known to govern both keratinocyte proliferation and differentiation. Collectively, these data show that &lt;em&gt;PRANCR&lt;/em&gt; is a novel lncRNA regulating epidermal homeostasis and identify other lncRNA candidates that may have roles in this process as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LncRNA-HGBC stabilized by HuR promotes gallbladder cancer progression by regulating miR-502-3p/SET/AKT axis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/31752906/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/31752906/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Erratum in:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Correction to: &lt;a href=&#34;https://molecular-cancer.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12943-021-01386-8&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;LncRNA-HGBC stabilized by HuR promotes gallbladder cancer progression by regulating miR-502-3p/SET/AKT axis&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Backgrounds:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Long non-coding RNAs (lncRNAs) are essential factors that regulate tumor development and metastasis via diverse molecular mechanisms in a broad type of cancers. However, the pathological roles of lncRNAs in gallbladder carcinoma (GBC) remain largely unknown. Here we discovered a novel lncRNA termed lncRNA Highly expressed in GBC (lncRNA-HGBC) which was upregulated in GBC tissue and aimed to investigate its role and regulatory mechanism in the development and progression of GBC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The expression level of lncRNA-HGBC in GBC tissue and different cell lines was determined by quantitative real-time PCR. The full length of lncRNA-HGBC was obtained by 5&amp;rsquo; and 3&amp;rsquo; rapid amplification of the cDNA ends (RACE). Cellular localization of lncRNA-HGBC was detected by fluorescence in situ hybridization (FISH) assays and subcellular fractionation assay. In vitro and in vivo assays were preformed to explore the biological effects of lncRNA-HGBC in GBC cells. RNA pull-down assay, mass spectrometry, and RNA immunoprecipitation (RIP) assay were used to identify lncRNA-HGBC-interacting proteins. Dual luciferase reporter assays, AGO2-RIP, and MS2-RIP assays were performed to verify the interaction between lncRNA-HGBC and miR-502-3p.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We found that lncRNA-HGBC was upregulated in GBC and its upregulation could predict poor survival. Overexpression or knockdown of lncRNA-HGBC in GBC cell lines resulted in increased or decreased, respectively, cell proliferation and invasion in vitro and in xenografted tumors. LncRNA-HGBC specifically bound to RNA binding protein Hu Antigen R (HuR) that in turn stabilized lncRNA-HGBC. LncRNA-HGBC functioned as a competitive endogenous RNA to bind to miR-502-3p that inhibits target gene SET. Overexpression, knockdown or mutation of lncRNA-HGBC altered the inhibitory effects of miR-502-3p on SET expression and downstream activation of AKT. Clinically, lncRNA-HGBC expression was negatively correlated with miR-502-3p, but positively correlated with SET and HuR in GBC tissue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our study demonstrates that lncRNA-HGBC promotes GBC metastasis via activation of the miR-502-3p-SET-AKT cascade, pointing to lncRNA-HGBC as a new prognostic predictor and a therapeutic target.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A high-throughput screen identifies the long non-coding RNA DRAIC as a regulator of autophagy</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/30872794/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/30872794/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Autophagy is a conserved degradation process that occurs in all eukaryotic cells and its dysfunction has been associated with various diseases including cancer. While a number of large-scale attempts have recently identified new molecular players in autophagy regulation, including proteins and microRNAs, little is known regarding the function of long non-coding RNAs (lncRNAs) in the regulation of this process. To identify new long non-coding RNAs with functional implications in autophagy, we performed a high-throughput RNAi screen targeting more than 600 lncRNA transcripts and monitored their effects on autophagy in MCF-7 cells. We identified 63 lncRNAs that affected GFP-LC3B puncta numbers significantly. We validated the strongest hit, the lncRNA DRAIC previously shown to impact cell proliferation, and revealed a novel role for this lncRNA in the regulation of autophagic flux. Interestingly, we find DRAIC&amp;rsquo;s pro-proliferative effects to be autophagy-independent. This study serves as a valuable resource for researchers from both the lncRNA and autophagy fields as it advances the current understanding of autophagy regulation by non-coding RNAs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Network of Noncoding Regulatory RNAs Acts in the Mammalian Brain</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/29887379/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/29887379/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Noncoding RNAs (ncRNAs) play increasingly appreciated gene-regulatory roles. Here, we describe a regulatory network centered on four ncRNAs-a long ncRNA, a circular RNA, and two microRNAs-using gene editing in mice to probe the molecular consequences of disrupting key components of this network. The long ncRNA Cyrano uses an extensively paired site to miR-7 to trigger destruction of this microRNA. Cyrano-directed miR-7 degradation is much more effective than previously described examples of target-directed microRNA degradation, which come primarily from studies of artificial and viral RNAs. By reducing miR-7 levels, Cyrano prevents repression of miR-7-targeted mRNAs and enables accumulation of Cdr1as, a circular RNA known to regulate neuronal activity. Without Cyrano, excess miR-7 causes cytoplasmic destruction of Cdr1as in neurons, in part through enhanced slicing of Cdr1as by a second miRNA, miR-671. Thus, several types of ncRNAs can collaborate to establish a sophisticated regulatory network.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Recognition of an Inducible Host lncRNA by RIG-I Feedback Restricts Innate Immune Response</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/29706547/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/29706547/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The innate RNA sensor RIG-I is critical in the initiation of antiviral type I interferons (IFNs) production upon recognition of &amp;ldquo;non-self&amp;rdquo; viral RNAs. Here, we identify a host-derived, IFN-inducible long noncoding RNA, lnc-Lsm3b, that can compete with viral RNAs in the binding of RIG-I monomers and feedback inactivate the RIG-I innate function at late stage of innate response. Mechanistically, binding of lnc-Lsm3b restricts RIG-I protein&amp;rsquo;s conformational shift and prevents downstream signaling, thereby terminating type I IFNs production. Multivalent structural motifs and long-stem structure are critical features of lnc-Lsm3b for RIG-I binding and inhibition. These data reveal a non-canonical self-recognition mode in the regulation of immune response and demonstrate an important role of an inducible &amp;ldquo;self&amp;rdquo; lncRNA acting as a potent molecular decoy actively saturating RIG-I binding sites to restrict the duration of &amp;ldquo;non-self&amp;rdquo; RNA-induced innate immune response and maintaining immune homeostasis, with potential utility in inflammatory disease management.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
