<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>lncRNAs | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/lncrnas/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/lncrnas/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>lncRNAs</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>lncRNAs</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/lncrnas/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Long non-coding RNAs: definitions, functions, challenges and recommendations</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/36596869/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/36596869/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Genes specifying long non-coding RNAs (lncRNAs) occupy a large fraction of the genomes of complex organisms. The term &amp;rsquo;lncRNAs&amp;rsquo; encompasses RNA polymerase I (Pol I), Pol II and Pol III transcribed RNAs, and RNAs from processed introns. The various functions of lncRNAs and their many isoforms and interleaved relationships with other genes make lncRNA classification and annotation difficult. Most lncRNAs evolve more rapidly than protein-coding sequences, are cell type specific and regulate many aspects of cell differentiation and development and other physiological processes. Many lncRNAs associate with chromatin-modifying complexes, are transcribed from enhancers and nucleate phase separation of nuclear condensates and domains, indicating an intimate link between lncRNA expression and the spatial control of gene expression during development. lncRNAs also have important roles in the cytoplasm and beyond, including in the regulation of translation, metabolism and signalling. lncRNAs often have a modular structure and are rich in repeats, which are increasingly being shown to be relevant to their function. In this Consensus Statement, we address the definition and nomenclature of lncRNAs and their conservation, expression, phenotypic visibility, structure and functions. We also discuss research challenges and provide recommendations to advance the understanding of the roles of lncRNAs in development, cell biology and disease.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RUNX2 stabilization by long non-coding RNAs contributes to hypertrophic changes in human chondrocytes</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36594090/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36594090/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Chondrocyte hypertrophy has been implicated in endochondral ossification and osteoarthritis (OA). In OA, hypertrophic chondrocytes contribute to the destruction and focal calcification of the joint cartilage. Although studies in this field have remarkably developed the modulation of joint inflammation using gene therapy and regeneration of damaged articular cartilage using cell therapy, studies that can modulate or prevent hypertrophic changes in articular chondrocytes are still lacking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;In vitro&lt;/em&gt; hypertrophic differentiation and inflammation assays were conducted using human normal chondrocyte cell lines, TC28a2 cells. Human cartilage tissues and primary articular chondrocytes were obtained from OA patients undergoing total knee arthroplasty. Long non-coding RNAs (lncRNAs), LINC02035 and LOC100130207, were selected through RNA-sequencing analysis using RNAs extracted from TC28a2 cells cultured in hypertrophic medium. The regulatory mechanism was evaluated using western blotting, real-time quantitative polymerase chain reaction, osteocalcin reporter assay, RNA-immunoprecipitation (RNA-IP), RNA-&lt;em&gt;in situ&lt;/em&gt; hybridization, and IP.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; LncRNAs are crucial regulators of various biological processes. In this study, we identified two important lncRNAs, LINC02035 and LOC100130207, which play important roles in hypertrophic changes in normal chondrocytes, through RNA sequencing. Interestingly, the expression level of RUNX2, a master regulator of chondrocyte hypertrophy, was regulated at the post-translational level during hypertrophic differentiation of the normal human chondrocyte cell line, TC28a2. RNA-immunoprecipitation proved the potential interaction between RUNX2 protein and both lncRNAs. Knockdown (KD) of LINC02035 or LOC100130207 promoted ubiquitin-mediated proteasomal degradation of RUNX2 and prevented hypertrophic differentiation of normal chondrocyte cell lines, whereas overexpression of both lncRNAs stabilized RUNX2 protein and generated hypertrophic changes. Furthermore, the KD of the two lncRNAs mitigated the destruction of important cartilage matrix proteins, COL2A1 and ACAN, by hypertrophic differentiation or inflammatory conditions. We also confirmed that the phenotypic changes raised by the two lncRNAs could be rescued by modulating &lt;em&gt;RUNX2&lt;/em&gt; expression. In addition, the KD of these two lncRNAs suppressed hypertrophic changes during chondrogenic differentiation of mesenchymal stem cells.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/em&gt; Therefore, this study suggests that LINC02035 and LOC100130207 contribute to hypertrophic changes in normal chondrocytes by regulating RUNX2, suggesting that these two novel lncRNAs could be potential therapeutic targets for delaying or preventing OA development, especially for preventing chondrocyte hypertrophy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The lncRNA LUCAT1 is elevated in inflammatory disease and restrains inflammation by regulating the splicing and stability of NR4A2</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36577072/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36577072/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Significance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Long non-coding RNAs (lncRNAs) are abundant in the human genome, yet, in contrast to proteins, only a small portion of lncRNAs have been functionally characterized. We further explore the molecular basis of LUCAT1-dependent regulation of the inflammatory response. In this study, we identify LUCAT1-binding proteins that are involved in splicing and processing of mRNAs including the anti-inflammatory NR4A2. LUCAT1 regulates splicing and stability of NR4A2 which contributes to the inhibitory effect of LUCAT1 on interferons and inflammatory cytokines. Finally, data from COPD and IBD patients indicate that LUCAT1 levels are elevated in these patient groups where expression is positively correlated with disease severity. Thus, LUCAT1 may serve as a diagnostic marker for inflammation and as a therapeutic target in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The nuclear long non-coding RNA LUCAT1 has previously been identified as a negative feedback regulator of type I interferon and inflammatory cytokine expression in human myeloid cells. Here, we define the mechanistic basis for the suppression of inflammatory gene expression by LUCAT1. Using comprehensive identification of RNA-binding proteins by mass spectrometry as well as RNA immunoprecipitation, we identified proteins important in processing and alternative splicing of mRNAs as LUCAT1-binding proteins. These included heterogeneous nuclear ribonucleoprotein C, M, and A2B1. Consistent with this finding, cells lacking LUCAT1 have altered splicing of selected immune genes. In particular, upon lipopolysaccharide stimulation, the splicing of the nuclear receptor 4A2 (NR4A2) gene was particularly affected. As a consequence, expression of NR4A2 was reduced and delayed in cells lacking LUCAT1. NR4A2-deficient cells had elevated expression of immune genes. These observations suggest that LUCAT1 is induced to control the splicing and stability of NR4A2, which is in part responsible for the anti-inflammatory effect of LUCAT1. Furthermore, we analyzed a large cohort of patients with inflammatory bowel disease as well as asthma and chronic obstructive pulmonary disease. In these patients, LUCAT1 levels were elevated and in both diseases, positively correlated with disease severity. Collectively, these studies define a key molecular mechanism of LUCAT1-dependent immune regulation through post-transcriptional regulation of mRNAs highlighting its role in the regulation of inflammatory disease.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Antisense-oligonucleotide-mediated perturbation of long non-coding RNA reveals functional features in stem cells and across cell types</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36577377/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36577377/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Molecular phenotyping shows richer functional annotation than cellular phenotyping&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Integration with chromatin interaction reveals cis- or trans-regulation of lncRNA&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;LINC02595&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;CATG00000090305.1&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;RP11-148B6.2&lt;/em&gt; modulate colony formation of iPSCs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Within the scope of the FANTOM6 consortium, we perform a large-scale knockdown of 200 long non-coding RNAs (lncRNAs) in human induced pluripotent stem cells (iPSCs) and systematically characterize their roles in self-renewal and pluripotency. We find 36 lncRNAs (18%) exhibiting cell growth inhibition. From the knockdown of 123 lncRNAs with transcriptome profiling, 36 lncRNAs (29.3%) show molecular phenotypes. Integrating the molecular phenotypes with chromatin-interaction assays further reveals cis- and trans-interacting partners as potential primary targets. Additionally, cell-type enrichment analysis identifies lncRNAs associated with pluripotency, while the knockdown of LINC02595, CATG00000090305.1, and RP11-148B6.2 modulates colony formation of iPSCs. We compare our results with previously published fibroblasts phenotyping data and find that 2.9% of the lncRNAs exhibit a consistent cell growth phenotype, whereas we observe 58.3% agreement in molecular phenotypes. This highlights that molecular phenotyping is more comprehensive in revealing affected pathways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mitochondrial Genome-Encoded Long Noncoding RNA and Mitochondrial Stability in Diabetic Retinopathy</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36563021/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36563021/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mitochondria experience genomic and functional instability in diabetes, and mitochondrial dysfunction has a critical role in the development of diabetic retinopathy. Diabetes also alters expressions of many long non-coding RNAs (LncRNAs), the RNAs with &amp;gt;200 nucleotides and no open reading frame. LncRNAs are mainly encoded by nuclear genome, but mtDNA also encodes three LncRNAs. Our goal was to investigate the effect of hyperglycemia on mtDNA-encoded LncRNA Cytochrome B (LncCytB) in mtDNA stability in diabetic retinopathy. Retinal endothelial cells, transfected with LncCytB- overexpressing plasmids or siRNA, incubated in 5mmols/L (NG) or 20mmols/L (HG) D-glucose for four days, were analyzed for LncCytB expression by strand-specific PCR, and its mitochondrial localization by RNA-FISH. Damage sensitive mtDNA regions were examined by micrococcal nuclease digestion-sequencing, and LncCytB occupancy at mtDNA by chromatin isolation by RNA purification. Protective nucleoids in mtDNA were analyzed by SYBR green-MitoTracker Red staining, and confirmed in isolated mitochondria by flow cytometry. Compared to NG, HG downregulated LncCytB by &amp;gt;50%, but had no significant effect on the other mtDNAencoded LncRNAs. mtDNA packaging was impaired and MNase sensitivity was increased, and LncCytB occupancy at mtDNA was decreased. While LncCytB overexpression ameliorated mtDNA damage and decrease in nucleoids and copy numbers, LncCytB-siRNA exacerbated damage and further reduced nucleoids. Retinal microvessels from streptozotocin-induced diabetic mice and human donors with diabetic retinopathy presented similar decrease in LncCytB and mtDNA nucleoids. Thus, LncCytB has a major role in maintaining mitochondrial genomic stability, and its downregulation in hyperglycemic milieu contributes to increased vulnerability of mtDNA to damage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mitochondria-localized lncRNA HITT inhibits fusion by attenuating formation of mitofusin-2 homo- or heterotypic complexes</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36567017/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36567017/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Long non-coding RNAs (lncRNAs) are emerging as essential players in multiple biological processes. Mitochondrial dynamics, comprising the continuous cycle of fission and fusion, are required for healthy mitochondria that function properly. Despite long-term recognition of its significance in cell-fate control, the mechanism underlying mitochondrial fusion is not completely understood, particularly regarding the involvement of lncRNAs. Here, we show that the lncRNA HITT (HIF-1α inhibitor at translation level), can specifically localize in mitochondria. Cells expressing higher levels of HITT contain fragmented mitochondria. Conversely, we show that HITT knockdown cells have more tubular mitochondria than is present in control cells. Mechanistically, we demonstrate HITT directly binds mitofusin-2 (MFN2), a core component that mediates mitochondrial outer membrane fusion, by the &lt;em&gt;in vitro&lt;/em&gt; RNA pull-down and UV-cross-linking RNA-IP (CLIP) assays. In doing so, we found HITT disturbs MFN2 homo- or heterotypic complex formation, attenuating mitochondrial fusion. Under stress conditions, such as ultraviolet radiation, we in addition show HITT stability increases as a consequence of MiR-205 downregulation, inhibiting MFN2-mediated fusion and leading to apoptosis. Overall, our data provide significant insights into the roles of organelle (mitochondria)-specific resident lncRNAs in regulating mitochondrial fusion, and also reveal how such a mechanism controls cellular sensitivity to UV radiation-induced apoptosis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Somatosensory neurons express specific sets of lincRNAs, and lincRNA CLAP promotes itch sensation in mice</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36524339/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36524339/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Somatosensory neurons are highly heterogeneous with distinct types of neural cells responding to specific stimuli. However, the distribution and roles of cell-type-specific long intergenic noncoding RNAs (lincRNAs) in somatosensory neurons remain largely unexplored. Here, by utilizing droplet-based single-cell RNA-seq (scRNA-seq) and full-length Smart-seq2, we show that lincRNAs, but not coding mRNAs, are enriched in specific types of mouse somatosensory neurons. Profiling of lincRNAs from single neurons located in dorsal root ganglia (DRG) identifies 200 lincRNAs localized in specific types or subtypes of somatosensory neurons. Among them, the conserved cell-type-specific lincRNA CLAP associates with pruritus and is abundantly expressed in somatostatin (SST)-positive neurons. CLAP knockdown reduces histamine-induced Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt; influx in cultured SST-positive neurons and in vivo reduces histamine-induced scratching in mice. In vivo knockdown of CLAP also decreases the expression of neuron-type-specific and itch-related genes in somatosensory neurons, and this partially depends on the RNA binding protein MSI2. Our data reveal a cell-type-specific landscape of lincRNAs and a function for CLAP in somatosensory neurons in sensory transmission.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alternative transcribed 3&#39; isoform of long non-coding RNA Malat1 inhibits mouse retinal oxidative stress</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36594014/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36594014/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Malat1&lt;/em&gt; is upregulated in replicative senescence (&lt;em&gt;in vitro&lt;/em&gt;) and brain aging (&lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A potential cryptic promoter drives 3′ &lt;em&gt;Malat1&lt;/em&gt; isoform expression in mouse brain &amp;amp; retina&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deletion of the 3′-&lt;em&gt;Malat1&lt;/em&gt; isoform region increases retinal oxidative stress in mice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;5’&amp;amp; 3′ &lt;em&gt;Malat1&lt;/em&gt; transcripts differentially regulates gene expression &lt;em&gt;in cis&lt;/em&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;em&gt;in trans&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The function of the cancer-associated lncRNA &lt;em&gt;Malat1&lt;/em&gt; during aging is as-of-yet uncharacterized. Here, we show that &lt;em&gt;Malat1&lt;/em&gt; interacts with Nucleophosmin (NPM) in young mouse brain, and with Lamin A/C, hnRNP C, and KAP1 with age. RNA-seq and RT-qPCR reveal a persistent expression of &lt;em&gt;Malat1_2&lt;/em&gt; (the 3&amp;rsquo;isoform of &lt;em&gt;Malat1&lt;/em&gt;) in &lt;em&gt;Malat1Δ1&lt;/em&gt; (5&amp;rsquo;-1.5 kb deletion) mouse retinas and brains at 1/4&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; level of the full-length &lt;em&gt;Malat1&lt;/em&gt;, while &lt;em&gt;Malat1_1&lt;/em&gt; (the 5&amp;rsquo;isoform) in &lt;em&gt;Malat1Δ2&lt;/em&gt; (deletion of 3&amp;rsquo;-conserved 5.7 kb) at a much lower level, suggesting an internal promoter driving the 3&amp;rsquo; isoform. The 1774 and 496 differentially expressed genes in &lt;em&gt;Malat1Δ2&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Malat1Δ1&lt;/em&gt; brains, respectively, suggest the 3&amp;rsquo; isoform regulates gene expression in trans and the 5&amp;rsquo; isoform in cis. Consistently, &lt;em&gt;Malat1Δ2&lt;/em&gt; mice show increased age-dependent retinal oxidative stress and corneal opacity, while &lt;em&gt;Malat1Δ1&lt;/em&gt; mice show no obvious phenotype. Collectively, this study reveals a physiological function of the lncRNA &lt;em&gt;Malat1&lt;/em&gt; 3&amp;rsquo;-isoform during the aging process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pan-cancer analyses reveal molecular and clinical characteristics of cuproptosis regulators</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/imt2.68/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/imt2.68/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therapeutics that discriminate between the genetic makeup of normal cells and tumour cells are valuable for treating and understanding cancer. Small molecules with oncogene-selective lethality may reveal novel functions of oncoproteins and enable the creation of more selective drugs. Here we describe the mechanism of action of the selective anti-tumour agent erastin, involving the RAS-RAF-MEK signalling pathway functioning in cell proliferation, differentiation and survival. Erastin exhibits greater lethality in human tumour cells harbouring mutations in the oncogenes HRAS, KRAS or BRAF. Using affinity purification and mass spectrometry, we discovered that erastin acts through mitochondrial voltage-dependent anion channels (VDACs)&amp;ndash;a novel target for anti-cancer drugs. We show that erastin treatment of cells harbouring oncogenic RAS causes the appearance of oxidative species and subsequent death through an oxidative, non-apoptotic mechanism. RNA-interference-mediated knockdown of VDAC2 or VDAC3 caused resistance to erastin, implicating these two VDAC isoforms in the mechanism of action of erastin. Moreover, using purified mitochondria expressing a single VDAC isoform, we found that erastin alters the permeability of the outer mitochondrial membrane. Finally, using a radiolabelled analogue and a filter-binding assay, we show that erastin binds directly to VDAC2. These results demonstrate that ligands to VDAC proteins can induce non-apoptotic cell death selectively in some tumour cells harbouring activating mutations in the RAS-RAF-MEK pathway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The N-Myc-responsive lncRNA MILIP promotes DNA double-strand break repair through non-homologous end joining</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36445966/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36445966/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Significance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here, we report that the lncRNA MILIP is transcriptionally regulated by N-Myc and functions to promote DNA double-strand break repair in neuroblastoma cells. MILIP is distinguished from other lncRNAs implicated in DNA repair through its scaffolding role in Ku complex formation, a requisite step to initiate the nonhomologous end-joining pathway. Our findings substantiate the long-postulated role of N-Myc in regulating DNA repair in neuroblastoma cells and reveal the functional importance of MILIP in cell survival, proliferation, and resistance to genotoxic stress, with practical implications of MILIP targeting, alone and in combination with DNA-damaging therapeutics, for neuroblastoma treatment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The protooncoprotein N-Myc, which is overexpressed in approximately 25% of neuroblastomas as the consequence of MYCN gene amplification, has long been postulated to regulate DNA double-strand break (DSB) repair in neuroblastoma cells, but experimental evidence of this function is presently scant. Here, we show that N-Myc transcriptionally activates the long noncoding RNA MILIP to promote nonhomologous end-joining (NHEJ) DNA repair through facilitating Ku70-Ku80 heterodimerization in neuroblastoma cells. High MILIP expression was associated with poor outcome and appeared as an independent prognostic factor in neuroblastoma patients. Knockdown of MILIP reduced neuroblastoma cell viability through the induction of apoptosis and inhibition of proliferation, retarded neuroblastoma xenograft growth, and sensitized neuroblastoma cells to DNA-damaging therapeutics. The effect of MILIP knockdown was associated with the accumulation of DNA DSBs in neuroblastoma cells largely due to decreased activity of the NHEJ DNA repair pathway. Mechanistical investigations revealed that binding of MILIP to Ku70 and Ku80 increased their heterodimerization, and this was required for MILIP-mediated promotion of NHEJ DNA repair. Disrupting the interaction between MILIP and Ku70 or Ku80 increased DNA DSBs and reduced cell viability with therapeutic potential revealed where targeting MILIP using Gapmers cooperated with the DNA-damaging drug cisplatin to inhibit neuroblastoma growth in vivo. Collectively, our findings identify MILIP as an N-Myc downstream effector critical for activation of the NHEJ DNA repair pathway in neuroblastoma cells, with practical implications of MILIP targeting, alone and in combination with DNA-damaging therapeutics, for neuroblastoma treatment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HIF1α-AS1 is a DNA:DNA:RNA triplex-forming lncRNA interacting with the HUSH complex</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36323673/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36323673/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DNA:DNA:RNA triplexes that are formed through Hoogsteen base-pairing of the RNA in the major groove of the DNA duplex have been observed in vitro, but the extent to which these interactions occur in cells and how they impact cellular functions remains elusive. Using a combination of bioinformatic techniques, RNA/DNA pulldown and biophysical studies, we set out to identify functionally important DNA:DNA:RNA triplex-forming long non-coding RNAs (lncRNA) in human endothelial cells. The lncRNA HIF1α-AS1 was retrieved as a top hit. Endogenous HIF1α-AS1 reduces the expression of numerous genes, including EPH Receptor A2 and Adrenomedullin through DNA:DNA:RNA triplex formation by acting as an adapter for the repressive human silencing hub complex (HUSH). Moreover, the oxygen-sensitive HIF1α-AS1 is down-regulated in pulmonary hypertension and loss-of-function approaches not only result in gene de-repression but also enhance angiogenic capacity. As exemplified here with HIF1α-AS1, DNA:DNA:RNA triplex formation is a functionally important mechanism of trans-acting gene expression control.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Translation and natural selection of micropeptides from long non-canonical RNAs</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36316320/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36316320/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Long noncoding RNAs (lncRNAs) are transcripts longer than 200 nucleotides but lacking canonical coding sequences. Apparently unable to produce peptides, lncRNA function seems to rely only on RNA expression, sequence and structure. Here, we exhaustively detect in-vivo translation of small open reading frames (small ORFs) within lncRNAs using Ribosomal profiling during &lt;em&gt;Drosophila melanogaster&lt;/em&gt; embryogenesis. We show that around 30% of lncRNAs contain small ORFs engaged by ribosomes, leading to regulated translation of 100 to 300 micropeptides. We identify lncRNA features that favour translation, such as cistronicity, Kozak sequences, and conservation. For the latter, we develop a bioinformatics pipeline to detect small ORF homologues, and reveal evidence of natural selection favouring the conservation of micropeptide sequence and function across evolution. Our results expand the repertoire of lncRNA biochemical functions, and suggest that lncRNAs give rise to novel coding genes throughout evolution. Since most lncRNAs contain small ORFs with as yet unknown translation potential, we propose to rename them &amp;ldquo;long non-canonical RNAs&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LncRNA H19 via miR-29a-3p is involved in lung inflammation and pulmonary fibrosis induced by neodymium oxide</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36326553/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36326553/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Exposure to Nd&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; causes an inflammatory reaction and fibrosis in lung tissue of mice.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nd&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; increases H19 and TNFRSF1A levels, decreases miR-29a-3p levels, and activates the NF-κB signaling pathway in RAW264.7 cells and mice.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;H19 via miR-29a-3p-regulated TNFRSF1A is involved in Nd&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;-induced lung inflammation and pulmonary fibrosis.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The study provide a tool for assessing lung injury risk of Nd&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; and other environmental factors that induce inflammatory response and pulmonary fibrosis-associated lncRNAs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The occupational and environmental health safety of rare earths has attracted considerable attention. In China, the rare earth neodymium oxide (Nd&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;) is extensively refined and utilized. However, the mechanisms of Nd&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;-induced lung injury are elusive. In the present study, we found that exposure of mice to Nd&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; caused an inflammatory reaction and fibrosis in lung tissues, which was in relation to the Nd&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;-induced higher levels of the lncRNA H19 (H19), tumor necrosis factor receptor 1 (TNFRSF1A), p-p65, and p-IKKβ and lower levels of miR-29a-3p. Further, in mouse monocyte macrophage leukemia cells (RAW264.7), Nd&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; induced an inflammatory reaction, increases of H19 and TNFRSF1A levels, decreases of miR-29a-3p levels, and activation of the nuclear factor (NF)-κB signaling pathway. Further, we established that miR-29a-3p regulates TNFRSF1A expression. Up-regulation of miR-29a-3p and down-regulation of H19 blocked the Nd&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;-induced secretion of TNF-α, MIP-1α, and IL-6; the increases of TNFRSF1A levels; and activation of the NF-κB signaling pathway in RAW264.7 cells. Further, in Nd&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;-treated RAW26.4 cells, H19 inhibited the expression of miR-29a-3p, which targets TNFRSF1A, and activated the NF-κB signaling pathway to enhance the expression of TNF-α, MIP-1α, and IL-6. Moreover, for mice, up-regulation of miR-29a-3p reversed lung tissue inflammation, pulmonary fibrosis, and activation of the NF-κB signaling pathway induced by Nd&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;. In sum, the present investigation shows that H19 via miR-29a-3p is involved in lung inflammation and pulmonary fibrosis induced by Nd&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;, which is a mechanism for the Nd&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;-induced lung inflammatory response and pulmonary fibrosis. This information is useful for development of a biomarker of Nd&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;-induced lung injury.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Immunosuppressive lncRNA LINC00624 promotes tumor progression and therapy resistance through ADAR1 stabilization</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36252997/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36252997/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Despite the success of HER2-targeted therapy in achieving prolonged survival in approximately 50% of treated individuals, treatment resistance is still an important challenge for HER2+ breast cancer (BC) patients. The influence of both adaptive and innate immune responses on the therapeutic outcomes of HER2+BC patients has been extensively demonstrated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; Long non-coding RNAs expressed in non-pathological complete response (pCR) HER2 positive BC were screened and validated by RNA-seq. Survival analysis were made by Kaplan-Meier method. Cell death assay and proliferation assay were performed to confirm the phenotype of LINC00624. RT-qPCR and western blot were used to assay the IFN response. Xenograft mouse model were used for in vivo confirmation of anti-neu treatment resistance. RNA pull-down and immunoblot were used to confirm the interaction of ADAR1 and LINC00624. ADAR1 recombinant protein were purified from baculovirus expression system. B16-OVA cells were used to study antigen presentation both in vitro and in vivo. Flow cytometry was used to determine the tumor infiltrated immune cells of xenograft model. Antisense oligonucleotides (ASOs) were used for in vivo treatment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; In this study, we found that LINC00624 blocked the antitumor effect of HER2- targeted therapy both in vitro and in vivo by inhibiting type I interferon (IFN) pathway activation. The double-stranded RNA-like structure of LINC00624 can bind and be edited by the adenosine (A) to inosine (I) RNA-editing enzyme adenosine deaminase RNA specific 1 (ADAR1), and this editing has been shown to release the growth inhibition and attenuate the innate immune response caused by the IFN response. Notably, LINC00624 promoted the stabilization of ADAR1 by inhibiting its ubiquitination-induced degradation triggered by β-TrCP. In contrast, LINC00624 inhibited major histocompatibility complex (MHC) class I antigen presentation and limited CD8+T cell infiltration in the cancer microenvironment, resulting in immune checkpoint blockade inhibition and anti-HER2 treatment resistance mediated through ADAR1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; In summary, these results suggest that LINC00624 is a cancer immunosuppressive lncRNA and targeting LINC00624 through ASOs in tumors expressing high levels of LINC00624 has great therapeutic potential in future clinical applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DeepLncPro: an interpretable convolutional neural network model for identifying long non-coding RNA promoters</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36209437/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36209437/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Long non-coding RNA (lncRNA) plays important roles in a series of biological processes. The transcription of lncRNA is regulated by its promoter. Hence, accurate identification of lncRNA promoter will be helpful to understand its regulatory mechanisms. Since experimental techniques remain time consuming for gnome-wide promoter identification, developing computational tools to identify promoters are necessary. However, only few computational methods have been proposed for lncRNA promoter prediction and their performances still have room to be improved. In the present work, a convolutional neural network based model, called &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/zhangtian-yang/DeepLncPro&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;DeepLncPro&lt;/a&gt;, was proposed to identify lncRNA promoters in human and mouse. Comparative results demonstrated that &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/zhangtian-yang/DeepLncPro&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;DeepLncPro&lt;/a&gt; was superior to both state-of-the-art machine learning methods and existing models for identifying lncRNA promoters. Furthermore, &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/zhangtian-yang/DeepLncPro&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;DeepLncPro&lt;/a&gt; has the ability to extract and analyze transcription factor binding motifs from lncRNAs, which made it become an interpretable model. These results indicate that the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/zhangtian-yang/DeepLncPro&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;DeepLncPro&lt;/a&gt; can server as a powerful tool for identifying lncRNA promoters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Targeting non-coding RNA H19: A potential therapeutic approach in pulmonary diseases</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/36188624/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/36188624/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Non-coding RNA is still one of the most popular fields in biology research. In recent years, people paid more attention to the roles of H19 in lung diseases, which expressed abnormally in various pathological process. Therefore, this review focus on the regulatory role of H19 in asthma, pulmonary arterial hypertension (PAH), idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis (IPF), lung injury, pneumonia, lung cancer, etc. And the potential therapeutic agents and molecular treatments of H19 are collected. The aim is to demonstrate its underlying mechanism in pulmonary diseases and to guide the basic research targeting H19 into clinical drug translation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Long noncoding RNA LINC00239 inhibits ferroptosis in colorectal cancer by binding to Keap1 to stabilize Nrf2</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36038548/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36038548/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ferroptosis, a novel regulated cell death induced by iron-dependent lipid peroxidation, plays an important role in tumor development and drug resistance. Long noncoding RNAs (lncRNAs) are associated with various types of cancer. However, the precise roles of many lncRNAs in tumorigenesis remain elusive. Here we explored the transcriptomic profiles of lncRNAs in primary CRC tissues and corresponding paired adjacent non-tumor tissues by RNA-seq and found that LINC00239 was significantly overexpressed in colorectal cancer tissues. Abnormally high expression of LINC00239 predicts poorer survival and prognosis in colorectal cancer patients. Concurrently, we elucidated the role of LINC00239 as a tumor-promoting factor in CRC through in vitro functional studies and in vivo tumor xenograft models. Importantly, overexpression of LINC00239 decreased the anti-tumor activity of erastin and RSL3 by inhibiting ferroptosis. Collectively, these data suggest that LINC00239 plays a novel and indispensable role in ferroptosis by nucleotides 1-315 of LINC00239 to interact with the Kelch domain (Nrf2-binding site) of Keap1, inhibiting Nrf2 ubiquitination and increasing Nrf2 protein stability. Considering the recurrence and chemoresistance constitute the leading cause of death in colorectal cancer (CRC), ferroptosis induction may be a promising therapeutic strategy for CRC patients with low LINC00239 expression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enterobacterial LPS-inducible LINC00152 is regulated by histone lactylation and promotes cancer cells invasion and migration</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35959377/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35959377/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gut microbes participate in pathogenesis by interacting with the host genome through epigenetic mechanisms, such as long non-coding RNAs. However, the mechanisms by which the microbiota induce expression alteration of long non-coding RNAs remains unclear. Here, we quantified the transcriptome alteration of human colon cell lines after being infected by a common enteric pathogen &lt;em&gt;Salmonella typhimurium SL1344&lt;/em&gt;. We observed a widespread lncRNAs expression alteration. Among them, the elevated expression of LINC00152 was verified and proved to be induced by enteric bacteria-derived lipopolysaccharide (LPS). The inducible LINC00152 were found to inhibit Salmonella invasion and inflammation response. LINC00152 was overexpressed in tumors of the clinical CRC samples compared with adjacent normal tissues. Accordingly, we also demonstrated that overexpression of LINC00152 promoted the migration and invasion of colorectal cancer cells. Consistently, we observed an increased abundance of gram-negative bacteria and LPS in tumors tissue. Taken together, the above data implicated that enriched gram-negative bacteria in tumor tissue might promote tumor growth through modulating the expression of LINC00152. Furthermore, we demonstrated that LPS upregulated the expression of LINC00152 by introducing histone lactylation on its promoter and decreasing the binding efficiency of the repressor, YY1, to it. Our results provide new insights into how enterobacteria affect host epigenetics in human disease.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LncRNA-PACERR induces pro-tumour macrophages via interacting with miR-671-3p and m6A-reader IGF2BP2 in pancreatic ductal adenocarcinoma</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35526050/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35526050/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; LncRNA-PACERR plays critical role in the polarization of tissue-associated macrophages (TAMs). In this study, we found the function and molecular mechanism of PACERR in TAMs to regulate pancreatic ductal adenocarcinoma (PDAC) progression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; We used qPCR to analyse the expression of PACERR in TAMs and M1-tissue-resident macrophages (M1-NTRMs) which were isolated from 46 PDAC tissues. The function of PACERR on macrophages polarization and PDAC proliferation, migration and invasion were confirmed through in vivo and in vitro assays. The molecular mechanism of PACERR was discussed via fluorescence in situ hybridization (FISH), RNA pull-down, ChIP-qPCR, RIP-qPCR and luciferase assays.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; LncRNA-PACERR was high expression in TAMs and associated with poor prognosis in PDAC patients. Our finding validated that LncRNA-PACERR increased the number of M2-polarized cells and facilized cell proliferation, invasion and migration in vitro and in vivo. Mechanistically, LncRNA-PACERR activate KLF12/p-AKT/c-myc pathway by binding to miR-671-3p. And LncRNA-PACERR which bound to IGF2BP2 acts as an m6A-dependent manner to enhance the stability of KLF12 and c-myc in cytoplasm. In addition, the promoter of LncRNA-PACERR was a target of KLF12 and LncRNA-PACERR recruited EP300 to increase the acetylation of histone by interacting with KLF12 in nucleus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; This study found that LncRNA-PACERR functions as key regulator of TAMs in PDAC microenvironment and revealed the novel mechanisms in cytoplasm and in nucleus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Long noncoding RNA LINC01606 protects colon cancer cells from ferroptotic cell death and promotes stemness by SCD1-Wnt/β-catenin-TFE3 feedback loop signalling</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35485210/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35485210/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Ferroptosis is principally caused by iron catalytic activity and intracellular lipid peroxidation. Long noncoding RNAs (lncRNAs) play crucial roles in tumorigenesis. However, the potential interplay between lncRNA LINC01606 and ferroptosis in colon cancer remains elusive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; The expression level of LNC01606 in colon cancer tissue was detected by quantitative real-time polymerase chain reaction. The functional role of LNC01606 was investigated by gain- and loss-of-function assays both in vitro and in vivo. The LINC01606-SCD1-Wnt/β-catenin-TFE3 axis were screened and validated by DNA/RNA pull down, gas chromatography-mass spectrometry, RNA immunoprecipitation and dual-luciferase reporter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; The expression of lncRNA LINC01606 was frequently upregulated in human colon cancer and strongly associated with a poor prognosis. LINC01606 functioned as an oncogene and promotes colon cancer cell growth, invasion and stemness both in vitro and in vivo. Moreover, LINC01606 protected colon cancer cells from ferroptosis by decreasing the concentration of iron, lipid reactive oxygen species, mitochondrial superoxide and increasing mitochondrial membrane potential. Mechanistically, LINC01606 enhanced the expression of stearoyl-CoA desaturase 1 (SCD1), serving as a competing endogenous RNA to modulate miR-423-5p expression, subsequently activating the canonical Wnt/β-catenin signaling, and transcription factor binding to IGHM enhancer 3 (TFE3) increased LINC01606 transcription after recruitment to the promoter regions of LINC01606. Furthermore, we confirmed that upregulated LINC01606 and Wnt/β-catenin formed a positive feedback regulatory loop, further inhibiting ferroptosis and enhancing stemness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; LINC01606 functions as an oncogene to facilitate tumor cell stemness, proliferation and inhibit ferroptosis and is a promising therapeutic target for colon cancer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Long noncoding RNA TLNC1 promotes the growth and metastasis of liver cancer via inhibition of p53 signaling</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35477447/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35477447/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Long non-coding RNAs (lncRNAs) have been demonstrated to play vital roles in cancer development and progression. However, their biological roles and function mechanisms in liver cancer remain largely unknown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; RNA-seq was performed with clinical hepatoma tissues and paired adjacent normal liver tissues to identify differentially expressed lncRNAs. qPCR was utilized to examine the expression levels of lncRNAs. We studied the function of TLNC1 in cell growth and metastasis of hepatoma with both cell and mouse models. RNA-seq, RNA pull-down coupled with mass spectrometry, RNA immunoprecipitation, dual luciferase reporter assay, and surface plasmon resonance analysis were used to analyze the functional mechanism of TLNC1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; Based on the intersection of our own RNA-seq, TCGA RNA-seq, and TCGA survival analysis data, TLNC1 was identified as a potential tumorigenic lncRNA of liver cancer. TLNC1 significantly enhanced the growth and metastasis of hepatoma cells both in vitro and in vivo. TLNC1 exerted its tumorigenic function through interaction with TPR and inducing the TPR-mediated transportation of p53 from nucleus to cytoplasm, thus repressing the transcription of p53 target genes and finally contributing to the progression of liver cancer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; TLNC1 is a promising prognostic factor of liver cancer, and the TLNC1-TPR-p53 axis can serve as a potential therapeutic target for hepatoma treatment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lupus enhancer risk variant causes dysregulation of IRF8 through cooperative lncRNA and DNA methylation machinery</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35388006/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35388006/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite strong evidence that human genetic variants affect the expression of many key transcription factors involved in autoimmune diseases, establishing biological links between non-coding risk variants and the gene targets they regulate remains a considerable challenge. Here, we combine genetic, epigenomic, and CRISPR activation approaches to screen for functional variants that regulate IRF8 expression. We demonstrate that the locus containing rs2280381 is a cell-type-specific enhancer for IRF8 that spatially interacts with the IRF8 promoter. Further, rs2280381 mediates IRF8 expression through enhancer RNA AC092723.1, which recruits TET1 to the IRF8 promoter regulating IRF8 expression by affecting methylation levels. The alleles of rs2280381 modulate PU.1 binding and chromatin state to regulate AC092723.1 and IRF8 expression differentially. Our work illustrates an integrative strategy to define functional genetic variants that regulate the expression of critical genes in autoimmune diseases and decipher the mechanisms underlying the dysregulation of IRF8 expression mediated by lupus risk variants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ImmReg: the regulon atlas of immune-related pathways across cancer types</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34755873/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34755873/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read to learn more:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Li Y., Jiang T., Zhou W., Li J., Li X., Wang Q., Jin X., Yin J., Chen L., Zhang Y. et al. &lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/32081859/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Pan-cancer characterization of immune-related lncRNAs identifies potential oncogenic biomarkers&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-020-14802-2&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nature Communications&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. 2020; 11:1000.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Immune system gene regulation perturbation has been found to be a major cause of the development of various types of cancer. Numbers of mechanisms contribute to gene expression regulation, thus, systematically identification of potential regulons of immune-related pathways is critical to cancer immunotherapy. Here, we comprehensively chart the landscape of transcription factors, microRNAs, RNA binding proteins and long noncoding RNAs regulation in 17 immune-related pathways across 33 cancers. The potential immunology regulons are likely to exhibit higher expressions in immune cells, show expression perturbations in cancer, and are significantly correlated with immune cell infiltrations. We also identify a panel of clinically relevant immunology regulons across cancers. Moreover, the regulon atlas of immune-related pathways helps prioritizing cancer-related genes (i.e. ETV7, miR-146a-5p, ZFP36 and HCP5). We further identified two molecular subtypes of glioma (cold and hot tumour phenotypes), which were characterized by differences in immune cell infiltrations, expression of checkpoints, and prognosis. Finally, we developed a user-friendly resource, &lt;a href=&#34;http://bio-bigdata.hrbmu.edu.cn/ImmReg/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;ImmReg&lt;/a&gt;, with multiple modules to visualize, browse, and download immunology regulation. Our study provides a comprehensive landscape of immunology regulons, which will shed light on future development of RNA-based cancer immunotherapies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IRF3-binding lncRNA-ISIR strengthens interferon production in viral infection and autoinflammation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34731629/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34731629/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interferon regulatory factor 3 (IRF3) is an essential transductor for initiation of many immune responses. Here, we show that lncRNA-ISIR directly binds IRF3 to promote its phosphorylation, dimerization, and nuclear translocation, along with enhanced target gene productions. In vivo lncRNA-ISIR deficiency results in reduced IFN production, uncontrolled viral replication, and increased mortality. The human homolog, AK131315, also binds IRF3 and promotes its activation. More important, AK131315 expression is positively correlated with type I interferon (IFN-I) level and severity in patients with lupus. Mechanistically, in resting cells, IRF3 is bound to suppressor protein Flightless-1 (Fli-1), which keeps its inactive state. Upon infection, IFN-I-induced lncRNA-ISIR binds IRF3 at DNA-binding domain in cytoplasm and removes Fli-1&amp;rsquo;s association from IRF3, consequently facilitating IRF3 activation. Our results demonstrate that IFN-I-inducible lncRNA-ISIR feedback strengthens IRF3 activation by removing suppressive Fli-1 in immune responses, revealing a method of lncRNA-mediated modulation of transcription factor (TF) activation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cis-acting lnc-Cxcl2 restrains neutrophil-mediated lung inflammation by inhibiting epithelial cell CXCL2 expression in virus infection</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34607953/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34607953/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chemokine production by epithelial cells is important for neutrophil recruitment during viral infection, the appropriate regulation of which is critical for restraining inflammation and attenuating subsequent tissue damage. Epithelial cell expression of long noncoding RNAs (lncRNAs), RNA-binding proteins, and their functional interactions during viral infection and inflammation remain to be fully understood. Here, we identified an inducible lncRNA in the &lt;em&gt;Cxcl2&lt;/em&gt; gene locus, lnc-Cxcl2, which could selectively inhibit &lt;em&gt;Cxcl2&lt;/em&gt; expression in mouse lung epithelial cells but not in macrophages. lnc-Cxcl2-deficient mice exhibited increased &lt;em&gt;Cxcl2&lt;/em&gt; expression, enhanced neutrophils recruitment, and more severe inflammation in the lung after influenza virus infection. Mechanistically, nucleus-localized lnc-Cxcl2 bound to &lt;em&gt;Cxcl2&lt;/em&gt; promoter, recruited a ribonucleoprotein La, which inhibited the chromatin accessibility of chemokine promoters, and consequently inhibited &lt;em&gt;Cxcl2&lt;/em&gt; transcription in cis However, unlike mouse lnc-Cxcl2, human lnc-CXCL2-4-1 inhibited multiple immune cytokine expressions including chemokines in human lung epithelial cells. Together, our results demonstrate a self-protecting mechanism within epithelial cells to restrain chemokine and neutrophil-mediated inflammation, providing clues for better understanding chemokine regulation and epithelial cell function in lung viral infection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LncRNA-encoded microproteins: A new form of cargo in cell culture-derived and circulating extracellular vesicles</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34276900/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34276900/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Advancements in omics-based technologies over the past few years have led to the discovery of numerous biologically relevant peptides encoded by small open reading frames (smORFs) embedded in long noncoding RNA (lncRNA) transcripts (referred to as microproteins here) in a variety of species. However, the mechanisms and modes of action that underlie the roles of microproteins have yet to be fully characterized. Herein, we provide the first experimental evidence of abundant microproteins in extracellular vesicles (EVs) derived from glioma cancer cells, indicating that the EV-mediated transfer of microproteins may represent a novel mechanism for intercellular communication. Intriguingly, when examining human plasma, 48, 11 and 3 microproteins were identified from purified EVs, whole plasma and EV-free plasma, respectively, suggesting that circulating microproteins are primarily enriched in EVs. Most importantly, the preliminary data showed that the expression profile of EV microproteins in glioma patient diverged from the health donors, suggesting that the circulating microproteins in EVs might have potential diagnostic application in identifying patients with glioma.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Long noncoding RNA BS-DRL1 modulates the DNA damage response and genome stability by interacting with HMGB1 in neurons</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34210972/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34210972/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Long noncoding RNAs (lncRNAs) are known to regulate DNA damage response (DDR) and genome stability in proliferative cells. However, it remains unknown whether lncRNAs are involved in these vital biological processes in post-mitotic neurons. Here, we report and characterize a lncRNA, termed Brain Specific DNA-damage Related lncRNA1 (BS-DRL1), in the central nervous system. BS-DRL1 is a brain-specific lncRNA and depletion of BS-DRL1 in neurons leads to impaired DDR upon etoposide treatment in vitro. Mechanistically, BS-DRL1 interacts with HMGB1, a chromatin protein that is important for genome stability, and is essential for the assembly of HMGB1 on chromatin. BS-DRL1 mediated DDR exhibits cell-type specificity in the cortex and cerebellum in gamma-irradiated mice and BS-DRL1 knockout mice show impaired motor function and concomitant purkinje cell degeneration. Our study extends the understanding of lncRNAs in DDR and genome stability and implies a protective role of lncRNA against neurodegeneration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deeply Mining a Universe of Peptides Encoded by Long Noncoding RNAs</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34129944/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34129944/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many small ORFs embedded in long noncoding RNA (lncRNA) transcripts have been shown to encode biologically functional polypeptides (small ORF-encoded polypeptides, short for SEPs) in different organisms. Despite some novel SEPs have been found, the identification is still hampered by their poor predictability, diminutive size, and low relative abundance. Here, we take advantage of NONCODE, a repository containing the most complete collection and annotation of lncRNA transcripts from different species, to build a novel database that attempts to maximize a collection of SEPs from human and mouse lncRNA transcripts. In order to further improve SEP discovery, we implemented two effective and complementary polypeptide enrichment strategies using 30-kDa molecular weight cutoff filter and C8 solid-phase extraction column. These combined strategies enabled us to discover 353 SEPs from eight human cell lines and 409 SEPs from three mouse cell lines and eight mouse tissues. Importantly, 19 of them were then verified through in vitro expression, immunoblotting, parallel reaction monitoring, and synthetic peptides. Subsequent bioinformatics analysis revealed that some of the physical and chemical properties of these novel SEPs, including amino acid composition and codon usage, are different from those commonly found in canonical proteins. Intriguingly, nearly 65% of the identified SEPs were found to be initiated with non-AUG start codons. The 762 novel SEPs probably represent the largest number of SEPs detected by MS reported to date. These novel SEPs might not only provide new clues for the annotation of noncoding elements in the genome but also serve as a valuable resource for functional study.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Long noncoding RNAs in cancer metastasis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/33953369/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/33953369/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Metastasis is a major contributor to cancer-associated deaths. It is characterized by a multistep process that occurs through the acquisition of molecular and phenotypic changes enabling cancer cells from a primary tumour to disseminate and colonize at distant organ sites. Over the past decade, the discovery and characterization of long noncoding RNAs (lncRNAs) have revealed the diversity of their regulatory roles, including key contributions throughout the metastatic cascade. Here, we review how lncRNAs promote metastasis by functioning in discrete pro-metastatic steps including the epithelial-mesenchymal transition, invasion and migration and organotrophic colonization, and by influencing the metastatic tumour microenvironment, often by interacting within ribonucleoprotein complexes or directly with other nucleic acid entities. We discuss well-characterized lncRNAs with in vivo phenotypes and highlight mechanistic commonalities such as convergence with the TGFβ-ZEB1/ZEB2 axis or the nuclear factor-κB pathway, in addition to lncRNAs with controversial mechanisms and the influence of methodologies on mechanistic interpretation. Furthermore, some lncRNAs can help identify tumours with increased metastatic risk and spur novel therapeutic strategies, with several lncRNAs having shown potential as novel targets for antisense oligonucleotide therapy in animal models. In addition to well-characterized examples of lncRNAs functioning in metastasis, we discuss controversies and ongoing challenges in lncRNA biology. Finally, we present areas for future study for this rapidly evolving field.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Databases make long non-coding RNAs closer</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tool/2021-03-12-db-lnc-rna/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/tool/2021-03-12-db-lnc-rna/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://v5.noncode.org/index.php&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;NONCODE&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is an integrated knowledge database dedicated to non-coding RNAs (excluding tRNAs and rRNAs). Now, there are 17 species in &lt;a href=&#34;http://v5.noncode.org/index.php&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;NONCODE&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (human, mouse, cow, rat, chicken, fruitfly, zebrafish, celegans, yeast, Arabidopsis, chimpanzee, gorilla, orangutan, rhesus macaque, opossum platypus and pig). The source of &lt;a href=&#34;http://v5.noncode.org/index.php&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;NONCODE&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; includes literature and other public databases. We searched &lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt; using key words &lt;code&gt;ncrna&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;noncoding&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;non-coding&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;no code&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;non-code&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;lncrna&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;lincrna&lt;/code&gt;. We retrieved the new identified lncRNAs and their annotation from the Supplementary Material or web site of these articles. Together with the newest data from &lt;a href=&#34;%28https://asia.ensembl.org/index.html%29&#34;&gt;Ensembl&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/refseq/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;RefSeq&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://lncrnadb.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;lncRNAdb&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gencodegenes.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;GENCODE&lt;/a&gt; were processed through a standard pipeline for each species.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://bicresources.jcbose.ac.in/zhumur/lncrbase/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;LncRBase&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a comprehensive database for long noncoding RNA (lncRNA) in Human and Mouse. With a total of 216562 lncRNA transcript entries,the database hosts information on basic lncRNA transcript features, with additional details on genomic location, overlapping small noncoding RNAs, associated Repeat Elements, associated imprinted genes, and lncRNA promoter information. Users can also search for microarray probes mapped to specific lncRNAs and associated disease information as well as search for lncRNA expression in a wide range of tissues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DIANA-&lt;a href=&#34;https://diana.e-ce.uth.gr/lncbasev3&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;LncBase&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; v3 is a reference repository with experimentally supported miRNA targets on non-coding transcripts. It catalogues approximately ~500,000 entries, corresponding to ~240,000 unique tissue and cell-type specific miRNA-lncRNA interactions. The incorporated interactions are defined by 15 distinct low-/high-throughput methodologies, corresponding to 243 distinct cell types/tissues and 162 experimental conditions. &lt;a href=&#34;https://diana.e-ce.uth.gr/lncbasev3&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;LncBase&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; indexes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;730 miRNA-lncRNA entries from manual curation of publications&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2,924 miRNA-lncRNA chimeric fragments&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2,094 interactions from the re-analysis of miRNA perturbation experiments&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;235,000 AGO-CLIP-Seq derived miRNA-lncRNA pairs from the re-analysis of 236 CLIP-Seq libraries with &lt;a href=&#34;www.microrna.gr/microCLIP&#34;&gt;microCLIP&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://starbase.sysu.edu.cn/index.php&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;ENCORI (The Encyclopedia of RNA Interactomes)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is an openly licensed and state-of-the-art platform to decode the cellular interaction networks among thousands of RNA binding proteins (RBPs) and various RNAs. We have identified millions of RBP-RNA and RNA-RNA interactions through analyzing thousands of CLIP-seq and various high-throughput sequencing data by developing new software and tools, and studied their functions and mechanisms in human diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bio-bigdata.net/LncACTdb/index.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;LncACTdb&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 3.0 is a comprehensive database of experimentally supported ceRNA interactions and personalized networks contributing to precision medicine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://lncipedia.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;LNCipedia&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a public database for long non-coding RNA (lncRNA) sequence and annotation. The current release contains 127,802 transcripts and 56,946 genes. Currently, &lt;a href=&#34;https://lncipedia.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;LNCipedia&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; offers 2,482 manually curated lncRNA articles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bio-bigdata.net/lnc2cancer/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lnc2Cancer&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, is a manually curated database that provides comprehensive experimentally supported associations between lncRNA or circRNA and human cancer. The current version of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bio-bigdata.net/lnc2cancer/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lnc2Cancer&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; documents 10,303 entries of associations between 2,659 human lncRNAs, 743 circRNAs and 216 human cancer subtypes through review of more than 1,5000 published papers. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bio-bigdata.net/lnc2cancer/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lnc2Cancer&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; also provides experimentally supported regulatory mechanism (microRNA, Transcription factor, variant, methylation and enhancer), biological function (cell growth, apoptosis, autophagy, Epithelial mesenchymal transformation, immune and coding ability) and clinical application (metastasis, recurrence, circulating, drug-resistant and prognostic) of lncRNAs and circRNAs in human cancer. Especially, an interactive analysis platform including RNA and single cell sequencing expression data is developed to help users explore lncRNAs in cancers with a standard processing pipeline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bio-bigdata.net/LnCeVar/index.jsp&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;LnCeVar&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a comprehensive database that aims to infer genomic variations that disturb lncRNA-associated ceRNA regulation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Manual curation of variation-ceRNA events from the published literature.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Manual curation of more than 2,000 experimentally supported circulating, drug-resistant and prognosis-related lncRNA biomarkers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Identification of somatic mutation-ceRNA events occurring in 33 cancers from TCGA and mutation profiles of over 1,000 cell lines from Cosmic.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Identification of CNV-ceRNA events in thousands of patients from TCGA.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Identification of SNP-ceRNA events from the 1000-Genome project.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://lncar.renlab.org/#welcome&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;lnCAR&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a catalog of human lncRNA expression profiles derived from re-annotation of public microarray expression data from over 57,000 samples spanning diverse cancers. &lt;a href=&#34;https://lncar.renlab.org/#welcome&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;lnCAR&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; enables the users to rapidly and intuitively explore differentially expressed lncRNAs of interest (annotated lncRNAs or any user-defined ones) in the context of different types of experiments. In addition, &lt;a href=&#34;https://lncar.renlab.org/#welcome&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;lnCAR&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is also a powerful platform for querying associations between lncRNA expression and cancer prognosis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Long non-coding RNAs (lncRNAs) are emerging as key factors in the regulation of various cellular processes and diseases. &lt;a href=&#34;http://bioinfo.life.hust.edu.cn/lncRNASNP#!/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;LncRNASNP&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a database providing comprehensive resources of single nucleotide polymorphisms (SNPs) in human/mouse lncRNAs. It contains SNPs in lncRNAs, SNP effects on lncRNA structure, mutation in lncRNAs and lncRNA:miRNA binding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Long noncoding RNAs (lncRNAs) play an important role in modulating gene expression or participating in some essential epigenetic regulation processes, including chromatin modification or DNA methylation. DNA methylation is a fundamental feature of epigenomes that can affect the expression of protein-coding or non-coding transcripts. &lt;a href=&#34;http://bio-bigdata.hrbmu.edu.cn/Lnc2Meth/index.jsp&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Lnc2Meth&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; aims to provide a comprehensive resource and web tool for clarifying the regulatory relationships between human lncRNAs and associated DNA methylation in diverse diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rna-society.org/rnalocate/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;RNALocate&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; aims to provide a resource for efficient manipulation, browsing and analysis of RNA subcellular localization. The second version of RNALocate documents more than 210,000 RNA-associated subcellular localization entries with experimental evidence, involving more than 110,000 RNAs with 171 subcellular localizations in 104 species. It will be of help in elucidating the entirety of RNA-associated subcellular localization, and developing new prediction methods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Long non-coding RNAs (lncRNAs) are expressed in a tissue-specific way, subcellular localizaitons of lncRNAs depend on the tissues or cell lines that they are expressed. Previous computational methods for predicting subcellular localizations of lncRNAs do not take this characteristic into account, they train a unified machine learning model for pooled lncRNAs from all available cell lines. It is of importance to develop a cell-line-specific computational method to predict lncRNA locations in different cell lines. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.csbio.sjtu.edu.cn/bioinf/lncLocator2/index.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;LncLocator&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 2.0, which trains a deep model per cell line for predicting lncRNA subcellular localization from sequences. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.csbio.sjtu.edu.cn/bioinf/lncLocator2/index.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;LncLocator&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 2.0 achieves varying effectiveness for different cell lines and demonstrates the necessity of training cell-line-specific models. Furthermore, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.csbio.sjtu.edu.cn/bioinf/lncLocator2/index.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;LncLocator&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 2.0 adopts Integrated Gradients to explain the proposed model, and find some potential patterns that determine the subcellular localizations of lncRNAs, suggesting that the subcellular localization of lncRNAs is linked to some specific nucleotides.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://lncatlas.crg.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;LncATLAS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is an easy to use web-based visualization tool to obtain useful information about expression localization of long non-coding class of RNAs. It is easy to use by just searching your lncRNA of interest in the search box. You can also use ENSEMBL gene IDs to select them. There are also some reference genes with a clear nuclear or cytoplasmatic expression profile. In some plots (3 and 4) you could also select the cell line from the dropdown menu to obtain a zoom into the distributions. Although many genes would have a similar profile among cell lines there might exist small changes. &lt;a href=&#34;https://lncatlas.crg.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;LncATLAS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; provides 6 charts that can be divided into 3 sections:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Inspect the cytoplasmic-nuclear localisation of your gene of interest (GOI): a barplot indicating the CN RCI values in each cell line for the selected gene(s)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Inspect the cytoplasmic-nuclear localisation of your GOI within the distribution of all genes: distribution of RCI values in each cell line for lncRNAs and mRNAs with the selected gene(s) highlighted&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Inspect the localisation of your GOI at sub-compartment level: localisation values within distributions for the K562 cell line subnuclear and subcytoplasmic compartments&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.exorbase.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;exoRBase&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a repository of extracellular vesicles (EVs) long RNAs (exLRs) derived from RNA-seq data analyses in different human body fluids. The exLRs contain messenger RNA (mRNA), long non-coding RNA (lncRNA), and circular RNA (circRNA). &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.exorbase.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;exoRBase&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 2.0 provides the comprehensive annotation and expression landscapes of exLRs. It will facilitate the identification of novel exLR signatures from human body fluids and will help discover new circulating biomarkers for the improvement of tumor diagnosis and therapy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://genome.igib.res.in/lncRNome/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;lncRNome&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a comprehensive searchable biologically oriented knowledgebase for long noncoding RNAs in Humans. The resource hosts information on over 17000 long noncoding RNAs in Human. The resource provides information on the types , chromosomal locations, description on the biological functions and disease associations of long noncoding RNAs. In addition, it provides access to datasets on protein-lncRNA interactions and genomic variations in lncRNA loci. The resource also provides a browsable interface for the datasets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://annolnc.gao-lab.org/index.php&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;AnnoLnc&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a web server to provide on-the-fly analysis for novel human or mouse lncRNAs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Long non-coding RNAs (lncRNAs) are an important category of non-coding RNAs (ncRNAs) which range from 200 nucleotides to multiple kilobases in length, with little or no protein-coding capacity. Circular RNAs (circRNAs) are widely expressed in diverse eukaryotic species and are characterized by covalently closed RNA loops through backsplicing events. Increasing evidence has highlighted the critical roles of lncRNAs and circRNAs in plenty of diseases development and progression. Here, we have updated the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rnanut.net/lncrnadisease/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;LncRNADisease&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; database to version 2.0 by integrating comprehensive experimentally supported and predicted ncRNA-disease associations curated from manual literatures and other resources. The new developments in &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rnanut.net/lncrnadisease/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;LncRNADisease&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; v2.0 include (I) over 40-fold ncRNA-disease associations enhancement compare to the previous version; (II) integrating experimentally supported circRNA-disease associations; (III) providing regulatory relationship among ncRNA, mRNA and miRNA; (IV) mapping disease name to the Disease Ontology and Medical Subject Headings (MeSH); (V) providing a confidence score for each ncRNA-disease association.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;RNA editing is a widespread post-transcriptional mechanism that can make discrete changes to specific nucleotide sequences within a RNA transcripts. RNA editing events can result in missense codon changes in mRNA, modulation of alternative splicing in mRNA, or modification of regulatory RNAs and their binding sites in small noncoding RNA, such as miRNA. Recent studies have developed computational methods to accurately detect more than 2 million A-to-I RNA editing from next-generation sequencing data in different species. However, the vast majority of these RNA sites are in noncoding regions of the genome and have unknown functional relevance. &lt;a href=&#34;http://bioinfo.life.hust.edu.cn/LNCediting/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;LNCediting&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; provides a comprehensive resource for the functional prediction of RNA editing in long noncoding RNAs (lncRNAs).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Long non-coding RNAs (lncRNAs) are emerging as key factors in the regulation of various cellular processes and diseases. &lt;a href=&#34;http://bioinfo.life.hust.edu.cn/lncRNASNP#!/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;LncRNASNP&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a database providing comprehensive resources of single nucleotide polymorphisms (SNPs) in human/mouse lncRNAs. It contains SNPs in lncRNAs, SNP effects on lncRNA structure, mutation in lncRNAs and lncRNA:miRNA binding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://rnasysu.com/chipbase3/index.php&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ChIPBase&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; v3.0 identified ~151,187,000 regulatory relationships between ~171,600 genes and ~3,000 regulators by analyzing ~55,000 ChIP-seq datasets, which represent a 30-fold expansion. Moreover, we de novo identified ~29,000 motif matrices of transcription factors. In addition, we constructed a novel “Enhancer” module to predict ~1,837,200 regulation regions functioning as poised, active or super enhancers under ~1300 conditions. Importantly, we constructed exhaustive coexpression maps between regulators and their target genes by integrating expression profiles of ∼65,000 normal and ∼15,000 tumor samples. We built a “Disease” module to obtain an atlas of the disease-associated variations in the regulation regions of genes. We also constructed an “EpiInter” module to explore potential interactions between epitranscriptome and epigenome. Finally, we designed “Network” module to provide extensive and gene-centred regulatory networks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Long noncoding RNAs (lncRNAs) play an important role in modulating gene expression or participating in some essential epigenetic regulation processes, including chromatin modification or DNA methylation. DNA methylation is a fundamental feature of epigenomes that can affect the expression of protein-coding or non-coding transcripts. Here, we constructed &lt;a href=&#34;http://bio-bigdata.hrbmu.edu.cn/Lnc2Meth/index.jsp&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lnc2Meth&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, aimed to provide a comprehensive resource and web tool for clarifying the regulatory relationships between human lncRNAs and associated DNA methylation in diverse diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This website &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gaemons.net/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Gaemons&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; hosts online services and databases developed by team of Dr Zhu and Dr Zhang at Southern Medical University, Guangzhou, China. And has have integrated LongTarget into &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gaemons.net/LongMan&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;LongMan&lt;/a&gt; to implement a seamless pipeline to implement this function.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;RNA editing is a widespread post-transcriptional mechanism that can make discrete changes to specific nucleotide sequences within a RNA transcripts. RNA editing events can result in missense codon changes in mRNA, modulation of alternative splicing in mRNA, or modification of regulatory RNAs and their binding sites in small noncoding RNA, such as miRNA. Recent studies have developed computational methods to accurately detect more than 2 million A-to-I RNA editing from next-generation sequencing data in different species. However, the vast majority of these RNA sites are in noncoding regions of the genome and have unknown functional relevance. &lt;a href=&#34;http://bioinfo.life.hust.edu.cn/LNCediting/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;LNCediting&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; provides a comprehensive resource for the functional prediction of RNA editing in long noncoding RNAs (lncRNAs).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;http://gtrd.biouml.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Gene Transcription Regulation Database (GTRD)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; contains uniformly annotated and processed NGS data related to gene transcription regulation: ChIP-seq, ChIP-exo, DNase-seq, MNase-seq, ATAC-seq and RNA-seq. With the latest release, the database has reached a new level of data integration. All cell types (cell lines and tissues) presented in the &lt;a href=&#34;http://gtrd.biouml.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;GTRD&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; were arranged into a dictionary and linked with different ontologies (BRENDA, Cell Ontology, Uberon, Cellosaurus and Experimental Factor Ontology) and with related experiments in specialized databases on transcription regulation (FANTOM5, ENCODE and GTEx). The updated version of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://gtrd.biouml.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;GTRD&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; provides an integrated view of transcription regulation through a dedicated web interface with advanced browsing and search capabilities, an integrated genome browser, and table reports by cell types, transcription factors, and genes of interest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://rna.sysu.edu.cn/deepbase3/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;deepBase&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a popular and openly licensed resource to facilitate the integrative and interactive display and analysis of expression, evolution, function of various ncRNAs by deeply mining thousands of high-throughput sequencing data from tissue, cancer and exosome samples. &lt;a href=&#34;https://rna.sysu.edu.cn/deepbase3/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;deepBase&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; provided the most comprehensive expression analysis of sRNAs and lncRNAs, the expression patterns of tRFs and snoRNAs from thousands of cancer and normal samples, the correlations between ncRNAs and patients’ survival and the function prediction of ncRNAs in tumor tumorigenesis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/tag/databases/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Databases&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/tool/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Tools &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Decreased Expression of the Host Long-Noncoding RNA-GM Facilitates Viral Escape by Inhibiting the Kinase activity TBK1 via S-glutathionylation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33326766/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33326766/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Viruses have evolved multiple strategies to evade elimination by the immune system. Here we examined the contribution of host long noncoding RNAs (lncRNAs) in viral immune evasion. By functional screening of lncRNAs whose expression decreased upon viral infection of macrophages, we identified a lncRNA (lncRNA-GM, Gene Symbol: AK189470.1) that promoted type I interferon (IFN-I) production and inhibited viral replication. Deficiency of lncRNA-GM in mice increased susceptibility to viral infection and impaired IFN-I production. Mechanistically, lncRNA-GM bound to glutathione S-transferase M1 (GSTM1) and blocked GSTM1 interaction with the kinase TBK1, reducing GSTM1-mediated S-glutathionylation of TBK1. Decreased S-glutathionylation enhanced TBK1 activity and downstream production of antiviral mediators. Viral infection reprogrammed intracellular glutathione metabolism and furthermore, an oxidized glutathione mimetic could inhibit TBK1 activity and promote viral replication. Our findings reveal regulation of TBK1 by S-glutathionylation and provide insight into the viral mediated metabolic changes that impact innate immunity and viral evasion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Online tools decoding RNA-RNA regulatory networks</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tool/2020-11-10-rri/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/tool/2020-11-10-rri/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://circinteractome.nia.nih.gov/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;CircInteractome&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; predicts the miRNAs which can potentially target the circRNAs using the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.targetscan.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Targetscan&lt;/a&gt; prediction tool. This computational tool enables the prediction and mapping of binding sites for RBPs and miRNAs on reported circRNAs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights of &lt;a href=&#34;%28https://circinteractome.nia.nih.gov/%29&#34;&gt;CircInteractome&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Searches circRNAs name&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Searches the genomic position and best-matching transcripts of the circRNA&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Retrieves genomic and mature circRNA sequences&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Searches RBPs binding to a circRNA and to sequences upstream/downstream of the circRNA&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Identifies RBPs binding to the circRNA junctions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Identifies miRNAs targeting a circRNA&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Designs divergent primers for circRNAs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Designs siRNAs Specific to circRNA&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://starbase.sysu.edu.cn/index.php&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;ENCORI (The Encyclopedia of RNA Interactomes)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is an openly licensed and state-of-the-art platform to decode the cellular interaction networks among thousands of RNA binding proteins (RBPs) and various RNAs. We have identified millions of RBP-RNA and RNA-RNA interactions through analyzing thousands of CLIP-seq and various high-throughput sequencing data by developing new software and tools, and studied their functions and mechanisms in human diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/tag/databases/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Databases&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/tool/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Tools &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Translation of noncoding RNAs and cancer</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/33038492/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/33038492/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some ncRNAs are translated into stable peptides or proteins, expanding the landscape of the proteome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some tools, methods and databases are designed for identifying and validating ncRNA-encoded peptides related with cancer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The translation of lncRNAs provides a novel molecular mechanism to participate in complex regulatory networks of cells.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CircRNA-encoded peptides in cancer may become drug targets and biomarkers for diagnosing or predicting the prognosis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The human genome contains thousands of noncoding RNAs (ncRNAs), which are thought to lack open reading frames (ORFs) and cannot be translated. Some ncRNAs reportedly have important functions, including epigenetic regulation, chromatin remolding, protein modification, and RNA degradation, but the functions of most ncRNAs remain elusive. Through the application and development of ribosome profiling and sequencing technologies, an increasing number of studies have discovered the translation of ncRNAs. Although ncRNAs were initially defined as noncoding RNAs, a number of ncRNAs actually contain ORFs that are translated into peptides. Here, we summarize the available methods, tools, and databases for identifying and validating ncRNA-encoded peptides/proteins, and the recent findings regarding ncRNA-encoded small peptides/proteins in cancer are compiled and synthesized. Importantly, the role of ncRNA-encoding peptides/proteins has application prospects in cancer research, but some potential challenges remain unresolved. The aim of this review is to provide a theoretical basis that might promote the discovery of more peptides/proteins encoded by ncRNAs and aid the further development of novel diagnostic and prognostic cancer markers and therapeutic targets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LncRNA Malat1 inhibition of TDP43 cleavage suppresses IRF3-initiated antiviral innate immunity</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32907941/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32907941/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Long noncoding RNAs (lncRNAs) involved in the regulation of antiviral innate immune responses need to be further identified. By functionally screening the lncRNAs in macrophages, here we identified lncRNA &lt;em&gt;Malat1&lt;/em&gt;, abundant in the nucleus but significantly down-regulated after viral infection, as a negative regulator of antiviral type I IFN (IFN-I) production. &lt;em&gt;Malat1&lt;/em&gt; directly bound to the transactive response DNA-binding protein (TDP43) in the nucleus and prevented activation of TDP43 by blocking the activated caspase-3-mediated TDP43 cleavage to TDP35. The cleaved TDP35 increased the nuclear IRF3 protein level by binding and degrading &lt;em&gt;Rbck1&lt;/em&gt; pre-mRNA to prevent IRF3 proteasomal degradation upon viral infection, thus selectively promoting antiviral IFN-I production. Deficiency of &lt;em&gt;Malat1&lt;/em&gt; enhanced antiviral innate responses in vivo, accompanying the increased IFN-I production and reduced viral burden. Importantly, the reduced &lt;em&gt;MALAT1&lt;/em&gt;, augmented IRF3, and increased &lt;em&gt;IFNA&lt;/em&gt; mRNA were found in peripheral blood mononuclear cells (PBMCs) from systemic lupus erythematosus (SLE) patients. Therefore, the down-regulation of &lt;em&gt;MALAT1&lt;/em&gt; in virus-infected cells or in human cells from autoimmune diseases will increase host resistance against viral infection or lead to autoinflammatory interferonopathies via the increased type I IFN production. Our results demonstrate that the nuclear &lt;em&gt;Malat1&lt;/em&gt; suppresses antiviral innate responses by targeting TDP43 activation via RNA-RBP interactive network, adding insight to the molecular regulation of innate responses and autoimmune pathogenesis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Significance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LncRNAs have been identified as regulating antiviral innate responses via different targets through various ways. Whether there is an abundant and highly conserved lncRNA in the nucleus which may regulate antiviral innate signaling through a new mechanism remains to be investigated. Here, we identify that viral infection-reduced expression of &lt;em&gt;Malat1&lt;/em&gt; feedback promotes IRF3-initiated type I IFN production in the innate response against viral infection. &lt;em&gt;Malat1&lt;/em&gt; binds to TDP43 and prevents its cleavage mediated by activated caspase-3. The cleaved TDP35 inhibits IRF3 degradation through promoting the degradation of pre-mRNA of Rbck1, an E3 ubiquitin ligase targeting IRF3. Aberrant &lt;em&gt;MALAT1&lt;/em&gt; reduction and IRF3 activation are found in SLE patients, providing one mechanistic explanation for why SLE patients always have type I interferonopathies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LncRNA PVT1 promotes gemcitabine resistance of pancreatic cancer via activating Wnt/β-catenin and autophagy pathway through modulating the miR-619-5p/Pygo2 and miR-619-5p/ATG14 axes</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32727463/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32727463/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pancreatic cancer is one of the most lethal malignancies and has an extremely poor diagnosis and prognosis. The development of resistance to gemcitabine is still a major challenge. The long noncoding RNA PVT1 was reported to be involved in carcinogenesis and chemoresistance; however, the mechanism by which PVT1 regulates the sensitivity of pancreatic cancer to gemcitabine remains poorly understood.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The viability of pancreatic cancer cells was assessed by MTT assay in vitro and xenograft tumor formation assay in vivo. The expression levels of PVT1 and miR-619-5p were detected by quantitative real-time polymerase chain reaction (qRT-PCR). Western blotting analysis and qRT-PCR were performed to assess the protein and mRNA levels of Pygo2 and ATG14, respectively. Autophagy was explored via autophagic flux detection under confocal microscopy and autophagic vacuole investigation under transmission electron microscopy (TEM). The functional role and mechanism of PVT1 were further investigated by gain- and loss-of-function assays in vitro.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the present study, we demonstrated that PVT1 was up-regulated in gemcitabine-resistant pancreatic cancer cell lines. Gain- and loss-of-function assays revealed that PVT1 impaired sensitivity to gemcitabine in vitro and in vivo. We further found that PVT1 up-regulated the expression of both Pygo2 and ATG14 and thus regulated Wnt/β-catenin signaling and autophagic activity to overcome gemcitabine resistance through sponging miR-619-5p. Moreover, we discovered three TCF/LEF binding elements (TBEs) in the promoter region of PVT1, and activation of Wnt/β-catenin signaling mediated by the up-regulation of Pygo2 increased PVT1 expression by direct binding to the TBE region. Furthermore, PVT1 was discovered to interact with ATG14, thus promoting assembly of the autophagy specific complex I (PtdIns3K-C1) and ATG14-dependent class III PtdIns3K activity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These data indicate that PVT1 plays a critical role in the sensitivity of pancreatic cancer to gemcitabine and highlight its potential as a valuable target for pancreatic cancer therapy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>lncRNA Sensing of a Viral Suppressor of RNAi Activates Non-canonical Innate Immune Signaling in Drosophila</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/31917956/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/31917956/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Antiviral immunity in insects is mediated by the RNA interference (RNAi) pathway. Viruses evade antiviral RNAi by expressing virulence factors known as viral suppressors of RNAi (VSR). Here, we report the identification of VINR, a Drosophila VSR-interacting long non-coding (lnc) RNA that activates non-canonical innate immune signaling upon detection of the dsRNA-binding VSR of Drosophila C virus (DCV). VINR is required for the induction of antimicrobial peptide (AMP) genes but dispensable for antiviral RNAi. VINR functions by preventing the ubiquitin proteasome-dependent degradation of Cactin, a coiled-coil and arginine-serine-rich domain-containing protein that regulates a non-cannonical antimicrobial pathway for AMP induction. CRISPR-Cas9 knockout of VINR in Drosophila cells enhances DCV replication independently of antiviral RNAi, and VINR-knockout adult flies exhibit enhanced disease susceptibility to DCV and bacteria. Our findings reveal a counter counter-defense strategy activated by a lncRNA in response to the viral suppression of the primary antiviral RNAi immunity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LncRNA PTPRE-AS1 modulates M2 macrophage activation and inflammatory diseases by epigenetic promotion of PTPRE</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/31844669/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/31844669/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Long noncoding RNAs (lncRNAs) are important regulators of diverse biological processes; however, their function in macrophage activation is undefined. We describe a new regulatory mechanism, where an unreported lncRNA, &lt;em&gt;PTPRE-AS1&lt;/em&gt;, targets receptor-type tyrosine protein phosphatase ε (PTPRE) to regulate macrophage activation. &lt;em&gt;PTPRE-AS1&lt;/em&gt; was selectively expressed in IL-4-stimulated macrophages, and its knockdown promoted M2 macrophage activation via MAPK/ERK 1/2 pathway. In vivo, PTPRE-AS1 deficiency enhanced IL-4-mediated M2 macrophage activation and accelerated pulmonary allergic inflammation while reducing chemical-induced colitis. Mechanistically, &lt;em&gt;PTPRE-AS1&lt;/em&gt; bound WDR5 directly, modulating H3K4me3 of the &lt;em&gt;PTPRE&lt;/em&gt; promoter to regulate &lt;em&gt;PTPRE&lt;/em&gt;-dependent signaling during M2 macrophage activation. Further, the expression of &lt;em&gt;PTPRE-AS1&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;PTPRE&lt;/em&gt; was significantly lower in peripheral blood mononuclear cells from patients with allergic asthma. These results provide evidence supporting the importance of &lt;em&gt;PTPRE-AS1&lt;/em&gt; in controlling macrophage function and the potential utility of &lt;em&gt;PTPRE-AS1&lt;/em&gt; as a target for controlling inflammatory diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A genome-wide long noncoding RNA CRISPRi screen identifies PRANCR as a novel regulator of epidermal homeostasis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/31804951/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/31804951/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Genome-wide association studies indicate that many disease susceptibility regions reside in non-protein-coding regions of the genome. Long noncoding RNAs (lncRNAs) are a major component of the noncoding genome, but their biological impacts are not fully understood. Here, we performed a CRISPR interference (CRISPRi) screen on 2263 epidermis-expressed lncRNAs and identified nine novel candidate lncRNAs regulating keratinocyte proliferation. We further characterized a top hit from the screen, progenitor renewal associated non-coding RNA (&lt;em&gt;PRANCR&lt;/em&gt;), using RNA interference-mediated knockdown and phenotypic analysis in organotypic human tissue. PRANCR regulates keratinocyte proliferation, cell cycle progression, and clonogenicity. &lt;em&gt;PRANCR&lt;/em&gt;-deficient epidermis displayed impaired stratification with reduced expression of differentiation genes that are altered in human skin diseases, including keratins 1 and 10, filaggrin, and loricrin. Transcriptome analysis showed that &lt;em&gt;PRANCR&lt;/em&gt; controls the expression of 1136 genes, with strong enrichment for late cell cycle genes containing a CHR promoter element. In addition, _PRANCR _depletion led to increased levels of both total and nuclear CDKN1A (also known as p21), which is known to govern both keratinocyte proliferation and differentiation. Collectively, these data show that &lt;em&gt;PRANCR&lt;/em&gt; is a novel lncRNA regulating epidermal homeostasis and identify other lncRNA candidates that may have roles in this process as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LncRNA-HGBC stabilized by HuR promotes gallbladder cancer progression by regulating miR-502-3p/SET/AKT axis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/31752906/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/31752906/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Erratum in:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Correction to: &lt;a href=&#34;https://molecular-cancer.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12943-021-01386-8&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;LncRNA-HGBC stabilized by HuR promotes gallbladder cancer progression by regulating miR-502-3p/SET/AKT axis&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Backgrounds:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Long non-coding RNAs (lncRNAs) are essential factors that regulate tumor development and metastasis via diverse molecular mechanisms in a broad type of cancers. However, the pathological roles of lncRNAs in gallbladder carcinoma (GBC) remain largely unknown. Here we discovered a novel lncRNA termed lncRNA Highly expressed in GBC (lncRNA-HGBC) which was upregulated in GBC tissue and aimed to investigate its role and regulatory mechanism in the development and progression of GBC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The expression level of lncRNA-HGBC in GBC tissue and different cell lines was determined by quantitative real-time PCR. The full length of lncRNA-HGBC was obtained by 5&amp;rsquo; and 3&amp;rsquo; rapid amplification of the cDNA ends (RACE). Cellular localization of lncRNA-HGBC was detected by fluorescence in situ hybridization (FISH) assays and subcellular fractionation assay. In vitro and in vivo assays were preformed to explore the biological effects of lncRNA-HGBC in GBC cells. RNA pull-down assay, mass spectrometry, and RNA immunoprecipitation (RIP) assay were used to identify lncRNA-HGBC-interacting proteins. Dual luciferase reporter assays, AGO2-RIP, and MS2-RIP assays were performed to verify the interaction between lncRNA-HGBC and miR-502-3p.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We found that lncRNA-HGBC was upregulated in GBC and its upregulation could predict poor survival. Overexpression or knockdown of lncRNA-HGBC in GBC cell lines resulted in increased or decreased, respectively, cell proliferation and invasion in vitro and in xenografted tumors. LncRNA-HGBC specifically bound to RNA binding protein Hu Antigen R (HuR) that in turn stabilized lncRNA-HGBC. LncRNA-HGBC functioned as a competitive endogenous RNA to bind to miR-502-3p that inhibits target gene SET. Overexpression, knockdown or mutation of lncRNA-HGBC altered the inhibitory effects of miR-502-3p on SET expression and downstream activation of AKT. Clinically, lncRNA-HGBC expression was negatively correlated with miR-502-3p, but positively correlated with SET and HuR in GBC tissue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our study demonstrates that lncRNA-HGBC promotes GBC metastasis via activation of the miR-502-3p-SET-AKT cascade, pointing to lncRNA-HGBC as a new prognostic predictor and a therapeutic target.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A high-throughput screen identifies the long non-coding RNA DRAIC as a regulator of autophagy</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/30872794/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/30872794/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Autophagy is a conserved degradation process that occurs in all eukaryotic cells and its dysfunction has been associated with various diseases including cancer. While a number of large-scale attempts have recently identified new molecular players in autophagy regulation, including proteins and microRNAs, little is known regarding the function of long non-coding RNAs (lncRNAs) in the regulation of this process. To identify new long non-coding RNAs with functional implications in autophagy, we performed a high-throughput RNAi screen targeting more than 600 lncRNA transcripts and monitored their effects on autophagy in MCF-7 cells. We identified 63 lncRNAs that affected GFP-LC3B puncta numbers significantly. We validated the strongest hit, the lncRNA DRAIC previously shown to impact cell proliferation, and revealed a novel role for this lncRNA in the regulation of autophagic flux. Interestingly, we find DRAIC&amp;rsquo;s pro-proliferative effects to be autophagy-independent. This study serves as a valuable resource for researchers from both the lncRNA and autophagy fields as it advances the current understanding of autophagy regulation by non-coding RNAs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Network of Noncoding Regulatory RNAs Acts in the Mammalian Brain</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/29887379/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/29887379/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Noncoding RNAs (ncRNAs) play increasingly appreciated gene-regulatory roles. Here, we describe a regulatory network centered on four ncRNAs-a long ncRNA, a circular RNA, and two microRNAs-using gene editing in mice to probe the molecular consequences of disrupting key components of this network. The long ncRNA Cyrano uses an extensively paired site to miR-7 to trigger destruction of this microRNA. Cyrano-directed miR-7 degradation is much more effective than previously described examples of target-directed microRNA degradation, which come primarily from studies of artificial and viral RNAs. By reducing miR-7 levels, Cyrano prevents repression of miR-7-targeted mRNAs and enables accumulation of Cdr1as, a circular RNA known to regulate neuronal activity. Without Cyrano, excess miR-7 causes cytoplasmic destruction of Cdr1as in neurons, in part through enhanced slicing of Cdr1as by a second miRNA, miR-671. Thus, several types of ncRNAs can collaborate to establish a sophisticated regulatory network.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Recognition of an Inducible Host lncRNA by RIG-I Feedback Restricts Innate Immune Response</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/29706547/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/29706547/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The innate RNA sensor RIG-I is critical in the initiation of antiviral type I interferons (IFNs) production upon recognition of &amp;ldquo;non-self&amp;rdquo; viral RNAs. Here, we identify a host-derived, IFN-inducible long noncoding RNA, lnc-Lsm3b, that can compete with viral RNAs in the binding of RIG-I monomers and feedback inactivate the RIG-I innate function at late stage of innate response. Mechanistically, binding of lnc-Lsm3b restricts RIG-I protein&amp;rsquo;s conformational shift and prevents downstream signaling, thereby terminating type I IFNs production. Multivalent structural motifs and long-stem structure are critical features of lnc-Lsm3b for RIG-I binding and inhibition. These data reveal a non-canonical self-recognition mode in the regulation of immune response and demonstrate an important role of an inducible &amp;ldquo;self&amp;rdquo; lncRNA acting as a potent molecular decoy actively saturating RIG-I binding sites to restrict the duration of &amp;ldquo;non-self&amp;rdquo; RNA-induced innate immune response and maintaining immune homeostasis, with potential utility in inflammatory disease management.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
