<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>lncRNAs | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/lncrnas/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/lncrnas/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>lncRNAs</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>lncRNAs</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/lncrnas/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>A specific G9a inhibitor unveils BGLT3 lncRNA as a universal mediator of chemically induced fetal globin gene expression</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36635268/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36635268/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sickle cell disease (SCD) is a heritable disorder caused by β-globin gene mutations. Induction of fetal γ-globin is an established therapeutic strategy. Recently, epigenetic modulators, including G9a inhibitors, have been proposed as therapeutic agents. However, the molecular mechanisms whereby these small molecules reactivate γ-globin remain unclear. Here we report the development of a highly selective and non-genotoxic G9a inhibitor, RK-701. RK-701 treatment induces fetal globin expression both in human erythroid cells and in mice. Using RK-701, we find that BGLT3 long non-coding RNA plays an essential role in γ-globin induction. RK-701 selectively upregulates BGLT3 by inhibiting the recruitment of two major γ-globin repressors in complex with G9a onto the BGLT3 gene locus through CHD4, a component of the NuRD complex. Remarkably, BGLT3 is indispensable for γ-globin induction by not only RK-701 but also hydroxyurea and other inducers. The universal role of BGLT3 in γ-globin induction suggests its importance in SCD treatment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anti-angiogenic effect of exo-LncRNA TUG1 in myocardial infarction and modulation by remote ischemic conditioning</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36635484/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36635484/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The successful use of exosomes in therapy after myocardial infarction depends on an improved understanding of their role in cardiac signaling and regulation. Here, we report that exosomes circulating after myocardial infarction (MI) carry LncRNA TUG1 which downregulates angiogenesis by disablement of the HIF-1α/VEGF-α axis and that this effect can be counterbalanced by remote ischemic conditioning (RIC). Rats with MI induced through left coronary artery ligation without (MI model) and with reperfusion (ischemia/reperfusion I/R model) were randomized to RIC, or MI (I/R) or sham-operated (SO) control. Data from one cohort study and one randomized-controlled trial of humans with MI were also utilized, the former involving patients who had not received percutaneous coronary intervention (PCI) and the latter patients with PCI. Exosome concentrations did not differ between intervention groups (RIC vs. control) in rats (MI and I/R model) as well as humans (with and without PCI). However, MI and I/R exosomes attenuated HIF-1α, VEGF-α, and endothelial function. LncRNA TUG1 was increased in MI and I/R exosomes, but decreased in SO and RIC exosomes. HIF-1α expression was downregulated with MI and I/R exosomes but increased with RIC exosomes. Exosome inhibition suppressed HIF-1α upregulation through RIC exosomes. VEGF-α was identified as HIF-1α-regulated target gene. Knockdown of HIF-1α decreased VEGF-α, endothelial cell capability, and tube formation. Overexpression of HIF-1α exerted opposite effects. Transfection and co-transfection of 293 T cells with exosome-inhibitor GW4869 and HIF-1α inhibitor si-HIF-1α confirmed the exosomal-LncRNA TUG1/HIF-1α/VEGF-α pathway. LncRNA TUG1 is a potential therapeutic target after MI with or without reperfusion through PCI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Long non-coding RNAs: definitions, functions, challenges and recommendations</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/36596869/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/36596869/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Genes specifying long non-coding RNAs (lncRNAs) occupy a large fraction of the genomes of complex organisms. The term &amp;rsquo;lncRNAs&amp;rsquo; encompasses RNA polymerase I (Pol I), Pol II and Pol III transcribed RNAs, and RNAs from processed introns. The various functions of lncRNAs and their many isoforms and interleaved relationships with other genes make lncRNA classification and annotation difficult. Most lncRNAs evolve more rapidly than protein-coding sequences, are cell type specific and regulate many aspects of cell differentiation and development and other physiological processes. Many lncRNAs associate with chromatin-modifying complexes, are transcribed from enhancers and nucleate phase separation of nuclear condensates and domains, indicating an intimate link between lncRNA expression and the spatial control of gene expression during development. lncRNAs also have important roles in the cytoplasm and beyond, including in the regulation of translation, metabolism and signalling. lncRNAs often have a modular structure and are rich in repeats, which are increasingly being shown to be relevant to their function. In this Consensus Statement, we address the definition and nomenclature of lncRNAs and their conservation, expression, phenotypic visibility, structure and functions. We also discuss research challenges and provide recommendations to advance the understanding of the roles of lncRNAs in development, cell biology and disease.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RUNX2 stabilization by long non-coding RNAs contributes to hypertrophic changes in human chondrocytes</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36594090/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36594090/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Chondrocyte hypertrophy has been implicated in endochondral ossification and osteoarthritis (OA). In OA, hypertrophic chondrocytes contribute to the destruction and focal calcification of the joint cartilage. Although studies in this field have remarkably developed the modulation of joint inflammation using gene therapy and regeneration of damaged articular cartilage using cell therapy, studies that can modulate or prevent hypertrophic changes in articular chondrocytes are still lacking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;In vitro&lt;/em&gt; hypertrophic differentiation and inflammation assays were conducted using human normal chondrocyte cell lines, TC28a2 cells. Human cartilage tissues and primary articular chondrocytes were obtained from OA patients undergoing total knee arthroplasty. Long non-coding RNAs (lncRNAs), LINC02035 and LOC100130207, were selected through RNA-sequencing analysis using RNAs extracted from TC28a2 cells cultured in hypertrophic medium. The regulatory mechanism was evaluated using western blotting, real-time quantitative polymerase chain reaction, osteocalcin reporter assay, RNA-immunoprecipitation (RNA-IP), RNA-&lt;em&gt;in situ&lt;/em&gt; hybridization, and IP.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; LncRNAs are crucial regulators of various biological processes. In this study, we identified two important lncRNAs, LINC02035 and LOC100130207, which play important roles in hypertrophic changes in normal chondrocytes, through RNA sequencing. Interestingly, the expression level of RUNX2, a master regulator of chondrocyte hypertrophy, was regulated at the post-translational level during hypertrophic differentiation of the normal human chondrocyte cell line, TC28a2. RNA-immunoprecipitation proved the potential interaction between RUNX2 protein and both lncRNAs. Knockdown (KD) of LINC02035 or LOC100130207 promoted ubiquitin-mediated proteasomal degradation of RUNX2 and prevented hypertrophic differentiation of normal chondrocyte cell lines, whereas overexpression of both lncRNAs stabilized RUNX2 protein and generated hypertrophic changes. Furthermore, the KD of the two lncRNAs mitigated the destruction of important cartilage matrix proteins, COL2A1 and ACAN, by hypertrophic differentiation or inflammatory conditions. We also confirmed that the phenotypic changes raised by the two lncRNAs could be rescued by modulating &lt;em&gt;RUNX2&lt;/em&gt; expression. In addition, the KD of these two lncRNAs suppressed hypertrophic changes during chondrogenic differentiation of mesenchymal stem cells.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/em&gt; Therefore, this study suggests that LINC02035 and LOC100130207 contribute to hypertrophic changes in normal chondrocytes by regulating RUNX2, suggesting that these two novel lncRNAs could be potential therapeutic targets for delaying or preventing OA development, especially for preventing chondrocyte hypertrophy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>APLF and long non-coding RNA NIHCOLE promote stable DNA synapsis in non-homologous end joining</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36640344/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36640344/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In NHEJ, APLF promotes synapsis of DNA ends for several minutes under piconewton forces&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ku70-Ku80 and APLF establish a minimal complex sufficient to support DNA synapsis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Long non-coding RNA NIHCOLE stabilizes a DNA synapsis mediated by Ku70-Ku80 and APLF&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A small and structured RNA domain of NIHCOLE promotes stable joining of DNA ends&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The synapsis of DNA ends is a critical step for the repair of double-strand breaks by non-homologous end joining (NHEJ). This is performed by a multicomponent protein complex assembled around Ku70-Ku80 heterodimers and regulated by accessory factors, including long non-coding RNAs, through poorly understood mechanisms. Here, we use magnetic tweezers to investigate the contributions of core NHEJ proteins and APLF and lncRNA NIHCOLE to DNA synapsis. APLF stabilizes DNA end bridging and, together with Ku70-Ku80, establishes a minimal complex that supports DNA synapsis for several minutes under piconewton forces. We find the C-terminal acidic region of APLF to be critical for bridging. NIHCOLE increases the dwell time of the synapses by Ku70-Ku80 and APLF. This effect is further enhanced by a small and structured RNA domain within NIHCOLE. We propose a model where Ku70-Ku80 can simultaneously bind DNA, APLF, and structured RNAs to promote the stable joining of DNA ends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The lncRNA LUCAT1 is elevated in inflammatory disease and restrains inflammation by regulating the splicing and stability of NR4A2</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36577072/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36577072/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Significance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Long non-coding RNAs (lncRNAs) are abundant in the human genome, yet, in contrast to proteins, only a small portion of lncRNAs have been functionally characterized. We further explore the molecular basis of LUCAT1-dependent regulation of the inflammatory response. In this study, we identify LUCAT1-binding proteins that are involved in splicing and processing of mRNAs including the anti-inflammatory NR4A2. LUCAT1 regulates splicing and stability of NR4A2 which contributes to the inhibitory effect of LUCAT1 on interferons and inflammatory cytokines. Finally, data from COPD and IBD patients indicate that LUCAT1 levels are elevated in these patient groups where expression is positively correlated with disease severity. Thus, LUCAT1 may serve as a diagnostic marker for inflammation and as a therapeutic target in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The nuclear long non-coding RNA LUCAT1 has previously been identified as a negative feedback regulator of type I interferon and inflammatory cytokine expression in human myeloid cells. Here, we define the mechanistic basis for the suppression of inflammatory gene expression by LUCAT1. Using comprehensive identification of RNA-binding proteins by mass spectrometry as well as RNA immunoprecipitation, we identified proteins important in processing and alternative splicing of mRNAs as LUCAT1-binding proteins. These included heterogeneous nuclear ribonucleoprotein C, M, and A2B1. Consistent with this finding, cells lacking LUCAT1 have altered splicing of selected immune genes. In particular, upon lipopolysaccharide stimulation, the splicing of the nuclear receptor 4A2 (NR4A2) gene was particularly affected. As a consequence, expression of NR4A2 was reduced and delayed in cells lacking LUCAT1. NR4A2-deficient cells had elevated expression of immune genes. These observations suggest that LUCAT1 is induced to control the splicing and stability of NR4A2, which is in part responsible for the anti-inflammatory effect of LUCAT1. Furthermore, we analyzed a large cohort of patients with inflammatory bowel disease as well as asthma and chronic obstructive pulmonary disease. In these patients, LUCAT1 levels were elevated and in both diseases, positively correlated with disease severity. Collectively, these studies define a key molecular mechanism of LUCAT1-dependent immune regulation through post-transcriptional regulation of mRNAs highlighting its role in the regulation of inflammatory disease.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Antisense-oligonucleotide-mediated perturbation of long non-coding RNA reveals functional features in stem cells and across cell types</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36577377/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36577377/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Molecular phenotyping shows richer functional annotation than cellular phenotyping&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Integration with chromatin interaction reveals cis- or trans-regulation of lncRNA&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;LINC02595&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;CATG00000090305.1&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;RP11-148B6.2&lt;/em&gt; modulate colony formation of iPSCs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Within the scope of the FANTOM6 consortium, we perform a large-scale knockdown of 200 long non-coding RNAs (lncRNAs) in human induced pluripotent stem cells (iPSCs) and systematically characterize their roles in self-renewal and pluripotency. We find 36 lncRNAs (18%) exhibiting cell growth inhibition. From the knockdown of 123 lncRNAs with transcriptome profiling, 36 lncRNAs (29.3%) show molecular phenotypes. Integrating the molecular phenotypes with chromatin-interaction assays further reveals cis- and trans-interacting partners as potential primary targets. Additionally, cell-type enrichment analysis identifies lncRNAs associated with pluripotency, while the knockdown of LINC02595, CATG00000090305.1, and RP11-148B6.2 modulates colony formation of iPSCs. We compare our results with previously published fibroblasts phenotyping data and find that 2.9% of the lncRNAs exhibit a consistent cell growth phenotype, whereas we observe 58.3% agreement in molecular phenotypes. This highlights that molecular phenotyping is more comprehensive in revealing affected pathways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exosomal LOC85009 inhibits docetaxel resistance in lung adenocarcinoma through regulating ATG5-induced autophagy</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36641841/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36641841/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Aims:&lt;/em&gt; This study aims at investigating the role of a neighbor long non-coding RNA (lncRNA) of HDAC4 (LOC85009) in docetaxel (DTX) resistance of lung adenocarcinoma (LUAD).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; RT-qPCR was used to analyze LOC85009 expression in DTX-resistant LUAD cells. &lt;em&gt;In vitro&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt; experiments were applied to detect the influence of LOC85009 on LUAD cell growth and xenograft tumor growth. DNA pull down assay, RNA pull down assay, ChIP assay, CoIP assay and RIP assay were performed to identify the direct interactions between factors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; LOC85009 was lowly-expressed in DTX-resistant LUAD cells. Functionally, LOC85009 overexpression inhibited DTX resistance and cell proliferation but triggered cell apoptosis. Moreover, we identified that LOC85009 was transferred from LUAD cells to DTX-resistant LUAD cells via exosomes. Exosomal LOC85009 inhibited DTX resistance, proliferation and autophagy while induced apoptosis in DTX-resistant cells. Additionally, we found that LOC85009 sequestered ubiquitin-specific proteinase 5 (USP5) to destabilize upstream transcription factor 1 (USF1) protein, thereby inactivating ATG5 transcription.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; Exosomal LOC85009 inhibits DTX resistance through regulation of ATG5-induced autophagy via USP5/USF1 axis, suggesting that LOC85009 might be a potential target to reverse DTX resistance in the treatment of LUAD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mitochondrial Genome-Encoded Long Noncoding RNA and Mitochondrial Stability in Diabetic Retinopathy</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36563021/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36563021/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mitochondria experience genomic and functional instability in diabetes, and mitochondrial dysfunction has a critical role in the development of diabetic retinopathy. Diabetes also alters expressions of many long non-coding RNAs (LncRNAs), the RNAs with &amp;gt;200 nucleotides and no open reading frame. LncRNAs are mainly encoded by nuclear genome, but mtDNA also encodes three LncRNAs. Our goal was to investigate the effect of hyperglycemia on mtDNA-encoded LncRNA Cytochrome B (LncCytB) in mtDNA stability in diabetic retinopathy. Retinal endothelial cells, transfected with LncCytB- overexpressing plasmids or siRNA, incubated in 5mmols/L (NG) or 20mmols/L (HG) D-glucose for four days, were analyzed for LncCytB expression by strand-specific PCR, and its mitochondrial localization by RNA-FISH. Damage sensitive mtDNA regions were examined by micrococcal nuclease digestion-sequencing, and LncCytB occupancy at mtDNA by chromatin isolation by RNA purification. Protective nucleoids in mtDNA were analyzed by SYBR green-MitoTracker Red staining, and confirmed in isolated mitochondria by flow cytometry. Compared to NG, HG downregulated LncCytB by &amp;gt;50%, but had no significant effect on the other mtDNAencoded LncRNAs. mtDNA packaging was impaired and MNase sensitivity was increased, and LncCytB occupancy at mtDNA was decreased. While LncCytB overexpression ameliorated mtDNA damage and decrease in nucleoids and copy numbers, LncCytB-siRNA exacerbated damage and further reduced nucleoids. Retinal microvessels from streptozotocin-induced diabetic mice and human donors with diabetic retinopathy presented similar decrease in LncCytB and mtDNA nucleoids. Thus, LncCytB has a major role in maintaining mitochondrial genomic stability, and its downregulation in hyperglycemic milieu contributes to increased vulnerability of mtDNA to damage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mitochondria-localized lncRNA HITT inhibits fusion by attenuating formation of mitofusin-2 homo- or heterotypic complexes</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36567017/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36567017/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Long non-coding RNAs (lncRNAs) are emerging as essential players in multiple biological processes. Mitochondrial dynamics, comprising the continuous cycle of fission and fusion, are required for healthy mitochondria that function properly. Despite long-term recognition of its significance in cell-fate control, the mechanism underlying mitochondrial fusion is not completely understood, particularly regarding the involvement of lncRNAs. Here, we show that the lncRNA HITT (HIF-1α inhibitor at translation level), can specifically localize in mitochondria. Cells expressing higher levels of HITT contain fragmented mitochondria. Conversely, we show that HITT knockdown cells have more tubular mitochondria than is present in control cells. Mechanistically, we demonstrate HITT directly binds mitofusin-2 (MFN2), a core component that mediates mitochondrial outer membrane fusion, by the &lt;em&gt;in vitro&lt;/em&gt; RNA pull-down and UV-cross-linking RNA-IP (CLIP) assays. In doing so, we found HITT disturbs MFN2 homo- or heterotypic complex formation, attenuating mitochondrial fusion. Under stress conditions, such as ultraviolet radiation, we in addition show HITT stability increases as a consequence of MiR-205 downregulation, inhibiting MFN2-mediated fusion and leading to apoptosis. Overall, our data provide significant insights into the roles of organelle (mitochondria)-specific resident lncRNAs in regulating mitochondrial fusion, and also reveal how such a mechanism controls cellular sensitivity to UV radiation-induced apoptosis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Somatosensory neurons express specific sets of lincRNAs, and lincRNA CLAP promotes itch sensation in mice</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36524339/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36524339/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Somatosensory neurons are highly heterogeneous with distinct types of neural cells responding to specific stimuli. However, the distribution and roles of cell-type-specific long intergenic noncoding RNAs (lincRNAs) in somatosensory neurons remain largely unexplored. Here, by utilizing droplet-based single-cell RNA-seq (scRNA-seq) and full-length Smart-seq2, we show that lincRNAs, but not coding mRNAs, are enriched in specific types of mouse somatosensory neurons. Profiling of lincRNAs from single neurons located in dorsal root ganglia (DRG) identifies 200 lincRNAs localized in specific types or subtypes of somatosensory neurons. Among them, the conserved cell-type-specific lincRNA CLAP associates with pruritus and is abundantly expressed in somatostatin (SST)-positive neurons. CLAP knockdown reduces histamine-induced Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt; influx in cultured SST-positive neurons and in vivo reduces histamine-induced scratching in mice. In vivo knockdown of CLAP also decreases the expression of neuron-type-specific and itch-related genes in somatosensory neurons, and this partially depends on the RNA binding protein MSI2. Our data reveal a cell-type-specific landscape of lincRNAs and a function for CLAP in somatosensory neurons in sensory transmission.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alternative transcribed 3&#39; isoform of long non-coding RNA Malat1 inhibits mouse retinal oxidative stress</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36594014/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36594014/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Malat1&lt;/em&gt; is upregulated in replicative senescence (&lt;em&gt;in vitro&lt;/em&gt;) and brain aging (&lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A potential cryptic promoter drives 3′ &lt;em&gt;Malat1&lt;/em&gt; isoform expression in mouse brain &amp;amp; retina&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deletion of the 3′-&lt;em&gt;Malat1&lt;/em&gt; isoform region increases retinal oxidative stress in mice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;5’&amp;amp; 3′ &lt;em&gt;Malat1&lt;/em&gt; transcripts differentially regulates gene expression &lt;em&gt;in cis&lt;/em&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;em&gt;in trans&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The function of the cancer-associated lncRNA &lt;em&gt;Malat1&lt;/em&gt; during aging is as-of-yet uncharacterized. Here, we show that &lt;em&gt;Malat1&lt;/em&gt; interacts with Nucleophosmin (NPM) in young mouse brain, and with Lamin A/C, hnRNP C, and KAP1 with age. RNA-seq and RT-qPCR reveal a persistent expression of &lt;em&gt;Malat1_2&lt;/em&gt; (the 3&amp;rsquo;isoform of &lt;em&gt;Malat1&lt;/em&gt;) in &lt;em&gt;Malat1Δ1&lt;/em&gt; (5&amp;rsquo;-1.5 kb deletion) mouse retinas and brains at 1/4&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; level of the full-length &lt;em&gt;Malat1&lt;/em&gt;, while &lt;em&gt;Malat1_1&lt;/em&gt; (the 5&amp;rsquo;isoform) in &lt;em&gt;Malat1Δ2&lt;/em&gt; (deletion of 3&amp;rsquo;-conserved 5.7 kb) at a much lower level, suggesting an internal promoter driving the 3&amp;rsquo; isoform. The 1774 and 496 differentially expressed genes in &lt;em&gt;Malat1Δ2&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Malat1Δ1&lt;/em&gt; brains, respectively, suggest the 3&amp;rsquo; isoform regulates gene expression in trans and the 5&amp;rsquo; isoform in cis. Consistently, &lt;em&gt;Malat1Δ2&lt;/em&gt; mice show increased age-dependent retinal oxidative stress and corneal opacity, while &lt;em&gt;Malat1Δ1&lt;/em&gt; mice show no obvious phenotype. Collectively, this study reveals a physiological function of the lncRNA &lt;em&gt;Malat1&lt;/em&gt; 3&amp;rsquo;-isoform during the aging process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pan-cancer analyses reveal molecular and clinical characteristics of cuproptosis regulators</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/imt2.68/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/imt2.68/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therapeutics that discriminate between the genetic makeup of normal cells and tumour cells are valuable for treating and understanding cancer. Small molecules with oncogene-selective lethality may reveal novel functions of oncoproteins and enable the creation of more selective drugs. Here we describe the mechanism of action of the selective anti-tumour agent erastin, involving the RAS-RAF-MEK signalling pathway functioning in cell proliferation, differentiation and survival. Erastin exhibits greater lethality in human tumour cells harbouring mutations in the oncogenes HRAS, KRAS or BRAF. Using affinity purification and mass spectrometry, we discovered that erastin acts through mitochondrial voltage-dependent anion channels (VDACs)&amp;ndash;a novel target for anti-cancer drugs. We show that erastin treatment of cells harbouring oncogenic RAS causes the appearance of oxidative species and subsequent death through an oxidative, non-apoptotic mechanism. RNA-interference-mediated knockdown of VDAC2 or VDAC3 caused resistance to erastin, implicating these two VDAC isoforms in the mechanism of action of erastin. Moreover, using purified mitochondria expressing a single VDAC isoform, we found that erastin alters the permeability of the outer mitochondrial membrane. Finally, using a radiolabelled analogue and a filter-binding assay, we show that erastin binds directly to VDAC2. These results demonstrate that ligands to VDAC proteins can induce non-apoptotic cell death selectively in some tumour cells harbouring activating mutations in the RAS-RAF-MEK pathway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The N-Myc-responsive lncRNA MILIP promotes DNA double-strand break repair through non-homologous end joining</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36445966/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36445966/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Significance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here, we report that the lncRNA MILIP is transcriptionally regulated by N-Myc and functions to promote DNA double-strand break repair in neuroblastoma cells. MILIP is distinguished from other lncRNAs implicated in DNA repair through its scaffolding role in Ku complex formation, a requisite step to initiate the nonhomologous end-joining pathway. Our findings substantiate the long-postulated role of N-Myc in regulating DNA repair in neuroblastoma cells and reveal the functional importance of MILIP in cell survival, proliferation, and resistance to genotoxic stress, with practical implications of MILIP targeting, alone and in combination with DNA-damaging therapeutics, for neuroblastoma treatment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The protooncoprotein N-Myc, which is overexpressed in approximately 25% of neuroblastomas as the consequence of MYCN gene amplification, has long been postulated to regulate DNA double-strand break (DSB) repair in neuroblastoma cells, but experimental evidence of this function is presently scant. Here, we show that N-Myc transcriptionally activates the long noncoding RNA MILIP to promote nonhomologous end-joining (NHEJ) DNA repair through facilitating Ku70-Ku80 heterodimerization in neuroblastoma cells. High MILIP expression was associated with poor outcome and appeared as an independent prognostic factor in neuroblastoma patients. Knockdown of MILIP reduced neuroblastoma cell viability through the induction of apoptosis and inhibition of proliferation, retarded neuroblastoma xenograft growth, and sensitized neuroblastoma cells to DNA-damaging therapeutics. The effect of MILIP knockdown was associated with the accumulation of DNA DSBs in neuroblastoma cells largely due to decreased activity of the NHEJ DNA repair pathway. Mechanistical investigations revealed that binding of MILIP to Ku70 and Ku80 increased their heterodimerization, and this was required for MILIP-mediated promotion of NHEJ DNA repair. Disrupting the interaction between MILIP and Ku70 or Ku80 increased DNA DSBs and reduced cell viability with therapeutic potential revealed where targeting MILIP using Gapmers cooperated with the DNA-damaging drug cisplatin to inhibit neuroblastoma growth in vivo. Collectively, our findings identify MILIP as an N-Myc downstream effector critical for activation of the NHEJ DNA repair pathway in neuroblastoma cells, with practical implications of MILIP targeting, alone and in combination with DNA-damaging therapeutics, for neuroblastoma treatment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HIF1α-AS1 is a DNA:DNA:RNA triplex-forming lncRNA interacting with the HUSH complex</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36323673/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36323673/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DNA:DNA:RNA triplexes that are formed through Hoogsteen base-pairing of the RNA in the major groove of the DNA duplex have been observed in vitro, but the extent to which these interactions occur in cells and how they impact cellular functions remains elusive. Using a combination of bioinformatic techniques, RNA/DNA pulldown and biophysical studies, we set out to identify functionally important DNA:DNA:RNA triplex-forming long non-coding RNAs (lncRNA) in human endothelial cells. The lncRNA HIF1α-AS1 was retrieved as a top hit. Endogenous HIF1α-AS1 reduces the expression of numerous genes, including EPH Receptor A2 and Adrenomedullin through DNA:DNA:RNA triplex formation by acting as an adapter for the repressive human silencing hub complex (HUSH). Moreover, the oxygen-sensitive HIF1α-AS1 is down-regulated in pulmonary hypertension and loss-of-function approaches not only result in gene de-repression but also enhance angiogenic capacity. As exemplified here with HIF1α-AS1, DNA:DNA:RNA triplex formation is a functionally important mechanism of trans-acting gene expression control.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Translation and natural selection of micropeptides from long non-canonical RNAs</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36316320/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36316320/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Long noncoding RNAs (lncRNAs) are transcripts longer than 200 nucleotides but lacking canonical coding sequences. Apparently unable to produce peptides, lncRNA function seems to rely only on RNA expression, sequence and structure. Here, we exhaustively detect in-vivo translation of small open reading frames (small ORFs) within lncRNAs using Ribosomal profiling during &lt;em&gt;Drosophila melanogaster&lt;/em&gt; embryogenesis. We show that around 30% of lncRNAs contain small ORFs engaged by ribosomes, leading to regulated translation of 100 to 300 micropeptides. We identify lncRNA features that favour translation, such as cistronicity, Kozak sequences, and conservation. For the latter, we develop a bioinformatics pipeline to detect small ORF homologues, and reveal evidence of natural selection favouring the conservation of micropeptide sequence and function across evolution. Our results expand the repertoire of lncRNA biochemical functions, and suggest that lncRNAs give rise to novel coding genes throughout evolution. Since most lncRNAs contain small ORFs with as yet unknown translation potential, we propose to rename them &amp;ldquo;long non-canonical RNAs&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LncRNA H19 via miR-29a-3p is involved in lung inflammation and pulmonary fibrosis induced by neodymium oxide</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36326553/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36326553/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Exposure to Nd&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; causes an inflammatory reaction and fibrosis in lung tissue of mice.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nd&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; increases H19 and TNFRSF1A levels, decreases miR-29a-3p levels, and activates the NF-κB signaling pathway in RAW264.7 cells and mice.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;H19 via miR-29a-3p-regulated TNFRSF1A is involved in Nd&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;-induced lung inflammation and pulmonary fibrosis.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The study provide a tool for assessing lung injury risk of Nd&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; and other environmental factors that induce inflammatory response and pulmonary fibrosis-associated lncRNAs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The occupational and environmental health safety of rare earths has attracted considerable attention. In China, the rare earth neodymium oxide (Nd&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;) is extensively refined and utilized. However, the mechanisms of Nd&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;-induced lung injury are elusive. In the present study, we found that exposure of mice to Nd&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; caused an inflammatory reaction and fibrosis in lung tissues, which was in relation to the Nd&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;-induced higher levels of the lncRNA H19 (H19), tumor necrosis factor receptor 1 (TNFRSF1A), p-p65, and p-IKKβ and lower levels of miR-29a-3p. Further, in mouse monocyte macrophage leukemia cells (RAW264.7), Nd&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; induced an inflammatory reaction, increases of H19 and TNFRSF1A levels, decreases of miR-29a-3p levels, and activation of the nuclear factor (NF)-κB signaling pathway. Further, we established that miR-29a-3p regulates TNFRSF1A expression. Up-regulation of miR-29a-3p and down-regulation of H19 blocked the Nd&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;-induced secretion of TNF-α, MIP-1α, and IL-6; the increases of TNFRSF1A levels; and activation of the NF-κB signaling pathway in RAW264.7 cells. Further, in Nd&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;-treated RAW26.4 cells, H19 inhibited the expression of miR-29a-3p, which targets TNFRSF1A, and activated the NF-κB signaling pathway to enhance the expression of TNF-α, MIP-1α, and IL-6. Moreover, for mice, up-regulation of miR-29a-3p reversed lung tissue inflammation, pulmonary fibrosis, and activation of the NF-κB signaling pathway induced by Nd&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;. In sum, the present investigation shows that H19 via miR-29a-3p is involved in lung inflammation and pulmonary fibrosis induced by Nd&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;, which is a mechanism for the Nd&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;-induced lung inflammatory response and pulmonary fibrosis. This information is useful for development of a biomarker of Nd&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;-induced lung injury.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Immunosuppressive lncRNA LINC00624 promotes tumor progression and therapy resistance through ADAR1 stabilization</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36252997/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36252997/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Despite the success of HER2-targeted therapy in achieving prolonged survival in approximately 50% of treated individuals, treatment resistance is still an important challenge for HER2+ breast cancer (BC) patients. The influence of both adaptive and innate immune responses on the therapeutic outcomes of HER2+BC patients has been extensively demonstrated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; Long non-coding RNAs expressed in non-pathological complete response (pCR) HER2 positive BC were screened and validated by RNA-seq. Survival analysis were made by Kaplan-Meier method. Cell death assay and proliferation assay were performed to confirm the phenotype of LINC00624. RT-qPCR and western blot were used to assay the IFN response. Xenograft mouse model were used for in vivo confirmation of anti-neu treatment resistance. RNA pull-down and immunoblot were used to confirm the interaction of ADAR1 and LINC00624. ADAR1 recombinant protein were purified from baculovirus expression system. B16-OVA cells were used to study antigen presentation both in vitro and in vivo. Flow cytometry was used to determine the tumor infiltrated immune cells of xenograft model. Antisense oligonucleotides (ASOs) were used for in vivo treatment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; In this study, we found that LINC00624 blocked the antitumor effect of HER2- targeted therapy both in vitro and in vivo by inhibiting type I interferon (IFN) pathway activation. The double-stranded RNA-like structure of LINC00624 can bind and be edited by the adenosine (A) to inosine (I) RNA-editing enzyme adenosine deaminase RNA specific 1 (ADAR1), and this editing has been shown to release the growth inhibition and attenuate the innate immune response caused by the IFN response. Notably, LINC00624 promoted the stabilization of ADAR1 by inhibiting its ubiquitination-induced degradation triggered by β-TrCP. In contrast, LINC00624 inhibited major histocompatibility complex (MHC) class I antigen presentation and limited CD8+T cell infiltration in the cancer microenvironment, resulting in immune checkpoint blockade inhibition and anti-HER2 treatment resistance mediated through ADAR1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; In summary, these results suggest that LINC00624 is a cancer immunosuppressive lncRNA and targeting LINC00624 through ASOs in tumors expressing high levels of LINC00624 has great therapeutic potential in future clinical applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DeepLncPro: an interpretable convolutional neural network model for identifying long non-coding RNA promoters</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36209437/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36209437/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Long non-coding RNA (lncRNA) plays important roles in a series of biological processes. The transcription of lncRNA is regulated by its promoter. Hence, accurate identification of lncRNA promoter will be helpful to understand its regulatory mechanisms. Since experimental techniques remain time consuming for gnome-wide promoter identification, developing computational tools to identify promoters are necessary. However, only few computational methods have been proposed for lncRNA promoter prediction and their performances still have room to be improved. In the present work, a convolutional neural network based model, called &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/zhangtian-yang/DeepLncPro&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;DeepLncPro&lt;/a&gt;, was proposed to identify lncRNA promoters in human and mouse. Comparative results demonstrated that &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/zhangtian-yang/DeepLncPro&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;DeepLncPro&lt;/a&gt; was superior to both state-of-the-art machine learning methods and existing models for identifying lncRNA promoters. Furthermore, &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/zhangtian-yang/DeepLncPro&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;DeepLncPro&lt;/a&gt; has the ability to extract and analyze transcription factor binding motifs from lncRNAs, which made it become an interpretable model. These results indicate that the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/zhangtian-yang/DeepLncPro&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;DeepLncPro&lt;/a&gt; can server as a powerful tool for identifying lncRNA promoters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Targeting non-coding RNA H19: A potential therapeutic approach in pulmonary diseases</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/36188624/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/36188624/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Non-coding RNA is still one of the most popular fields in biology research. In recent years, people paid more attention to the roles of H19 in lung diseases, which expressed abnormally in various pathological process. Therefore, this review focus on the regulatory role of H19 in asthma, pulmonary arterial hypertension (PAH), idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis (IPF), lung injury, pneumonia, lung cancer, etc. And the potential therapeutic agents and molecular treatments of H19 are collected. The aim is to demonstrate its underlying mechanism in pulmonary diseases and to guide the basic research targeting H19 into clinical drug translation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Activation of long non-coding RNA NEAT1 leads to survival advantage of multiple myeloma cells by supporting a positive regulatory loop with DNA repair proteins</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36073514/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36073514/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Long non-coding RNA NEAT1 is the core structural component of the nuclear paraspeckle (PS) organelles and it has been found to be deregulated in multiple myeloma (MM) patients. Experimental evidence indicated that NEAT1 silencing negatively impacts proliferation and viability of MM cells, both in vitro and in vivo, suggesting a role in DNA damage repair (DDR). In order to elucidate the biological and molecular relevance of NEAT1 upregulation in MM disease we exploited the CRISPR/Cas9 synergistic activation mediator genome editing system to engineer the AMO-1 MM cell line and generate two clones that para-physiologically transactivate NEAT1 at different levels. NEAT1 overexpression is associated with oncogenic and prosurvival advantages in MM cells exposed to nutrient starvation or a hypoxic microenvironment, which are stressful conditions often associated with more aggressive disease phases. Furthermore, we highlighted the NEAT1 involvement in virtually all DDR processes through, at least, two different mechanisms. On one side NEAT1 positively regulates the posttranslational stabilization of essential PS proteins, which are involved in almost all DDR systems, thus increasing their availability within cells. On the other hand, NEAT1 plays a crucial role as a major regulator of a molecular axis that includes ATM and the catalytic subunit of DNA-PK kinase proteins, and their direct targets pRPA32 and pCHK2. Overall, we provided novel important insightsthe role of NEAT1 in supporting MM cells adaptation to stressful conditions by improving the maintenance of DNA integrity. Taken together, our results suggest that NEAT1, and probably PS organelles, could represent a potential therapeutic target for MM treatment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Long noncoding RNA LINC00239 inhibits ferroptosis in colorectal cancer by binding to Keap1 to stabilize Nrf2</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36038548/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36038548/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ferroptosis, a novel regulated cell death induced by iron-dependent lipid peroxidation, plays an important role in tumor development and drug resistance. Long noncoding RNAs (lncRNAs) are associated with various types of cancer. However, the precise roles of many lncRNAs in tumorigenesis remain elusive. Here we explored the transcriptomic profiles of lncRNAs in primary CRC tissues and corresponding paired adjacent non-tumor tissues by RNA-seq and found that LINC00239 was significantly overexpressed in colorectal cancer tissues. Abnormally high expression of LINC00239 predicts poorer survival and prognosis in colorectal cancer patients. Concurrently, we elucidated the role of LINC00239 as a tumor-promoting factor in CRC through in vitro functional studies and in vivo tumor xenograft models. Importantly, overexpression of LINC00239 decreased the anti-tumor activity of erastin and RSL3 by inhibiting ferroptosis. Collectively, these data suggest that LINC00239 plays a novel and indispensable role in ferroptosis by nucleotides 1-315 of LINC00239 to interact with the Kelch domain (Nrf2-binding site) of Keap1, inhibiting Nrf2 ubiquitination and increasing Nrf2 protein stability. Considering the recurrence and chemoresistance constitute the leading cause of death in colorectal cancer (CRC), ferroptosis induction may be a promising therapeutic strategy for CRC patients with low LINC00239 expression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Long noncoding RNA CHROMR regulates antiviral immunity in humans</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36001732/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36001732/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Significance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An effective innate immune response to virus infection requires the induction of type I interferons and up-regulation of hundreds of interferon-stimulated genes (ISGs) that instruct antiviral functions and immune regulation. Deciphering the regulatory mechanisms that direct expression of the ISG network is critical for understanding the fundamental organization of the innate immune response and the development of antiviral therapies. We define a regulatory role for the primate-specific long noncoding RNA &lt;em&gt;CHROMR&lt;/em&gt; in coordinating ISG transcription. &lt;em&gt;CHROMR&lt;/em&gt; sequesters the interferon regulatory factor (IRF)-2/IRF2BP2 complex that restrains ISG transcription and thus is required to restrict influenza virus replication. These data identify a novel regulator of the antiviral gene program in humans and provide insights into the multilayered regulatory network that controls the innate immune response.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Long noncoding RNAs (lncRNAs) have emerged as critical regulators of gene expression, yet their contribution to immune regulation in humans remains poorly understood. Here, we report that the primate-specific lncRNA &lt;em&gt;CHROMR&lt;/em&gt; is induced by influenza A virus and SARS-CoV-2 infection and coordinates the expression of interferon-stimulated genes (ISGs) that execute antiviral responses. &lt;em&gt;CHROMR&lt;/em&gt; depletion in human macrophages reduces histone acetylation at regulatory regions of ISG loci and attenuates ISG expression in response to microbial stimuli. Mechanistically, we show that &lt;em&gt;CHROMR&lt;/em&gt; sequesters the interferon regulatory factor (IRF)-2-dependent transcriptional corepressor IRF2BP2, thereby licensing IRF-dependent signaling and transcription of the ISG network. Consequently, &lt;em&gt;CHROMR&lt;/em&gt; expression is essential to restrict viral infection of macrophages. Our findings identify &lt;em&gt;CHROMR&lt;/em&gt; as a key arbitrator of antiviral innate immune signaling in humans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hypoxia-induced lncRNA STEAP3-AS1 activates Wnt/β-catenin signaling to promote colorectal cancer progression by preventing m6A-mediated degradation of STEAP3 mRNA</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35986274/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35986274/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Hypoxia, a typical hallmark of solid tumors, exhibits an essential role in the progression of colorectal cancer (CRC), in which the dysregulation of long non-coding RNAs (lncRNAs) is frequently observed. However, the underlying mechanisms are not clearly defined.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; The TCGA database was analyzed to identify differential lncRNA expression involved in hypoxia-induced CRC progression. qRT-PCR was conducted to validate the upregulation of lncRNA &lt;em&gt;STEAP3-AS1&lt;/em&gt; in CRC cell lines and tumor-bearing mouse and zebrafish models under hypoxia. ChIP-qRT-PCR was used to detect the transcriptional activation of STEAP3-AS1 mediated by HIF-1α. RNA-seq, fluorescent in situ hybridization, RNA pulldown, RNA immunoprecipitation, co-immunoprecipitation, immunofluorescence and immunoblot experiments were used to ascertain the involved mechanisms. Functional assays were performed in both in vitro and in vivo models to investigate the regulatory role of &lt;em&gt;STEAP3-AS1&lt;/em&gt;/STEAP3/Wnt/β-catenin axis in CRC proliferation and metastasis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; Here, we identified a hypoxia-induced antisense lncRNA &lt;em&gt;STEAP3-AS1&lt;/em&gt; that was highly expressed in clinical CRC tissues and positively correlated with poor prognosis of CRC patients. Upregulation of lncRNA &lt;em&gt;STEAP3-AS1&lt;/em&gt;, which was induced by HIF-1α-mediated transcriptional activation, facilitated the proliferation and metastasis of CRC cells both in vitro and in vivo. Mechanistically, &lt;em&gt;STEAP3-AS1&lt;/em&gt; interacted competitively with the YTH domain-containing family protein 2 (YTHDF2), a N&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;-methyladenosine (m&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;A) reader, leading to the disassociation of YTHDF2 with &lt;em&gt;STEAP3&lt;/em&gt; mRNA. This effect protected &lt;em&gt;STEAP3&lt;/em&gt; mRNA from m6A-mediated degradation, enabling the high expression of STEAP3 protein and subsequent production of cellular ferrous iron (Fe&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt;). Increased Fe&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt; levels elevated Ser 9 phosphorylation of glycogen synthase kinase 3 beta (GSK3β) and inhibited its kinase activity, thus releasing β-catenin for nuclear translocation and subsequent activation of Wnt signaling to support CRC progression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; Taken together, our study highlights the mechanisms of lncRNA &lt;em&gt;STEAP3-AS1&lt;/em&gt; in facilitating CRC progression involving the &lt;em&gt;STEAP3-AS1&lt;/em&gt;/STEAP3/Wnt/β-catenin axis, which may provide novel diagnostic biomarkers or therapeutic targets to benefit CRC treatment. Hypoxia-induced HIF-1α transcriptionally upregulates the expression of lncRNA STEAP3-AS1, which interacts competitively with YTHDF2, thus upregulating mRNA stability of STEAP3 and consequent STEAP3 protein expression. The enhanced STEAP3 expression results in production of cellular ferrous iron (Fe&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt;), which induces the Ser 9 phosphorylation and inactivation of GSK3β, releasing β-catenin for nuclear translocation and contributing to subsequent activation of Wnt signaling to promote CRC progression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A novel long noncoding RNA SP100-AS1 induces radioresistance of colorectal cancer via sponging miR-622 and stabilizing ATG3</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35978049/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35978049/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although radiotherapy is an essential modality in the treatment of colorectal cancer (CRC), the incidence of radioresistance remains high clinically. Long noncoding RNAs (lncRNAs) reportedly play critical roles in CRC radioresistance by regulating genes or proteins at the transcriptional or post-translational levels. This study aimed to identify novel lncRNAs involved in radioresistance. We found that SP100-AS1 (lncRNA targeting antisense sequence of SP100 gene) was upregulated in radioresistant CRC patient tissues using RNA-seq analysis. Importantly, knockdown of SP100-AS1 significantly reduced radioresistance, cell proliferation, and tumor formation in vitro and in vivo. Mechanistically, mass spectrometry and bioinformatics analyses were used to identify the interacting proteins and microRNAs of SP100-AS1, respectively. Moreover, SP100-AS1 was found to interact with and stabilize ATG3 protein through the ubiquitination-dependent proteasome pathway. In addition, it could serve as a sponge for miR-622, which targeted ATG3 mRNA and affected autophagic activity. Thus, lncRNA SP100-AS1 could act as a radioresistance factor in CRC patients via RNA sponging and protein stabilizing mechanisms. In conclusion, the present study indicates that SP100-AS1/miR-622/ATG3 axis contributes to radioresistance and autophagic activity in CRC patients, suggesting it has huge prospects as a therapeutic target for improving CRC response to radiation therapy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>lncRNA CYTOR promotes aberrant glycolysis and mitochondrial respiration via HNRNPC-mediated ZEB1 stabilization in oral squamous cell carcinoma</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35963855/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35963855/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oral squamous cell carcinoma (OSCC), the most common malignancy of the oral and maxillofacial region, severely affects human health. However, current treatments for OSCC commonly show only a ~60% 5-year survival rate of patients with distant metastases, indicating an urgent need for targeted treatments for patients with advanced metastases. Here, we report a survival-related long non-coding RNA, CYTOR, which is highly expressed in the lesions of oral cancer patients. We found that CYTOR can promote both migration and invasion in oral cancer cells as well as the epithelial-mesenchymal transition (EMT). RNA-sequencing of CYTOR-knockdown oral cancer cells revealed that CYTOR can regulate mitochondrial respiration and RNA splicing. Mechanistically, we found that nuclear-localized CYTOR interacts with HNRNPC, resulting in stabilization of ZEB1 mRNAs by inhibiting the nondegradative ubiquitination of HNRNPC. By synthesizing CYTOR-targeting small interfering RNAs (siRNAs) encapsulated in Nanoscale Metal Organic Frameworks (NMOFs), we demonstrate the targeted suppression of CYTOR to inhibit invasion and metastasis of oral cancer cells in a nude mouse model. Cumulatively, this study reveals the potential role of the CYTOR-HNRNPC-ZEB1 axis in regulating mitochondrial metabolism and glycolysis of oral cancer cells, and illustrates the effective use of lncRNA targeting in anti-metastatic cancer therapies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LncRNA MNX1-AS1 sustains inactivation of Hippo pathway through a positive feedback loop with USP16/IGF2BP3 axis in gallbladder cancer</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35953000/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35953000/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MNX1-AS1 expression is upregulated in GBC and predicts poor prognosis.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Overexpression of MNX1-AS1 facilitates the proliferation and metastasis of GBC cells in vitro and in vivo.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MNX1-AS1 acts as a scaffold for recruiting USP16 to stabilize IGF2BP3.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MNX1-AS1/IGF2BP3/Hippo pathway positive feedback loop contributes to GBC progression.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The long non-coding RNAs (lncRNAs) have been implicated in multiple human cancers, which may offer great potential as putative targets for cancer diagnosis and treatment. However, the roles of most lncRNAs in gallbladder cancer (GBC) remain poorly understood. The objective of this research involves investigating the clinical implications and underlying mechanism of lncRNA motor neuron and pancreas homeobo×1 antisense RNA 1 (MNX1-AS1) in GBC. This study shows that MNX1-AS1 expression is elevated in the tissues of GBC patients, and is strongly associated with reduced patient survival. Functionally, MNX1-AS1 significantly stimulates the proliferation and metastasis of GBC cells in vitro and in vivo. Mechanistically, MNX1-AS1 is transcriptionally activated by TEA domain family member 4 (TEAD4), and suppresses insulin-like growing factor 2 mRNA-binding protein 3 (IGF2BP3) degradation by recruiting ubiquitin specific peptidase 16 (USP16). Furthermore, MNX1-AS1/IGF2BP3 axis inhibits the Hippo signaling pathway and subsequently activates TEAD4, thereby forming a positive feedback loop. According to our results, MNX1-AS1 facilitates tumorigenesis, progression and metastasis of GBC through a MNX1-AS1/IGF2BP3/Hippo pathway positive feedback loop, which could be both diagnostically and therapeutically helpful in GBC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In Vivo Genome-Wide CRISPR Activation Screening Identifies Functionally Important Long Noncoding RNAs in Hepatocellular Carcinoma</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35944892/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35944892/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background &amp;amp; aims:&lt;/em&gt; Long noncoding RNAs (lncRNAs) are found to have profound impacts on diverse cellular processes. Although high-throughput sequencing studies have shown the differential lncRNA expression profiles between hepatocellular carcinoma (HCC) and nontumor livers, the functional impacts of lncRNAs on HCC development await further investigation. Herein, we sought to address the functional roles of lncRNAs in HCC pathogenesis by in vivo functional screening.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; We performed genome-wide clustered regularly interspaced short palindromic repeats (CRISPR)/dead CRISPR-associated protein 9 (dCas9) lncRNA activation screening in HCC xenografts. We characterized the clinical relevance of positively selected lncRNAs using transcriptomic data sets. We used CRISPR-based gene activation and knockdown approaches to show the functional roles of positively selected lncRNAs including Cancer Susceptibility 11 (CASC11) in HCC. RNA sequencing and chromatin isolation by RNA purification sequencing were used to investigate the molecular mechanisms of CASC11 in HCC progression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; The in vivo functional screening identified 1603 positively selected lncRNAs, 538 of which were overexpressed in HCC patients. Systematic transcriptomic data analysis and clinical investigation showed that patients with high expression of these lncRNA candidates correlated with aggressive tumor behaviors. Overexpression of these lncRNAs aggravated HCC cell growth. Detailed characterization of a lncRNA candidate, CASC11, showed its pivotal role in cell proliferation and tumor growth. Mechanistically, chromatin isolation by RNA purification sequencing showed that CASC11 was bound to the CASC11/MYC proto-oncogene shared promoter region on chromosome 8q24. CASC11 modulated the transcriptional activity of MYC in a cis-regulatory manner, which affected the expression of MYC downstream target genes, consequently promoting G1/S progression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; Our study showed the power of in vivo CRISPR screening, which comprehensively investigated the functionality of lncRNAs in HCC progression, providing a rationale for targeting these lncRNAs clinically.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Identification of programmed cell death-related gene signature and associated regulatory axis in cerebral ischemia/reperfusion injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35991562/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35991562/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Numerous studies have suggested that programmed cell death (PCD) pathways play vital roles in cerebral ischemia/reperfusion (I/R) injury. However, the specific mechanisms underlying cell death during cerebral I/R injury have yet to be completely clarified. There is thus a need to identify the PCD-related gene signatures and the associated regulatory axes in cerebral I/R injury, which should provide novel therapeutic targets against cerebral I/R injury.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; We analyzed transcriptome signatures of brain tissue samples from mice subjected to middle cerebral artery occlusion/reperfusion (MCAO/R) and matched controls, and identified differentially expressed genes related to the three types of PCD(apoptosis, pyroptosis, and necroptosis). We next performed functional enrichment analysis and constructed PCD-related competing endogenous RNA (ceRNA) regulatory networks. We also conducted hub gene analysis to identify hub nodes and key regulatory axes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; Fifteen PCD-related genes were identified. Functional enrichment analysis showed that they were particularly associated with corresponding PCD-related biological processes, inflammatory response, and reactive oxygen species metabolic processes. The apoptosis-related ceRNA regulatory network was constructed, which included 24 long noncoding RNAs (lncRNAs), 41 microRNAs (miRNAs), and 4 messenger RNAs (mRNAs); the necroptosis-related ceRNA regulatory network included 16 lncRNAs, 20 miRNAs, and 6 mRNAs; and the pyroptosis-related ceRNA regulatory network included 15 lncRNAs, 18 miRNAs, and 6 mRNAs. Hub gene analysis identified hub nodes in each PCD-related ceRNA regulatory network and seven key regulatory axes in total, namely, lncRNA Malat1/miR-181a-5p/Mapt, lncRNA Malat1/miR-181b-5p/Mapt, lncRNA Neat1/miR-181a-5p/Mapt, and lncRNA Neat1/miR-181b-5p/Mapt for the apoptosis-related ceRNA regulatory network; lncRNA Neat1/miR-181a-5p/Tnf for the necroptosis-related ceRNA regulatory network; lncRNA Malat1/miR-181c-5p/Tnf for the pyroptosis-related ceRNA regulatory network; and lncRNAMalat1/miR-181a-5p for both necroptosis-related and pyroptosis-related ceRNA regulatory networks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/em&gt; The results of this study supported the hypothesis that these PCD pathways (apoptosis, necroptosis, pyroptosis, and PANoptosis) and crosstalk among them might be involved in ischemic stroke and that the key nodes and regulatory axes identified in this study might play vital roles in regulating the above processes. This may offer new insights into the potential mechanisms underlying cell death during cerebral I/R injury and provide new therapeutic targets for neuroprotection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Long non‑coding RNA CASC11 interacts with YBX1 to promote prostate cancer progression by suppressing the p53 pathway</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35904175/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35904175/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prostate cancer (PCa) is one of the principal causes of cancer‑related death worldwide. The roles and mechanisms of long non‑coding RNA (lncRNA) involved in the development of PCa remain incompletely understood. The present study aimed to investigate the role and mechanism of lncRNA in PCa tumorigenesis. In the present study, lncRNA cancer susceptibility candidate 11 (CASC11) was revealed to be a crucial regulator of PCa progression. The expression profiles of CASC11 in PCa were identified through analysis of The Cancer Genome Atlas and Gene Expression Omnibus datasets, and validated in human PCa specimens and cell lines. Gain‑ and loss‑of‑function assays were utilized to explore the biological role of CASC11 in PCa initiation and progression. RNA‑sequencing, RNA pull‑down and RNA immunoprecipitation analyses were used to explore potential mechanisms with which CASC11 may be associated. Rescue experiments were further conducted to confirm this association. The present results revealed that CASC11 was dominantly distributed in the nuclei of PCa cells, and was highly expressed in PCa tissues and cells. Overexpression of CASC11 was markedly associated with increased tumor proliferation and migratory ability. Functionally, decreased proliferation and migration, as well as inhibited xenograft tumor growth, were observed in CASC11‑silenced PCa cells, whereas the opposite effects were detected in CASC11‑overexpressing cells. Mechanistically, CASC11 promoted progression of the cell cycle and competitively interacted with Y‑box binding protein 1 (YBX1) to block the p53 pathway. Given this, poly (β‑amino ester) (PBAE)/small interfering RNA‑CASC11 (si‑CASC11) nanoparticles were applied to inhibit CASC11 expression and enhance the antitumor effect in vivo. The results revealed that PBAE/si‑CASC11 nanoparticles augmented the antitumor efficacy of CASC11 knockdown in vivo. In conclusion, the present study suggested that CASC11 may regulate PCa progression and elucidated a novel CASC11/YBX1/p53 signaling axis, providing a potential lncRNA‑directed therapeutic strategy particularly for the treatment of patients with PCa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LncRNA RMRP Contributes to the Development and Progression of Spinal Cord Injury by Regulating miR-766-5p/FAM83A Axis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35902548/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35902548/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spinal cord injury (SCI) is known as a central nervous system disorder. Previous studies suggested that long-non-coding RNA RMRP (LncRNA RMRP) was abnormally expressed in SCI, but the potential underlying mechanism remains to be further explored. To explore the regulatory roles of LncRNA RMRP/miR-766-5p/FAM83A axis in SCI. Spinal T9 hemisection was performed on healthy adult male Sprague Dawley (SD) rats to establish the SCI rat models. The expressions of LncRNA RMRP in spinal cord of rats in different groups were examined by RT-qPCR. Moreover, AGE1.HN and PC12 cells were treated with hypoxic condition, and expression of LncRNA RMRP was examined by RT-qPCR methods. Furthermore, hypoxic PC12 cells were transfected with LncRNA RMRP OE, and the cell viability, proliferation, and apoptosis were examined. Next, the direct targeting relationship between LncRNA RMRP and miR-766-5p, as well as miR-766-5p and FAM83A, was confirmed by dual-luciferase reporter and RNA pull-down assays. Finally, the effects of LncRNA RMRP/miR-766-5p/FAM83A axis on cell viability, proliferation, and apoptosis were examined. LncRNA RMRP was downregulated in SCI rats and over-expression of LncRNA RMRP alleviated the SCI condition. LncRNA RMRP over-expression increased the viability and proliferation, and inhibited the apoptosis of hypoxic PC12 cells in vitro. miR-766-5p was confirmed as a target of LncRNA RMRP, and FAM83A was confirmed as a target of miR-766-5p. LncRNA RMRP could regulate the proliferation and apoptosis of hypoxic PC12 cells via regulating miR-766-5p/FAM83A axis in vitro. LncRNA RMRP may contribute to the pathogenesis of SCI via regulating miR-766-5p/FAM83A axis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HOTAIR interacts with PRC2 complex regulating the regional preadipocyte transcriptome and human fat distribution</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35905723/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35905723/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;HOTAIR&lt;/em&gt; is expressed specifically in the gluteal adipose tissue depot&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;In vitro&lt;/em&gt; impairment of &lt;em&gt;HOTAIR&lt;/em&gt; prevents gluteal adipocyte development&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Minor allele carriers of a &lt;em&gt;HOTAIR&lt;/em&gt;-lowering eQTL have reduced lower-body fat mass&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mechanisms governing regional human adipose tissue (AT) development remain undefined. Here, we show that the long non-coding RNA &lt;em&gt;HOTAIR&lt;/em&gt; (HOX transcript antisense RNA) is exclusively expressed in gluteofemoral AT, where it is essential for adipocyte development. We find that &lt;em&gt;HOTAIR&lt;/em&gt; interacts with polycomb repressive complex 2 (PRC2) and we identify core &lt;em&gt;HOTAIR&lt;/em&gt;-PRC2 target genes involved in adipocyte lineage determination. Repression of target genes coincides with PRC2 promoter occupancy and H3K27 trimethylation. &lt;em&gt;HOTAIR&lt;/em&gt; is also involved in modifying the gluteal adipocyte transcriptome through alternative splicing. Gluteal-specific expression of &lt;em&gt;HOTAIR&lt;/em&gt; is maintained by defined regions of open chromatin across the &lt;em&gt;HOTAIR&lt;/em&gt; promoter. &lt;em&gt;HOTAIR&lt;/em&gt; expression levels can be modified by hormonal (estrogen, glucocorticoids) and genetic variation (rs1443512 is a &lt;em&gt;HOTAIR&lt;/em&gt; eQTL associated with reduced gynoid fat mass). These data identify &lt;em&gt;HOTAIR&lt;/em&gt; as a dynamic regulator of the gluteal adipocyte transcriptome and epigenome with functional importance for human regional AT development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enterobacterial LPS-inducible LINC00152 is regulated by histone lactylation and promotes cancer cells invasion and migration</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35959377/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35959377/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gut microbes participate in pathogenesis by interacting with the host genome through epigenetic mechanisms, such as long non-coding RNAs. However, the mechanisms by which the microbiota induce expression alteration of long non-coding RNAs remains unclear. Here, we quantified the transcriptome alteration of human colon cell lines after being infected by a common enteric pathogen &lt;em&gt;Salmonella typhimurium SL1344&lt;/em&gt;. We observed a widespread lncRNAs expression alteration. Among them, the elevated expression of LINC00152 was verified and proved to be induced by enteric bacteria-derived lipopolysaccharide (LPS). The inducible LINC00152 were found to inhibit Salmonella invasion and inflammation response. LINC00152 was overexpressed in tumors of the clinical CRC samples compared with adjacent normal tissues. Accordingly, we also demonstrated that overexpression of LINC00152 promoted the migration and invasion of colorectal cancer cells. Consistently, we observed an increased abundance of gram-negative bacteria and LPS in tumors tissue. Taken together, the above data implicated that enriched gram-negative bacteria in tumor tissue might promote tumor growth through modulating the expression of LINC00152. Furthermore, we demonstrated that LPS upregulated the expression of LINC00152 by introducing histone lactylation on its promoter and decreasing the binding efficiency of the repressor, YY1, to it. Our results provide new insights into how enterobacteria affect host epigenetics in human disease.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Long non-coding RNA (lncRNA): A potential therapeutic target in acute lung injury</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/35873025/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/35873025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acute Lung Injury (ALI) and its severe form Acute Respiratory Distress Syndrome (ARDS) are the major cause of ICU death worldwide. ALI/ARDS is characterized by severe hypoxemia and inflammation that leads to poor lung compliance. Despite many advances in understanding and management, ALI/ARDS is still causing significant morbidity and mortality. Long non-coding RNA (lncRNA) is a fast-growing topic in lung inflammation and injury. lncRNA is a class of non-coding RNA having a length of more than 200 nucleotides. It has been a center of research for understanding the pathophysiology of various diseases in the past few years. Multiple studies have shown that lncRNAs are abundant in acute lung injury/injuries in mouse models and cell lines. By targeting these long non-coding RNAs, many investigators have demonstrated the alleviation of ALI in various mouse models. Therefore, lncRNAs show great promise as a therapeutic target in ALI. This review provides the current state of knowledge about the relationship between lncRNAs in various biological processes in acute lung injury and its use as a potential therapeutic target.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docetaxel resistance-derived LINC01085 contributes to the immunotherapy of hormone-independent prostate cancer by activating the STING/MAVS signaling pathway</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35868534/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35868534/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;LINC01085&lt;/em&gt; is deleted in hormone-independent prostate cancer (HIPC) which can predict better outcomes of HIPC patients.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;LINC01085 acts as a tumor suppressor in the tumourigenicity and metastasis of HIPC.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;LINC01085 exerts its functions by both interacting with TBK1 and GSK3β, accelerated TBK1 phosphorylation at the Ser-172 site, in HIPC.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;LINC01085 combined with PARP inhibitor and anti-PD-L1 treatment may be pivotal in the treatment of HIPC patients.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acquired docetaxel (doc) resistance, one of the major reasons for unfavorable prognosis in patients with aggressive hormone-independent prostate cancer (HIPC), is a major obstacle for patient treatment. Dysregulation of long non-coding RNAs promotes or suppresses chemoresistance in multiple cancers; however, the specific molecular mechanisms underlying HIPC remain unknown. In this study, we found that the LINC01085, as a tumor-suppressor, which showed significant clinically relevant in HIPC patients with doc-resistance. Mechanistically, in docetaxel-sensitive cells, LINC01085 could specifically bind to both TANK-binding kinase 1 (TBK1) and glycogen synthase kinase 3β (GSK3β), and higher LINC01085 RNA levels could inhibit TBK1 dimerization. Whereas, in doc-resistant cells, lower LINC01085 RNA level lost the strong binding with both, meanwhile, the interaction between TBK1 and GSK3β enhanced which accelerated TBK1 phosphorylation at the Ser-172 site, resulting in decreased expression levels of PD-L1 and NF-κB as well as the secretion of type I/III interferons. Thus, Overexpression of LINC01085 combined with immune checkpoint blockade is an effective strategy for the treatment of HIPC patients.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Long non-coding RNA EVADR induced by Fusobacterium nucleatum infection promotes colorectal cancer metastasis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35858553/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35858553/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highli&lt;/strong&gt;ghts&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;F. nucleatum&lt;/em&gt; infection is enriched in CRC tissues with metastasis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;F. nucleatum&lt;/em&gt; promotes CRC cell metastasis to the liver and lung in mouse models&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;EVADR induced by &lt;em&gt;F. nucleatum&lt;/em&gt; increases CRC metastasis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;EVADR interacts with YBX1 to enhance the translation of EMT-related factors&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both &lt;em&gt;Fusobacterium nucleatum&lt;/em&gt; (&lt;em&gt;F. nucleatum&lt;/em&gt;) and long non-coding RNA (lncRNA) EVADR are associated with colorectal cancer (CRC), but their relationship with CRC metastasis and the mechanisms by which EVADR promotes CRC metastasis are poorly understood. Here, we report that &lt;em&gt;F. nucleatum&lt;/em&gt; promotes colorectal cancer cell metastasis to the liver and lung and that it can be detected in CRC-metastasis colonization in mouse models. Furthermore, &lt;em&gt;F. nucleatum&lt;/em&gt; upregulates the expression of EVADR, which can increase the metastatic ability of CRC cells in vivo and in vitro. Mechanistically, elevated EVADR serves as a modular scaffold for the Y-box binding protein 1 (YBX1) to directly enhance the translation of epithelial-mesenchymal transition (EMT)-related factors, such as Snail, Slug, and Zeb1. These findings suggest that EVADR induced by &lt;em&gt;F. nucleatum&lt;/em&gt; promotes colorectal cancer metastasis through YBX1-dependent translation. The EVADR-YBX1 axis may be useful for the prevention and treatment of patients with &lt;em&gt;F. nucleatum&lt;/em&gt;-associated CRC metastas&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exosomal lncRNA TUG1 derived from human urine-derived stem cells attenuates renal ischemia/reperfusion injury by interacting with SRSF1 to regulate ASCL4-mediated ferroptosis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35841017/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35841017/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;LncRNA TUG1 carried by USC-Exo regulates cell ferroptosis.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;LncRNA TUG1 regulates the stability of ACSL4 mRNA by interacting with SRSF1.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;LncRNA TUG1 alleviates IRI-induced AKI by suppressing ACSL4-mediated ferroptosis.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Human urine-derived stem cells (USCs)-derived exosomes (USC-Exo) could improve kidney ischemia/reperfusion injury (IRI), while the underlying mechanisms of this protective effect remain unclear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; Human USCs and USC-Exo were isolated and verified by morphology and specific biomarkers. The effects of USC-Exo on ferroptosis and kidney injury were detected in the IRI-induced acute kidney injury (AKI) model in C57BL/6 mice. The effects of USC-Exo on ferroptosis and lncRNA taurine-upregulated gene 1 (TUG1) were detected in hypoxia/reoxygenation (H/R)-treated human proximal tubular epithelial cells (HK-2). The interaction of SRSF1 and TUG1, ACSL4 was checked via RNA pull-down/RIP and RNA stability assays. The effects of LncRNA TUG1 on SRSF1/ACSL4-mediated ferroptosis were verified in H/R-treated HK-2 cells and the IRI-induced AKI mouse models.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; USC-Exo treatment improved kidney injury and ameliorated ferroptosis in IRI-induced AKI mouse models. USC-Exo were rich in lncRNA TUG1, which suppressed ferroptosis in HK-2 cells exposed to H/R. Mechanistically, lncRNA TUG1 regulates the stability of ACSL4 mRNA by interacting with RNA-binding protein SRSF1. In addition, SRSF1 upregulation or ACSL4 downregulation partially reversed the protective effect of lncRNA TUG1 on ferroptosis in H/R-treated HK-2 cells. Further, ACSL4 upregulation partially reversed TUG1&amp;rsquo;s repression on kidney injury and ferroptosis in IRI-induced AKI mice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/em&gt; Collectively, lncRNA TUG1 carried by USC-Exo regulated ASCL4-mediated ferroptosis by interacting with SRSF1 and then protected IRI-induced AKI. Potentially, USC-Exo rich in lncRNA TUG1 can serve as a promising therapeutic method for IRI-AKI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Long Non-Coding Antisense RNA JHDM1D-AS1 Regulates Inflammatory Responses in Human Monocytes</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35903199/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35903199/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Monocytes are key players in innate immunity, with their ability to regulate inflammatory responses and combat invading pathogens. There is a growing body of evidence indicating that long non-coding RNA (lncRNA) participate in various cellular biological processes, including the innate immune response. The immunoregulatory properties of numerous lncRNAs discovered in monocytes remain largely unexplored. Here, by RNA sequencing, we identified a lncRNA JHDM1D-AS1, which was upregulated in blood monocytes obtained from patients with sepsis relative to healthy controls. &lt;em&gt;JHDM1D-AS1&lt;/em&gt; expression was induced in primary human monocytes exposed to Toll-like receptor ligands, such as lipopolysaccharide (LPS), or bacteria. The inducibility of &lt;em&gt;JHDM1D-AS1&lt;/em&gt; expression in monocytes depended, at least in part, on nuclear factor-κB activation. &lt;em&gt;JHDM1D-AS1&lt;/em&gt; knockdown experiments in human monocyte-derived macrophages revealed significantly enhanced expression of inflammatory mediators, before and after exposure to LPS, relative to control cells. Specifically, genes involved in inflammatory responses were upregulated (e.g., &lt;em&gt;CXCL2&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;CXCL8&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;IL1RN&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;TREM1&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;TNF&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;IL6&lt;/em&gt;), whereas genes involved in anti-inflammatory pathways were downregulated (e.g., &lt;em&gt;SOCS1&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;IL10RA&lt;/em&gt;). &lt;em&gt;JHDM1D-AS1&lt;/em&gt; overexpression in a pro-monocytic cell line revealed diminished pro-inflammatory responses subsequent to LPS challenge. Collectively, these findings identify &lt;em&gt;JHDM1D-AS1&lt;/em&gt; as a potential anti-inflammatory mediator induced in response to inflammatory stimuli.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LINC00893 inhibits the progression of prostate cancer through miR-3173-5p/SOCS3/JAK2/STAT3 pathway</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35818076/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35818076/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Prostate cancer (PCa) is one of the most common malignant tumors in the male urinary system. In recent years, the morbidity and mortality of PCa have been increasing due to the limited effects of existing treatment strategies. Long non-coding RNA (lncRNA) LINC00893 was reported to inhibit the proliferation and metastasis of papillary thyroid cancer cells, but its role in PCa has not been reported. This study aims to investigate the role and underlying mechanism of LINC00893 in regulating the progression of PCa cells.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; We first compared LINC00893 expression levels between PCa tissues and normal prostate tissues through TCGA database. The relative LINC00893 expression levels were further validated in 66 pairs of PCa tissues and para-cancerous normal tissues, as well as in PCa cell lines. Gain-of-function experiment was performed by transfecting PCa cell with LINC00893 expression vector, and CCK (Cell count kit)-8, 5-Ethynyl-2&amp;rsquo;-deoxyuridine (EdU) incorporation, colony information and transwell assays were conducted to assess the functional phenotypes. Dual-luciferase reporter, RNA-binding protein immunoprecipitation (RIP) and RNA pull-down assays were performed to evaluate the molecular interactions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; LINC00893 was downregulated in PCa tissues and cell lines, and patients with low expression of LINC00893 were associated with a poorer overall survival rate. LINC00893 overexpression hindered the proliferation, epithelial-mesenchymal transition (EMT) as well as the migratory ability of PCa cells, and suppressed the tumorigenesis of PCa cells in nude mice. We further demonstrated that LINC00893 acted as a sponge for miR-3173-5p and inhibited its activity, which in turn regulated the suppressor of cytokine signaling 3 (SOCS3)/Janus Kinase 2 (JAK2)/signal transducer and activator of transcription 3 (STAT3) signaling axis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; Our study demonstrated that LINC00893 suppresses the progression of PCa cells through targeting miR-3173-5p/SOCS3/JAK2/STAT3 axis. Our data uncovers a novel tumor-suppressor role of LINC00893 in PCa, which may serve as a potential strategy for targeted therapy in PCa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AAV capsid engineering identified two novel variants with improved in vivo tropism for cardiomyocytes</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35810332/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35810332/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AAV vectors are promising delivery tools for human gene therapy. However, broad tissue tropism and pre-existing immunity against natural serotypes limit their clinical use. We identified two AAV capsid variants, AAV2-THGTPAD and AAV2-NLPGSGD, by in vivo AAV2 peptide display library screening in a murine model of pressure overload-induced cardiac hypertrophy. Both variants showed significantly improved efficacy in in vivo cardiomyocyte transduction compared with the parental serotype AAV2 as indicated by a higher number of AAV vector episomes in the nucleus and significant improved transduction efficiency. Both variants also outcompeted the reference serotype AAV9 regarding cardiomyocyte tropism, reaching comparable cardiac transduction efficiencies accompanied with liver de-targeting and decreased transduction efficiency of non-cardiac cells. Capsid modification influenced immunogenicity as sera of mice treated with AAV2-THGTPAD and AAV2-NLPGSGD demonstrated a poor neutralization capacity for the parental serotype and the novel variants. In a therapeutic setting, using the long non-coding RNA H19 in low vector dose conditions, novel AAV variants mediated superior anti-hypertrophic effects and revealed a further improved target-to-noise ratio, i.e., cardiomyocyte tropism. In conclusion, AAV2-THGTPAD and AAV2-NLPGSGD are promising novel tools for cardiac-directed gene therapy outperforming AAV9 regarding the specificity and therapeutic efficiency of in vivo cardiomyocyte transduction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HOTAIR/miR-1277-5p/ZEB1 axis mediates hypoxia-induced oxaliplatin resistance via regulating epithelial-mesenchymal transition in colorectal cancer</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35798695/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35798695/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The hypoxic microenvironment contributes to the chemoresistance of many malignant tumors including colorectal cancer (CRC). Accumulating studies have indicated that long non-coding RNAs (lncRNAs) play important roles in chemotherapy resistance. In this study, we aimed to determine the effect of lncRNAs in hypoxia-mediated resistance in CRC and its potential mechanism. Here, we discovered that hypoxia-induced oxaliplatin resistance and HOX transcript antisense RNA (HOTAIR) expression was increased in hypoxia-treated CRC cell lines and CRC tumors. Knockdown of HOTAIR by siRNA reduced the viability and proliferation of CRC cells treated with oxaliplatin and reversed hypoxia-induced resistance. Mechanically, we found that HOTAIR modulates zinc finger E-box binding homeobox 1 (ZEB1) expression by negative regulations of miR-1277-5p. When miR-1277-5p was silenced, knockdown of HOTAIR was unable to reduce the oxaliplatin resistance in CRC cells. In mouse models of CRC, HOTAIR knockdown markedly inhibited the tumor growth when treated with oxaliplatin. Thus, HOTAIR/miR-1277-5p/ZEB1 axis appears a promising therapeutic target for improving the oxaliplatin efficacy in CRC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A novel lncRNA RP11-386G11.10 reprograms lipid metabolism to promote hepatocellular carcinoma progression</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35798238/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35798238/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;LncRNA &lt;em&gt;RP11-386G11.10&lt;/em&gt; was up-regulated in HCC.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Overexpression of lncRNA &lt;em&gt;RP11-386G11.10&lt;/em&gt; promoted the proliferation, metastasis of HCC cells in vivo and in vitro.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We confirmed that regulation of HNRNPU expression by RP11-286H15.1 resulted in lipid accumulation in HCC cells.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;HNRNPU forms a ZBTB7A-&lt;em&gt;RP11-386G11.10&lt;/em&gt;-HNRNPU positive feedback loop by promoting mRNA stability of ZBTB7A.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Objective:&lt;/em&gt; Emerging studies suggest that long non-coding RNAs (lncRNAs) play crucial roles in hepatocellular carcinoma (HCC). A rapidly increasing number of studies have shown that metabolic changes including lipid metabolic reprogramming play a significant role in the progression of HCC. But it remains to be elucidated how lncRNAs affect tumor cell metabolism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; Through analysis and screening of The Cancer Genome Atlas-Liver Hepatocellular Carcinoma (TCGA-LIHC) dataset, we found a novel lncRNA RP11-386G11.10 was overexpressed, related to prognosis, conserved and non-protein-coding in HCC and related to poor prognosis. Then, CCK-8, colony formation, Transwell invasion, wound healing assays were performed and nude mouse subcutaneous tumour formation and lung metastasis models were established to explore the effect of RP11-386G11.10 on HCC tumour growth and metastasis. Chromatography-mass spectrometry (GC-MS) and Nile red staining detected the effect of RP11-386G11.10 on lipid metabolism in HCC. Mechanistically, we clarified the RP11-386G11.10/miR-345-3p/HNRNPU signalling pathway through dual luciferase reporter, RNA immunoprecipitation (RIP) and chromatin immunoprecipitation (ChIP) assays and identified ZBTB7A as a transcription factor of RP11-386G11.10.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; RP11-386G11.10 was overexpressed in HCC and positively correlated with tumour size, TNM stage, and poor prognosis in HCC patients. RP11-386G11.10 promoted the proliferation and metastasis of HCC cells in vitro and in vivo. Mechanistically, RP11-386G11.10 acted as a competing endogenous RNA (ceRNA) for miR-345-3p to regulate the expression of HNRNPU and its downstream lipogenic enzymes, leading to lipid accumulation in HCC cells and promoting their growth and metastasis. In addition, we identified ZBTB7A as a transcription factor of RP11-386G11.10. Moreover, HNRNPU promoted the expression of ZBTB7A in HCC cells, thereby increasing the transcriptional activity of RP11-386G11.10, and forming a positive feedback loop, ultimately leading continuous lipid accumulation, growth and metastasis in HCC cells.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; Our results indicated that the lncRNA RP11-386G11.10 was a novel oncogenic lncRNA that was strongly correlated with the poor prognosis of HCC. The ZBTB7A-RP11-386G11.10-HNRNPU positive feedback loop promoted the progression of HCC by regulating lipid anabolism. RP11-386G11.10 may become a new diagnostic and prognostic biomarker and therapy target for HCC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OCT4 activates a Suv39h1-repressive antisense lncRNA to couple histone H3 Lysine 9 methylation to pluripotency</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35762231/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35762231/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Histone H3 Lysine 9 (H3K9) methylation, a characteristic mark of heterochromatin, is progressively implemented during development to contribute to cell fate restriction as differentiation proceeds. Accordingly, in undifferentiated and pluripotent mouse Embryonic Stem (ES) cells the global levels of H3K9 methylation are rather low and increase only upon differentiation. How global H3K9 methylation levels are coupled with the loss of pluripotency remains largely unknown. Here, we identify SUV39H1, a major H3K9 di- and tri-methylase, as an indirect target of the pluripotency network of Transcription Factors (TFs). We find that pluripotency TFs, principally OCT4, activate the expression of Suv39h1as, an antisense long non-coding RNA to Suv39h1. In turn, Suv39h1as downregulates Suv39h1 transcription in cis via a mechanism involving the modulation of the chromatin status of the locus. The targeted deletion of the Suv39h1as promoter region triggers increased SUV39H1 expression and H3K9me2 and H3K9me3 levels, affecting all heterochromatic regions, particularly peri-centromeric major satellites and retrotransposons. This increase in heterochromatinization efficiency leads to accelerated and more efficient commitment into differentiation. We report, therefore, a simple genetic circuitry coupling the genetic control of pluripotency with the global efficiency of H3K9 methylation associated with a major cell fate restriction, the irreversible loss of pluripotency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LncRNA EPR-induced METTL7A1 modulates target gene translation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35748870/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35748870/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;EPR&lt;/em&gt; is a long non-coding RNA (lncRNA) that controls cell proliferation in mammary gland cells by regulating gene transcription. Here, we report on &lt;em&gt;Mettl7a1&lt;/em&gt; as a direct target of &lt;em&gt;EPR&lt;/em&gt;. We show that &lt;em&gt;EPR&lt;/em&gt; induces &lt;em&gt;Mettl7a1&lt;/em&gt; transcription by rewiring three-dimensional chromatin interactions at the &lt;em&gt;Mettl7a1&lt;/em&gt; locus. Our data indicate that METTL7A1 contributes to &lt;em&gt;EPR&lt;/em&gt;-dependent inhibition of TGF-β signaling. METTL7A1 is absent in tumorigenic murine mammary gland cells and its human ortholog (METTL7A) is downregulated in breast cancers. Importantly, re-expression of METTL7A1 in 4T1 tumorigenic cells attenuates their transformation potential, with the putative methyltransferase activity of METTL7A1 being dispensable for its biological functions. We found that METTL7A1 localizes in the cytoplasm whereby it interacts with factors implicated in the early steps of mRNA translation, associates with ribosomes, and affects the levels of target proteins without altering mRNA abundance. Overall, our data indicates that METTL7A1-a transcriptional target of &lt;em&gt;EPR&lt;/em&gt;-modulates translation of select transcripts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lipid metabolism-related lncRNA SLC25A21-AS1 promotes the progression of oesophageal squamous cell carcinoma by regulating the NPM1/c-Myc axis and SLC25A21 expression</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35735113/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35735113/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Obesity alters metabolic microenvironment and is thus associated with several tumours. The aim of the present study was to investigate the role, molecular mechanism of action, and potential clinical value of lipid metabolism-related long non-coding RNA (lncRNA) SLC25A21-AS1 in oesophageal squamous cell carcinoma (ESCC).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; A high-fat diets (HFDs)-induced obesity nude mouse model was established, and targeted metabolomics analysis was used to identify critical medium-long chain fatty acids influencing the growth of ESCC cells. Transcriptomic analysis of public dataset GSE53625 confirmed that lncRNA SLC25A21-AS1 was a lipid metabolism-related lncRNA. The biological function of lncRNA SLC25A21-AS1 in ESCC was investigated both in vivo and in vitro. Chromatin immunoprecipitation(ChIP)assay, RNA-pull down, mass spectrometry, co-IP, and RNA IP(RIP) were performed to explore the molecular mechanism. Finally, an ESCC cDNA microarray was used to determine the clinical prognostic value of SLC25A21-AS1 by RT-qPCR.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; Palmitic acid (PA) is an important fatty acid component of HFD and had an inhibitory effect on ESCC cell lines. LncRNA SLC25A21-AS1 expression was downregulated by PA and associated with the proliferation and migration of ESCC cells in vitro and in vivo. Mechanistically, SLC25A21-AS1 interacted with nucleophosmin-1 (NPM1) protein to promote the downstream gene transcription of the c-Myc in the nucleus. In the cytoplasm, SLC25A21-AS1 maintained the stability of SLC25A21 mRNA and reduced the intracellular NAD+ /NADH ratio by influencing tryptophan catabolism. Finally, we demonstrated that high expression of SLC25A21-AS1 promoted resistance to cisplatin-induced apoptosis and was correlated with poor tumour grade and overall survival.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; HFD/PA has an inhibitory effect on ESCC cells and SLC25A21-AS1 expression. SLC25A21-AS1 promotes the proliferation and migration of ESCC cells by regulating the NPM1/c-Myc axis and SLC25A21 expression. In addition, lncRNA SLC25A21-AS1 may serve as a favourable prognostic biomarker and a potential therapeutic target for ESCC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LINC01194 recruits NUMA1 to promote ubiquitination of RYR2 to enhance malignant progression in triple-negative breast cancer</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35750275/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35750275/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;LINC01194 was highly expressed in TNBC.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;LINC01194 recruited NUMA1 to stabilize UBE2C mRNA, thereby promoting RYR2 ubiquitination and degradation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;LINC01194/NUMA1/UBE2C/RYR2/Wnt/β-catenin signaling pathway might provide an effective therapeutic strategy for TNBC.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Long intergenic nonprotein coding RNA 1194 (LINC01194) has been reported as an oncogene in several cancer types, but its expression and potential role in triple-negative breast cancer (TNBC) are still unclear. We found that LINC01194 was significantly highly expressed in TNBC based on The Cancer Genome Atlas (TCGA) database. Data from in vitro experiments and in vivo assays demonstrated that LINC01194 promoted TNBC progression. Through bioinformatics prediction, mass spectrometry, and mechanical experiments, we found that LINC01194 could recruit nuclear mitotic apparatus protein 1 (NUMA1) to bind to the untranslated region (3&amp;rsquo;UTR) of ubiquitin-conjugating enzyme E2 C (UBE2C) 3&amp;rsquo; and stabilize UBE2C mRNA. Moreover, we found that UBE2C acted as an ubiquitin ligase to promote the ubiquitination and degradation of ryanodine receptor type 2 (RYR2) that inhibited the progression of TNBC by inhibiting the Wnt/β-catenin signaling pathway. In summary, LINC01194 activate the Wnt/β-catenin signaling pathway and accelerates the malignant progression of TNBC by recruiting NUMA1 to stabilize UBE2C mRNA and thus promotes RYR2 ubiquitination and degradation. These findings might provide a more effective therapeutic strategy for TNBC patients.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Long non-coding RNA MIR4435-2HG: a key molecule in progression of cancer and non-cancerous disorders</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/35715800/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/35715800/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MIR4435-2HG (LINC00978) is a long non-coding RNA (lncRNA) that acts as an oncogene in almost all cancers. This lncRNA participates in the molecular cascades involved in other disorders such as coronary artery diseases, osteonecrosis, osteoarthritis, osteoporosis, and periodontitis. MIR4435-2HG exerts its functions via the spectrum of different mechanisms, including inhibition of apoptosis, sponging microRNAs (miRNAs), promoting cell proliferation, increasing cell invasion and migration, and enhancing epithelial to mesenchymal transition (EMT). MIR4435-2HG can regulate several signaling pathways, including Wnt, TGF-β/SMAD, Nrf2/HO-1, PI3K/AKT, MAPK/ERK, and FAK/AKT/β‑catenin signaling pathways; therefore, it can lead to tumor progression. In the present review, we aimed to discuss the potential roles of lncRNA MIR4435-2HG in developing cancerous and non-cancerous conditions. Due to its pivotal role in different disorders, this lncRNA can serve as a potential biomarker in future investigations. Moreover, it may serve as a potential therapeutic target for the treatment of various diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Whole transcriptome sequencing analysis revealed key RNA profiles and toxicity in mice after chronic exposure to microplastics</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35718033/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35718033/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Investigating the long-term effects of microplastics (MPs) in vivo is necessary for evaluating its biological toxicity. Previously, we showed that MPs elicit vascular dysfunctions in atherosclerotic mice. However, the effects of long-term treatment with environmental levels of MPs on biological functions and RNA expression profiles in wild-type mice are unknown. Here, C57BL/6 mice were administered 1000 μg/L MPs through their drinking water for 180 days. Transcriptomic analyses, biochemical analysis, and histopathological examination were conducted to determine the key signals and molecular mechanisms triggered by MPs in vivo using whole transcriptome sequencing, enzyme-linked immunosorbent assay, and histopathological analysis. Notably, our data revealed that MPs aggravated vascular lesions and organ injuries, particularly liver, kidney, and heart injuries. Additionally, MPs exacerbated oxidative injuries by inhibiting the activities of antioxidant enzymes and increasing the levels of the serum biochemistry indicator of organ damage. RNA sequencing of vascular tissues showed that 674 mRNAs, 39 lncRNAs, 196 miRNAs, and 565 circRNAs were abnormally expressed in MPs-treated mice compared with the untreated group. Pathway enrichment analyses identified pathways linked to the toxicity of MPs, including lysosomal, NOD-like receptor, and peroxisome proliferator-activated receptor pathways. Additionally, competing endogenous RNA networks were constructed and hub RNAs were identified using bioinformatics analysis. Taken together, our data suggested that toxicity induced by long-term exposure to MPs continually presents with extensive changes in biological features and global gene expression profiles. Our data provides new insights into the biological toxicity of MPs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CREB1 contributes colorectal cancer cell plasticity by regulating lncRNA CCAT1 and NF-κB pathways</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35696016/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35696016/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The CREB1 gene encodes an exceptionally pleiotropic transcription factor that frequently dysregulated in human cancers. CREB1 can regulate tumor cell status of proliferation and/or migration; however, the molecular basis for this switch involvement in cell plasticity has not fully been understood yet. Here, we first show that knocking out CREB1 triggers a remarkable effect of epithelial-mesenchymal transition (EMT) and leads to the occurrence of inhibited proliferation and enhanced motility in HCT116 colorectal cancer cells. By monitoring 45 cellular signaling pathway activities, we find that multiple growth-related pathways decline significantly while inflammatory pathways including NF-κB are largely upregulated in comparing between the CREB1 wild-type and knocked out cells. Mechanistically, cells with CREB1 knocked out show downregulation of MYC as a result of impaired CREB1-dependent transcription of the oncogenic lncRNA CCAT1. Interestingly, the unbalanced competition between the coactivator CBP/p300 for CREB1 and p65 leads to the activation of the NF-κB pathway in cells with CREB1 disrupted, which induces an obvious EMT phenotype of the cancer cells. Taken together, these studies identify previously unknown mechanisms of CREB1 in CRC cell plasticity via regulating lncRNA CCAT1 and NF-κB pathways, providing a critical insight into a combined strategy for CREB1-targeted tumor therapies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exosomes deliver lncRNA DARS-AS1 siRNA to inhibit chronic unpredictable mild stress-induced TNBC metastasis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35688263/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35688263/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Exosomes are natural nanocarriers for efficient delivery of siRNA to recipient cells.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SiRNA-loaded exosomes were performed by modified calcium-mediated transfection method.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SiRNA-loaded exosomes demonstrated dose-dependent knockdown efficiency.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SiRNA-loaded exosomes showed strong antitumor activity on TNBC cells in vitro.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SiRNA-loaded exosomes intensively inhibited TNBC tumor growth and metastasis in vivo.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Triple-negative breast cancer (TNBC) is a rapidly recurring and highly metastatic malignancy with high heterogeneity and chemoradiotherapy resistance. Chronic unpredictable mild stress (CUMS) can induce the occurrence of tumors and enhance lymphatic infiltration and distant metastasis through direct interaction with the sympathetic nervous system; however, its relevance in TNBC is yet to be clarified. In this study, DARS-AS1, a newly reported CUMS-responsive lncRNA, was found to be enriched in TNBC clinical tumors and cells and positively correlated with late clinical stage in patients with TNBC. DARS-AS1 overexpression significantly enhanced the migration and invasion of TNBC tumors by inhibiting miR-129-2-3p and upregulated CDK1 to activate the NF-κB/STAT3 signaling pathway both &lt;em&gt;in vitro&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt;. Treatment with DARS-AS1 siRNA-loaded exosomes (EXOs) substantially slowed CUMS-induced TNBC cell growth and liver metastasis. Therefore, DARS-AS1 represents a potential therapeutic target for metastatic TNBC, and EXOs may serve as siRNA delivery carriers in clinical therapy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lockd promotes myoblast proliferation and muscle regeneration via binding with DHX36 to facilitate 5&#39; UTR rG4 unwinding and Anp32e translation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35675771/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35675771/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Lockd&lt;/em&gt; is highly induced in activated satellite cells and promotes cell proliferation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Lockd&lt;/em&gt; interacts with DHX36 and regulates the translation of DHX36-bound mRNAs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Lockd&lt;/em&gt;/DHX36 regulate &lt;em&gt;Anp32e&lt;/em&gt; translation via modulating the 5′ UTR rG4 structure&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Lockd&lt;/em&gt; stabilizes the interaction of DHX36 and EIF3B proteins&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adult muscle stem cells, also known as satellite cells (SCs), play pivotal roles in muscle regeneration, and long non-coding RNA (lncRNA) functions in SCs remain largely unknown. Here, we identify a lncRNA, &lt;em&gt;Lockd&lt;/em&gt;, which is induced in activated SCs upon acute muscle injury. We demonstrate that &lt;em&gt;Lockd&lt;/em&gt; promotes SC proliferation; deletion of &lt;em&gt;Lockd&lt;/em&gt; leads to cell-cycle arrest, and &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt; repression of &lt;em&gt;Lockd&lt;/em&gt; in mouse muscles hinders regeneration process. Mechanistically, we show that &lt;em&gt;Lockd&lt;/em&gt; directly interacts with RNA helicase DHX36 and the 5&amp;rsquo;end of &lt;em&gt;Lockd&lt;/em&gt; possesses the strongest binding with DHX36. Furthermore, we demonstrate that &lt;em&gt;Lockd&lt;/em&gt; stabilizes the interaction between DHX36 and EIF3B proteins; synergistically, this complex unwinds the RNA G-quadruplex (rG4) structure formed at &lt;em&gt;Anp32e&lt;/em&gt; mRNA 5&amp;rsquo; UTR and promotes the translation of ANP32E protein, which is required for myoblast proliferation. Altogether, our findings identify a regulatory &lt;em&gt;Lockd&lt;/em&gt;/DHX36/Anp32e axis that promotes myoblast proliferation and acute-injury-induced muscle regeneration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>KMT2B promotes the growth of renal cell carcinoma via upregulation of SNHG12 expression and promotion of CEP55 transcription</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35597996/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35597996/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; This study aims to clarify the mechanistic action of long non-coding RNA (lncRNA) SNHG12 in the development of renal cell carcinoma (RCC), which may be associated with promoter methylation modification by KMT2B and the regulation of the E2F1/CEP55 axis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; TCGA and GEO databases were used to predict the involvement of SNHG12 in RCC. Knockdown of SNHG12/E2F1/CEP55 was performed. Next, SNHG12 expression and other mRNAs were quantified by RT-qPCR. Subsequently, CCK-8 was used to detect cell proliferation. Wound healing assay and Transwell assay were used to detect cell migration and invasion, respectively. The in vitro angiogenesis of human umbilical vein endothelial cells (HUVECs) was explored by matrigel-based capillary-like tube formation assay. ChIP assay was used to detect H3K4me3 in SNHG12 promoter region. The binding of E2F1 to CEP55 promoter region was analyzed with ChIP and dual luciferase reporter assays. RIP assay was used to detect the binding of SNHG12 to E2F1. Finally, the effect of SNHG12 on the tumor formation and angiogenesis of RCC was assessed in nude mouse xenograft model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; SNHG12 was highly expressed in RCC tissues and cells, and it was related to the poor prognosis of RCC patients. SNHG12 knockdown significantly inhibited RCC cell proliferation, migration, and invasion and HUVEC angiogenesis. KMT2B up-regulated SNHG12 expression through modifying H3K4me3 in its promoter region. In addition, SNHG12 promoted CEP55 expression by recruiting the transcription factor E2F1. Knockdown of SNHG12 blocked E2F1 recruitment and down-regulated the expression of CEP55, thereby inhibiting tumor formation and angiogenesis in nude mice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/em&gt; The evidence provided by our study highlighted the involvement of KMT2B in up-regulation of lncRNA as well as the transcription of CEP55, resulting in the promotion of angiogenesis and growth of RCC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analysis of PANoptosis-Related LncRNA-miRNA-mRNA Network Reveals LncRNA SNHG7 Involved in Chemo-Resistance in Colon Adenocarcinoma</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35646635/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35646635/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Colon adenocarcinoma (COAD) is one of the most common malignancies, and its metastatic lesions are the leading cause of death in COAD patients. PANoptosis is a recently identified pathway for programmed cell death implicated in developing COAD. Long non-coding RNAs (lncRNAs) are key regulators of cancer occurrence and progress. Although their function has captured much attention in COAD, the relationship between COAD metastasis-associated lncRNA expression and PANoptosis remains elusive. Therefore, this study aimed to explore the potential regulatory roles of metastasis- and PANoptosis-associated lncRNAs in COAD. Nine lncRNAs associated with metastasis and PANoptosis in COAD were identified from The Cancer Genome Atlas (TCGA) and GEO databases. Their functions were analyzed by multiple bioinformatics methods, and the lncRNA-miRNA-mRNA network was constructed. Multivariate Cox analysis identified one lncRNA (SNHG7) significantly related to COAD prognosis. Subsequent analyses showed its expression correlated with tumor stage and lymph node metastasis. Moreover, drug sensitivity analysis and in vitro experiments suggest that lncRNA SNHG7 contributes to drug resistance in COAD. In summary, lncRNA SNHG7 is a potential target for diagnosing and treating COAD and plays a crucial role in regulating apoptosis, metastasis, and drug resistance in COAD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LncRNA-PACERR induces pro-tumour macrophages via interacting with miR-671-3p and m6A-reader IGF2BP2 in pancreatic ductal adenocarcinoma</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35526050/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35526050/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; LncRNA-PACERR plays critical role in the polarization of tissue-associated macrophages (TAMs). In this study, we found the function and molecular mechanism of PACERR in TAMs to regulate pancreatic ductal adenocarcinoma (PDAC) progression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; We used qPCR to analyse the expression of PACERR in TAMs and M1-tissue-resident macrophages (M1-NTRMs) which were isolated from 46 PDAC tissues. The function of PACERR on macrophages polarization and PDAC proliferation, migration and invasion were confirmed through in vivo and in vitro assays. The molecular mechanism of PACERR was discussed via fluorescence in situ hybridization (FISH), RNA pull-down, ChIP-qPCR, RIP-qPCR and luciferase assays.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; LncRNA-PACERR was high expression in TAMs and associated with poor prognosis in PDAC patients. Our finding validated that LncRNA-PACERR increased the number of M2-polarized cells and facilized cell proliferation, invasion and migration in vitro and in vivo. Mechanistically, LncRNA-PACERR activate KLF12/p-AKT/c-myc pathway by binding to miR-671-3p. And LncRNA-PACERR which bound to IGF2BP2 acts as an m6A-dependent manner to enhance the stability of KLF12 and c-myc in cytoplasm. In addition, the promoter of LncRNA-PACERR was a target of KLF12 and LncRNA-PACERR recruited EP300 to increase the acetylation of histone by interacting with KLF12 in nucleus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; This study found that LncRNA-PACERR functions as key regulator of TAMs in PDAC microenvironment and revealed the novel mechanisms in cytoplasm and in nucleus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Long noncoding RNA LINC01606 protects colon cancer cells from ferroptotic cell death and promotes stemness by SCD1-Wnt/β-catenin-TFE3 feedback loop signalling</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35485210/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35485210/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Ferroptosis is principally caused by iron catalytic activity and intracellular lipid peroxidation. Long noncoding RNAs (lncRNAs) play crucial roles in tumorigenesis. However, the potential interplay between lncRNA LINC01606 and ferroptosis in colon cancer remains elusive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; The expression level of LNC01606 in colon cancer tissue was detected by quantitative real-time polymerase chain reaction. The functional role of LNC01606 was investigated by gain- and loss-of-function assays both in vitro and in vivo. The LINC01606-SCD1-Wnt/β-catenin-TFE3 axis were screened and validated by DNA/RNA pull down, gas chromatography-mass spectrometry, RNA immunoprecipitation and dual-luciferase reporter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; The expression of lncRNA LINC01606 was frequently upregulated in human colon cancer and strongly associated with a poor prognosis. LINC01606 functioned as an oncogene and promotes colon cancer cell growth, invasion and stemness both in vitro and in vivo. Moreover, LINC01606 protected colon cancer cells from ferroptosis by decreasing the concentration of iron, lipid reactive oxygen species, mitochondrial superoxide and increasing mitochondrial membrane potential. Mechanistically, LINC01606 enhanced the expression of stearoyl-CoA desaturase 1 (SCD1), serving as a competing endogenous RNA to modulate miR-423-5p expression, subsequently activating the canonical Wnt/β-catenin signaling, and transcription factor binding to IGHM enhancer 3 (TFE3) increased LINC01606 transcription after recruitment to the promoter regions of LINC01606. Furthermore, we confirmed that upregulated LINC01606 and Wnt/β-catenin formed a positive feedback regulatory loop, further inhibiting ferroptosis and enhancing stemness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; LINC01606 functions as an oncogene to facilitate tumor cell stemness, proliferation and inhibit ferroptosis and is a promising therapeutic target for colon cancer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Long noncoding RNA TLNC1 promotes the growth and metastasis of liver cancer via inhibition of p53 signaling</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35477447/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35477447/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Long non-coding RNAs (lncRNAs) have been demonstrated to play vital roles in cancer development and progression. However, their biological roles and function mechanisms in liver cancer remain largely unknown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; RNA-seq was performed with clinical hepatoma tissues and paired adjacent normal liver tissues to identify differentially expressed lncRNAs. qPCR was utilized to examine the expression levels of lncRNAs. We studied the function of TLNC1 in cell growth and metastasis of hepatoma with both cell and mouse models. RNA-seq, RNA pull-down coupled with mass spectrometry, RNA immunoprecipitation, dual luciferase reporter assay, and surface plasmon resonance analysis were used to analyze the functional mechanism of TLNC1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; Based on the intersection of our own RNA-seq, TCGA RNA-seq, and TCGA survival analysis data, TLNC1 was identified as a potential tumorigenic lncRNA of liver cancer. TLNC1 significantly enhanced the growth and metastasis of hepatoma cells both in vitro and in vivo. TLNC1 exerted its tumorigenic function through interaction with TPR and inducing the TPR-mediated transportation of p53 from nucleus to cytoplasm, thus repressing the transcription of p53 target genes and finally contributing to the progression of liver cancer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; TLNC1 is a promising prognostic factor of liver cancer, and the TLNC1-TPR-p53 axis can serve as a potential therapeutic target for hepatoma treatment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crosstalk between lncRNAs in the apoptotic pathway and therapeutic targets in cancer</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/35597701/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/35597701/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The assertion that a significant portion of the mammalian genome has not been translated and that non-coding RNA accounts for over half of polyadenylate RNA have received much attention. In recent years, increasing evidence proposes non-coding RNAs (ncRNAs) as new regulators of various cellular processes, including cancer progression and nerve damage. Apoptosis is a type of programmed cell death critical for homeostasis and tissue development. Cancer cells often have inhibited apoptotic pathways. It has recently been demonstrated that up/down-regulation of various lncRNAs in certain types of tumors shapes cancer cells&amp;rsquo; response to apoptotic stimuli. This review discusses the most recent studies on lncRNAs and apoptosis in healthy and cancer cells. In addition, the role of lncRNAs as novel targets for cancer therapy is reviewed here. Finally, since it has been shown that lncRNA expression is associated with specific types of cancer, the potential for using lncRNAs as biomarkers is also discussed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lupus enhancer risk variant causes dysregulation of IRF8 through cooperative lncRNA and DNA methylation machinery</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35388006/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35388006/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite strong evidence that human genetic variants affect the expression of many key transcription factors involved in autoimmune diseases, establishing biological links between non-coding risk variants and the gene targets they regulate remains a considerable challenge. Here, we combine genetic, epigenomic, and CRISPR activation approaches to screen for functional variants that regulate IRF8 expression. We demonstrate that the locus containing rs2280381 is a cell-type-specific enhancer for IRF8 that spatially interacts with the IRF8 promoter. Further, rs2280381 mediates IRF8 expression through enhancer RNA AC092723.1, which recruits TET1 to the IRF8 promoter regulating IRF8 expression by affecting methylation levels. The alleles of rs2280381 modulate PU.1 binding and chromatin state to regulate AC092723.1 and IRF8 expression differentially. Our work illustrates an integrative strategy to define functional genetic variants that regulate the expression of critical genes in autoimmune diseases and decipher the mechanisms underlying the dysregulation of IRF8 expression mediated by lupus risk variants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Promoter and enhancer RNAs regulate chromatin reorganization and activation of miR-10b/HOXD locus, and neoplastic transformation in glioma</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35390275/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35390275/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chromatin topology of the HOXD locus is altered between the brain and glioblastoma&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;lncRNAs regulate CTCF/cohesin-dependent loop formation and HOXD gene expression&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Activation of LINC01116 enhancer RNA leads to astrocyte transformation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The transformation depends on the loop formation and miR-10b derepression&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;miR-10b is silenced in normal neuroglial cells of the brain but commonly activated in glioma, where it assumes an essential tumor-promoting role. We demonstrate that the entire miR-10b-hosting HOXD locus is activated in glioma via the cis-acting mechanism involving 3D chromatin reorganization and CTCF-cohesin-mediated looping. This mechanism requires two interacting lncRNAs, HOXD-AS2 and LINC01116, one associated with HOXD3/HOXD4/miR-10b promoter and another with the remote enhancer. Knockdown of either lncRNA in glioma cells alters CTCF and cohesin binding, abolishes chromatin looping, inhibits the expression of all genes within HOXD locus, and leads to glioma cell death. Conversely, in cortical astrocytes, enhancer activation is sufficient for HOXD/miR-10b locus reorganization, gene derepression, and neoplastic cell transformation. LINC01116 RNA is essential for this process. Our results demonstrate the interplay of two lncRNAs in the chromatin folding and concordant regulation of miR-10b and multiple HOXD genes normally silenced in astrocytes and triggering the neoplastic glial transformation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Molecular Mechanism of Long Non-Coding RNA (LncRNA) Regulation of Notch Signaling in Glucose-Induced Apoptosis of Human Retinal Vascular Endothelial Cell</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35715905/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35715905/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Diabetes, a global health concern, affects the health of more than 500 million adults. The absence of Notch protein can cause an imbalance in the retinal vascular environment and cause retinal vascular disease. Long noncoding RNA (lncRNA) is known to be involved in the regulation of many signaling pathways. We hope to understand the specific mechanism of apoptosis in retinal vascular endothelial cells (RVECs) by exploring the regulatory effect of lncRNA on the Notch pathway. In this study, we found that RVECs treated with glucose showed increased levels of Notch transcript and protein expression. The lentiviral interference with Notch RNAi reversed this response. When Notch activity decreased, oxidative stress also decreased, accompanied by increased levels of Caspase-9 and Caspase-3 and an increased rate of apoptosis. Therefore, we believe that Notch is involved in the development of diabetic retinopathy and loss of expression promotes apoptosis of human RVECs. By inhibiting the Notch pathway, lncRNA promotes apoptosis of human RVECs in a high-glucose environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ImmReg: the regulon atlas of immune-related pathways across cancer types</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34755873/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34755873/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read to learn more:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Li Y., Jiang T., Zhou W., Li J., Li X., Wang Q., Jin X., Yin J., Chen L., Zhang Y. et al. &lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/32081859/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Pan-cancer characterization of immune-related lncRNAs identifies potential oncogenic biomarkers&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-020-14802-2&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nature Communications&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. 2020; 11:1000.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Immune system gene regulation perturbation has been found to be a major cause of the development of various types of cancer. Numbers of mechanisms contribute to gene expression regulation, thus, systematically identification of potential regulons of immune-related pathways is critical to cancer immunotherapy. Here, we comprehensively chart the landscape of transcription factors, microRNAs, RNA binding proteins and long noncoding RNAs regulation in 17 immune-related pathways across 33 cancers. The potential immunology regulons are likely to exhibit higher expressions in immune cells, show expression perturbations in cancer, and are significantly correlated with immune cell infiltrations. We also identify a panel of clinically relevant immunology regulons across cancers. Moreover, the regulon atlas of immune-related pathways helps prioritizing cancer-related genes (i.e. ETV7, miR-146a-5p, ZFP36 and HCP5). We further identified two molecular subtypes of glioma (cold and hot tumour phenotypes), which were characterized by differences in immune cell infiltrations, expression of checkpoints, and prognosis. Finally, we developed a user-friendly resource, &lt;a href=&#34;http://bio-bigdata.hrbmu.edu.cn/ImmReg/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;ImmReg&lt;/a&gt;, with multiple modules to visualize, browse, and download immunology regulation. Our study provides a comprehensive landscape of immunology regulons, which will shed light on future development of RNA-based cancer immunotherapies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IRF3-binding lncRNA-ISIR strengthens interferon production in viral infection and autoinflammation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34731629/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34731629/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interferon regulatory factor 3 (IRF3) is an essential transductor for initiation of many immune responses. Here, we show that lncRNA-ISIR directly binds IRF3 to promote its phosphorylation, dimerization, and nuclear translocation, along with enhanced target gene productions. In vivo lncRNA-ISIR deficiency results in reduced IFN production, uncontrolled viral replication, and increased mortality. The human homolog, AK131315, also binds IRF3 and promotes its activation. More important, AK131315 expression is positively correlated with type I interferon (IFN-I) level and severity in patients with lupus. Mechanistically, in resting cells, IRF3 is bound to suppressor protein Flightless-1 (Fli-1), which keeps its inactive state. Upon infection, IFN-I-induced lncRNA-ISIR binds IRF3 at DNA-binding domain in cytoplasm and removes Fli-1&amp;rsquo;s association from IRF3, consequently facilitating IRF3 activation. Our results demonstrate that IFN-I-inducible lncRNA-ISIR feedback strengthens IRF3 activation by removing suppressive Fli-1 in immune responses, revealing a method of lncRNA-mediated modulation of transcription factor (TF) activation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cis-acting lnc-Cxcl2 restrains neutrophil-mediated lung inflammation by inhibiting epithelial cell CXCL2 expression in virus infection</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34607953/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34607953/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chemokine production by epithelial cells is important for neutrophil recruitment during viral infection, the appropriate regulation of which is critical for restraining inflammation and attenuating subsequent tissue damage. Epithelial cell expression of long noncoding RNAs (lncRNAs), RNA-binding proteins, and their functional interactions during viral infection and inflammation remain to be fully understood. Here, we identified an inducible lncRNA in the &lt;em&gt;Cxcl2&lt;/em&gt; gene locus, lnc-Cxcl2, which could selectively inhibit &lt;em&gt;Cxcl2&lt;/em&gt; expression in mouse lung epithelial cells but not in macrophages. lnc-Cxcl2-deficient mice exhibited increased &lt;em&gt;Cxcl2&lt;/em&gt; expression, enhanced neutrophils recruitment, and more severe inflammation in the lung after influenza virus infection. Mechanistically, nucleus-localized lnc-Cxcl2 bound to &lt;em&gt;Cxcl2&lt;/em&gt; promoter, recruited a ribonucleoprotein La, which inhibited the chromatin accessibility of chemokine promoters, and consequently inhibited &lt;em&gt;Cxcl2&lt;/em&gt; transcription in cis However, unlike mouse lnc-Cxcl2, human lnc-CXCL2-4-1 inhibited multiple immune cytokine expressions including chemokines in human lung epithelial cells. Together, our results demonstrate a self-protecting mechanism within epithelial cells to restrain chemokine and neutrophil-mediated inflammation, providing clues for better understanding chemokine regulation and epithelial cell function in lung viral infection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LncRNA-encoded microproteins: A new form of cargo in cell culture-derived and circulating extracellular vesicles</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34276900/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34276900/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Advancements in omics-based technologies over the past few years have led to the discovery of numerous biologically relevant peptides encoded by small open reading frames (smORFs) embedded in long noncoding RNA (lncRNA) transcripts (referred to as microproteins here) in a variety of species. However, the mechanisms and modes of action that underlie the roles of microproteins have yet to be fully characterized. Herein, we provide the first experimental evidence of abundant microproteins in extracellular vesicles (EVs) derived from glioma cancer cells, indicating that the EV-mediated transfer of microproteins may represent a novel mechanism for intercellular communication. Intriguingly, when examining human plasma, 48, 11 and 3 microproteins were identified from purified EVs, whole plasma and EV-free plasma, respectively, suggesting that circulating microproteins are primarily enriched in EVs. Most importantly, the preliminary data showed that the expression profile of EV microproteins in glioma patient diverged from the health donors, suggesting that the circulating microproteins in EVs might have potential diagnostic application in identifying patients with glioma.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Long noncoding RNA BS-DRL1 modulates the DNA damage response and genome stability by interacting with HMGB1 in neurons</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34210972/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34210972/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Long noncoding RNAs (lncRNAs) are known to regulate DNA damage response (DDR) and genome stability in proliferative cells. However, it remains unknown whether lncRNAs are involved in these vital biological processes in post-mitotic neurons. Here, we report and characterize a lncRNA, termed Brain Specific DNA-damage Related lncRNA1 (BS-DRL1), in the central nervous system. BS-DRL1 is a brain-specific lncRNA and depletion of BS-DRL1 in neurons leads to impaired DDR upon etoposide treatment in vitro. Mechanistically, BS-DRL1 interacts with HMGB1, a chromatin protein that is important for genome stability, and is essential for the assembly of HMGB1 on chromatin. BS-DRL1 mediated DDR exhibits cell-type specificity in the cortex and cerebellum in gamma-irradiated mice and BS-DRL1 knockout mice show impaired motor function and concomitant purkinje cell degeneration. Our study extends the understanding of lncRNAs in DDR and genome stability and implies a protective role of lncRNA against neurodegeneration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deeply Mining a Universe of Peptides Encoded by Long Noncoding RNAs</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/34129944/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/34129944/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many small ORFs embedded in long noncoding RNA (lncRNA) transcripts have been shown to encode biologically functional polypeptides (small ORF-encoded polypeptides, short for SEPs) in different organisms. Despite some novel SEPs have been found, the identification is still hampered by their poor predictability, diminutive size, and low relative abundance. Here, we take advantage of NONCODE, a repository containing the most complete collection and annotation of lncRNA transcripts from different species, to build a novel database that attempts to maximize a collection of SEPs from human and mouse lncRNA transcripts. In order to further improve SEP discovery, we implemented two effective and complementary polypeptide enrichment strategies using 30-kDa molecular weight cutoff filter and C8 solid-phase extraction column. These combined strategies enabled us to discover 353 SEPs from eight human cell lines and 409 SEPs from three mouse cell lines and eight mouse tissues. Importantly, 19 of them were then verified through in vitro expression, immunoblotting, parallel reaction monitoring, and synthetic peptides. Subsequent bioinformatics analysis revealed that some of the physical and chemical properties of these novel SEPs, including amino acid composition and codon usage, are different from those commonly found in canonical proteins. Intriguingly, nearly 65% of the identified SEPs were found to be initiated with non-AUG start codons. The 762 novel SEPs probably represent the largest number of SEPs detected by MS reported to date. These novel SEPs might not only provide new clues for the annotation of noncoding elements in the genome but also serve as a valuable resource for functional study.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Long noncoding RNAs in cancer metastasis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/33953369/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/33953369/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Metastasis is a major contributor to cancer-associated deaths. It is characterized by a multistep process that occurs through the acquisition of molecular and phenotypic changes enabling cancer cells from a primary tumour to disseminate and colonize at distant organ sites. Over the past decade, the discovery and characterization of long noncoding RNAs (lncRNAs) have revealed the diversity of their regulatory roles, including key contributions throughout the metastatic cascade. Here, we review how lncRNAs promote metastasis by functioning in discrete pro-metastatic steps including the epithelial-mesenchymal transition, invasion and migration and organotrophic colonization, and by influencing the metastatic tumour microenvironment, often by interacting within ribonucleoprotein complexes or directly with other nucleic acid entities. We discuss well-characterized lncRNAs with in vivo phenotypes and highlight mechanistic commonalities such as convergence with the TGFβ-ZEB1/ZEB2 axis or the nuclear factor-κB pathway, in addition to lncRNAs with controversial mechanisms and the influence of methodologies on mechanistic interpretation. Furthermore, some lncRNAs can help identify tumours with increased metastatic risk and spur novel therapeutic strategies, with several lncRNAs having shown potential as novel targets for antisense oligonucleotide therapy in animal models. In addition to well-characterized examples of lncRNAs functioning in metastasis, we discuss controversies and ongoing challenges in lncRNA biology. Finally, we present areas for future study for this rapidly evolving field.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Databases make long non-coding RNAs closer</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tool/2021-03-12-db-lnc-rna/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/tool/2021-03-12-db-lnc-rna/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://v5.noncode.org/index.php&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;NONCODE&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is an integrated knowledge database dedicated to non-coding RNAs (excluding tRNAs and rRNAs). Now, there are 17 species in &lt;a href=&#34;http://v5.noncode.org/index.php&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;NONCODE&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (human, mouse, cow, rat, chicken, fruitfly, zebrafish, celegans, yeast, Arabidopsis, chimpanzee, gorilla, orangutan, rhesus macaque, opossum platypus and pig). The source of &lt;a href=&#34;http://v5.noncode.org/index.php&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;NONCODE&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; includes literature and other public databases. We searched &lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt; using key words &lt;code&gt;ncrna&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;noncoding&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;non-coding&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;no code&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;non-code&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;lncrna&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;lincrna&lt;/code&gt;. We retrieved the new identified lncRNAs and their annotation from the Supplementary Material or web site of these articles. Together with the newest data from &lt;a href=&#34;%28https://asia.ensembl.org/index.html%29&#34;&gt;Ensembl&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/refseq/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;RefSeq&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://lncrnadb.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;lncRNAdb&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gencodegenes.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;GENCODE&lt;/a&gt; were processed through a standard pipeline for each species.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://bicresources.jcbose.ac.in/zhumur/lncrbase/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;LncRBase&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a comprehensive database for long noncoding RNA (lncRNA) in Human and Mouse. With a total of 216562 lncRNA transcript entries,the database hosts information on basic lncRNA transcript features, with additional details on genomic location, overlapping small noncoding RNAs, associated Repeat Elements, associated imprinted genes, and lncRNA promoter information. Users can also search for microarray probes mapped to specific lncRNAs and associated disease information as well as search for lncRNA expression in a wide range of tissues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DIANA-&lt;a href=&#34;https://diana.e-ce.uth.gr/lncbasev3&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;LncBase&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; v3 is a reference repository with experimentally supported miRNA targets on non-coding transcripts. It catalogues approximately ~500,000 entries, corresponding to ~240,000 unique tissue and cell-type specific miRNA-lncRNA interactions. The incorporated interactions are defined by 15 distinct low-/high-throughput methodologies, corresponding to 243 distinct cell types/tissues and 162 experimental conditions. &lt;a href=&#34;https://diana.e-ce.uth.gr/lncbasev3&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;LncBase&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; indexes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;730 miRNA-lncRNA entries from manual curation of publications&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2,924 miRNA-lncRNA chimeric fragments&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2,094 interactions from the re-analysis of miRNA perturbation experiments&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;235,000 AGO-CLIP-Seq derived miRNA-lncRNA pairs from the re-analysis of 236 CLIP-Seq libraries with &lt;a href=&#34;www.microrna.gr/microCLIP&#34;&gt;microCLIP&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://starbase.sysu.edu.cn/index.php&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;ENCORI (The Encyclopedia of RNA Interactomes)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is an openly licensed and state-of-the-art platform to decode the cellular interaction networks among thousands of RNA binding proteins (RBPs) and various RNAs. We have identified millions of RBP-RNA and RNA-RNA interactions through analyzing thousands of CLIP-seq and various high-throughput sequencing data by developing new software and tools, and studied their functions and mechanisms in human diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bio-bigdata.net/LncACTdb/index.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;LncACTdb&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 3.0 is a comprehensive database of experimentally supported ceRNA interactions and personalized networks contributing to precision medicine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://lncipedia.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;LNCipedia&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a public database for long non-coding RNA (lncRNA) sequence and annotation. The current release contains 127,802 transcripts and 56,946 genes. Currently, &lt;a href=&#34;https://lncipedia.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;LNCipedia&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; offers 2,482 manually curated lncRNA articles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bio-bigdata.net/lnc2cancer/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lnc2Cancer&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, is a manually curated database that provides comprehensive experimentally supported associations between lncRNA or circRNA and human cancer. The current version of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bio-bigdata.net/lnc2cancer/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lnc2Cancer&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; documents 10,303 entries of associations between 2,659 human lncRNAs, 743 circRNAs and 216 human cancer subtypes through review of more than 1,5000 published papers. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bio-bigdata.net/lnc2cancer/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lnc2Cancer&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; also provides experimentally supported regulatory mechanism (microRNA, Transcription factor, variant, methylation and enhancer), biological function (cell growth, apoptosis, autophagy, Epithelial mesenchymal transformation, immune and coding ability) and clinical application (metastasis, recurrence, circulating, drug-resistant and prognostic) of lncRNAs and circRNAs in human cancer. Especially, an interactive analysis platform including RNA and single cell sequencing expression data is developed to help users explore lncRNAs in cancers with a standard processing pipeline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bio-bigdata.net/LnCeVar/index.jsp&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;LnCeVar&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a comprehensive database that aims to infer genomic variations that disturb lncRNA-associated ceRNA regulation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Manual curation of variation-ceRNA events from the published literature.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Manual curation of more than 2,000 experimentally supported circulating, drug-resistant and prognosis-related lncRNA biomarkers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Identification of somatic mutation-ceRNA events occurring in 33 cancers from TCGA and mutation profiles of over 1,000 cell lines from Cosmic.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Identification of CNV-ceRNA events in thousands of patients from TCGA.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Identification of SNP-ceRNA events from the 1000-Genome project.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://lncar.renlab.org/#welcome&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;lnCAR&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a catalog of human lncRNA expression profiles derived from re-annotation of public microarray expression data from over 57,000 samples spanning diverse cancers. &lt;a href=&#34;https://lncar.renlab.org/#welcome&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;lnCAR&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; enables the users to rapidly and intuitively explore differentially expressed lncRNAs of interest (annotated lncRNAs or any user-defined ones) in the context of different types of experiments. In addition, &lt;a href=&#34;https://lncar.renlab.org/#welcome&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;lnCAR&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is also a powerful platform for querying associations between lncRNA expression and cancer prognosis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Long non-coding RNAs (lncRNAs) are emerging as key factors in the regulation of various cellular processes and diseases. &lt;a href=&#34;http://bioinfo.life.hust.edu.cn/lncRNASNP#!/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;LncRNASNP&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a database providing comprehensive resources of single nucleotide polymorphisms (SNPs) in human/mouse lncRNAs. It contains SNPs in lncRNAs, SNP effects on lncRNA structure, mutation in lncRNAs and lncRNA:miRNA binding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Long noncoding RNAs (lncRNAs) play an important role in modulating gene expression or participating in some essential epigenetic regulation processes, including chromatin modification or DNA methylation. DNA methylation is a fundamental feature of epigenomes that can affect the expression of protein-coding or non-coding transcripts. &lt;a href=&#34;http://bio-bigdata.hrbmu.edu.cn/Lnc2Meth/index.jsp&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Lnc2Meth&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; aims to provide a comprehensive resource and web tool for clarifying the regulatory relationships between human lncRNAs and associated DNA methylation in diverse diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rna-society.org/rnalocate/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;RNALocate&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; aims to provide a resource for efficient manipulation, browsing and analysis of RNA subcellular localization. The second version of RNALocate documents more than 210,000 RNA-associated subcellular localization entries with experimental evidence, involving more than 110,000 RNAs with 171 subcellular localizations in 104 species. It will be of help in elucidating the entirety of RNA-associated subcellular localization, and developing new prediction methods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Long non-coding RNAs (lncRNAs) are expressed in a tissue-specific way, subcellular localizaitons of lncRNAs depend on the tissues or cell lines that they are expressed. Previous computational methods for predicting subcellular localizations of lncRNAs do not take this characteristic into account, they train a unified machine learning model for pooled lncRNAs from all available cell lines. It is of importance to develop a cell-line-specific computational method to predict lncRNA locations in different cell lines. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.csbio.sjtu.edu.cn/bioinf/lncLocator2/index.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;LncLocator&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 2.0, which trains a deep model per cell line for predicting lncRNA subcellular localization from sequences. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.csbio.sjtu.edu.cn/bioinf/lncLocator2/index.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;LncLocator&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 2.0 achieves varying effectiveness for different cell lines and demonstrates the necessity of training cell-line-specific models. Furthermore, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.csbio.sjtu.edu.cn/bioinf/lncLocator2/index.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;LncLocator&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 2.0 adopts Integrated Gradients to explain the proposed model, and find some potential patterns that determine the subcellular localizations of lncRNAs, suggesting that the subcellular localization of lncRNAs is linked to some specific nucleotides.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://lncatlas.crg.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;LncATLAS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is an easy to use web-based visualization tool to obtain useful information about expression localization of long non-coding class of RNAs. It is easy to use by just searching your lncRNA of interest in the search box. You can also use ENSEMBL gene IDs to select them. There are also some reference genes with a clear nuclear or cytoplasmatic expression profile. In some plots (3 and 4) you could also select the cell line from the dropdown menu to obtain a zoom into the distributions. Although many genes would have a similar profile among cell lines there might exist small changes. &lt;a href=&#34;https://lncatlas.crg.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;LncATLAS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; provides 6 charts that can be divided into 3 sections:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Inspect the cytoplasmic-nuclear localisation of your gene of interest (GOI): a barplot indicating the CN RCI values in each cell line for the selected gene(s)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Inspect the cytoplasmic-nuclear localisation of your GOI within the distribution of all genes: distribution of RCI values in each cell line for lncRNAs and mRNAs with the selected gene(s) highlighted&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Inspect the localisation of your GOI at sub-compartment level: localisation values within distributions for the K562 cell line subnuclear and subcytoplasmic compartments&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.exorbase.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;exoRBase&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a repository of extracellular vesicles (EVs) long RNAs (exLRs) derived from RNA-seq data analyses in different human body fluids. The exLRs contain messenger RNA (mRNA), long non-coding RNA (lncRNA), and circular RNA (circRNA). &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.exorbase.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;exoRBase&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 2.0 provides the comprehensive annotation and expression landscapes of exLRs. It will facilitate the identification of novel exLR signatures from human body fluids and will help discover new circulating biomarkers for the improvement of tumor diagnosis and therapy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://genome.igib.res.in/lncRNome/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;lncRNome&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a comprehensive searchable biologically oriented knowledgebase for long noncoding RNAs in Humans. The resource hosts information on over 17000 long noncoding RNAs in Human. The resource provides information on the types , chromosomal locations, description on the biological functions and disease associations of long noncoding RNAs. In addition, it provides access to datasets on protein-lncRNA interactions and genomic variations in lncRNA loci. The resource also provides a browsable interface for the datasets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://annolnc.gao-lab.org/index.php&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;AnnoLnc&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a web server to provide on-the-fly analysis for novel human or mouse lncRNAs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Long non-coding RNAs (lncRNAs) are an important category of non-coding RNAs (ncRNAs) which range from 200 nucleotides to multiple kilobases in length, with little or no protein-coding capacity. Circular RNAs (circRNAs) are widely expressed in diverse eukaryotic species and are characterized by covalently closed RNA loops through backsplicing events. Increasing evidence has highlighted the critical roles of lncRNAs and circRNAs in plenty of diseases development and progression. Here, we have updated the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rnanut.net/lncrnadisease/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;LncRNADisease&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; database to version 2.0 by integrating comprehensive experimentally supported and predicted ncRNA-disease associations curated from manual literatures and other resources. The new developments in &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rnanut.net/lncrnadisease/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;LncRNADisease&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; v2.0 include (I) over 40-fold ncRNA-disease associations enhancement compare to the previous version; (II) integrating experimentally supported circRNA-disease associations; (III) providing regulatory relationship among ncRNA, mRNA and miRNA; (IV) mapping disease name to the Disease Ontology and Medical Subject Headings (MeSH); (V) providing a confidence score for each ncRNA-disease association.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;RNA editing is a widespread post-transcriptional mechanism that can make discrete changes to specific nucleotide sequences within a RNA transcripts. RNA editing events can result in missense codon changes in mRNA, modulation of alternative splicing in mRNA, or modification of regulatory RNAs and their binding sites in small noncoding RNA, such as miRNA. Recent studies have developed computational methods to accurately detect more than 2 million A-to-I RNA editing from next-generation sequencing data in different species. However, the vast majority of these RNA sites are in noncoding regions of the genome and have unknown functional relevance. &lt;a href=&#34;http://bioinfo.life.hust.edu.cn/LNCediting/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;LNCediting&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; provides a comprehensive resource for the functional prediction of RNA editing in long noncoding RNAs (lncRNAs).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Long non-coding RNAs (lncRNAs) are emerging as key factors in the regulation of various cellular processes and diseases. &lt;a href=&#34;http://bioinfo.life.hust.edu.cn/lncRNASNP#!/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;LncRNASNP&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a database providing comprehensive resources of single nucleotide polymorphisms (SNPs) in human/mouse lncRNAs. It contains SNPs in lncRNAs, SNP effects on lncRNA structure, mutation in lncRNAs and lncRNA:miRNA binding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://rnasysu.com/chipbase3/index.php&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ChIPBase&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; v3.0 identified ~151,187,000 regulatory relationships between ~171,600 genes and ~3,000 regulators by analyzing ~55,000 ChIP-seq datasets, which represent a 30-fold expansion. Moreover, we de novo identified ~29,000 motif matrices of transcription factors. In addition, we constructed a novel “Enhancer” module to predict ~1,837,200 regulation regions functioning as poised, active or super enhancers under ~1300 conditions. Importantly, we constructed exhaustive coexpression maps between regulators and their target genes by integrating expression profiles of ∼65,000 normal and ∼15,000 tumor samples. We built a “Disease” module to obtain an atlas of the disease-associated variations in the regulation regions of genes. We also constructed an “EpiInter” module to explore potential interactions between epitranscriptome and epigenome. Finally, we designed “Network” module to provide extensive and gene-centred regulatory networks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Long noncoding RNAs (lncRNAs) play an important role in modulating gene expression or participating in some essential epigenetic regulation processes, including chromatin modification or DNA methylation. DNA methylation is a fundamental feature of epigenomes that can affect the expression of protein-coding or non-coding transcripts. Here, we constructed &lt;a href=&#34;http://bio-bigdata.hrbmu.edu.cn/Lnc2Meth/index.jsp&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lnc2Meth&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, aimed to provide a comprehensive resource and web tool for clarifying the regulatory relationships between human lncRNAs and associated DNA methylation in diverse diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This website &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gaemons.net/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Gaemons&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; hosts online services and databases developed by team of Dr Zhu and Dr Zhang at Southern Medical University, Guangzhou, China. And has have integrated LongTarget into &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gaemons.net/LongMan&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;LongMan&lt;/a&gt; to implement a seamless pipeline to implement this function.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;RNA editing is a widespread post-transcriptional mechanism that can make discrete changes to specific nucleotide sequences within a RNA transcripts. RNA editing events can result in missense codon changes in mRNA, modulation of alternative splicing in mRNA, or modification of regulatory RNAs and their binding sites in small noncoding RNA, such as miRNA. Recent studies have developed computational methods to accurately detect more than 2 million A-to-I RNA editing from next-generation sequencing data in different species. However, the vast majority of these RNA sites are in noncoding regions of the genome and have unknown functional relevance. &lt;a href=&#34;http://bioinfo.life.hust.edu.cn/LNCediting/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;LNCediting&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; provides a comprehensive resource for the functional prediction of RNA editing in long noncoding RNAs (lncRNAs).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;http://gtrd.biouml.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Gene Transcription Regulation Database (GTRD)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; contains uniformly annotated and processed NGS data related to gene transcription regulation: ChIP-seq, ChIP-exo, DNase-seq, MNase-seq, ATAC-seq and RNA-seq. With the latest release, the database has reached a new level of data integration. All cell types (cell lines and tissues) presented in the &lt;a href=&#34;http://gtrd.biouml.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;GTRD&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; were arranged into a dictionary and linked with different ontologies (BRENDA, Cell Ontology, Uberon, Cellosaurus and Experimental Factor Ontology) and with related experiments in specialized databases on transcription regulation (FANTOM5, ENCODE and GTEx). The updated version of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://gtrd.biouml.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;GTRD&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; provides an integrated view of transcription regulation through a dedicated web interface with advanced browsing and search capabilities, an integrated genome browser, and table reports by cell types, transcription factors, and genes of interest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://rna.sysu.edu.cn/deepbase3/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;deepBase&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a popular and openly licensed resource to facilitate the integrative and interactive display and analysis of expression, evolution, function of various ncRNAs by deeply mining thousands of high-throughput sequencing data from tissue, cancer and exosome samples. &lt;a href=&#34;https://rna.sysu.edu.cn/deepbase3/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;deepBase&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; provided the most comprehensive expression analysis of sRNAs and lncRNAs, the expression patterns of tRFs and snoRNAs from thousands of cancer and normal samples, the correlations between ncRNAs and patients’ survival and the function prediction of ncRNAs in tumor tumorigenesis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/tag/databases/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Databases&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/tool/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Tools &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Long noncoding RNAs (lncRNAs) in human lymphomas</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/35685474/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/35685474/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lymphomas are a diverse group of haematologic malignancies, which occur in infection-fighting cells of the lymphatic system. Long non-coding RNAs (lncRNAs) are non-coding RNAs, which have recently received significant attention as the main mediators of gene expression. In this review, we summarize the current knowledge on lncRNAs involved in lymphomas, their molecular functions, as well as their potential clinical value. Relevant literature was identified by a PubMed search of English language papers using the following terms: Lymphoma, LncRNA, leukemia, proliferation, apoptosis, and prognosis. LncRNAs are imperative for lymphoma carcinogenesis through affecting apoptosis, cell proliferation, invasion, and response to chemotherapy. The expression level of lncRNAs can affect chemotherapy-induced apoptosis. Taken together, lncRNA dysregulation in lymphoma cells is not only an epiphenomenon but also lncRNA transcription is critically related to the initiation and progression of lymphomas. Aberrant expression of lncRNAs can lead to the transformation of normal lymphocytes into lymphoma cells.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Decreased Expression of the Host Long-Noncoding RNA-GM Facilitates Viral Escape by Inhibiting the Kinase activity TBK1 via S-glutathionylation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/33326766/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/33326766/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Viruses have evolved multiple strategies to evade elimination by the immune system. Here we examined the contribution of host long noncoding RNAs (lncRNAs) in viral immune evasion. By functional screening of lncRNAs whose expression decreased upon viral infection of macrophages, we identified a lncRNA (lncRNA-GM, Gene Symbol: AK189470.1) that promoted type I interferon (IFN-I) production and inhibited viral replication. Deficiency of lncRNA-GM in mice increased susceptibility to viral infection and impaired IFN-I production. Mechanistically, lncRNA-GM bound to glutathione S-transferase M1 (GSTM1) and blocked GSTM1 interaction with the kinase TBK1, reducing GSTM1-mediated S-glutathionylation of TBK1. Decreased S-glutathionylation enhanced TBK1 activity and downstream production of antiviral mediators. Viral infection reprogrammed intracellular glutathione metabolism and furthermore, an oxidized glutathione mimetic could inhibit TBK1 activity and promote viral replication. Our findings reveal regulation of TBK1 by S-glutathionylation and provide insight into the viral mediated metabolic changes that impact innate immunity and viral evasion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Online tools decoding RNA-RNA regulatory networks</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tool/2020-11-10-rri/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/tool/2020-11-10-rri/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://circinteractome.nia.nih.gov/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;CircInteractome&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; predicts the miRNAs which can potentially target the circRNAs using the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.targetscan.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Targetscan&lt;/a&gt; prediction tool. This computational tool enables the prediction and mapping of binding sites for RBPs and miRNAs on reported circRNAs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights of &lt;a href=&#34;%28https://circinteractome.nia.nih.gov/%29&#34;&gt;CircInteractome&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Searches circRNAs name&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Searches the genomic position and best-matching transcripts of the circRNA&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Retrieves genomic and mature circRNA sequences&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Searches RBPs binding to a circRNA and to sequences upstream/downstream of the circRNA&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Identifies RBPs binding to the circRNA junctions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Identifies miRNAs targeting a circRNA&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Designs divergent primers for circRNAs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Designs siRNAs Specific to circRNA&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://starbase.sysu.edu.cn/index.php&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;ENCORI (The Encyclopedia of RNA Interactomes)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is an openly licensed and state-of-the-art platform to decode the cellular interaction networks among thousands of RNA binding proteins (RBPs) and various RNAs. We have identified millions of RBP-RNA and RNA-RNA interactions through analyzing thousands of CLIP-seq and various high-throughput sequencing data by developing new software and tools, and studied their functions and mechanisms in human diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/tag/databases/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Databases&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/tool/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Tools &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Translation of noncoding RNAs and cancer</title>
      <link>https://example.com/review/33038492/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/review/33038492/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some ncRNAs are translated into stable peptides or proteins, expanding the landscape of the proteome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some tools, methods and databases are designed for identifying and validating ncRNA-encoded peptides related with cancer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The translation of lncRNAs provides a novel molecular mechanism to participate in complex regulatory networks of cells.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CircRNA-encoded peptides in cancer may become drug targets and biomarkers for diagnosing or predicting the prognosis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The human genome contains thousands of noncoding RNAs (ncRNAs), which are thought to lack open reading frames (ORFs) and cannot be translated. Some ncRNAs reportedly have important functions, including epigenetic regulation, chromatin remolding, protein modification, and RNA degradation, but the functions of most ncRNAs remain elusive. Through the application and development of ribosome profiling and sequencing technologies, an increasing number of studies have discovered the translation of ncRNAs. Although ncRNAs were initially defined as noncoding RNAs, a number of ncRNAs actually contain ORFs that are translated into peptides. Here, we summarize the available methods, tools, and databases for identifying and validating ncRNA-encoded peptides/proteins, and the recent findings regarding ncRNA-encoded small peptides/proteins in cancer are compiled and synthesized. Importantly, the role of ncRNA-encoding peptides/proteins has application prospects in cancer research, but some potential challenges remain unresolved. The aim of this review is to provide a theoretical basis that might promote the discovery of more peptides/proteins encoded by ncRNAs and aid the further development of novel diagnostic and prognostic cancer markers and therapeutic targets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/review/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Reviews &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LncRNA Malat1 inhibition of TDP43 cleavage suppresses IRF3-initiated antiviral innate immunity</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32907941/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32907941/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Long noncoding RNAs (lncRNAs) involved in the regulation of antiviral innate immune responses need to be further identified. By functionally screening the lncRNAs in macrophages, here we identified lncRNA &lt;em&gt;Malat1&lt;/em&gt;, abundant in the nucleus but significantly down-regulated after viral infection, as a negative regulator of antiviral type I IFN (IFN-I) production. &lt;em&gt;Malat1&lt;/em&gt; directly bound to the transactive response DNA-binding protein (TDP43) in the nucleus and prevented activation of TDP43 by blocking the activated caspase-3-mediated TDP43 cleavage to TDP35. The cleaved TDP35 increased the nuclear IRF3 protein level by binding and degrading &lt;em&gt;Rbck1&lt;/em&gt; pre-mRNA to prevent IRF3 proteasomal degradation upon viral infection, thus selectively promoting antiviral IFN-I production. Deficiency of &lt;em&gt;Malat1&lt;/em&gt; enhanced antiviral innate responses in vivo, accompanying the increased IFN-I production and reduced viral burden. Importantly, the reduced &lt;em&gt;MALAT1&lt;/em&gt;, augmented IRF3, and increased &lt;em&gt;IFNA&lt;/em&gt; mRNA were found in peripheral blood mononuclear cells (PBMCs) from systemic lupus erythematosus (SLE) patients. Therefore, the down-regulation of &lt;em&gt;MALAT1&lt;/em&gt; in virus-infected cells or in human cells from autoimmune diseases will increase host resistance against viral infection or lead to autoinflammatory interferonopathies via the increased type I IFN production. Our results demonstrate that the nuclear &lt;em&gt;Malat1&lt;/em&gt; suppresses antiviral innate responses by targeting TDP43 activation via RNA-RBP interactive network, adding insight to the molecular regulation of innate responses and autoimmune pathogenesis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Significance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LncRNAs have been identified as regulating antiviral innate responses via different targets through various ways. Whether there is an abundant and highly conserved lncRNA in the nucleus which may regulate antiviral innate signaling through a new mechanism remains to be investigated. Here, we identify that viral infection-reduced expression of &lt;em&gt;Malat1&lt;/em&gt; feedback promotes IRF3-initiated type I IFN production in the innate response against viral infection. &lt;em&gt;Malat1&lt;/em&gt; binds to TDP43 and prevents its cleavage mediated by activated caspase-3. The cleaved TDP35 inhibits IRF3 degradation through promoting the degradation of pre-mRNA of Rbck1, an E3 ubiquitin ligase targeting IRF3. Aberrant &lt;em&gt;MALAT1&lt;/em&gt; reduction and IRF3 activation are found in SLE patients, providing one mechanistic explanation for why SLE patients always have type I interferonopathies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LncRNA PVT1 promotes gemcitabine resistance of pancreatic cancer via activating Wnt/β-catenin and autophagy pathway through modulating the miR-619-5p/Pygo2 and miR-619-5p/ATG14 axes</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/32727463/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/32727463/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pancreatic cancer is one of the most lethal malignancies and has an extremely poor diagnosis and prognosis. The development of resistance to gemcitabine is still a major challenge. The long noncoding RNA PVT1 was reported to be involved in carcinogenesis and chemoresistance; however, the mechanism by which PVT1 regulates the sensitivity of pancreatic cancer to gemcitabine remains poorly understood.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The viability of pancreatic cancer cells was assessed by MTT assay in vitro and xenograft tumor formation assay in vivo. The expression levels of PVT1 and miR-619-5p were detected by quantitative real-time polymerase chain reaction (qRT-PCR). Western blotting analysis and qRT-PCR were performed to assess the protein and mRNA levels of Pygo2 and ATG14, respectively. Autophagy was explored via autophagic flux detection under confocal microscopy and autophagic vacuole investigation under transmission electron microscopy (TEM). The functional role and mechanism of PVT1 were further investigated by gain- and loss-of-function assays in vitro.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the present study, we demonstrated that PVT1 was up-regulated in gemcitabine-resistant pancreatic cancer cell lines. Gain- and loss-of-function assays revealed that PVT1 impaired sensitivity to gemcitabine in vitro and in vivo. We further found that PVT1 up-regulated the expression of both Pygo2 and ATG14 and thus regulated Wnt/β-catenin signaling and autophagic activity to overcome gemcitabine resistance through sponging miR-619-5p. Moreover, we discovered three TCF/LEF binding elements (TBEs) in the promoter region of PVT1, and activation of Wnt/β-catenin signaling mediated by the up-regulation of Pygo2 increased PVT1 expression by direct binding to the TBE region. Furthermore, PVT1 was discovered to interact with ATG14, thus promoting assembly of the autophagy specific complex I (PtdIns3K-C1) and ATG14-dependent class III PtdIns3K activity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These data indicate that PVT1 plays a critical role in the sensitivity of pancreatic cancer to gemcitabine and highlight its potential as a valuable target for pancreatic cancer therapy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>lncRNA Sensing of a Viral Suppressor of RNAi Activates Non-canonical Innate Immune Signaling in Drosophila</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/31917956/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/31917956/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Antiviral immunity in insects is mediated by the RNA interference (RNAi) pathway. Viruses evade antiviral RNAi by expressing virulence factors known as viral suppressors of RNAi (VSR). Here, we report the identification of VINR, a Drosophila VSR-interacting long non-coding (lnc) RNA that activates non-canonical innate immune signaling upon detection of the dsRNA-binding VSR of Drosophila C virus (DCV). VINR is required for the induction of antimicrobial peptide (AMP) genes but dispensable for antiviral RNAi. VINR functions by preventing the ubiquitin proteasome-dependent degradation of Cactin, a coiled-coil and arginine-serine-rich domain-containing protein that regulates a non-cannonical antimicrobial pathway for AMP induction. CRISPR-Cas9 knockout of VINR in Drosophila cells enhances DCV replication independently of antiviral RNAi, and VINR-knockout adult flies exhibit enhanced disease susceptibility to DCV and bacteria. Our findings reveal a counter counter-defense strategy activated by a lncRNA in response to the viral suppression of the primary antiviral RNAi immunity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LncRNA PTPRE-AS1 modulates M2 macrophage activation and inflammatory diseases by epigenetic promotion of PTPRE</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/31844669/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/31844669/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Long noncoding RNAs (lncRNAs) are important regulators of diverse biological processes; however, their function in macrophage activation is undefined. We describe a new regulatory mechanism, where an unreported lncRNA, &lt;em&gt;PTPRE-AS1&lt;/em&gt;, targets receptor-type tyrosine protein phosphatase ε (PTPRE) to regulate macrophage activation. &lt;em&gt;PTPRE-AS1&lt;/em&gt; was selectively expressed in IL-4-stimulated macrophages, and its knockdown promoted M2 macrophage activation via MAPK/ERK 1/2 pathway. In vivo, PTPRE-AS1 deficiency enhanced IL-4-mediated M2 macrophage activation and accelerated pulmonary allergic inflammation while reducing chemical-induced colitis. Mechanistically, &lt;em&gt;PTPRE-AS1&lt;/em&gt; bound WDR5 directly, modulating H3K4me3 of the &lt;em&gt;PTPRE&lt;/em&gt; promoter to regulate &lt;em&gt;PTPRE&lt;/em&gt;-dependent signaling during M2 macrophage activation. Further, the expression of &lt;em&gt;PTPRE-AS1&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;PTPRE&lt;/em&gt; was significantly lower in peripheral blood mononuclear cells from patients with allergic asthma. These results provide evidence supporting the importance of &lt;em&gt;PTPRE-AS1&lt;/em&gt; in controlling macrophage function and the potential utility of &lt;em&gt;PTPRE-AS1&lt;/em&gt; as a target for controlling inflammatory diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A genome-wide long noncoding RNA CRISPRi screen identifies PRANCR as a novel regulator of epidermal homeostasis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/31804951/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/31804951/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Genome-wide association studies indicate that many disease susceptibility regions reside in non-protein-coding regions of the genome. Long noncoding RNAs (lncRNAs) are a major component of the noncoding genome, but their biological impacts are not fully understood. Here, we performed a CRISPR interference (CRISPRi) screen on 2263 epidermis-expressed lncRNAs and identified nine novel candidate lncRNAs regulating keratinocyte proliferation. We further characterized a top hit from the screen, progenitor renewal associated non-coding RNA (&lt;em&gt;PRANCR&lt;/em&gt;), using RNA interference-mediated knockdown and phenotypic analysis in organotypic human tissue. PRANCR regulates keratinocyte proliferation, cell cycle progression, and clonogenicity. &lt;em&gt;PRANCR&lt;/em&gt;-deficient epidermis displayed impaired stratification with reduced expression of differentiation genes that are altered in human skin diseases, including keratins 1 and 10, filaggrin, and loricrin. Transcriptome analysis showed that &lt;em&gt;PRANCR&lt;/em&gt; controls the expression of 1136 genes, with strong enrichment for late cell cycle genes containing a CHR promoter element. In addition, _PRANCR _depletion led to increased levels of both total and nuclear CDKN1A (also known as p21), which is known to govern both keratinocyte proliferation and differentiation. Collectively, these data show that &lt;em&gt;PRANCR&lt;/em&gt; is a novel lncRNA regulating epidermal homeostasis and identify other lncRNA candidates that may have roles in this process as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LncRNA-HGBC stabilized by HuR promotes gallbladder cancer progression by regulating miR-502-3p/SET/AKT axis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/31752906/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/31752906/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Erratum in:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Correction to: &lt;a href=&#34;https://molecular-cancer.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12943-021-01386-8&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;LncRNA-HGBC stabilized by HuR promotes gallbladder cancer progression by regulating miR-502-3p/SET/AKT axis&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Backgrounds:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Long non-coding RNAs (lncRNAs) are essential factors that regulate tumor development and metastasis via diverse molecular mechanisms in a broad type of cancers. However, the pathological roles of lncRNAs in gallbladder carcinoma (GBC) remain largely unknown. Here we discovered a novel lncRNA termed lncRNA Highly expressed in GBC (lncRNA-HGBC) which was upregulated in GBC tissue and aimed to investigate its role and regulatory mechanism in the development and progression of GBC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The expression level of lncRNA-HGBC in GBC tissue and different cell lines was determined by quantitative real-time PCR. The full length of lncRNA-HGBC was obtained by 5&amp;rsquo; and 3&amp;rsquo; rapid amplification of the cDNA ends (RACE). Cellular localization of lncRNA-HGBC was detected by fluorescence in situ hybridization (FISH) assays and subcellular fractionation assay. In vitro and in vivo assays were preformed to explore the biological effects of lncRNA-HGBC in GBC cells. RNA pull-down assay, mass spectrometry, and RNA immunoprecipitation (RIP) assay were used to identify lncRNA-HGBC-interacting proteins. Dual luciferase reporter assays, AGO2-RIP, and MS2-RIP assays were performed to verify the interaction between lncRNA-HGBC and miR-502-3p.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We found that lncRNA-HGBC was upregulated in GBC and its upregulation could predict poor survival. Overexpression or knockdown of lncRNA-HGBC in GBC cell lines resulted in increased or decreased, respectively, cell proliferation and invasion in vitro and in xenografted tumors. LncRNA-HGBC specifically bound to RNA binding protein Hu Antigen R (HuR) that in turn stabilized lncRNA-HGBC. LncRNA-HGBC functioned as a competitive endogenous RNA to bind to miR-502-3p that inhibits target gene SET. Overexpression, knockdown or mutation of lncRNA-HGBC altered the inhibitory effects of miR-502-3p on SET expression and downstream activation of AKT. Clinically, lncRNA-HGBC expression was negatively correlated with miR-502-3p, but positively correlated with SET and HuR in GBC tissue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our study demonstrates that lncRNA-HGBC promotes GBC metastasis via activation of the miR-502-3p-SET-AKT cascade, pointing to lncRNA-HGBC as a new prognostic predictor and a therapeutic target.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A high-throughput screen identifies the long non-coding RNA DRAIC as a regulator of autophagy</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/30872794/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/30872794/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Autophagy is a conserved degradation process that occurs in all eukaryotic cells and its dysfunction has been associated with various diseases including cancer. While a number of large-scale attempts have recently identified new molecular players in autophagy regulation, including proteins and microRNAs, little is known regarding the function of long non-coding RNAs (lncRNAs) in the regulation of this process. To identify new long non-coding RNAs with functional implications in autophagy, we performed a high-throughput RNAi screen targeting more than 600 lncRNA transcripts and monitored their effects on autophagy in MCF-7 cells. We identified 63 lncRNAs that affected GFP-LC3B puncta numbers significantly. We validated the strongest hit, the lncRNA DRAIC previously shown to impact cell proliferation, and revealed a novel role for this lncRNA in the regulation of autophagic flux. Interestingly, we find DRAIC&amp;rsquo;s pro-proliferative effects to be autophagy-independent. This study serves as a valuable resource for researchers from both the lncRNA and autophagy fields as it advances the current understanding of autophagy regulation by non-coding RNAs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Network of Noncoding Regulatory RNAs Acts in the Mammalian Brain</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/29887379/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/29887379/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Noncoding RNAs (ncRNAs) play increasingly appreciated gene-regulatory roles. Here, we describe a regulatory network centered on four ncRNAs-a long ncRNA, a circular RNA, and two microRNAs-using gene editing in mice to probe the molecular consequences of disrupting key components of this network. The long ncRNA Cyrano uses an extensively paired site to miR-7 to trigger destruction of this microRNA. Cyrano-directed miR-7 degradation is much more effective than previously described examples of target-directed microRNA degradation, which come primarily from studies of artificial and viral RNAs. By reducing miR-7 levels, Cyrano prevents repression of miR-7-targeted mRNAs and enables accumulation of Cdr1as, a circular RNA known to regulate neuronal activity. Without Cyrano, excess miR-7 causes cytoplasmic destruction of Cdr1as in neurons, in part through enhanced slicing of Cdr1as by a second miRNA, miR-671. Thus, several types of ncRNAs can collaborate to establish a sophisticated regulatory network.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Recognition of an Inducible Host lncRNA by RIG-I Feedback Restricts Innate Immune Response</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/29706547/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/29706547/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The innate RNA sensor RIG-I is critical in the initiation of antiviral type I interferons (IFNs) production upon recognition of &amp;ldquo;non-self&amp;rdquo; viral RNAs. Here, we identify a host-derived, IFN-inducible long noncoding RNA, lnc-Lsm3b, that can compete with viral RNAs in the binding of RIG-I monomers and feedback inactivate the RIG-I innate function at late stage of innate response. Mechanistically, binding of lnc-Lsm3b restricts RIG-I protein&amp;rsquo;s conformational shift and prevents downstream signaling, thereby terminating type I IFNs production. Multivalent structural motifs and long-stem structure are critical features of lnc-Lsm3b for RIG-I binding and inhibition. These data reveal a non-canonical self-recognition mode in the regulation of immune response and demonstrate an important role of an inducible &amp;ldquo;self&amp;rdquo; lncRNA acting as a potent molecular decoy actively saturating RIG-I binding sites to restrict the duration of &amp;ldquo;non-self&amp;rdquo; RNA-induced innate immune response and maintaining immune homeostasis, with potential utility in inflammatory disease management.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
