<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>MAPK | BM Sci-Tech Memento</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/mapk/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/mapk/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>MAPK</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>MAPK</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/mapk/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>The main e-cigarette component vegetable glycerin enhances neutrophil migration and fibrosis in endotoxin-induced lung injury via p38 MAPK activation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36627690/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36627690/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We investigated the effects of vegetable glycerin (VG), a main e-cigarette constituent, on endotoxin-induced acute lung injury (ALI). Mice received intratracheal administration of 30% VG in phosphate buffered saline (PBS) vehicle or only PBS (control) for 4 days. On Day 5, mice received an intratracheal instillation of lipopolysaccharide (LPS) (LPS group and VG + LPS group) or PBS (VG group and control group). Lung histopathology, expression of chemokine receptors, and regulatory signaling were analyzed 24 h after the Day 5 treatment. VG significantly increased ALI-associated histopathological and fibrotic changes in both the VG group and LPS-induced ALI mice (VG + LPS group). Immunohistochemistry (IHC) and western blot analyses revealed that VG administration resulted in upregulation of neutrophil markers [lymphocyte antigen 6 complex locus G6D (Ly6G) and myeloperoxidase (MPO)] as well as upregulation of the expression of transforming growth factor-β (TGF-β), a central mediator of fibrogenesis, in the lungs of both VG and VG + LPS groups. VG enhanced the expression of adhesion molecules [very late antigen 4 (VLA-4) and vascular cell adhesion molecule 1 (VCAM-1)] and increased activation of p38 mitogen-activated protein kinase (p38 MAPK) to prompt neutrophil recruitment in the lungs of mice with ALI. Intraperitoneal administration of a p38 inhibitor attenuated these histopathological changes significantly as well as VG-induced upregulation in expression of Ly6G, MPO, VLA-4, VCAM-1, TGF-β, and collagen-1 in mice with ALI. In conclusion, VG enhances neutrophil chemotaxis and fibrosis and it amplifies the inflammatory response associated with LPS-induced ALI in the lungs via enhancement of p38 MAPK activity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eupalinolide B attenuates lipopolysaccharide-induced acute lung injury through inhibition of NF-κB and MAPKs signaling by targeting TAK1 protein</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35988521/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35988521/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Eupalinolide B (EB) inhibit LPS-induced acute lung injury in mice.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;EB directly binds to TAK1, and inhibits NF-κB and MAPKs activation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The α,γ-unsaturated lactone of EB is vital for its anti-inflammatory effect.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acute lung injury (ALI) is a life-threatening disease characterized by severe inflammatory response, which has no pharmacological therapy in clinic. In this study, we found that eupalinolide B (EB), a sesquiterpene lactone isolated from Eupatorium lindleyanum, significantly ameliorated lipopolysaccharide (LPS)-induced ALI in mice, which manifests as reduction in lung injury score, activity of myeloperoxidase, and release of cytokines interleukin (IL)-1β, IL-6, tumor necrosis factor-α (TNF-α), and monocyte chemoattractant protein-1 (MCP-1). In RAW264.7 murine macrophages, EB effectively inhibited LPS-induced production of nitric oxide (NO) and prostaglandin E2 (PGE2) by down-regulating the expression of inducible nitric oxide synthase (iNOS) and cyclooxygenase-2 (COX2), respectively. Mechanistically, EB not only blocked LPS-induced phosphorylation of inhibitor of nuclear factor kappa B kinase-α/β (IKKα/β), phosphorylation and degradation of inhibitor of nuclear factor-kappa B alpha (IκBα), and phosphorylation and nuclear translocation of nuclear factor-kappa B (NF-κB) P65, but also suppressed LPS-induced phosphorylation of mitogen-activated protein kinases (MAPKs) &lt;em&gt;in vitro&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt;. Through cellular thermal shift assay and western blotting, EB was demonstrated to target and inactivate transforming growth factor β activated kinase-1 (TAK1), which is an important upstream kinase for the activation of NF-κB and MAPKs pathways. Additionally, EB-mediated actions were markedly abolished by dithiothreitol in LPS-exposed RAW264.7 cells, suggesting a crucial role of the α,γ-unsaturated lactone for the anti-inflammatory activity of EB. In conclusion, our findings showed that EB could effectively alleviate ALI in mice, and attenuate inflammatory response by inhibiting the activation of TAK1, and TAK1-mediated activation of NF-κB and MAPKs cascades.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oxypeucedanin relieves LPS-induced acute lung injury by inhibiting the inflammation and maintaining the integrity of the lung air-blood barrier</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35985771/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35985771/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Introduction:&lt;/em&gt; Acute lung injury (ALI) is commonly accompanied by a severe inflammatory reaction process, and effectively managing inflammatory reactions is an important therapeutic approach for alleviating ALI. Macrophages play an important role in the inflammatory response, and this role is proinflammatory in the early stages of inflammation and anti-inflammatory in the late stages. Oxypeucedanin is a natural product with a wide range of pharmacological functions. This study aimed to determine the effect of oxypeucedanin on lipopolysaccharide (LPS)-induced ALI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods and results:&lt;/em&gt; In this study, the following experiments were performed based on LPS-induced models &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;in vitro&lt;/em&gt;. Using myeloperoxidase activity measurement, ELISA, qRT-PCR, and Western blotting, we found that oxypeucedanin modulated the activity of myeloperoxidase and decreased the expression levels of inflammatory mediators such as TNF-α, IL-6, IL-1β, MPO, COX-2 and iNOS in LPS-induced inflammation models. Meanwhile, oxypeucedanin inhibited the activation of PI3K/AKT and its downstream NF-κB and MAPK signaling pathways. In addition, oxypeucedanin significantly decreased the pulmonary vascular permeability, which was induced by LPSs, and the enhanced expression of tight junction proteins (Occludin and Claudin 3).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/em&gt; In conclusion, this study demonstrated that the anti-inflammatory mechanism of oxypeucedanin is associated with the inhibition of the activation of PI3K/AKT/NF-κB and MAPK signaling pathways and the maintenance of the integrity of the lung air-blood barrier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Acadesine alleviates acute pancreatitis-related lung injury by mediating the barrier protective function of pulmonary microvascular endothelial cells</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35987144/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35987144/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pretreatment with acadesine shows therapeutic potential SAP-ALI in vivo and vitro.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Endothelial injury is critical for the initiation and progression of severe acute pancreatitis-related acute lung injury.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The beneficial effects of acadesine may involve reducing ROS accumulation and inhibiting apoptosis.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Acadesine inhibits the impairment of SAP-ALI by activating the AMPK/Nrf2 pathway.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Severe acute pancreatitis (SAP) is a condition characterized by highly fatal acute inflammation and is usually associated with multiple organ dysfunction syndrome. Acute lung injury (ALI) is the most common complications of SAP, which is the accelerator of other organ dysfunction caused by SAP and the primary cause of early death due to SAP. Acadesine, an adenosine analog and an AMPK activator, has been discovered to modulate glucose and lipid metabolism, and inhibit the production of pro-inflammatory cytokines and iNOS. However, its role in SAP-ALI and its mechanism remains unclear and need to be explored. Herein, we discovered that acadesine mitigated the generation of reactive oxygen species (ROS) in human pulmonary microvascular endothelial cells (HPMECs), alleviated apoptosis and recovered barrier integrity, thereby contributing to anti-inflammatory effects in vitro and in vivo. Moreover, Nrf2 deficiency partially eliminated the effects of acadesine-induced antioxidant effects and thus weakened the protective effects on cells and Nrf2-knockout (Nrf2&lt;Sup&gt;-/-&lt;/Sup&gt;) mice. This study demonstrates that acadesine attenuated SAP-ALI associated inflammation and tissue damage by modulating the Nrf2-dependent antioxidant pathway by triggering AMPK. These findings are of great significance for the treatment of SAP-related lung injury.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Macrophage SAMSN1 protects against sepsis-induced acute lung injury in mice</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35981417/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35981417/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Objective:&lt;/em&gt; Inflammation and oxidative stress contribute to the progression of sepsis-induced acute lung injury (ALI). SAM domain, SH3 domain and nuclear localization signals 1 (SAMSN1) is a signaling adaptor protein, and mainly regulates inflammatory response of various immune cells. The present study generates macrophage-specific SAMSN1-knockout (Samsn1MKO) and SAMSN1-transgenic (Samsn1MTG) mice to investigate its role and mechanism in sepsis-induced ALI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;Samsn1&lt;sup&gt;MKO&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Samsn1&lt;sup&gt;MTG&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; mice were exposed to lipopolysaccharide (LPS) instillation or cecal ligation and puncture (CLP) surgery to induce sepsis-induced ALI. Bone marrow transplantation, cellular depletion and non-invasive adoptive transfer of bone marrow-derived macrophages (BMDMs) were performed to validate the role of macrophage SAMSN1 in sepsis-induced ALI in vivo. Meanwhile, BMDMs were isolated from Samsn1MKO or Samsn1MTG mice to further clarify the role of SAMSN1 in vitro.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; Macrophage SAMSN1 expression was increased in response to LPS stimulation, and negatively correlated with LPS-induced ALI in mice. Macrophage SAMSN1 deficiency exacerbated, while macrophage SAMSN1 overexpression ameliorated LPS-induced inflammation, oxidative stress and ALI in mice and in BMDMs. Mechanistically, we found that macrophage SAMSN1 overexpression prevented LPS-induced ALI though activating AMP-activated protein kinase α2 (AMPKα2) &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;in vitro&lt;/em&gt;. Further studies revealed that SAMSN1 directly bound to growth factor receptor bound protein 2-associated protein 1 (GAB1) to prevent its protein degradation, and subsequently enhanced protein kinase A (PKA)/AMPKα2 activation in a protein tyrosine phosphatase, non-receptor type 11 (PTPN11, also known as SHP2)-dependent manner. Moreover, we observed that macrophage SAMSN1 overexpression diminished CLP-induced ALI in mice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/em&gt; Our study documents the protective role of macrophage SAMSN1 against sepsis-induced inflammation, oxidative stress and ALI through activating AMPKα2 in a GAB1/SHP2/PKA pathway, and defines it as a promising biomarker and therapeutic target to treat sepsis-induced ALI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Identification of the key ferroptosis-related genes involved in sepsis progression and experimental validation in vivo</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36188533/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36188533/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Ferroptosis has a vital role in sepsis, but the mechanism is not known. Understanding the mechanism of ferroptosis during sepsis will aid in developing improved therapeutic strategies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; We used the Gene Expression Omnibus database and FerrDb database to obtain ferroptosis-related differentially expressed genes (DEGs) between sepsis patients and healthy volunteers (HVs). Analyses of PPI networks, functional enrichment, as well as use of the MCODE algorithm were used to identify key ferroptosis-related DEGs. Expression of key ferroptosis-related DEGs was verified using: GSE57065 and GSE65682 datasets; rats in which ferroptosis was induced with erastin; sepsis-induced acute lung injury (siALI) rats. The effects of acupoint catgut embedding (ACE) on ferroptosis and expression of key ferroptosis-related DEGs in the lungs of siALI rats were also observed. A Cox proportional hazard model was used to verify the effect of key ferroptosis-related DEGs on the survival of sepsis patients. Cytoscape was used to construct ceRNA networks and gene-transcription factor networks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; Between sepsis patients and HVs, we identified 33 ferroptosis-related DEGs. According to analyses of PPI networks and the MCODE algorithm, we obtained four modules, of which the most significant module contained nine ferroptosis-related DEGs. Functional-enrichment analyses showed that four of the nine DEGs were enriched in the MAPK signaling pathway: &lt;em&gt;MAPK14&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;VEGFA&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;TGFBR1&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;DUSP1&lt;/em&gt;. We verified expression of these four genes in GSE57065 and GSE65682 datasets and ferroptosis rats. In addition, expression of these four genes and that of the oxidative-stress indicators GSSG and MDA was upregulated, and glutathione peroxidase-4 (GPX4) expression was downregulated, in siALI rats, but ACE reversed these changes. The Cox proportional hazard model showed that survival of sepsis patients in the high-risk group was shorter than that in the low-risk group. We found that the XIST-hsa-let-7b-5p-TGFBR1/DUSP1 ceRNA network and transcription factor E2F1 may be important regulators of these four DEGs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/em&gt; Our results suggest that &lt;em&gt;MAPK14&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;VEGFA,&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;TGFBR1&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;DUSP1&lt;/em&gt; may be key regulatory targets of ferroptosis in sepsis, and that ACE pretreatment may be antioxidant treatment for sepsis and alleviate ferroptosis. These findings provide a basis for further ferroptosis-related study in sepsis and provide new targets for its treatment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Allyl methyl trisulfide protected against LPS-induced acute lung injury in mice via inhibition of the NF-κB and MAPK pathways</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/36003507/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/36003507/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Allyl methyl trisulfide (AMTS) is one major lipid-soluble organosulfur compound of garlic. Previous studies have reported the potential therapeutic effect of garlic on acute lung injury (ALI) or its severe condition acute respiratory distress syndrome (ARDS), but the specific substances that exert the regulatory effects are still unclear. In this study, we investigate the protective effects of AMTS on lipopolysaccharide (LPS)-induced ALI mice and explored the underlying mechanisms. &lt;em&gt;In vivo&lt;/em&gt; experiments, ICR mice were pretreated with 25-100 mg/kg AMTS for 7 days and followed by intratracheal instillation of LPS (1.5 mg/kg). The results showed that AMTS significantly attenuated LPS-induced deterioration of lung pathology, demonstrated by ameliorative edema and protein leakage, and improved pulmonary histopathological morphology. Meanwhile, the expression of inflammatory mediators and the infiltration of inflammation-regulation cells induced by LPS were also inhibited. &lt;em&gt;In vitro&lt;/em&gt; experiments also revealed that AMTS could alleviate inflammation response and inhibit the exaggeration of macrophage M1 polarization in LPS-induced RAW264.7 cells. Mechanistically, we identified that AMTS treatment could attenuate the LPS-induced elevation of protein expression of p-IκBα, nuclear NF-κB-p65, COX2, iNOS, p-P38, p-ERK1/2, and p-JNK. Collectively, these data suggest that AMTS could attenuate LPS-induced ALI and the molecular mechanisms should be related to the suppression of the NF-κB and MAPKs pathways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extracellular histones induce inflammation and senescence of vascular smooth muscle cells by activating the AMPK/FOXO4 signaling pathway</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35913584/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35913584/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background:&lt;/em&gt; Sepsis is an abnormal immune-inflammatory response that is mainly caused by infection. It can lead to life-threatening organ dysfunction and death. Severely damaged tissue cells will release intracellular histones into the circulation as damage-related molecular patterns (DAMPs) to accelerate the systemic immune response. Although various histone-related cytotoxicity mechanisms have been explored, those that affect extracellular histones involved in vascular smooth muscle cell (VSMC) dysfunction are yet to be determined.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; Mouse aortic vascular smooth muscle cells (VSMCs) were stimulated with different concentrations of histones, and cell viability was detected by CCK-8 assay. Cellular senescence was assessed by SA β-gal staining. C57BL/6 mice were treated with histones with or without BML-275 treatment. RT-qPCR was performed to determine the expression of inflammatory cytokines. Western blotting was used to analyze the expression of NLRP3, ASC and caspase-1 inflammasome proteins. The interaction of NLRP3 and ASC was detected by CoIP and immunofluorescence staining.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; In this study, we found that extracellular histones induced senescence and inflammatory response in a dose-dependent manner in cultured VSMCs. Histone treatment significantly promoted apoptosis-associated speck-like protein containing CARD (ASC) as well as NACHT, LRR and PYD domains-containing protein 3 (NLRP3) interaction of inflammasomes in VSMCs. Forkhead box protein O4 (FOXO4), which is a downstream effector molecule of extracellular histones, was found to be involved in histone-regulated VSMC inflammatory response and senescence. Furthermore, the 5&amp;rsquo;-AMP-activated protein kinase (AMPK) signaling pathway was confirmed to mediate extracellular histone-induced FOXO4 expression, and blocking this signaling pathway with an inhibitor can suppress vascular inflammation induced by extracellular histones &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;in vitro&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/em&gt; Extracellular histones induce inflammation and senescence in VSMCs, and blocking the AMPK/FOXO4 pathway is a potential target for the treatment of histonemediated organ injury.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Glaesserella parasuis induces IL-17 production might through PKC-ERK/MAPK and IκB/NF-κB signaling pathways</title>
      <link>https://example.com/article/35932516/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/article/35932516/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;G. parasuis&lt;/em&gt; infections upregulated IL-17 production both in vitro and in vivo.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Virulent &lt;em&gt;G. parasuis&lt;/em&gt; strains could induced higher IL-17 production.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IL-17 expression positively correlated with degree of pathological tissue injury.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;G. parasuis&lt;/em&gt; infection induced IL-17 production through PKC-ERK/MAPK and IκB/NF-κB pathways.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In our previous study, the outer membrane protein P2 of &lt;em&gt;Glaesserella parasuis&lt;/em&gt; (&lt;em&gt;G. parasuis&lt;/em&gt;) induced the production of interleukin-17A (IL-17A) in host cells. However, how the &lt;em&gt;G. parasuis&lt;/em&gt; infection produces IL-17A in the host is unknown. In this study, at 48 hpi in piglets, the proportion of Th17 cells in the peripheral blood significantly increased as determined by flow cytometry, but the overall proportion was low. IL-17 mRNA and protein levels significantly increased in the lungs and spleens of infected piglets. Histopathological examination staining, immunohistochemistry and viability counts, revealed that IL-17 expression might be positively correlated with bacterial content and the degree of pathological injury in lung and spleen tissues. Furthermore, when infected with the &lt;em&gt;G. parasuis&lt;/em&gt; Nagasaki strain compared with avirulent strain C5, the primary porcine alveolar macrophages (PAMs) significantly produced IL-17 in a time-dose dependent manner. In addition, we demonstrated that PKC, MEK and NF-κB signaling pathways were essential for &lt;em&gt;G. parasuis&lt;/em&gt;-induced IL-17 production because the addition of corresponding inhibitors dramatically reduced IL-17 mRNA production. The phosphorylation levels of PKC, ERK1/2 and IκB in &lt;em&gt;G. parasuis&lt;/em&gt;-infected primary PAMs also increased significantly as the infection dose increased as assessed by western blotting. Thus, these finding imply that IL-17 induced by &lt;em&gt;G. parasuis&lt;/em&gt; infection is dependent on activation of PKC-ERK/MAPK and IκB/NF-κB signaling pathways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/article/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Articles &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Homepage &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
